<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- freesand-->
<!-- Game Text - New -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<!--Please place any new text entries into this file-->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Great People[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Time and again through history, there have arisen men and women who have profoundly changed the world around them - artists, scientists, prophets and others whose genius sets them head and shoulders above the rest. In Civilization IV, such visionaries are called "Great People."[PARAGRAPH:2]There are five different kinds of great people in the game: Great Prophets, Great Merchants, Great Artists, Great Scientists, and Great Engineers. Each has a special ability.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Generating Great People[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Great people are generated in cities. Each city generates a separate pool of "great people points" - when the city has earned enough points, it will generate a great person. The cost of generating a great person escalates throughout the game: the first great person costs 100 great people points, the second costs 200, and so forth. (The number of points needed to produce a great person is different on the Quick and Epic game speeds.)[PARAGRAPH:2]The first civilization to discover certain technologies will also receive a free great person in their capital city. For example, the first civ to discover [LINK=TECH_MUSIC]Music[\LINK] receives a Great Artist.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Great People Points[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A city generates great people points in a number of ways: by constructing [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK], by assigning citizens to be specialists, and by choosing certain [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Wonders:[\BOLD] A wonder will generate a certain number of great people points each turn. Further, some wonders can increase a city's (or entire civilization's!) great people point generation significantly (see the [LINK=BUILDING_PARTHENON]Parthenon[\LINK] for an example). Like specialists (see next), some wonders increase the chances of generating a specific type of great person in their city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Specialists:[\BOLD] In each [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City[\LINK] you can assign citizens to be "specialists." Each specialist provides some kind of production bonus to its city; in addition, most generate great people points (the citizen specialist being the sole exception). Further, the kinds of specialists you have in a city determine which great people you generate: if all of your specialists in a city are priests, when that city generates a great person, he or she will be a great prophet. If half the specialists are merchants and the other half artists, you'll have a fifty-fifty chance of generating a great artist or great merchant.Moving the mouse over the great person points bar will display the percentage of getting each type of great person.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Civics:[\BOLD] Some [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] increase the speed at which you generate great people.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Great People Characterists[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]As mentioned above, there are five types of great people. Each type has its own special abilities, but they all share some characteristics:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Can Discover New Technologies:[\BOLD] You can expend a great person to discover a new technology. Typically this technology will be in the great person's area of expertise (prophets will usually discover religious technologies and so on), but not always. Once all of the relatively inexpensive technologies have been discovered, the great person may not be able to entirely discover a new tech, but he or she can dramatically decrease the time it takes you to discover it.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Golden Ages:[\BOLD] You can expend two or more great people to start a [LINK=CONCEPT_GOLDEN_AGE]"Golden Age"[\LINK]; see that section for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Settling in Cities:[\BOLD] All great persons also have the ability to settle in a city as a sort of "super-specialist". Settling a great person in a city will add certain bonuses to that city each turn; for example, a Great Prophet will add 2 production and 5 gold to the city it settles in. [PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Special Abilities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] In addition to their common abilities, each great person type has other unique abilities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Artists:[\BOLD] Great Artists can create great works of art in a city; this immediately gives that city additional [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Culture[\LINK] points (from 2,000 to 6,000, depending upon game speed). This is extremely useful if a city is under cultural threat from a neighbor (or you wish to culturally attack those cities!). Great Artists can also "permanently settle" in a city, providing a continuing large cultural and small research boost to the city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Engineers:[\BOLD] Great Engineers can "hurry" a city's production, greatly speeding up the creation of whatever the city is presently constructing. Most early wonders can be completed in a single turn by Great Engineers, and later ones can be sped up dramatically. Great Engineers can permanently settle in a city, providing a continuing large production and small research boost to that city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Merchants:[\BOLD] A Great Merchant can conduct a "trade mission" which will immediately give you a whole bunch of gold. To conduct a trade mission, first move the merchant to a wealthy and powerful city as far away from your cities as possible. When the merchant reaches the target city you'll be able to conduct the mission; trade missions can ONLY be carried out in foreign cities. The value of the mission increases the further away and wealthier the target city is. Great Merchants can also settle permanently in a city, providing a continuing large commerce and small food boost to the city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Prophet:[\BOLD] Great Prophets can create religious shrines - the [LINK=BUILDING_JEWISH_SHRINE]Temple of Solomon[\LINK] and the [LINK=BUILDING_CONFUCIAN_SHRINE]Kong Miao[\LINK], for example. However, Great Prophets can create religious shrines ONLY in a city where a religion was founded. Using a Great Prophet is the only way to build a religion's shrine. Great Prophets can also settle in a city, providing a continuing large commerce and small production boost to that city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Scientist:[\BOLD] Great Scientists can construct an [LINK=BUILDING_ACADEMY]Academy[\LINK], a building which greatly boots a city's scientific research as well as its culture. Great Scientists can also settle permanently in a city, providing a large research and small production boost to the city.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]历史伟人[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在历史长河中，出现了许多对世界产生过深刻影响的天才人物——艺术家，科学家，预言家等等，他们的成就远远超越常人。在文明IV中，这样的人物被称为“历史伟人”。[PARAGRAPH:2]游戏中共有五种历史伟人：大预言家，大商业家，大艺术家，大科学家，大工程师。每种伟人都有特殊的作用。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]产生历史伟人[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]历史伟人在城市中产生。每座城市都可积累一定的“历史伟人点数”——当城市积累了足够的点数，将产生一位历史伟人。产生历史伟人所需点数会随着游戏的进程而提升：第一位历史伟人需要100历史伟人点数，第二位需要200，以此类推。（具体需要的点数在游戏速度设为快速和史诗时会有变化.）[PARAGRAPH:2]率先发现特定科技的文明可自动在首都产生一位历史伟人。例如，率先发现[LINK=TECH_MUSIC]音乐[\LINK]的文明可获得一位大艺术家。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]历史伟人点数[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]城市产生历史伟人点数的途径包括：建造[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]，将市民转化为专业人员，选择特定[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]奇观:[\BOLD]奇观可在每回合产生一定的历史伟人点数。此外，某些奇观还可大大增加所在城市的（或整个文明的所有城市!）历史伟人点数（例如[LINK=BUILDING_PARTHENON]帕特农神庙[\LINK]）。除了专业人员（见下文），某些奇观也能增加所在城市产生特定类型历史伟人的几率。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]专业人员:[\BOLD]每座[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]可以将部分市民转化为“专业人员.”每种专业人员能为城市提供特定的产出加成；此外，他们还能产生历史伟人点数（市民型专业人员除外）。而且，城市中专业人员的类型还会影响所产生的历史伟人类型：所以城市中所有专业人员都是神学家，则城市产生的历史伟人将会是大预言家。如果城市专业人员中半数为商业家，半数为艺术家，则产生大艺术家和大商业家的几率就是一半对一半。将鼠标移动到历史伟人点数栏，将可查看现有历史伟人点数的类型分布。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]内政法令:[\BOLD]某些[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]可提升历史伟人出现几率。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]历史伟人的特性[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如上所述，共有五种类型的历史伟人。每种类型都有特殊的作用，但他们也有一些共同特性:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]能够发现新科技:[\BOLD]你可让历史伟人发现一项新科技。具体的科技通常与历史伟人的类型相关（如大预言家会发现宗教类科技等），但不是必然如此。如果相关的主要科技已经发现完毕，历史伟人可能无法发现新科技，但仍可以大大减少发现其他新科技所需的时间。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]黄金时代:[\BOLD]你凭借两位以上的历史伟人为开创一个[LINK=CONCEPT_GOLDEN_AGE]“黄金时代”[\LINK]；详情见相应小节。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]定居于城市:[\BOLD]任何历史伟人都可以在城市中定居，成为“超级专业人员”。让历史伟人在城市中定居，可每轮获得一定利益；例如，定居的大预言家可使城市工业产能+2，金币收入+5。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]特殊能力[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]除了共同的特性，每种历史伟人还拥有一定的特殊能力。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大艺术家:[\BOLD]大艺术家可在城市中创作一项艺术杰作；这将使城市获得大量[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化[\LINK]点数（具体数值根据游戏速度2,000至6,000不等）。这特别有助于帮助城市摆脱外来文化影响（或是对外国城市施加文化影响!）。大艺术家还可在城市中“永久定居”，提供大量文化点数，并促进科学研究。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大工程师:[\BOLD]大工程师可能“加速”城市的建设，使城市当前进行的工程项目迅速完成。许多早期奇观如果有大工程师帮助，一个回合就可完成，后期的奇观也可大大加速。大工程师可在城市中永久定居，提供大量工业产能，并促进科学研究。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大商业家:[\BOLD]大商业家可开展“贸易事业”获得大量金钱收入。要开展贸易事业，先将大商业家移至尽可能遥远而且富庶的异国大城市。即可在当地开展贸易事业；贸易事业只能在异国城市开展。具体收入由目标城市的遥远程度和富庶程度决定。大商业家可也在城市中永久定居，提供大量商业收入，并促进科学研究。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大预言家:[\BOLD]大预言家能建立宗教圣坛——例如[LINK=BUILDING_JEWISH_SHRINE]所罗门圣殿[\LINK]和[LINK=BUILDING_CONFUCIAN_SHRINE]孔庙[\LINK]。但是，大预言家只能在创立宗教的城市建立相应宗教的圣殿。大预言家是唯一能建立宗教圣殿的单位。大预言家也能在城市中永久定居，提供大量商业收入，少量工业产能，并促进科学研究。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大科学家:[\BOLD]大科学家能建立[LINK=BUILDING_ACADEMY]科学院[\LINK]，大幅度促进所在城市的科学研究和文化发展。大科学家也能在城市中永久定居，提供大量科研点数，少量工业产能。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_MENU_CIV_TYPE</Tag>
		<English>Civ Type:</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>文明类型:</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_EXPERIENCE_IN_BORDERS</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1%% Experience gained from Combat within own Borders</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]在国境内作战斗时积累的经验%D1%%</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BORDER_OBSTACLE</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Prevents Barbarians from Entering Borders on Continent</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]防止蛮族跨越本大洲的国境线</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>CHANGED_TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRIREME_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Triremes were ancient war galleys with three rows of oars on each side. The trireme was an improvement upon an older type of ship called the "pentekonter," which was similar in design but possessed only one row of oars on each side. (The standard "galleys" found in Civilization IV are pentekonters.) The staggered seating of the rowers on the trireme allowed for more people to be packed into roughly the same amount of space, and (more importantly) the extra manpower allowed triremes to travel at faster speeds. Some ancient sources claim that the trireme existed as far back as the eighth century BC, but the first known account of their use was by Polycrates of Samos in 525 BC during an invasion of Egypt. By the middle of the fifth century BC, triremes were in common use throughout Greece. [PARAGRAPH:1]The average trireme was about 35 meters long, carrying 170 oarsmen, 20 crew members, and 10 marines under the command of a captain. According to ancient sources, triremes could reach a maximum speed of about 20 km/hour in battle, or sustain a slower speed of 13 km/hour for a long stretch of time. Triremes also possessed sails but they were not used during combat. A Trireme's main offensive weapon was its "beak," a stout piece of sharpened wood (often clad in metal) which protruded directly forward from its bow, at or below the waterline. In battle the primary tactic was to use the beaks to ram and sink enemy ships, which required building up as much speed as possible to punch through the opposing ship's hull. This was a difficult task and required a great deal of cooperation from the rowers, as even a single rower moving out of place could greatly slow the ship. For this reason the rowers on Greek triremes were not slaves but instead well-trained free men who received good pay for their services. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Persian War, the Greeks used their triremes to defeat the Persians at the decisive Battle of Salamis. Triremes also formed the backbone of the Athenian navy during the Peloponnesian War. As the war progressed Sparta and her allies created their own powerful fleet of triremes; these would be put into good use in 404 BC during the Battle at Aegospotami, when Lysander destroyed Athen's navy, cutting off the city-state's trade and eventually starving her into submission. [PARAGRAPH:1]Triremes would eventually be supplanted by the larger and faster quinqueremes, but the design was revived years later by the Romans, who, facing no major naval enemies, preferred the smaller and cheaper triremes to the more expensive quinqueremes. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>三层桨战船（trireme）是古代专门用与海战的一种大型桨帆船。它由早期的“单层桨战船”（pentekonter）改进而来，后者的每侧船舷只设有一列划桨。（文明IV中的普通“桨帆船”实际上就是单层桨战船。）三层桨战船上的桨座是交错排列的，使得在同样空间里能够安装更多的划桨手，使其能以更快的速度航行。有些古代文献宣称三层桨战船早在公元前8世纪就已出现，但已知最早的可靠记录是在公元前525年，萨摩斯岛的僭主波利克拉特斯使用三层桨战船入侵埃及。到公元前5世纪中叶，三层桨战船已在希腊各地普遍使用。[PARAGRAPH:1]三层桨战船通常有35米长，运载有20名水手，10名战士，由一位船长指挥。据古文献记载，三层桨战船的最高航速可达20公里/小时，远距离正常航行速度则可保持在13公里/小时。三层桨战船也装有风帆，但作战时需要收起。三层桨战船配备的主要武器是被称为“喙”的撞角，是用圆木削尖制成（外包金属），装在船首吃水线的位置向前突出。三层桨战船的基本作战策略是使用撞角撞沉敌船，因此需要以高速度带来的惯性穿透对方的船壳。要做到这一点是相当困难的，需要桨手之间进行充分的协同配合，只要有一个桨手步调不一致就会极大减慢航速。因此希腊三层桨战船的桨手并非奴隶，而是训练有素、报酬丰厚的自由民。 [PARAGRAPH:1]在希腊战争期间，希腊人使用三层桨战船在萨拉米斯湾海战中大败波斯舰队。在伯罗奔尼撒战争中，三层桨战船也是雅典海军的主力。在战争后期，斯巴达及其盟国也建立了强大的三层桨战船队；斯巴达将军莱桑德在伊哥斯波塔米海战中决定性地摧毁了雅典海军，切断了对方的贸易及补给线路，最终迫使雅典投降。[PARAGRAPH:1]三层桨战船后来又被更大更快的五层桨战船（quinquereme）所取代，但罗马人仍然继续沿用三层桨战船的设计，因为他们没有足够强大的海上敌人要对付，所以宁可使用吨位较小、造价也较便宜的三层桨战船。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>CHANGED_TXT_KEY_GREEKWAR_CIV_AMPHIPOLIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The city-state (or "polis") of Amphipolis was founded by Athenian colonists under the command of Hagnon in 437 BC after three previous failed attempts. Barely six years later the Peloponnesian War broke out. The city's location was of great strategic importance: it sat at the mouth of the Strymon River and consequently controlled the route from northern Greece to the Hellespont. There were also a number of valuable gold and silver mines in the region, and ample supplies of lumber for use in shipbuilding. [PARAGRAPH:2]In 424 BC Amphipolis was attacked and captured by the Spartan general Brasidas. The famous historian Thucydides, who was an Athenian general at the time, was held accountable for the disaster and was sent into exile. Athens attempted to recapture the city two years later with a force under the command of Cleon; the Spartans routed the Athenians in the subsequent Battle of Amphipolis, a brutal fight during which both commanders were killed. During a temporary truce in 421 BC the city was restored to Athens, but Athens had much bigger things on its mind and Amphipolis enjoyed de facto independence until 357 BC, when it was conquered by Philip of Macedon. [PARAGRAPH:2]Since that time Amphipolous has all but faded from the world stage. In present times it is perhaps best known as the birthplace of television's fictional warrior-princess, "Xena"[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>安菲波利斯（“波利斯”即“城邦”之意）是公元前437年由哈格农建立的雅典殖民城，此前雅典人还曾经历了三次失败的尝试。仅仅六年之后即爆发了伯罗奔尼撒战争。该城的选址具有非常重要的战略意义：她位于斯特里蒙河口，扼守着希腊北部通往赫拉斯彭特的通道。当地还有许多黄金和白银矿藏，以及大量适于造船的木材资源[PARAGRAPH:2]公元前424年，安菲波斯斯被布拉希达斯统帅的斯巴达军队攻占。著名的历史学家修昔底德（当时是一位雅典将军）带着这场惨烈战事的珍贵记录逃出了险境。两年以后，雅典军队在克列翁的率领下试图收复该城，布拉希达斯再次击溃了雅典人，两位统帅都在激战中阵亡。在公元前421年双方签订了临时停战协议，安菲波利斯被交还给雅典，不过安菲波利斯仍然拥有事实上的独立地位，直到公元前357年被马其顿国王腓力征服。[PARAGRAPH:2]此后的安菲波利斯从世界历史舞台上消失了。不过美国人还是很熟悉这个地名，因为她是一部著名的电视剧集的女主角——公主战士“西娜”的家乡。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CHANGED_CIV_OTTOMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Ottoman Empire was a Turkish state situated upon the eastern Mediterranean that lasted for some 630 years, from 1299 - 1922 AD. At the height of its power, in the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries, the Ottoman domains stretched across vast regions in Anatolia, the Balkans, the Near East and northern Africa. For several centuries it was one of the foremost military powers in the world (until it began to stagnate technologically and fell far behind its competitors).[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottoman state began as a vassal of the earlier Seljuk Turks, who had formed a large empire in the Near East in the eleventh century. When the Seljuk state of Rum in Anatolia collapsed, the Ottomans took advantage of the ensuing power vacuum and rose in power. According to tradition, Osman I became the bey, or chief, of the state of S&#246;g&#252;t in 1281. When Osman captured the Byzantine city of Bilecik in 1299, he declared his state's independence from the Seljuks. This is the traditional date given as the foundation of the Ottoman Empire - which was named after its first leader, Osman. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottomans expanded rapidly in Anatolia throughout the fourteenth century. A series of capable military leaders made many gains against the tottering Byzantine state. The important cities of Nicaea and Nicomedia fell in 1331 and 1337, and by the 1360s the Ottomans had crossed over into Europe and began capturing territory in Thrace. As a sign of this growing power, Murad I declared himself a sultan (or king) in 1383. Around the year 1400, Timur invaded Anatolia. This caused a great deal of disruption, but the Ottomans bounced back and continued to make territorial gains. Under the rule of Mehmed II, the Ottomans attacked and captured Constantinople, whose mighty walls finally fell to the cannon of the Ottomans. This destroyed the Byzantine Empire, and the Ottomans made Constantinople their capital. Mehmed II became known as "Mehmed the Conqueror." Suleiman I, also known as Suleiman the Magnificent, continued to expand and consolidate the Empire; the Ottomans were at the height of their power and influence during his reign[PARAGRAPH:2]After the capture of Constantinople the Ottoman state virtually adopted the Byzantine civil service to run the empire, and its administration was generally sound (until the nineteenth century, when it began to fossilize and became outdated). The Ottoman Empire was very much a pre-modern dynastic state, made up of many different nationalities - in fact, Greeks largely ran its bureaucracy and were vital to its continued success. Militarily, the Ottomans were very strong largely because of their early adoption of gunpowder and their powerful cavalry forces. The military also employed elite slave soldiers known as "janissaries" who won victory after victory for the expanding Ottoman state. The military remained powerful until the late eighteenth century, when they fell fatally behind Western Europe in military technology. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottomans were known for their religious tolerance. The Empire was an Islamic state, and Islamic law dominated its legal system, but non-Muslims were generally well treated and enjoyed the freedom to worship their own religion. The Ottoman Empire was long seen as a refuge for Jews across Europe. Economically, the Ottoman Empire was somewhat of a failure. Most of the region's commerce was carried on by Greek or Italian merchants, which slowed the development of Turkish industry. Once the European voyages of exploration found new routes to India and China which did not involve passing through the Near East, the Ottoman Empire began a slow commercial decline. [PARAGRAPH:2]By the start of the nineteenth century, the Ottoman Empire still held enormous amounts of land, but the empire was stagnant and corrupt, and was widely viewed as the "sick man of Europe." The western powers, their commercial and military strength exploding under the influence of the Industrial Revolution, began to snap up vulnerable Ottoman territories. Britain and France forced humiliating commercial treaties on the Ottomans, and the Ottoman state was forced to take out massive loans to cover its debts - the start of a vicious cycle which only incurred more debt for the empire. [PARAGRAPH:2]While some positive reforms were carried out in terms of modernizing the Ottoman state, custom and tradition prevented the reformers from moving fast enough. Furthermore, the rising tide of nationalism began to tear the empire apart, as Serbians, Bulgarians, Romanians, and Greeks all declared their independence and set up their own nations. By the outbreak of World War I, the Ottomans had lost virtually all of their holdings in Europe. Desperate to preserve what was left, the Ottomans threw in their lot with the Central Powers (Germany and Austria), only to be defeated by a British-led Arab revolt in the Near East. When the war ended the victors partitioned and dissolved the Ottoman Empire at the Paris Peace Conference. However, the Turkish Revolution prevented the planned division of Anatolia from taking place. With the creation of the nation of Turkey in 1922, and the deposition of the final sultan Mehmed VI, the Ottoman Empire came to a close. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>奥斯曼帝国最初是一个位于地中海东岸的土耳其人（突厥人）小邦，至今约有630年的历史（1299-1922）。在其处于力量巅峰时期的16至17世纪，奥斯曼帝国的领土包括安纳托利亚、巴尔干、近东及北非的大部分地区，并拥有世界上最强大的军事实力（但后来其发展陷入停滞，开始落后于欧洲列强）。[PARAGRAPH:2]奥斯曼最初只是塞尔柱土耳其的附庸，塞尔柱土耳其是11世纪时近东地区的一个大帝国。当塞尔柱人在安纳托利亚地区的统治崩溃之后，奥斯曼人抓住时机开始崛起。据记载，奥斯曼一世于1281年成为索古特邦的拜伊（首领）。1299年他率军攻占拜占庭帝国的城市比莱奇克之后，他宣布脱离塞尔柱独立建国。这被认为是奥斯曼帝国建立的标志——帝国的名称也是来自于她的创立者奥斯曼一世。[PARAGRAPH:2]整个14世纪，奥斯曼人在安纳托利亚迅速扩张。一系列能力出众的军事领袖使其从风雨飘摇的拜占庭帝国夺取了大片土地。地位显要的重镇尼西亚和尼科美迪亚分别于1331年和1337年落入奥斯曼人之手，到14世纪60年代，奥斯曼人已跨越海峡进入欧洲，开始控制色雷斯地区。随着实力的不断增强，穆拉德一世于1383年宣布自己为“苏丹”（国王）。到1400年左右，帖木儿率军入侵安纳托利亚，对奥斯曼人造成了巨大的打击，但奥斯曼人很快恢复了元气，重新开始扩张。在穆罕默德二世统治时期，奥斯曼人凭借大炮的威力攻占了君士坦丁堡，灭亡了拜占庭帝国，并将君士坦丁堡定为新首都。穆罕默德二世也因此获得了“征服者穆罕默德”的称号。苏莱曼一世（“苏莱曼大帝”）继续帝国的扩张与巩固事业，在他的统治下，奥斯曼帝国达到其力量与影响的顶峰。[PARAGRAPH:2]在占领君士坦丁堡后，奥斯曼人实际上开始依靠拜占庭所建立的一套文官制度管理整个帝国，政府机构基本运转良好（但到19世纪时这套制度已变得僵化过时）。奥斯曼帝国是一个传统型的封建王朝，境内居住着各位不同的族群——事实上，希腊人是帝国官僚系统的最主要组成部分。在军事方面，奥斯曼帝国具有很强的实力，这主要是因为其迅速引入了火器，并拥有强大的骑兵部队。奥斯曼军队还包括一支由奴隶战士组成的精锐部队“苏丹亲兵”，这支部队在帝国的扩张战争中发挥了巨大的作用。但到18世纪晚期，奥斯曼的军事实力走向衰落，在军事技术方面严重落后于欧洲列强。[PARAGRAPH:2]奥斯曼帝国实行宽松的宗教政策。虽然伊斯兰教是官方信仰，伊斯兰法主导着帝国的司法系统，但非穆斯林也受到良好的对待，可以自由地信奉各自的神灵。奥斯曼帝国长期被欧洲各地的犹太人视为他们的避难所。在经济方面，可以说奥斯曼帝国做得相当失败。各地的商业活动主要被希腊和意大利商人所把持，这导致土耳其民族工业的发展陷于停滞。随着开始大航海时代的到来，欧洲人建立了通向印度和中国的新商路，无须再经过近东地区，奥斯曼帝国在商业上日益衰退。[PARAGRAPH:2]到19世纪初，奥斯曼帝国虽然仍控制着大片领土，但帝国的根基已经腐败变质，被世人视为“欧洲病夫”。西方列强的经济军事实力由于工业革命的影响而呈现爆炸性的增长，他们不断蚕食日益衰落的奥斯曼帝国的领地。英国和法国迫使奥斯曼帝国签订屈辱的商业条约，奥斯曼人为弥补国债而不断大量贷款——由此形成恶性循环，帝国的债务变得越来越多。[PARAGRAPH:2]虽然奥斯曼人积极尝试进行现代化改革，强大的传统习惯势力却使得改革者步履维艰。与此同时，民族主义浪潮也开始兴起，将帝国冲得四分五裂，塞尔维亚人、保加利亚人、罗马尼亚人以及希腊人纷纷宣布独立建国。到第一次世界大战爆发时，奥斯曼人实际上已经失去了几乎所有的欧洲领地。为了保住剩余的领土，奥斯曼人将赌注押在中欧强权（德国和奥匈帝国）身上，结果却是一场惨败。英国人帮助阿拉伯人在近东发动大规模起义。到大战结束时，战胜国通过凡尔赛和约使奥斯曼帝国走向解体。然而，进一步分割安纳托利亚的企图被土耳其革命的爆发所阻止。随着土耳其共和国于1922年成立，末代苏丹穆罕默德六世被废黜，奥斯曼帝国的历史也走到了尽头。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_AUGUSTUS_CAESAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Augustus Caesar [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Roman Emperor [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 63 BC - 14 AD[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Born Gaius Octavius, Augustus would become the first (and possibly greatest) Roman Emperor. He ended a century of civil wars and initiated two hundred years of the Pax Romana (Roman Peace) while overseeing a golden age of Roman literature and culture. Octavius was born in 63 BC. His father (also named Gaius Octavius) was a respectable but undistinguished member of the equestrian order. His mother, however, was a niece of Julius Caesar. Octavius' father died when he was only four years old, and he was brought up in the house of his stepfather Lucius Marcus Phillippus. [PARAGRAPH:2]At the age of fifteen, Octavius put on the toga virilis ("manly robes"), the symbol that he had reached adulthood and was elected to the College of Pontiffs. In 46 BC he joined Julius Caesar during Caesar's last campaign in Spain. In Spain he made such a fine impression on the great general that Julius Caesar changed his will to make Octavius his heir. When Caesar was murdered on the Ides of March in 44 BC, all the wealth that Caesar had spent a lifetime accumulating passed into the hands of the 18-year old Octavius. He would use them well. [PARAGRAPH:2]At the time of Caesar's assassination, Octavius was with some of his soldiers in modern-day Albania. Upon hearing the news he went to Italy and recruited an army from among Caesar's veterans, gaining their loyalty by stressing that he was Caesar's heir. Once in Rome, Octavius allied with Marc Antony and Marcus Lepidus to form what is known as the "Second Triumvirate," directed against Caesar's killers Marcus Brutus and Gaius Cassius. Octavius' and Antony's armies tracked down Brutus and Cassius in Greece, where they defeated the assassins' army at Philippi (42 BC). Brutus and Cassius both committed suicide after their defeat. [PARAGRAPH:2]Antony married Octavius' sister Octavia to cement their alliance, and the two leaders divided Rome's territory between them. Octavius took the west, while Antony went to the east, where he entered into a torrid affair with Cleopatra, the ruler of Egypt. Octavius saw Antony's actions as an insult to his sister and to his family, and relations between the co-rulers soon soured. While Antony enjoyed the pleasures of Egypt, back in Rome Octavius strengthened his political position and his armies. The two eventually went to war, and in 31 BC Octavius defeated the forces of Antony and Cleopatra at the naval battle of Actium. The lovers were pursued to Egypt, where they both committed suicide. [PARAGRAPH:2]Octavius was now the undisputed master of Rome. He surrendered his extraordinary powers to the Senate, which was filled with his allies; in return the Senate named , him "Augustus" (one who is marked by dignity and greatness) and showered him with honors. More importantly, they also gave him the powers of a Roman consul, tribune, and censor, which had never before been combined into one office. All permanent legal power within Rome officially remained within the Senate - but since Octavius controlled the senate, this was mostly a legal fiction. Although he had all of the power of an Emperor, Augustus preferred to style himself "Princeps," or "first citizen" (probably to avoid further antagonizing the remaining republicans in Rome). [PARAGRAPH:2]During his reign Augustus presided over four decades of peace and prosperity, a welcome relief to Rome after almost a century of civil strife. He carried out a great building program in the ancient city, constructing a new Senate house as well as great temples to Apollo and "Divine Julius" (his deceased great-uncle). Later, Augustus would boast - with justification - that he had found Rome a city of brick and left it marble. Under his patronage many of the most famous Roman authors and poets created their great works: Virgil, Ovid, Horace, and Livy all flourished during his reign. [PARAGRAPH:2]Augustus' generals also enjoyed great success and were quite relieved to be once again turning their military strength against external enemies instead of one another. Rome's borders were extended to the Danube; northern Spain was finally conquered; and Armenia was pacified in the east. By Augustus' death in 14 AD, a return to the old system of the Republic was unthinkable. He was peacefully succeeded by the Emperor Tiberius, and for more than two centuries the Roman Empire would dominate the Mediterranean without any major wars - due in large part to the wise statesmanship of Augustus. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]奥古斯都·恺撒[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]罗马皇帝[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]前63-14[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景：[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]奥古斯都原名盖乌斯·屋大维，他是第一位罗马皇帝（也可以说是最伟大的一位）。他结束了持续一个世纪的内战，并开创了持续两百多年的“太平盛世”——罗马统治下的和平，这是罗马文化和艺术极度繁荣的黄金时代。屋大维出生于公元前63年。他的父亲（也叫盖乌斯·屋大维）来自一个尊贵但并不出名的罗马特权者家族。而他的母亲刚是朱利乌斯·恺撒的侄女。屋大维年仅四岁时他父亲就去世了，由继父鲁西乌斯·马库斯·菲利浦斯抚养长大。[PARAGRAPH:2]在15岁时，屋大维穿上了“男人的长袍”，这在罗马是成年的象征，并入选罗马祭司团。公元前46年，他作为朱利乌斯·恺撒的下属参加了西班牙战役。朱利乌斯对他在战场上的表现留下了深刻的印象，以至于修改了自已的遗嘱，将屋大维收为自己的养子和继承人。公元前44年三月中恺撒遇刺身亡后，他一生所积累的财富均转入年仅18岁的屋大维名下。而他很好地利用了这笔财富。[PARAGRAPH:2]在恺撒遇刺的时候，屋大维正在今阿尔巴尼亚地区率兵作战。得知此消息后他立即返回意大利，召集恺撒的旧部组成一支军队，作为恺撒的继承人，他赢得了军队的忠心。到达罗马后，屋大维与马可·安东尼、马库斯·列庇都斯结成政治同盟，史称“后三头执政”，与刺杀恺撒的马库斯·布鲁图斯和盖乌斯·卡西乌斯相对抗。屋大维与安东尼将布鲁图斯和卡西乌斯赶到希腊，最终在公元前42年的腓力比战役中消灭了他们的军队。不久布鲁图斯和卡西乌斯均自杀身亡。[PARAGRAPH:2]安东尼迎娶了屋大维的姐姐屋大维娅以巩固这个政治同盟，两人分别统治半个罗马。屋大维得到西部，安东尼则来到东部，他在那里迷上了埃及女王克利奥帕特拉。屋大维将安东尼的行为视作对他姐姐和整个家族的侮辱，两人的关系迅速恶化。安东尼沉醉于埃及的富贵温柔乡，屋大维则在罗马努力巩固自己的政治地位、加强自己的军事力量。双方最终爆发了战争，公元前31年，屋大维在阿克提乌姆湾海战中击败安东尼和克利奥帕特拉的舰队。这对情人逃回埃及，双双自杀身亡。[PARAGRAPH:2]在此之后，屋大维成为全罗马无可争议的主人。他将大量权力让渡给元老院，而那里则完全由他的盟友所把持；作为回报，元老院则授予他一个至高无上的称号：“奥古斯都”（象征着权力和荣耀）。更重要的是，元老院还允许他身兼罗马执政官、保民官、监察官三大职位，这在罗马历史上是从来没有过的。罗马的永久性法权仍然归于元老院——但屋大维掌握着元老院，因此这只是名义上的分权而已。虽然奥古斯都实际上已经拥有一位皇帝所应拥有的所有权力，但他还是喜欢称自己为“第一公民”（Princeps），这可能是为了避免进一步伤害罗马共和派所剩无几的自尊心。[PARAGRAPH:2]奥古斯都治下的和平繁荣持续了四十余年，这对刚刚经历近一个世纪内乱的罗马来说是弥足珍贵的。他在这座古老的城市中大兴土木，包括新的元老院、阿波罗神庙，以及“朱利乌斯神庙”（纪念他伟大的养父）。后来奥古斯都自豪地宣称——他将原先用砖造的罗马城变成了用大理石造的罗马城。他还赞助过许多著名的罗马文学家和诗人：维吉尔、奥维德、霍拉斯、李维等等。[PARAGRAPH:2]奥古斯都手下的将军们也不断赢得辉煌的胜利，他们不必再自相残杀而是一致对外。罗马的北方边界一直推进到多瑙河；西班牙北部地区也终于被征服；东方的亚美尼亚也告平定。到公元14年奥古斯都去世时，旧共和国体制已经没有恢复的可能了。所有权力被和平地移交给他的养子提比略，此后两个多世纪，罗马帝国统治下的整个地中海地区没有发生任何大的战事——这大部分要归功于奥古斯都超人的政治智慧。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CHANGED_UNIT_VIKING_BESERKER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Berserks (or berserkers) were Viking warriors who worked themselves up into terribles rage before going into battle. The word berserker comes from the Norse words "bjorn" (meaning bear) or "bare" (meaning naked) and "serkr" (meaning shirt); a berserk was either someone who went into battle wearing the "shirt" of a bear (i.e. someone who was bear-like in rage and strength) or someone who went into battle naked. Berserks thought that by wearing the fur of a bear they would be possessed by the spirit of the animal and possibly even shift into its form. Berserks were also known to have sworn allegiance to the Norse sky god Odin, and they believed that he would protect them and give them superhuman strength. The Vikings also believed that if death came while fighting as a berserk, the deceased would travel straight to the warrior paradise of Valhalla. [PARAGRAPH:2]No one is exactly sure how berserks induced the crazed state of violence described by contemporaries. Some theories speculate that the wild behavior was prompted by the taking of various hallucinogenic drugs, or was caused by mild epilepsy, or even a genetic disorder that caused overly large skull growth. Perhaps the most likely explanation is that before going into battle the berserks simply worked themselves into frenzies by painting their faces, howling like animals, beating helmets and drums - and drinking large quantities of alcohol. [PARAGRAPH:2]All stories about berserks agree that they fought with crazed strength and were immune to pain until battle was ended. Berserks were often portrayed as villains, slaying anything that moved - including their own family members. In battle even the Berserks' allies usually chose to keep them at arm's length and were never comfortable in their presence. Scandinavian kings refused to employ them as bodyguards for fear that they would forget who to protect in the fighting. [PARAGRAPH:2]In 1015, Berserks were outlawed in Norway, and Gr&#225;g&#225;s, the medieval Icelandic law code, sentenced berserk warriors to exile. After the widespread adoption of Christianity across Scandinavia, in 1100 AD the organization of berserk warbands disappeared. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>世人将凶悍好斗的维京战士称为“狂暴战士”（“berserk”或“berserker”）。这个词可能来源于挪威语“bjorn”（意为“熊”）或“bare”（意为“赤裸”）以及“serkr”（意为“衬衣”），因此其含义或是“披着熊皮的战士”（亦即“象熊一样凶猛狂暴的战士”），或是“赤身的战士”。狂暴战士认为身披熊皮就可以拥有熊的凶猛和力量，甚至成为熊的化身。狂暴战士只效忠于北欧神话中的天神奥丁，相信奥丁能赋予他们超人的力量。维京人认为阵亡的狂暴战士将能进入传说中的瓦尔哈拉神殿获得永生。[PARAGRAPH:2]现在我们无法确定是什么导致狂暴战士陷入当时人们所描述的那种狂暴状态。有人猜测是由于服用了某种致幻剂的结果，或者是中度癫痫症发作，甚至可能是遗传性疾病使头部发育出现异常。也许最合理的解释是因为狂暴战士在上战场之前会用颜料涂抹脸部，模仿野兽大声喊叫，伴随着战鼓的节奏用武器敲打头盔——并且会大量饮酒。[PARAGRAPH:2]有关狂暴战士的故事一致描述说：他们在作战时会变得极其疯狂、力大无穷而且刀枪不入。狂暴战士在发怒时会不分青红皂白地杀死任何活人——包括自己的亲人。甚至连处于同一阵线的战友也不敢同他们靠得太近，并时刻保持警惕。斯堪的纳维亚的国王们拒绝让他们做自己的帖身护卫，因为害怕一旦打起仗来，狂暴战士会忘记自己要保护的对象。[PARAGRAPH:2]挪威国王埃里克一世曾于1015年宣布禁绝狂暴战士，而中世纪的冰岛法典“格拉加斯”也规定对狂暴战士须加以放逐。随着基督教在斯堪的纳亚的传播，到1100年时，狂暴战士的团体已经销声匿迹了。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_RAGNAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Ragnar Lodbrok [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of Sweden and Denmark [\BOLD][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Ragnar Lodbrok was a semi-legendary king of Sweden and Denmark who ruled sometime in the eighth or ninth centuries. The exact dates surrounding Ragnar's life are unknown, but most likely he was a Viking warlord who went on raids from approximately 835 to 865 AD. Ragnar is described as being part of the Yngling Dynasty of Swedish kings, descended from the Swedish king Sigurd Ring. The word Lodbrok means "hairy breeches" and refers to a pair of trousers his wife made for him out of animal skins. Ragnar was a pagan and believed that he was a direct descendant of the Norse god Odin. Christian churches and monasteries were among his favorite targets for attack. [PARAGRAPH:2]Many of the details surrounding Ragnar's life are known only through legend, and must be viewed with a certain amount of skepticism, but he appears to have been a remarkable individual. Ragnar spent most of his life as a pirate and raider. He would demand a huge ransom from his victims for their lives, and then return a short while later to extort another payment in exchange for leaving. Based upon the number of Vikings who agreed to follow him, Ragnar must have been a successful and charismatic leader. In 845 Ragnar led a force of 120 ships carrying 5000 Vikings to the mouth of the Seine River, and from there to the city of Paris. The city was captured easily, and the Frankish king Charles the Bald (a grandson of Charlemagne) agreed to pay an enormous sum of money to Ragnar for sparing the city from destruction. According to Viking sources, Ragnar demanded a whopping 7000 pounds of silver, which he got. Though he honored the deal and left Paris (more or less) intact, that did not stop Ragnar from pillaging his way across the rest of northern France, destroying whatever crossed his path. [PARAGRAPH:2]After having his way in France, in 865 Ragnar turned north and landed in England. He came aground in the northern kingdom of Northumbria, which was ruled at the time by King Aelle II. Ragnar met Aelle in battle the same year, and for the first and only time in his life Ragnar was defeated. He was also captured and thrown into a pit full of poisonous snakes. [PARAGRAPH:2]As he was dying, Ragnar is said to have exclaimed, "How the little pigs would grunt if they knew the situation of the old boar!" This was a reference to his sons in Sweden, and it would have been well if Aelle II had paid his words closer attention, for in 866, the following year, Ragnar's fourth son Ivar the Boneless led a major Viking expedition to England seeking revenge. Ivar met King Aelle in battle, defeated him, and subjected him in turn to an agonizing death. [PARAGRAPH:2]Whether or not it was launched to exact revenge for Ragnar's death, the Viking invasion had serious consequences for England - the kingdoms of Northumbria, Mercia, and East Anglia were all attacked and destroyed. The descendents of Ragnar were at last stopped in 871, when they were finally defeated by Alfred the Great of Wessex. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]雷格那·罗德布洛克[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]瑞典与丹麦国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]背景：[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]雷格那·罗德布洛克是位半传奇性的历史人物，据说他在8世纪或9世纪时统治着瑞典和丹麦两国。雷格那的具体生卒年份已经无法确定，他很可能是在约535至865年间在北欧各地征战劫掠的一位维京军事首领。据记载雷格那是传奇瑞典王西格德·林创立的英凌王朝的君主之一。“罗德布洛克”的原意为“毛皮裤”，指他穿着妻子用野兽皮做成的裤子。传说格雷那有北欧天神奥丁的血脉，他蔑视任何其他神灵，最喜欢劫掠的目标就是基督教堂和修道院。[PARAGRAPH:2]雷格那生平事迹的细节只能通过北欧传奇故事去了解，其真实性颇具疑问，我们只知道他在传奇故事里是一位非凡的人物。在雷格那一生中大部分时间里，他是一位海盗和劫掠者。他绑架权贵，勒索赎金后扬长而去，过不多久又会再度来访索取钱财。有许多维京人追随在雷格那左右，因此他应该是一位才能出众、魅力超群的领袖。公元845年，雷格那率领一支拥有120艘船只、5000名战士的维京大军进入塞纳河口直抵巴黎。这座城市被轻易攻陷，当时的法王秃头查理（查理曼的孙子）被迫向雷格那支付一大笔赎金，以免城市被夷为平地。根据维京人的说法，光头查理付给雷格那7000镑白银的巨款。虽然在收到赎金之后归还了巴黎城（还算完好无损），但法国北部其他地区却几乎被雷格那劫掠一空。[PARAGRAPH:2]在横扫法国之后的公元865年，雷格那又北上登陆英格兰。他侵入英格兰北部的诺森伯利亚王国，与其统治者艾雷二世大战一场，有生以来第一次尝到失败的滋味。雷格那被俘虏，并被扔进一个爬满毒蛇的大坑。[PARAGRAPH:2]传说雷格那在弥留之际曾说了这样一句话：“老野猪的痛苦会令小野猪如何愤怒？”他指的是他在瑞典的儿子们，艾雷二世没有将他的警告放在心上。一年之后的866年，雷格那的四儿子“无骨者”伊瓦尔即率领维京人发动大规模入侵。伊瓦尔击败并俘虏了艾雷二世，也给他选择了一种痛苦的死法。[PARAGRAPH:2]不管是不是为了给雷格那报仇雪恨，总之这场入侵给英格兰带来了灭顶之灾——诺森伯利亚、麦西亚、东盎格利亚等王国均遭征服。入侵直到871年才暂告停止，西撒克斯王国的阿尔弗雷德大帝击败了他们。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_CHANGED_FIRST_CONTACT_LEADER_RAGNAR_LODBROK_1</Tag>
		<English>Hail and well met, [CT_NAME]! I am [OUR_NAME], ruler of the glorious [OUR_CIV_SHORT].  So tell me: does [CT_NAME] have a lot of rich and unprotected coastal cities, or what?</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>向你致以问候，[CT_NAME]！我是[OUR_NAME]，[OUR_CIV_SHORT]的统治者。打听一下：[CT_NAME]有没有很多足够富庶而缺乏防御的海滨城市啊？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_CHANGED_FIRST_CONTACT_LEADER_RAMESSES_II_1</Tag>
		<English>Mighty [OUR_NAME], all-powerful god-king of [OUR_CIV_SHORT] welcomes you, [CT_NAME]! Feel free to grovel in terror and awe if the mood takes you.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>强大的[OUR_NAME]，[OUR_CIV_SHORT]的无所不能的天神般的统治者向你致以问候，[CT_NAME]！请尽管在我面前惊恐颤抖、卑躬屈膝吧。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_CHANGED_GREETINGS_ATT_FUR_LEADER_SHAKA_1</Tag>
		<English>So you have emerged from your fetid country and come to me, [CT_NAME]. To what do I owe this extremely dubious honor?</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>你告别你那臭烘烘的国家到我这里来了？[CT_NAME]。我该如何应对这种可疑的举动呢？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_CHANGED_DEMAND_TRIBUTE_POWER_EQUAL_MEHMED_1</Tag>
		<English>We require mighty [CT_CIV_SHORT]'s assistance. I hope you won't disappoint us.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>我们需要强大的[CT_CIV_SHORT]提供帮助。希望你不会让我们失望。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CHANGED_CIV_VIKING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>More properly known as Scandinavians or Norsemen, the Vikings were a group of people from northern Europe who became famous for carrying out a series of raids across the continent between roughly 800 - 1050 AD. The period is sometimes known as the "Viking Age," and it was an era of chaos and disruption for large parts of Europe. The Vikings can be classified into three main groups: the Danes largely attacked England; the Norwegians visited Scotland, Ireland, and points further west; while the Swedes invaded the river systems of what is now Russia. Although the Vikings usually employed hit and run tactics, many of them settled in new communities in the areas they had subjugated, eventually mixing with the local population. And while the Vikings are thought today to be bloodthirsty brigands, they probably acted more often as commercial traders than as warriors.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Historians debate the reason why the Vikings suddenly emerged from Scandinavia at the end of the eighth century AD and began preying upon other parts of Europe. Theories include: the Vikings were suffering overpopulation caused by better agricultural tools; that the unification of Norway led to an excess of idle warriors; the Vikings were reacting to attempts by the Franks to muscle them out of trade with the east; or that the men went off to raid and pillage out of simple boredom. One particularly interesting theory is that the climate of Europe was warmer during the early Middle Ages, leading to an excess population in Scandinavia and the subsequent Viking colonization of places such as Iceland and Greenland. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Whatever the actual reason for their expansion, the Viking drive outward began with the sacking of the important island monastery of Lindisfarne, located off the coast of Britain, in 793 AD. England was regularly raided by the Danes in the following decade, and in 865 a major invasion landed in East Anglia. This force was led by several landless Viking kings; in the battles that followed most of the English kingdoms were defeated, but the state of Wessex under Alfred the Great managed to hold the invaders off. The Vikings settled in Northumbria, and their territory became known as the "Danela" (most of these Vikings were Danes). [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Another wave of Vikings landed in England in 947 under the command of Erik Bloodaxe, who managed to capture the city of York. Vikings would largely remain in control of England until the Norman invasion of 1066 - and the Normans were themselves the French descendents of Vikings. Scotland and Ireland also experienced a heavy Norwegian Viking presence at this time; a number of important cities were founded by them - including Dublin. Eventually the Vikings settled down and intermarried with the native Irish. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The main target for Viking aggression, however, was France. All throughout the ninth century the Vikings sailed up and down the Seine River with impunity, sacking French towns and monasteries at their leisure. Finally the French king Charles the Simple made an agreement with the Viking leader Hrolf Ganger in 911, in which Hrolf was granted control over territory in northern France. In exchange, Hrolf and his men agreed to convert to Christianity and become vassals of the French king. Hrolf's name was changed to Rollo and he became duke of the province of Normandy (named for the Norsemen who settled in it). The Normans retained their martial edge even after conversion to Christianity, and would go on to make a number of important conquests in England, the Mediterranean, and during the Crusades. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The exploits of the Viking sailors were the stuff of legend. Viking mariners found their way to Iceland, Greenland, and even Newfoundland in North America, setting up colonies in all of these locations. Viking longboats were both fast and seaworthy, and their shallow drafts allowed them to sail far up the river systems of Europe. The Vikings could strike from the sea and be gone again before the military forces of a kingdom could be marshaled to meet them. In the east, the Swedes traveled down the rivers of modern Russia and founded the state of Kievan Rus', which grew rich off the river trade between the Baltic and the Byzantine Empire. These Vikings also found employment as mercenaries within the Byzantine domains, and their most elite warriors found employment in the Byzantine Varangian Guard. The Viking Age finally came to a close around 1050AD, as the Vikings were incorporated into Christian Europe and settled down to the less exciting but more stable pursuits of agriculture and fishing; their reputation as fierce invaders from the sea has endured to this day. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>“维京人”的更准确名称应为“斯堪的那维亚人”或“北欧人”，他们巨大声名主要来自于800至1050年间在欧洲各地的劫掠生涯。这一时期也因而被称为“维京时代”，当时的欧洲大部分地区都因维京入侵而陷于混乱和恐慌。维京人可以细分为三大族群：丹麦人，他们入侵的对象主要是英格兰；挪威人，他们航行的方向包括苏格兰、爱尔兰，以及更遥远的西方；瑞典人则沿河流深入今属俄罗斯的广袤原野。维京人通常都是四处流动袭扰，但其中也有一部分在他们所征服的土地上定居下来，最终同原住民融合在一起。虽然当代的人们总是把维京人视为一群嗜血的暴徒，但是他们最常从事的职业其实是商人而非战士。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]对于8世纪末的维京人为何突然离开斯堪的纳维亚掀起入侵欧洲大陆的风潮，历史学家仍在争论不休。相关的理论包括：维京人农业技术的发展造成人口过度膨胀；挪威的统一导致大批战士无所事事；法兰克人大力挤占东欧贸易份额激起维京人的报复；或仅仅是由于维京人厌倦了沉闷无趣的定居生活想找点刺激……另一个有趣的理论认为中世纪早期欧洲气候变暖导致斯堪的纳维亚人口大量增加，也使得冰岛和格陵兰更适于移民居住。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]无论真正的原因为何，维京人扩张的时代开始了，他们最早发动的一次袭击是在793年洗劫不列颠东部海滨著名的林迪斯法尼岛修道院。此后十余年英格兰频繁遭丹麦人入侵，包括865年对东盎格利亚的大规模进攻。这批维京入侵者包括多名失去领地的维京王族，当时的英格兰诸王国大都被摧垮，只有西撒克斯王国在阿尔弗雷德大帝的领导下击退了入侵者。这批维京人随后在诺森伯兰定居下来，其领地被称为“丹尼拉”（因为他们主要来自丹麦）。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]947年，另一批维京人在埃里克·布拉德艾克斯的率领下登陆英格兰并攻占了约克。此后维京人继续统治英格兰大部分地区，直到1066年的诺曼征服——而实际上诺曼人就是定居法国的维京人后裔（详情见后文）。在这一时期，苏格兰与爱尔兰也处于来自挪威的维京人控制之下，当地的许多城市都是他们建立的——包括都柏林。维京移民与爱尔兰原住民相互通婚，逐渐融合到一起。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]不过维京入侵的最主要对象还是法国。在整个9世纪，维京人沿塞纳河横行无阻，随心所欲地劫掠法国城镇与修道院。911年，当时的法王“庸人”查理与维京人首领赫罗夫·冈格尔签订和约，赫罗夫获得了法国西北地区的统治权，作为交换，赫罗夫及其手下皈依了基督教并承认法王的宗主权，他们被称为“诺曼人”（即“北方人”之意），改名罗洛的赫罗夫也就成为诺曼底公爵。诺曼人在皈依基督教之后仍然保持着尚武的传统，他们对英格兰及地中海沿岸的征服在历史上造成了深远的影响，也是十字军东征的重要参与者。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]维京人的海上探险历险仿佛是一部传奇。维京航海家的足迹远至冰岛、格陵兰，甚至北美洲的纽芬兰，在这些地方建立了许多定居点。维京人的海船航速极快且易与操纵，由于吃水较浅也能够深入欧洲内河。因此维京人能够快速自海上发动袭击，并在敌人的大军赶到前扬长而去。瑞典人在东欧溯江而上，建立了后来的基辅罗斯公国，基辅罗斯凭借内河航运优势在波罗的海诸国与拜占庭帝国之间开展繁忙的贸易活动。许多维京人还成为了拜占庭帝国的雇佣军，即“瓦兰吉卫士”。随着维京人逐渐融入欧洲基督教世界，他们转而从事农业和渔业，开始平静的定居生活。到1050年左右，维京时代最终结束，但他们的海上劫掠生涯留给世人的印象实在太深刻了，直到今天，“维京人”依然是“海盗”的同意词。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CHANGED_BUILDING_AMERICAN_MALL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>During the 20th Century, the advent of the automobile has created an urban and suburban landscape in which people live in one area but can shop, play and work elsewhere - often miles away from their homes. Nowhere is this more true than in the United States of America, whose citizens are noted for an almost fanatical devotion to their cars. This has had important social, environmental and economic affects upon life in America, leading to (among other things) the creation of that most American of institution - the shopping mall.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]American shopping malls are surrounded by acres and acres of parking lots, and they may contain dozens (if not hundreds) of stores selling everything from clothing to jewelry to electronics to books to computers to videos. In some ways American shopping malls are akin in spirit to the old Arabian markets (although Americans don't particularly enjoy haggling and prices are generally fixed). [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The earliest automobile-centered shopping center was the "Market Square," opened in Chicago, Illinois, in 1916. Constructed in Minnesota in 1992, the "Mall of America" is the largest mall in the world. It contains over 500 shops, 80 restaurants, a theme park, hotel, and movie theatres. It is housed in a building large enough to hold over 30 Boeing 747 airplanes.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在20世纪，汽车的发明使城市的郊区不断向乡村延伸，人们的居住地同购物、娱乐和工作所在地之间的距离可能有十数英里之遥。特别是在美国，市民对汽车的钟爱简直到了狂热的程度。这种情况对美国人的生活方式造成了深刻的影响，催生了许多新事物——其中之一就是购物中心。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]美国的购物中心周围都辟有大片的停车场，内部则包括数十家甚至数百家各式各样的店铺，出售的商品从电器、书籍、电脑到音像制品，应有尽有。从某种角度看来，美国的购物中心包罗万象的特点与古老的阿拉伯集市十分类似（不过美国人不太喜欢讨价还价，商品价格通常都是明码标示的）。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]最早的一家专门针对通勤顾客的购物中心是位于伊利诺伊州芝加哥市的“集市广场”，于1916年开业。1992年开业的“美利坚购物中心”位于明尼苏达州，是世界上最大的购物中心。中心内有超过500家专业店铺、80家餐馆、一座主题公园、一家酒店及一家电影院。其主体建筑足够容纳30架波音747客机。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BOMBARD_DEFENSE_MOD</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1_Mod%% Damage to Defenses from Bombardment (Except vs. Gunpowder-based Units)</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]轰炸对防御方的损伤%D1_Mod%% (对火器单位无效)</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLE_OF_ARTEMIS_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Temple of Artemis[COLOR_REVERT] increases its city's trade route income, and places a [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Priest[COLOR_REVERT] specialist in that city.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]阿尔忒弥斯神庙[COLOR_REVERT]提升城市商路的收益，并为所在城市免费提供一位[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]神学家[COLOR_REVERT]。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_WALL_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Great Wall[COLOR_REVERT] affects the area inside its owner's cultural borders on that continent, even if it is physically outside of the Great Wall. The effects are that [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Barbarians[COLOR_REVERT] cannot enter that area, and the owner receives more [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Great General[COLOR_REVERT] points from combat within that area.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]长城[COLOR_REVERT]的作用范围覆盖文明的整个文化疆界，即包括地图上位于长城以外的国土。长城可使[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]蛮族[COLOR_REVERT]无法进入文明的领地，还能使在文明领地内进行的战斗带来更多的[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]大军事家[COLOR_REVERT]点数。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UNIVERSITY_OF_SANKORE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>If you have a state religion, the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]University of Sankore[COLOR_REVERT] causes all of that religion's buildings to generate research for your civilization.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>如果你确立了官方信仰，[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]桑科雷大学[COLOR_REVERT]可使本文明所有宗教建筑提供额外科研点数。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EGYPTIAN_OBELISK_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>The [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Egyptian Obelisk[COLOR_REVERT], the Egyptian replacement for the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Monument[COLOR_REVERT], provides its city with a small amount of culture and also allows the city to have 2 priest specialist.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]方尖碑[COLOR_REVERT]是埃及的特色建筑，替代[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]纪念碑[COLOR_REVERT]，可提供少量文化点数，并允许城市供养2位神学家。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONEHENGE_STRATEGY</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Stonehenge[COLOR_REVERT] provides a free [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Monument[COLOR_REVERT] in all your cities and centers the world map. It increases its city's odds of generating a [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Great Prophet[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]巨石阵[COLOR_REVERT]可免费为你的所有城市提供一座[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]纪念碑[COLOR_REVERT]。并能提升城市产生[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]历史伟人[COLOR_REVERT]的几率。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
