<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- freesand -->
<!-- Game Text Buildings and Projects -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>When populations began to organize their communities into cities, their governments became more structured and formalized. At an early stage, the ruler of the city established headquarters from which the business of running the city was conducted. In many cases, these buildings also served as the living quarters of the ruler. In wealthy cities, these facilities often expanded into immense, sprawling palaces. These richly adorned, imposing buildings were a source of civic pride, and helped to reinforce the aura of power surrounding the ruler.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>当人们开始在城市中聚居时，相应的政府机构也变得更有组织，更为正规。起初，城市的领袖建起指挥所并在其中发号施令。而通常这样的建筑也同时成为领袖的住处。在富庶的城市中，原有建筑往往不断重修扩建，成为占地广阔的宫殿。宫殿由于外观壮丽，装饰豪华而令市民感到自豪，并且有助于强化领袖的统治威势。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_PALACE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A collection of imperial structures in Beijing, the Forbidden Palace stands as a testament to the Chinese architectural ingenuity and aesthetic. Ornamental gardens, terraces and fountains surround the magnificent structure, which became the capital of China in 1421. It was the residence of 24 emperors of the Ming and Qing Dynasties until the last emperor abdicated in 1911. Although the correct title for the building is the Imperial Palace, it is more widely known as the "Forbidden" Palace because ordinary people were barred from entering its grounds. With a 160-foot moat and walls 30 feet tall, there was little chance that they would get inside unwanted. The Forbidden Palace is enormous; it occupies 170 acres and contains 8,706 rooms. An estimated eight to ten thousand people lived inside the palace to serve the needs of the emperor. Today, the Forbidden Palace is a major tourist attraction, and it is still used as a symbol of Chinese sovereignty.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>紫禁城是位于北京的一座皇室建筑群，作为中国建筑技术与建筑风格的集中体现而闻名于世。紫禁城中殿堂宫室气势恢宏，亭台楼阁不计其数，1421年，永乐皇帝正式迁都北京。此后明清两朝的24位皇帝均居住于此，直到1911年末代皇帝宣统的退位。皇宫大内戒备森严，禁止平民百姓入内，故此称为“禁宫”。环绕紫禁城的是宽160英尺的护城河与高30英尺的城墙，外来者想要闯入难如登天。整座皇宫占地170亩，拥有大小房间8,706间。估计当时有八千至一万人生活其中，以随时服侍皇帝。在今天，紫禁城已成为一个重要旅游景点，并且仍然是中国最高统治权的象征。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VERSAILLES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Palace of Versailles began life as a hunting lodge constructed at the instructions of King Louix XIII, who enjoyed hunting in the nearby woods. In 1660, his son Louis XIV decided to turn the "chateau" into a palace. Louis XIV took up residence in 1682, and construction on the palace was completed in 1688. During Louis' lifetime this huge, ungainly, and ornate building was not only his residence, but it also housed the royal court and central bureaucracy of France. Versailles is a complex of richly appointed buildings centered in one-and-a-half square miles of fine parkland. It is surrounded by beautiful fountains, statues, and magnificent formal gardens. [PARAGRAPH:2]At the very center of the palace was, of course, Louis' bedroom, a massive and ostentatious room. At the center of the bedroom was the Royal Bed, which was surrounded by a railing, suggesting that the king did indeed hold large audiences while reclining in the bed and needed a way to keep the visitors' fingers from messing up the royal linens. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Hall of Mirrors is another impressive room in Versailles. Over 200 feet in length and 30 feet wide, the hall contains 578 mirrors and 17 ornate windows. On the ceiling Louis had painted 30 pictures showing his many triumphs and the benefits of his rule. [PARAGRAPH:2]While appearing to many a massive exercise in royal excess, Louis had good reason for constructing Versailles; with one stroke he removed the nobility and bureaucracy from the intrigues of Paris and made them more immediately responsible to him. In this way he was able to render the once powerful nobility largely impotent; great families which had once battled each other for the throne of France now found themselves instead intriguing for the privilege of attending Louis' bath. [PARAGRAPH:2]Nonetheless, Versailles was, in fact, an extraordinarily expensive building. It has been estimated that maintaining the palace and its noble denizens consumed 6%% of the entire French national budget. For a comparison, the United States' President's 2006 budget estimates that the US will take in about 2.2 trillion dollars in revenue in 2006. Six percent of that amount is 132 billion dollars. [PARAGRAPH:2]After the French Revolution and the dissolution of the monarchy, Versailles fell into disrepair and disuse. The German Army made the complex its headquarters after defeating France in the Franco-Prussian war in 1870. The building remained in decay until the 1960s, when Pierre Verlet conceived the bold idea of refurbishing Versailles to its glory days under Louis XIV. Since then the curators have managed to retrieve many of the original furnishings from across Europe.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>凡尔赛宫原本只是路易十三建造的猎宫，这位国王非常喜欢在附近的森林中狩猎。他的儿子路易十四在1660年决定将这座“城堡”改建为宫殿，并于1682年移驾此地，但整个工程却是在1688年完工。在路易十四有生之年，这一宏伟，庄严，华丽的建筑不仅是他的住处，同时还是法国的中央官僚机构的驻地。凡尔赛宫以一座占地1.5平方公里的，富丽堂皇的宫殿为中心。它的四周则是漂亮的喷泉、雕像以及华丽的花园。[PARAGRAPH:2]在宫殿的最中心是国王的卧室，这是一个庞大而又浮华的房间。在卧室的中央是国王的床，旁边则被栏杆围绕着，这意味着国王在此处接见臣下时，臣子们的手不能触碰到国王的卧具。[PARAGRAPH:2]镜厅是凡尔赛宫内另一个给人深刻印象的房间，它长达200英尺，宽达30英尺，其间有578面镜子和17面装饰华丽的窗户。路易十四让人在天花板上画了30幅壁画，用来夸耀自己的文治武功。[PARAGRAPH:2]尽管凡尔赛宫对于王室来说也太过豪华，但路易十四之所以这么做也有他自己的原因：他可以通过让贵族和官僚机构移居此地，从而一劳永逸地解决内部问题，让他们只对自己负责。他使原本强大的贵族势力变得软弱无力，曾经为争夺法王宝座而互相争斗的贵族现在发现他们只能通过讨好路易十四而获得特权。[PARAGRAPH:2]即使如此，凡尔赛宫也显得太过奢华。据估计，仅仅是维持凡尔赛宫及宫廷的正常运转就需要耗费法国国家预算的百分之六。与之相比，2006年度美国国家预算总额为2.2万亿美圆，百分之六就意味着1320亿美元。[PARAGRAPH:2]法国大革命以后，君主制土崩瓦解，凡尔赛宫则被废弃不用。德国人在1870年普法战争中击败法国后将此处作为陆军司令部。这一建筑直到20世纪60年代一直处于荒废状态，直到皮埃尔·维尔莱提出了翻修凡尔赛宫，让它重新焕发路易十四时代荣光的大胆设想。直到今日，凡尔赛博物馆已经从欧洲各地找回了原本保存于凡尔赛宫的大量馆藏品。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WALLS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Before the establishment of centralized governments capable of supporting strong, national armies, individual cities were left to fend for themselves when it came to defense. As a result, many cities constructed city walls to protect against raiders and bandits. City walls represented a major investment in both time and materials, requiring years to complete and constant repairs to maintain their strength and integrity. However, these walls turned the city into a fortress capable of withstanding all but the most determined attack. The development of gunpowder largely put an end to the usefulness of walls in stopping large armies. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在有能力维持强大国家军队的中央集权政府建立起来之前，地方城市往往需要自行组织防御力量。因此，许多城市都会修建城墙阻止入侵者以及盗贼的攻击。修建城墙意味着大量的时间与金钱投入，在花费数年时间建造完成之后，仍需时时维护以确保其坚固完好。不过，城墙的确能使城市变成一座军事要塞，让大量来犯之敌无功而返。在火药发明之后，城墙基本失去了阻止敌军进攻的作用。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CASTLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Castles served many functions in medieval Europe; not only were they formidable defensive positions, but they served as administrative and judicial centers and as the seat of a lord's power. Since food and supplies could be stockpiled at castles, they exerted strong influence over very large surrounding territories. Secular lords were not the only ones to build castles; religious officials often did so as well, to provide themselves with stronger power bases. Early castles were usually little more than wooden stockades constructed on dirt mounds and perhaps surrounded by a shallow trench; by the time of the reign of Edward the Confessor in 13th century England, castle-building had become a much more elaborate affair, with hundreds of laborers and specialists constructing huge stone fortresses with intricate defenses in carefully selected geographic locations. After gunpowder brought cannons into widespread use, castles failed to provide the same protection from attack, and later rulers built palaces more along aesthetic than defensive lines.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>城堡在中世纪的欧洲有许多作用；并不仅仅是作为一个强大的防御工事而存在，它们同时还是行政和司法的中心，以及领主权力的象征。因为事物和其它补给可以大量存放在城堡内，其影响力就可以覆盖附近的广大地区。并不是只有领主才会建造城堡；教会的高层也常常这样做，这是为了有一个强大的权力基础。早期的城堡不过是建造在土堆上的木制围墙，或许还会有浅壕沟环绕于外；直到13世纪的英格兰国王忏悔者爱德华统治时期，建造城堡才成了一项精细的工程，需要有数以百计的工人和专家，在精心选择的地点建造高大的石制要塞和复杂的防御工事。但在火药的广泛使用之后，城堡已无法对抗攻击武器，所以此后建造的城堡注重美学价值更甚于注重防御用途。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BARRACKS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Warfare has been a recurring phenomenon throughout the history of mankind, and it continues to plague the world today. Although war is not a desirable situation, it is important that even the most peaceful of societies be prepared for the possibility of war. When warring nations are closely matched in technology and manpower, the army with the best training usually wins battles.Military schools and academies exist all over the world, established for the purpose of training military personnel in the latest methods, tactics, and technology. Men and women who graduate from such facilities possess higher than average command and military and technological skills, making them more effective in combat situations.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>战争是人类历史上频繁出现的现象，直到今天仍给人类制造着灾难。尽管战争并非人们所愿，但即便是最和平的社会也要随时防备着它的来临。当交战国在科技和人力方面相匹敌时，更训练有素的军队通常能赢得战斗。军事院校今天已遍布世界，其建立的目的是为了用最新的方法，战术，科技培训军事人员。军事学院的毕业生拥有更高水准的指挥，军事和科技技能，从而使他们在战场环境中的能力更强。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BUNKER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The term "bunker" is often used to denote military bomb shelters, often those housing high officials of the military and government. As shown in the second United States-Iraq War, a country with air dominance over a foe can do significant amounts of damage to a city with just a few bombs. Military and political leaders are prime targets for such attacks; often these officials will be protected in bunkers far below city streets. Bunkers are also used to protect communications networks, another important target. [PARAGRAPH:1]Any improvement in defense usually sparks an improvement in offensive weapons. The United States is building special "bunker-buster" bombs, designed to burrow deep into the ground before exploding. While such bombs may not destroy the deepest bunkers, they can cut off their communications, escape routes and air supply.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>地堡通常表示军用防弹掩体，它们是为军方和政府的高层服务的。就像第二次美国——伊拉克战争中表现出的那样，拥有绝对制空权的一方可以用少量炸弹造成敌人的严重损失。而军方和政府首脑通常是空中打击的首要目标；所以这些官员必须在城市地表下接受地堡的保护。地堡还要用来保护另一个重要目标——通信网络。[PARAGRAPH:1]但任何防御上的提高必然面临攻击武器性能的提升。美国已经开发出了“地堡终结者”，它可以在穿透地层到达目标后才爆炸。但即使是这种炸弹也无法摧毁那些深入地下的掩体，只能通过切断其通信，迂回进路及空气来源而使它们失去作用。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BOMB_SHELTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A bomb shelter is a structure designed to protect the people inside from falling bombs. Today's bomb shelters are designed to shield one from the destruction of a nuclear attack. People have constructed bomb shelters since the first artillery piece was put into action. Sometimes these are rude caves dug in a hillside; sometimes they are elaborate and complicated affairs, self-sustaining for weeks, dug hundreds of feet below the surface.[PARAGRAPH:1]In the 1950s during the Cold War, American citizens began constructing bomb shelters in their back yards and basements, hoping to avoid destruction during the atomic war they were sure was coming. The US government embarked on an ambitious program to create large bomb shelters in all major cities, stocking them with food, water, blankets, and other essential supplies. These are mostly abandoned today, probably because of the realization that most of them are not strong enough to do much good in the event of a nuclear attack.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>防空洞原本是为了让人们躲避炸弹而建造的。现代防空洞的设计意图则是为了防御核打击。自从炮兵出现后，人类就开始建造此类设施。有些防空洞只是简单地在山腹挖个洞；有些则是精心建造的复杂工事，位于地下数百米处，可以在失去同外界联系的情况支持许多个星期。[PARAGRAPH:1]在20世纪50年代的冷战时期，美国人纷纷在自家后院建造防空洞，希望藉此在看上去必将来临的核子战争中存活下来。美国政府则把注意力放到在各个主要城市建造巨型防空洞上，并在里面堆放大量食物、饮用水、毯子以及其它必需的物资。这些防空洞现在几乎都被废弃了，这可能是因为人们意识到它们并不足以防御核打击。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRANARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Early humans were nomadic, settling in specific regions only for brief periods of time. When the food supply was exhausted in one area, the nomads would move on to search for more. Cities became possible only when the development of agriculture made the supply of food more abundant and dependable. However, cities still needed a way to keep the food supply stable throughout all four seasons. To do so, the citizens had to come up with a way to store seasonal crops for later use. The Granary was designed for the storage and protection of surplus food. Food storage technology meant that a smaller percentage of the population could produce and store enough food for everyone, allowing the remainder to pursue other jobs and activities.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>早期人类过着游牧生活，只在特定的地方作短期居留。当一个地方的食物用尽之后，这些游牧民族就会继续寻找新的地方。城市的形成是在发明农耕而粮食供给变得更加丰富可靠之后。然而，城市仍然需要一个四季都可以稳定提供粮食的方法。为此，人们想出一个办法，可以贮存这些季节性的作物，供日后食用。粮仓就是设计用来贮存粮食的设施。粮食贮存技术意味着只需较少的人口就可以生产并贮存足够的粮食，而让其他人从事别的工作和活动。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AQUEDUCT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A major obstacle to population growth and expansion in early cities was the scarcity of water. In many cases, the solution to this problem was an aqueduct. Aqueducts were large, elevated stone "canals" through which water from nearby hills and mountains was channeled into the city. Aqueducts allowed cities to grow much larger by significantly increasing the amount of available water. At the same time aqueducts reduced the chance of contracting water-borne diseases, by reducing the dependence on stagnant ponds and wells as water sources. Aqueducts also allowed cities to be built in normally inhospitable environments, such as deserts, by providing an outside water source. Modern day Los Angeles, for example, obtains its water supply from the Colorado River, through a system of aqueducts over 200 miles long.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>限制早期城市人口增长的主要问题是水的缺乏。在多数情况下，人们修筑水渠以解决这一问题。水渠是石筑的大型高架沟槽，附近高山与丘陵中的水由此被引导至城市之中。由于引水渠给城市提供了大量的水，人口数量和城市的大扩展成为可能。同时水渠的应用使得人们对蓄水池和井的依赖性降低从而减少了感染水传播疾病的几率。通过从外地引来水源，水渠也使得人们可以在以往被认为不适宜居住的地方，例如沙漠之中，建立城市。现代的洛杉矶，它的城市用水就是通过一个引水渠道系统从200英里之外的科罗拉多河取得的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOSPITAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Hospitals are institutions that focus on the diagnosis and treatment of disease and trauma. While dispensing these services, they also provide housing. With technological innovation in medicine, hospitals have increasingly become community hubs, expanding their role to include teaching and research. Throughout history a hospital's role has shifted from a place to secure the ill or insane, to one of hope and health.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>医院是诊断，治疗疾病及创伤的机构，除此之外，还提供住院服务。在医疗改革之后，医院也开始更重要的角色，它变成了社会进行医学教学以及研究的中心。而医院的角色也从历史上提供病人安养的地方变成了希望及健康的象征。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RECYCLING_CENTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The continual growth in city populations leads to an inevitable increase in garbage. Eventually, existing landfills and garbage dumps are  filled, forcing new dumping sites to be established. This leads to the gradual but steady destruction of the local environment. To reverse this problem, many areas have established recycling centers, where much of the garbage is sorted and reduced to reusable components through various means. These components are then used to manufacture new products. In this way, much of the trash produced is turned into raw materials for production, rather than contributing to the ever-increasing pollution problem.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>城市人口的不断增长必然导致废弃物的增加。终于，现有的垃圾填埋场和堆放点都塞满了垃圾，人们不得不建立新的填埋地。这将逐渐对当地环境造成难以消除的破坏。为了解决这个问题，许多地方建立了回收中心。人们在那里将垃圾分类并通过很多方法将其变为可重复利用的资源。这些资源将被用来制造新的产品。由此，大量的废弃物被转换成工业生产的原料，而不是造成更多的污染问题。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LIGHTHOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A lighthouse is a tower constructed on the shoreline, usually near a harbor or busy waterway. A powerful light sits atop the tower, making the structure visible to mariners for miles around. Lighthouses are built to mark the location of rocks and shoals or other hazards in the dead of night or midst of storms. Before the invention of radar, electricity, and global positioning systems, any vessel sailing near the shore ran a risk of running into such hazards and sinking. Naturally, sailors preferred to sail to destinations that had a method of marking these perils, so harbors with lighthouses flourished. [PARAGRAPH:1]The original "lighthouse" was probably a bonfire lit by villagers to guide the village's fishing vessels back to harbor at night. Over time people realized that the fires could be seen much farther away if they were built atop platforms or towers. Further improvements were made as technology advanced; mirrors were built to direct the light in the desired directions; oil lamps replaced the more dangerous bonfires, which were in turn replaced by electric lamps. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>灯塔是建造在海岸线上的一座塔，一般位于毗邻海港或者繁忙的航线上。塔顶发出醒目的光，使数十英里范围内的船员都可以看到。建造灯塔是为了在漆黑的夜里或者暴风雨中标示暗礁，浅滩或其他危险的地方。在雷达，电和全球定位系统发明以前，近海航行的船只都要冒着沉没或搁浅的巨大风险。自然的，海员更倾向于航行在那些标记了危险地段的线路上，因此，建有灯塔的海港变得繁荣起来。[PARAGRAPH:1]最初的灯塔大概就是村民们为了引导晚归渔船安全回港燃起的篝火。时光流逝，人们认识到如果把火放在平台或者塔的顶上，那么很远都可以看得见。随着技术的进步，灯塔逐步升级换代；镜子被用来把光引导到预期的方向；油灯取代了危险的篝火，后来又被电灯取代。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HARBOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Just because a city is built in a coastal region doesn't guarantee that the city is readily accessible by ship. In order for a port city to establish a steady trade, fishing, or other shipping industry, the city must have a harbor. A harbor is a protected body of water that opens into an ocean or lake that shelters ships from waves and high winds. Although some coastal cities are established in areas where a natural harbor exists, most seaports are forced either to improve the existing natural harbor, or to build a man-made harbor to shelter ships and provide channels deep enough to accommodate large vessels.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>城市座落在海岸边并不表示这个城市可以让船只停靠。一个城市想要建立稳定的海上贸易，捕鱼业和其他航运业，就必须拥有一个港口。港口可以为海洋或湖泊上的船只躲避大风巨浪时提供保护。虽然一些沿海城市拥有天然的港湾，但是大多数这样的天然海港仍需要进行改善或者建筑人工港口以收容船只并挖掘能通行大型船舶的深水航道。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DRYDOCK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A drydock is a facility for constructing and repairing ships. Drydocks may be floating structures or land-based. They contain one or more large bays in which the ship-work is done.  These bays are below sea-level and contain drainage systems and water-tight doors. While construction or repairs are going on, the drydock is dry, the vessel sitting on the dock's floor supported by an elaborate structure of scaffolding. When construction or repairs are complete, the dock is flooded and the ship floats gently off the scaffolding. Once the water level inside the dock reaches sea-level, the drydock's doors are opened and the ship can proceed to sea.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>干船坞是用于船只建造和修理的设施。干船坞分为浮船坞和固定船坞。它包含一个或多个用于船只作业的大型汊港。这些汊港底部低于海平面，并装有排水系统和防水闸门。当建造或修理工作进行时，船坞是干的，船停放在船坞板上并由精心制作的脚手架支撑。当建造或者修理工作结束时，船坞注水使船浮起渐渐离开脚手架。一旦船坞里的水达到了水平面的高度，船坞的防水闸门就会打开让里面的船驶向大海。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AIRPORT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Since the middle of the 20th century, the airplane has been one of the chief means of long-distance transport in the world. Nearly every major metropolitan area today has at least one airport, with facilities to handle passengers and ticketing, as well as facilities for refueling and repairing the aircraft that land there. Beginning in the 1940s, the growing role of airplanes as combat vehicles led to the widespread construction of military air bases. Nearly 400 of these facilities in the U.S. alone act as bases and maintenance facilities for aircraft assigned to all branches of the military.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在二十世纪中期，飞机已经成为世界上主要的长途运输工具之一。而现在，几乎每个大都会都有至少一座机场，它们即能为旅客提供客运和票务服务，又能为着陆的飞机提供加油及维修服务。在20世纪40年代初期，越来越多的飞机被用作战斗，这造成了大量空军基地的出现。现在美国境内有多达400座的军用机场做为基地，并为部署在各军事部门的飞机提供维护服务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FORGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A forge is a furnace where metal is heated or melted. In ancient times smiths with small forges could be found in most settlements. The furnaces were stoked with coal, which was fanned by manually pumped bellows to create intense heat. The blacksmith would heat the metal in the oven and then shape it by putting the metal on an anvil and beating it with heavy hammers. The finished product was then put into cold water to harden and cool. The smith might also melt the metal and pour it into molds. [PARAGRAPH:1]Modern forges are huge industrial structures requiring many workers to operate. The operation is similar to that in the smithy; except on a grand scale.  Tons of ore are poured into massive vats, which are conveyed into the furnace. Once the metal is smelted, it may be mixed with other materials to create an alloy such as steel, and it may undergo a number of different processes to remove impurities. The finished metal can then be rolled into sheets, poured into molds, stamped into coins, and so forth.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>煅造场的熔炉是一个能让金属加热熔化的炉子。在远古时代所有的定居点都能找到自带小熔炉的铁匠。炉子里面放着碳，在用人力风箱吹进去的风作用下，发出大量热能。铁匠在炉子里加热金属，再把它放到铁砧上通过用重锤不停的敲击来塑形。接着，成品被放进冷水中冷却成形。铁匠也可以熔化金属然后把它灌注到模子中。[PARAGRAPH:1]现代熔炉是一个大型的工业建筑需要很多工人来操作。其实，操作流程和古代的铁匠铺里的操作相似，只是规模巨大而已。数以吨计的矿石被倾泻到结实的桶中，搬进熔炉里。一旦金属被冶炼，往冶炼过的金属中加入其他的材料就生成了合金，例如钢，它可能会经历数种不同的处理来去除杂质。完成的金属被轧成一片片的，被灌注到模子里，被压印成硬币和其它的用途。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FACTORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Early examples of factory-like production, where a number of individuals work cooperatively to produce goods for sale or trade, can be found as far back as ancient Greece and Rome. Modern factories, however, evolved from the concept of specialized labor, where each worker performed a single step in the overall production of an item. This specialization allows factories to increase the speed and efficiency of the manufacturing process, far surpassing earlier means of production. The development of the factory system as a means of production played a key role in the Industrial Revolution.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>工厂的雏型可追溯到古希腊及古罗马时期。当时的工厂只是一群个体相互合作去生产用于销售或交易的物品。而现代的工厂则是从专有分工这一概念发展而来，每个工人只负责整个生产流程中的一个步骤。这些专有分工提高了工厂的生产效率，大大超过了以前的合作生产方式。在工业革命时期，工厂系统作为一种生产方式不断地发展，并扮演着一个很重要的角色。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COAL_PLANT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Coal has been used sporadically as a fuel since ancient times, but it was not until the Industrial Revolution that the industrial applications of coal became understood. Most early factories used coal as a power supply, burning the fossil fuel to release the energy needed to drive the plant's machines. Coal power provided much more energy than relying on the strength of humans or animals, at the cost of releasing large amounts of toxic pollution into the atmosphere. Despite the environmental hazards associated with coal plants, they remain common today. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>煤很早就被用作燃料，到工业革命时期，煤在工业上开始广泛应用。大部分的早期工厂使用煤作为能源，燃烧这种古老的燃料来释放能量，驱动工厂里的机器。火力相比人力和畜力，能提供多得多的能量，但其代价就是释放大量的有毒的污染物进入大气层。尽管它们的存在对周围环境带来危害，但是火电站在今天仍然十分普遍。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HYDRO_PLANT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>One alternative to power generation utilizing coal or petroleum fuels is the hydroelectric power plant. This facility utilizes the energy of rapidly moving water to turn the turbines of its generators and produce electricity. In locations where a source of moving water is available, hydro plants offer a clean, safe alternative to coal, petroleum, and nuclear power generation. Hydro plants have their own set of  environmental dangers, however. The disruption of a river's normal flow and the massive flooding of the land behind the facility's dam can destroy the habitat of the wildlife inhabiting the river basin.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>替代使用煤及石油来发电的另外一种方案就是水力发电站。它的原理是靠快速流动的水流来推动涡轮并产生电力。在一个适合水力发电的地点上建立水电站，它就可以提供比燃煤、石油和核能更干净，安全的电力来源。水电站当然也会造成环境破坏，那就是利用水坝来阻断河流的正常流动会破坏流域上的野生动物的栖息地。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NUCLEAR_PLANT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Nuclear power plants utilize radioactive materials and the process of nuclear fission to generate the heat and steam needed to run electrical generators and produce electricity. Because nuclear power doesn't cause the air pollution associated with the burning of coal or petroleum products, this means of generating power is considered a viable alternative energy source. However, the toxic nature of the byproducts produced by the fission process creates serious problems of its own. No method of safely disposing of this toxic waste has been found, and the volatile nature of the fission reaction can lead to a meltdown of the reactor core if the reaction is not properly controlled. Because of these problems, the future of nuclear power is uncertain.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>核电站利用放射性材料和核裂变方法产生热量和蒸汽，驱动发电机发电。由于核能不会导致煤或油燃烧所产生的空气污染，因为它被视为一种可选择的替代能源。然而，核裂变所产生的放射性副产品产生了很严重的问题。目前还没有发现安全处理这些有毒废料的方法，而且裂变反应有不稳定性，如果控制不当，会导致核反应堆熔毁。正是由于这些问题，使得核能的未来尚难确定。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_OBELISK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An obelisk is a structure that reminds people of an important event that occured in the area, or an important person who lived, such as famous generals of rememberances of a particulary bloody conflict. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>方尖碑是用来记录当地发生过的重要事件，或者生活过的重要人物的建筑物，例如记念指挥某场战役的著名将领。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ACADEMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An academy is a school for advanced learning. Though China, Egypt, and India had such institutes earlier, the term "academy" was first applied to the Athenian school of philosophy, founded by Plato in approximately 390 BC. The school was built near a sacred grove named "Hekademia." [PARAGRAPH:1]An academy was an important asset for a city. It attracted both brilliant scholars and the children of wealthy or noble parents, who might then decide to settle in the city permanently. The academy could provide a broad, general education to its students, or it might concentrate upon a specific subject such as philosophy, mathematics, art, natural philosophy (the world and everything in it), or the martial arts. [PARAGRAPH:1]Today there are many educational facilities which bear the name "academy." The term is used loosely now, and in addition to its original meaning, is often applied to schools for children and teenagers. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>科学院是一个从事深入学术研究的机构。虽然中国，埃及和印度很早就有这样的机构，但是科学院（“阿卡德美”）一词最早是指柏拉图于公元前390年建立于雅典的哲学学园。这个学园坐落在一处名叫“赫卡德米亚”的神圣小树林附近。[PARAGRAPH:1]科学院是一个城市的重要资产。他既吸引有才华的学者，又招徕来自贵族或富人家庭的子女，而他们则可能在此后一直定居于这座城市。科学院可以为求学者提供内容广博的教育，也可以专注于某项特定的科目，例如哲学，数学，艺术，自然科学（世界及世间万物的科学）或者武术。[PARAGRAPH:1]现在很多教育机构都举着“科学院”的旗号。现在这个术语的使用宽松了，除了原始的意思，它还经常被用于进行儿童和青少年教育的学校。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LIBRARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The development of writing meant that the accumulated knowledge of a society could be written down and stored rather than memorized and passed along by word of mouth. The accumulated written material was stored in a library. The libraries of the ancient world, especially those at Alexandria and Pergamum, became leading centers of science and scholarship. The librarians actively collected the books of the world, accelerating the spread of knowledge.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>文字的发明使前人积累的知识可以通过文字留存下来，而不是以口头讲述以及记忆的方式来传递这些知识。这些累积的知识可以被存放在一座图书馆之中。图书馆在古代，特别是在亚历山大及帕加马，成为了科学以及哲学的领导核心。图书馆主动地收集世界上的书籍，加速了知识的传播。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UNIVERSITY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Universities are institutions of higher learning. Early universities, established in the Middle Ages, were usually built in cities that had a large or important cathedral. Studies at these institutions focused on matters concerning the church. The curricula quickly expanded to include classical art, literature, and languages. Modern universities provide the opportunity to study a wide array of subjects. They have also become centers for research into many fields, serving as the source of major advances in computers, medicine, physics, and a variety of other subjects.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>大学是高等教育机构。建立于中古时期的大学通常建造在有大型或重要教堂的城市之中，而这些大学的学习重点也着重于教会的事物上。不过后来很快地就扩展到古典艺术，文学以及语言之上。现代的大学则提供了相当广泛的学习机会，同时也培育了很多新学科，例如电子计算机、医学、物理等。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_OBSERVATORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An observatory is a building designed to allow those inside to study the stars, usually with the aid of a telescope. Early observatories consisted of buildings with conveniently-placed windows or high platforms, while later models have sophisticated rotating roofs with an aperture to hold a massive telescope. The rooftop rotates to allow the telescope to point in any direction. [PARAGRAPH:1]An observatory's location has much to do with its efficacy. Smog and other pollutants cut down on visibility; further, stars become more difficult to observe when there are other light-sources visible; so modern observatories are usually built as far away from cities as practical. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>天文台是一种通常放置着望远镜，供人们研究星辰的建筑物。早期的天文台由一些方便开启的窗户或者高台组成，近代的样式则装有可旋转的屋顶，并有一个洞口可以放置巨大的望远镜。旋转屋顶可以使望远镜朝向任何一个方向。[PARAGRAPH:1]天文台的位置极大地影响着望远镜观测的效果。烟尘和其他污染物会遮挡住可见光；而且，如果附近有其他的可见光源，星星将更加难以观测；所以现代天文台经常建在尽可能远离城市的地方。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LABORATORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Historically, libraries and universities have acted as the primary centers of research for new ideas and technologies. The growth of private industry in the Modern Age has also given birth to hundreds of privately owned research facilities. These private laboratories, usually dedicated to research in a single field related to their founding company, have made tremendous advances in many fields including physics, biology, chemistry, and medicine. The growth of privately-funded research has vastly increased the speed at which mankind achieves new advances in science and technology.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>历史上，图书馆和大学是研究新思想和新科技的重要中心。现代私营企业的成长也催生了成千上百的私人研究机构。这些私人实验室通常致力研究与他们创建的公司有关的单一领域，并在物理学、生物学、化学、医学等诸多领域取得了巨大进步。这些私人资助的研究大大推动了人类的科技进步。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_THEATRE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A theatre is a building in which audiences can watch a play or other theatrical performance. The earliest theatres were outdoors, constructed in a bowl-shaped depression to allow all in the audience to see the stage. Later, specific buildings were constructed to house theatres.[PARAGRAPH:1] Modern theatres are similar in layout to the earliest buildings. The audience sits or stands facing a stage; behind the stage is an extensive backstage area holding sets, props, dressing rooms and so forth. The primary difference between stages of Shakespeare's time and modern theaters is that the latter have electrical systems allowing them to light the stage as needed and to amplify the actors' voices.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>剧场是一种供观众在欣赏歌剧或者其他戏剧节目的建筑场所。最古老的剧场是露天的，被设计成逐渐下凹的碗状，这样所有观众们都可以看到舞台。后来，剧场被设计成室内建筑。[PARAGRAPH:1]现代剧场在形式上保留了一些古典建筑的特色。观众或坐或站的面对着舞台；在舞台之后是一个大型的后台区域，包括舞台布景、道具、化妆间及其他设施。现今的剧场相比莎士比亚时期的剧场，主要的差别是增加了一系列电子设备，在需要的时候可以给舞台照明或者放大演员的声音。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COLOSSEUM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The original colosseum provided entertainment for the common people of Roman society by presenting them with spectacles and events as a temporary escape from day-to-day life. This concept has been revived in the 20th Century. Modern-day stadiums and civic centers provide an arena for entertainment ranging from concerts to professional sporting events. Although the violent spectacle of gladiatorial combat is a thing of the past, today's colosseums still provide entertainment and diversion for the masses.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>最初，竞技场的作用是取悦罗马公民，日复一日平淡生活的他们可以从中获得解脱。这个概念在二十世纪又开始流行了。现代的体育场和市中心也提供娱乐场所，包括音乐会和职业体育赛事。虽然血腥刺激的角斗活动是古老时代的产物，不过今天的竞技场仍旧提供了人民大众喜闻乐见的娱乐及消遣。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROADCAST_TOWER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Although newspapers are published on a daily basis, they cannot often keep up to date on what is happening at the moment. Radio provides a means of doing that, as well as providing entertainment sources that would not otherwise be possible. With many events that occur in the world, it is important that the goverment be able to repudiate claims made by others, especially those that are true! Although radio has been superceeded by the television in most parts of the world, it is still a valuable tool to disseminate pro-goverment propaganda to the populace.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>即使报纸现在以日报的形式出版，仍然有很多消息不能及时登报。无线电广播就可以做到这一点，同时它也可以传播其他途径无法传送的信息资源。每时每刻，在这个世界上都会发生很多事件，对政府来说，驳斥他人的言论是非常重要的，尤其是那言论本身是正确的时候！尽管无线电广播在世界上很多地方已经被电视所取代，它仍然是政府用来向民众传播思想的有用的工具。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As cities grew and prospered, trade between the farmers, artisans, and craftsmen who lived in the vicinity contributed to the economic health of the city. It soon became apparent that the best way for conducting trade within the city was to have a central location, or marketplace, where the people offering goods and services, or seeking them, could meet and conduct business. As a city's marketplace grew larger and more active, the economic vitality of the city grew as well.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>当城市成长并繁荣起来，住在城市邻近区域的农夫、工匠、技工们就会开始互相交易，同时对城市的经济做出贡献。显而易见，在市中心有个固定场所，比如市场，是最好的贸易方式，人们可以在这里出售货物或提供服务，也方面他们寻觅货物或接洽生意。当一个城市的市场变得庞大而且更加活跃，城市的经济活力也相应增长起来。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GROCER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The word "grocer" is the ancient term for a grocery store. It denotes a market, usually under single ownership (unlike the older bazaar-style markets, which contain dozens or hundreds of small independent operations). The store sells fresh foodstuffs as well as canned goods and other household staples. [PARAGRAPH:1]Modern groceries - also known as "supermarkets" - are much larger than the originals, thanks in large part to the invention of refrigeration. They contain an extensive variety of foods from all over the world. Comparatively, food prices are much lower than they used to be, and today's families spend a historically low portion of their income on food of much higher variety than that offered to shoppers in the past.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>“杂货店”是综合店铺的旧式称谓。它代表着一类市场，通常由一位业主管理（不像古代中东的街市那样有很多个体小商贩组成）。杂货店里贮存并销售多种新鲜的食品、罐头食品和其他日常用品。[PARAGRAPH:1]现代杂货店——就是我们熟知的“超级市场”——比传统的店铺更大，这要归功于冷藏技术的发明。这里保存着来自世界各个地方的多种多样的食物。同时这里的食物价格相比小店铺要便宜不少，今天的家庭花在食物上的支出要比过去少得多，而购买的选择却多得多。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BANK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A highly developed banking system is one of the cornerstones of an advanced civilization. Banks lend money to individuals or groups, providing capital for industrial and real estate development. Banks also contribute to the economic growth of a city or region by stimulating the development of production facilities. Individual citizens can also benefit by investing their own surplus money in the bank and  earning interest on it.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>拥有一个高度发达的银行融体系是成为一个先进国家的基石。银行可以贷款给个人或是集体，也可以向工业及不动产业的发展提供资本。通过刺激工业产品生产，银行还促进了城市的经济发展。而市民个人也可以把他们多余的钱存在银行来赚取利息。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SUPERMARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Supermarkets are large, self-service retail stores that sell a wide variety of food items and household goods  to the general public. The first true supermarket, King Kullen, was established in 1930 in the borough of Queens, New York City, by Michael Cullen. Improved storage techniques and refrigeration allowed supermarkets to stock and sell perishable foods in large quantities, reducing the price to the consumer. The combination of ready availability and low prices made the supermarket an instant success in the U.S. during the years of the Great Depression.  The supermarket continues to grow in popularity in countries around the world.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>超级市场是大型的自选零售商场，向人们出售各种各样的食物和日常用品。第一家真正的超级市场是1930年在纽约市皇后区成立的金顾伦商场，创始人为麦克尔·顾伦。储存技术和冷藏技术的发展使超级市场可以大批量的供应新鲜食品，并降低商品的价格。选择多样和价格便宜使超级市场即使在美国大萧条时期仍然迅速获得成功。目前，超级市场正在世界范围内普及开来。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COURTHOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As kingdoms and empires expanded, it became increasingly difficult for the rulers to maintain control over the more distant regions of their realm. To ensure that the far-flung cities of the empire contributed their expected share of duties and taxes to the government, rulers constructed courthouses to help unify their domains. These local centers of government meted out justice and helped preserve order in the midst of the furthest wilderness. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>当国家领土大大扩张之后，统治者控制疆域内每个遥远地区的难度日益增加。为了确保偏远的城市也能对政府的赋税有所贡献，地方法庭开始设立起来。这些地方分支统治机构负责伸张正义，保证边远地区的正常社会秩序。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JAIL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A jail is a building for holding prisoners. Jails can range in size from a single room to a sprawling complex of buildings inside miles of barbed wire. Prisoners incarcerated in a jail may be there for a variety of reasons. Some may be common criminals; others may be brutal murderers. Some may be captured enemy soldiers and spies. Some might be political prisoners, dissidents, or simply people who fell into bad grace with their rulers. Some might be mad - incarceration being a common way to deal with the insane before the creation of mental hospitals and sanitariums. [PARAGRAPH:1] The facilities inside jails vary widely. A jail for commoners or enemies of the state might be horrible, overcrowded dark pits that are infested with rats, while a king's prison may be indistinguishable from royal quarters, except for the small matter of which side of the door on which the guards stand. Mostly, jails are unpleasant and unhappy places.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>监狱是用来关押犯人的建筑物，通常由数公里的铁丝网围成的区域内放置若干排单人房间构成。犯人可能因为很多原因被关进监狱。有些可能是普通的罪犯；而另一些可能就是杀人犯。有些可能是敌国被俘虏的士兵和间谍。有些则可能是政治犯，持不同政见者，或者是普通的被统治者迫害的老百姓。有些则是精神病患者——在专门的精神病院和疗养院建立之前，精神病人通常也是在那里关押的。[PARAGRAPH:1]监狱的用途很广泛。关押平民或者国家敌人的监狱是相当可怕的，在那里，狭小地窖的昏暗角落里遍布老鼠。不过除了卫兵在门外还是门内站岗位置的差别之外，关押国王的监狱和往往和普通的王宫并无差别。总之，监狱是一个令人痛苦和不舒服的地方。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>According to Jewish tradition, Solomon's Temple was the first Jewish temple in Jerusalem, and, as the "dwelling place of God," the single most important building in the Jewish religion. Construction was begun by King David and completed by his son, Solomon. The temple was built by Phoenician workers using the finest materials available - stones quarried from beneath the city, wood from Lebanon, and 3000 tons of gold and 30,000 tons of silver. The result was an astonishingly beautiful edifice standing some 30 yards long by 10 yards wide by 16 yards in height. It took seven years to complete the Temple.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Temple consisted of three main rooms surrounded by smaller chambers. Upon climbing a set of stairs, the visitor would enter the vestibule, which was topped with two enormous pillars given the names of Jachin and Boaz. From there the visitor would proceed into the "Greater House" or "Holy Place," wherein important religious services were performed. Beyond the Greater House lay the "Holy of Holies," a square, cedar-lined room which held the "Ark of the Covenant." The Ark of the Covenant was a sacred container which held the stone tablets upon which were written the Ten Commandments, given by God to Moses. The building was surrounded by a courtyard in which the people worshipped. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Temple was pillaged many times over the years, and it was finally looted and burned to the ground by King Nebuchadnezzar II of Babylon some time around 580 BC, during the time of the "Babylonian Captivity." Years later, many of the Temple's treasures were returned to the Jews by King [LINK=LEADER_CYRUS]Cyrus[\LINK] of Persia, but the Ark was missing. Some believe that the Ark was removed and hidden before the Babylonian attack, while others believe that the Ark was captured by Babylon and then destroyed or lost. The Ethiopian Orthodox Church claims to possess the Ark, it having been brought there by one of Solomon's sons. In any case, the destruction of the Temple was total, and there is much controversy and debate about where it originally stood. [PARAGRAPH:2]The "Second Temple" was constructed in Jerusalem in approximately 500 BC. It in turn was destroyed by the Romans in 70 AD. All that remains of this building is the "Western Wall," also known as the "Wailing Wall."</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>据犹太典籍记载，耶路撒冷的所罗门圣殿是犹太教的“第一圣殿”，作为“神的居所”，是犹太信仰中最重要的一座建筑。圣殿工程由大卫王发起，并由其子所罗门最终建成。圣殿由腓尼基工匠使用最好的材料建造——采自耶路撒冷地下的岩石，来自黎巴嫩的香柏木，3000吨黄金以及30,000吨白银等。完成的圣殿长30码，宽10码，高16码。全部工程共耗时七年完成。[PARAGRAPH:2]整个圣殿建筑群包括三个主厅及环绕四周的许多小厅。访问者需先通过长长的台阶到达殿廊，殿廊前立有由两根巨大的铜柱，名为“雅斤”和“波阿斯”。穿过殿廊即进入主殿（或称“圣所”）。献祭仪式在此处进行。在主殿之后还有“至圣所”，此处以雪松木装饰，用于放置神圣的“约柜”。当初神所赐予摩西，刻写着十戒的两块石板即保存于约柜之中。围绕圣殿的是供百姓进行祈祷的宽阔场院。[PARAGRAPH:2]所罗门圣殿在历史上曾多次遭受劫难，最终于约公元前580年被巴比伦国王尼布甲尼撒所焚毁，在持续多年的“巴比伦之囚”结束之后，波斯国王[LINK=LEADER_CYRUS]居鲁士[\LINK]将圣殿中原有的许多珍宝归还给犹太人，但是约柜却已经丢失。有人认为约柜在巴比伦军队入城之前已被转移藏匿，也有人认为是在落入巴比伦人之手后被毁或失踪。埃塞俄比亚正教会曾宣称约柜在其手中，是所罗门的后裔带往当地的。无伦如何，圣殿已彻底被毁，其具体所在位置也成了一个充满争议的问题。[PARAGRAPH:2]耶路撒冷的“第二圣殿”建于约公元前500年。在公元70年又被罗马人摧毁。存留至今的圣殿遗迹只有其西墙，即著名的“哭墙”。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple. [PARAGRAPH:1]Traditionally, the term "synagogue" is used to describe all Jewish houses of worship. For purposes of game clarity, Civilization IV uses the term to describe only the larger and more imposing structures; smaller religious structures are called "Jewish temples." [PARAGRAPH:1]Temples are places of prayer and study. Worshipers attend services on the "Shabbat" (or Sabbath), the day of rest which begins at sundown on Friday and ends at nightfall on Saturday. Jewish temples are often the center of Jewish life in a community, and may serve as schools, meeting places, libraries, and so forth.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，寺庙（或礼拜堂）被定义为宗教信徒进行宗教活动的建筑。基教徒称之为“礼拜堂”，穆斯林称之为“清真寺”，犹太人则简单地称之为“会堂”，此类建筑比大教堂更为常见，但规模及华丽程度则不及后者。甚至连最小的村庄也可能会拥有一座“寺庙”。[PARAGRAPH:1]传统上，犹太教的宗教活动场所一律被称为“会堂”。但为了在游戏中进行区分，文明IV用这一称谓专指大型的犹太教建筑；较小的则称之为“犹太礼拜堂”。[PARAGRAPH:1]犹太礼拜堂是祈祷和研习经书的场所。祈祷仪式在“安息日”进行，即从星期五的日落时分直到星期六晚上。犹太礼拜堂往往是犹太人社交生活的中心，可能充当学校、会场、图书馆等功能。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A monastery is a building where monks can retreat from the world and concentrate upon the divine. Usually a monastery will have strict rules of conduct to protect its unworldly members from temptation. In some monasteries, the monks are totally silent; in others no visitors are allowed inside. Monasteries usually have many daily rituals and religious services. [PARAGRAPH:1] Throughout the ages monasteries have often been centers of learning. In remote areas the monks may be the only literate people for miles around. Monks have often been employed as scribes, copying out the words of their religion's sacred scripture. Monasteries frequently have extensive libraries, holding religious, scientific, medical and philosophical texts. [PARAGRAPH:1]Though Judaism does not possess monasteries in the traditional sense, it does have Talmudic Academies, centers of learning where Rabbis discuss and debate the "Talmud," a record of rabbinical writings on Jewish law, ethics and custom. Aside from the Bible, the Talmud is the sole authority on many aspects of Jewish life and religious practice. Based upon earlier Jewish oral tradition, the Talmud was first put to paper in the second century, AD. It has been added to, debated and studied ever since.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>修道院是那些希望远离尘世，追求圣洁生活的宗教僧侣们的静修场所。通常修道院都规定有严格的行为准则，确保修道者免受外来的骚扰和诱惑。有的修道院要求人人保持静默；有的完全禁止访问者入内。僧侣们每日都须在修道院中举行宗教仪式。[PARAGRAPH:1]在古代，修道院往往也成为学术研究的中心。在边远地区，僧侣可能是当地仅有的有文化者。僧侣们经常担任抄写工作，负责传抄本宗教的经书文献。修道院通常会附有图书馆，用于存放神学、科学、医学和哲学书籍。[PARAGRAPH:1]虽然严格来说，犹太教并无传统意义上的修道院，但也建有“塔木德学院”作为其学术中心，犹太教的拉比（学者）们在其中讨论“塔木德经”（犹太法典），道德与传统规范等。除了圣经，塔木德经是犹太人生活和信仰各方面最重要的行为规范。根据记载，塔木德经的最初文本完成于公元二世纪。并在此后不断得到探讨和完善。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JEWISH_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a cathedral is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create cathedrals, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen. For example, the Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris, France, took over two centuries to complete. [PARAGRAPH:1]Traditionally, the term "synagogue" is used to describe all Jewish houses of worship. For purposes of game clarity, Civilization IV uses the term to describe only the larger and more imposing structures; smaller religious structures are called "Jewish temples." [PARAGRAPH:1]A Jewish synagogue is a place both of worship and of study. Worship and prayer take place in the main room. The prayer may be led by a "rabbi" (teacher), but it is not necessary, and many synagogues do not have a rabbi in attendance. Many of the most beautiful synagogues in the world are found in Eastern Europe. Unfortunately, many of the local worshipers were killed during the Holocaust, and most survivors fled to Israel, leaving these holy buildings sadly unattended.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，大教堂是指规模巨大，装饰华丽的宗教性建筑。只有非常繁荣的城市才有能力建造大教堂，因为此类建筑需要消耗大量原材料，并需要大批技艺精湛的工匠经年累月的努力。例如法国巴黎的圣母大教堂（巴黎圣母院）花费了两个世纪的时间才建造完成。[PARAGRAPH:1]传统上，犹太教的宗教活动场所一律被称为“会堂”。但为了在游戏中进行区分，文明IV用这一称谓专指大型的犹太教建筑；较小的则称之为“犹太礼拜堂”。[PARAGRAPH:1]犹太教会堂即是祈祷场所，也从事犹太典籍的研究。祈祷活动在会堂大厅举行。可能由一位“拉比”（犹太教学者）主持，但这并非必需，许多会堂并没有常驻的拉比。世界上最华美的犹太教会堂集中于东欧地区。不幸的是，许多当地的犹太人死于纳粹的种族大屠杀，幸存者多数逃到了以色列，这些建筑大都已经荒废。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple. [PARAGRAPH:1]Facing Roman persecution, the earliest Christians worshiped in secret in private homes, catacombs, and the like. The Emperor Constantine I legalized Christianity in 325 AD. Though not a Christian himself as is often mistakenly claimed, Constantine I built many Christian churches across Roman territory, including the Church of the Nativity in Bethlehem, which many Christians believe is on the site where Jesus was born.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，寺庙（或礼拜堂）被定义为宗教信徒进行宗教活动的建筑。基教徒称之为“礼拜堂”，穆斯林称之为“清真寺”，犹太人则简单地称之为“会堂”，此类建筑比大教堂更为常见，但规模及华丽程度则不及后者。甚至连最小的村庄也可能会拥有一座“寺庙”。[PARAGRAPH:1]由于遭受罗马人的迫害，早期的基督徒往往在私人宅院甚至墓室中秘密集会进行祈祷。君士坦丁一世于325年宣布基督教合法化。虽然其本人并非真正的基督徒（后人往往误解这一点），君士坦丁一世还是下令在帝国各地兴建了大批基督教建筑，其中包括伯利恒的圣诞大教堂，基督徒认为耶稣即是在此地诞生。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a cathedral is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create cathedrals, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen. For example, the Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris, France, took over two centuries to complete. [PARAGRAPH:1]Christian cathedrals are considered among the most beautiful buildings in the world. Many of the most imposing were built during the Middle Ages. Lofty buildings with beautiful stained glass, the early Christian cathedrals tended to collapse suddenly, with unfortunate results for those inside, until the invention of the flying buttress. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，大教堂是指规模巨大，装饰华丽的宗教性建筑。只有非常繁荣的城市才有能力建造大教堂，因为此类建筑需要消耗大量原材料，并需要大批技艺精湛的工匠经年累月的努力。例如法国巴黎的圣母大教堂（巴黎圣母院）花费了两个世纪的时间才建造完成。[PARAGRAPH:1]许多基督教大教堂都位列全世界最美丽建筑的名单之中。其中最著名的几座均建成于中世纪。这些大教堂均极其宏伟，装饰有大量玻璃镶嵌的美丽花窗，早期的基督教大教堂往往会突然坍塌，造成不幸事件，直到飞拱结构发明后问题才得以解决。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A monastery is a building where monks can retreat from the world and concentrate upon the divine. Usually a monastery will have strict rules of conduct to protect its unworldly members from temptation. In some monasteries, the monks are totally silent; in others no visitors are allowed inside. Monasteries usually have many daily rituals and religious services. [PARAGRAPH:1] Throughout the ages monasteries have often been centers of learning. In remote areas the monks may be the only literate people for miles around. Monks have often been employed as scribes, copying out the words of their religion's sacred scripture. Monasteries frequently have extensive libraries, holding religious, scientific, medical and philosophical texts. [PARAGRAPH:1]The first recorded Christian monastery was founded by Saint Anthony in Egypt around 300 AD. The idea spread throughout the Christian world, and eventually Christian monasteries could be found across North Africa, the Middle East, Western Asia, and Europe. The Roman Catholic Church has dozens of monastic orders, including the Benedictine, Franciscan, Jesuit, Carmelite, Trappist, Augustinian, and Knights Templar.  </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>修道院是那些希望远离尘世，追求圣洁生活的宗教僧侣们的静修场所。通常修道院都规定有严格的行为准则，确保修道者免受外来的骚扰和诱惑。有的修道院要求人人保持静默；有的完全禁止访问者入内。僧侣们每日都须在修道院中举行宗教仪式。[PARAGRAPH:1]在古代，修道院往往也成为学术研究的中心。在边远地区，僧侣可能是当地仅有的有文化者。僧侣们经常担任抄写工作，负责传抄本宗教的经书文献。修道院通常会附有图书馆，用于存放神学、科学、医学和哲学书籍。[PARAGRAPH:1]根据记载，第一座基督教修道院是由圣安东尼于公元300年在埃及建立的。这种做法在整个基督教世界得到了普遍接受，很快修道院就遍布了北非，中东，西亚和欧洲各地。罗马天主教会下属的修会团体就达十余个，包括本笃会、圣芳济会、耶稣会、卡迈尔会、特拉普会、奥古斯丁会以及圣殿骑士团等。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHRISTIAN_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Church of the Nativity was built in Bethlehem, atop the place where Jesus was born. Constructed in 325 AD, burnt during the Samaritan Revolt in 529 and then rebuilt over the next 50 years, the Church is one of the oldest continuously operating Christian churches in the world. It is also one of the most fought over. Over time the Church has been held by Crusaders, Muslims, and various Christian sects. [PARAGRAPH:2]Externally, the Church represents more a fortress than it does a house of worship. It is surrounded by a thick stone wall with few windows or entrances. The Church is laid out in the typical Roman basilica design, with three aisles leading to a semicircular apse containing the altar. The main room once featured walls covered with golden mosaics, but is now somewhat fallen into decay. Beneath the Basilica lies the "Grotto of the Nativity," an underground cave covering the place where Jesus is said to have been born. The exact spot of Jesus' birth is marked by a silver star and surrounded by silver lamps.[PARAGRAPH:2]The compound containing the church is approximately 14,000 square yards in size. In addition to the Basilica, it contains a number of other important religious sites and three convents. [PARAGRAPH:2]Since its inception, Christianity has fragmented into a number of distinct sects. For many years these different groups have fought for control of the Church, and much blood has been shed on the sacred grounds. In recent years it has been administered by a coalition of Roman Catholic, Armenian and Greek Orthodox clerics, who in uneasy alliance make the Church available to all who wish to enter. Each year the Church is visited by thousands of Christian pilgrims. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Church's recent history has been as turbulent as it's past. The town of Bethlehem is in the West Bank of Palestine, which is periodically under Israeli occupation, and in 2002 the Church itself was occupied by 50 Palestinian fighters seeking refuge from Israeli defense forces. Somewhat miraculously the Church itself has suffered no damage in the recent conflicts, although the turmoil has greatly diminished the number of visitors to the site, which in turn limits the money available for its upkeep. [PARAGRAPH:2]Still, the Church remains one of Christianity's holiest of places, where God's only Son and the Savior of mankind entered the world. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>圣诞大教堂在耶稣的出生地伯利恒。建于公元325年，在529年撒马利亚起义期间被焚毁，又在其后50年重建，该教堂是世界上延续至今最古老的教堂之一，也是无数人竞相夺取的目标。在历史上，圣诞大教堂曾先后被十字军，穆斯林以及其他许多基督教政权所控制。[PARAGRAPH:2]圣诞大教堂的外观更象是一座要塞而不象是宗教场所。它由厚厚的石墙所围绕，只有很少几个门窗与外界相通。教堂的设计采用传统的罗马方堂建筑结构，有三条走廊通向放置圣坛的半圆形后殿。教堂主厅内墙一度全为黄金镶嵌，但现在已经不复存在。在教堂地基之下有“圣诞洞”，传说耶稣即降生于此。该处有一颗银星标示耶稣诞生的位置，周围环绕着许多银灯。[PARAGRAPH:2]整个建筑群占地约14,000平方码。除了教堂本身，还包括其他一些重要宗教设施和三座修女院。[PARAGRAPH:2]随着时间的推移，基督教逐渐分裂为多个不同教派。各教派间不断在争夺圣诞大教堂的控制权，在这片圣地之上流下了无数的鲜血。近年来，圣诞大教堂由罗马天主教会和亚美尼亚，希腊东正教会的神职人员联合管理，以尽可能满足所有人进入教堂的要求。每年都有成千上万的基督教朝圣者访问圣诞大教堂。[PARAGRAPH:2]现在的圣诞大教堂仍然象过去一样充满着动荡和不安。伯利恒市地处巴勒西坦约旦河西岸地区，目前在以色利的占领之下，在2002年时有50名巴勒斯坦武装人员进入教堂躲避以色利国防军的围捕。教堂在近几年中的武装冲突中能够保持完好无损，不能不说一个奇迹，但是紧张的局势使得访问者大量减少，造成教堂的维护资金日益紧缺。[PARAGRAPH:2]无论如何，圣诞大教堂仍然是基督教世界最重要的圣地之一，上帝唯一的爱子，人类拯救者就是在这里降生世间。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple. [PARAGRAPH:1]In common usage, the term "mosque" is used to describe any Islamic house of worship. In this game that term is reserved for the more important and impressive structures; common mosques are called "Islamic temples. There are Islamic temples across the world. Many contain towers from which the worshipers are called to perform "salah," the five daily prayers each Muslim must perform.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，寺庙（或礼拜堂）被定义为宗教信徒进行宗教活动的建筑。基教徒称之为“礼拜堂”，穆斯林称之为“清真寺”，犹太人则简单地称之为“会堂”，此类建筑比大教堂更为常见，但规模及华丽程度则不及后者。甚至连最小的村庄也可能会拥有一座“寺庙”。[PARAGRAPH:1]伊斯兰教的宗教场所通常一律被称为“清真寺”。但为了在游戏中进行区分，这一名称用来专指更大型的伊斯兰教建筑；普通的清真寺则称为“伊斯兰礼拜堂”。世界各地均建有伊斯兰礼拜堂。此类建筑通常都带有尖塔，以及时召集穆斯林进行每日五次的“时礼”。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a cathedral is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create cathedrals, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen. For example, the Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris, France, took over two centuries to complete. [PARAGRAPH:1]In common usage, the term "mosque" is used to describe any Islamic house of worship. In this game that term is reserved for the more important and impressive structures; common mosques are called "Islamic temples." The first mosque built was the "Kaaba," in Mecca, which resides inside of the the Masjid al-Haram. According to tradition, the Kaaba was originally a temple constructed by the prophet Abraham and his son, Ishmael. By the Prophet Muhammad's time, the Kaaba was being used to worship many "false" gods; he destroyed the idols and rededicated the structure to Allah when he captured Mecca in 630 AD. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，大教堂是指规模巨大，装饰华丽的宗教性建筑。只有非常繁荣的城市才有能力建造大教堂，因为此类建筑需要消耗大量原材料，并需要大批技艺精湛的工匠经年累月的努力。例如法国巴黎的圣母大教堂（巴黎圣母院）花费了两个世纪的时间才建造完成。[PARAGRAPH:1]伊斯兰教的宗教场所通常一律被称为“清真寺”。但为了在游戏中进行区分，这一名称用来专指更大型的伊斯兰教建筑；普通的清真寺则称为“伊斯兰礼拜堂”。第一座清真寺建筑是麦加的“克尔白天房”，现位于阿尔-哈拉姆大清真寺的中心。传统上认为，克尔白天房最初是先知亚伯拉罕及其子以实玛利所建造。到先知穆罕默德时代，克尔白天房曾被用于祭祀多种“伪神”；穆罕默德于630年攻占麦加，摧毁了其中供奉的偶像，确认安拉为世间唯一的真主。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A monastery is a building where monks can retreat from the world and concentrate upon the divine. Usually a monastery will have strict rules of conduct to protect its unworldly members from temptation. In some monasteries, the monks are totally silent; in others no visitors are allowed inside. Monasteries usually have many daily rituals and religious services. [PARAGRAPH:1] Throughout the ages monasteries have often been centers of learning. In remote areas the monks may be the only literate people for miles around. Monks have often been employed as scribes, copying out the words of their religion's sacred scripture. Monasteries frequently have extensive libraries, holding religious, scientific, medical and philosophical texts. [PARAGRAPH:1]Islam has a great reverence for places of religious learning, no matter what religion. The Koran says, "Did not God check one people by means of another, there would surely have been pulled down monasteries, churches, synagogues and mosques, in which the name of God is commemorated in abundant measure."</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>修道院是那些希望远离尘世，追求圣洁生活的宗教僧侣们的静修场所。通常修道院都规定有严格的行为准则，确保修道者免受外来的骚扰和诱惑。有的修道院要求人人保持静默；有的完全禁止访问者入内。僧侣们每日都须在修道院中举行宗教仪式。[PARAGRAPH:1]在古代，修道院往往也成为学术研究的中心。在边远地区，僧侣可能是当地仅有的有文化者。僧侣们经常担任抄写工作，负责传抄本宗教的经书文献。修道院通常会附有图书馆，用于存放神学、科学、医学和哲学书籍。[PARAGRAPH:1]伊斯兰教非常尊重信仰的学术研究，且不论其属于何种宗教。可兰经上说，“真主眼中的世人并无分别，不论是修道院、教堂、会堂还是清真寺，都是在全力敬奉真主之名。”</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISLAMIC_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Masjid al-Haram is an Islamic mosque in the center of the holy city of Mecca, which is located in western Saudi Arabia. The mosque contains the Kaaba, an ancient cube-shaped building which is said to have been built by the Prophet Ibrahim (Abraham) and his son, Ishmael, at the orders of Allah, and which is believed to be the holiest place on Earth. The Kaaba in turn houses the "Black Stone," which it is said has fallen from heaven and has the power to cleanse worshippers of their sins. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Kaaba has always been revered as a holy place. Before the rise of Islam, the Kaaba was filled with idols, and Arabs from miles around came to worship there. Upon his return from exile, the Prophet Muhammad smashed the idols and rededicated the mosque to Allah and Islam. It has remained an Islamic holy place ever since and non-Muslims are forbidden to enter Mecca. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Masjid al-Haram is the focal point of the "hajj," a religious pilgrimage to Mecca required of all able-bodied Muslims (at least according to the Sunni sect). Every year during the holy month of Dhu'l-Hijjah, upwards of three million people visit the holy city and the most holy mosque within, thus fulfilling one of the "five pillars of Islam." The mosque has been enlarged and modernized to handle the extraordinary influx of faithful, but both the city and the mosque can barely handle the traffic. [PARAGRAPH:2]The mosque is in the form of a huge sprawling building surrounding a mighty courtyard with the Kaaba in the center. The building is extraordinarily beautiful and constructed of marble and porcelain and gold and bedecked with graceful minarets (towers). The interior is a wonder of columned halls filled with tapestries and other marvelous decorations. The courtyard itself is paved with marble. Truly a magnificent place of worship, Masjid al-Haram is said by some to surpass the Taj Mahal in glory and wonder.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>克尔白天房位于沙特阿拉伯西部的伊斯兰教圣城麦加市中心的阿尔-哈拉姆大清真寺（“禁寺”）内，是一座古老的方形建筑，传说为先知亚伯拉罕（易卜拉颀）及其子以实玛利依照安拉的命令所建造，是世界上最神圣的场所。天房中安放有一块“黑石”，据说来自天界，能使信徒消除自身的罪孽。[PARAGRAPH:2]自古以来克尔白天房就是一处圣地。在伊斯兰教兴起之前，天房中供奉着许多偶像，各处的阿拉伯人都前往该地祭拜。在先知穆罕默德经历流放生涯返回麦加之后，其中的偶像全被捣毁，成为专门敬奉安拉的伊斯兰清真寺。在此后，麦加一直是伊斯兰教的圣地，完全禁止非穆斯林进入。[PARAGRAPH:2]任何有能力的穆斯林在一生中都必须前往禁寺进行一次朝圣之旅（至少对于逊尼派来说）。在每年的朝圣月期间，总有超过三百万人前往圣城的禁寺，以完成“伊斯兰五功”之一（念、礼、斋、课、朝）。为此近年来禁寺不断进行扩建和现代代改造，但圣城和禁寺仍然是不堪重负。[PARAGRAPH:2]整座禁寺围绕着克尔白天房所在的大广场而建造。建筑风格极其精美，外部以大理石、陶瓷、黄金装饰，并点缀以数座尖塔。禁寺内大厅则密布挂毯等饰物。广场也完全以大理石铺成，是世上最豪华的宗教场所之一。许多人认为这座禁寺比泰姬玛哈陵还要更为宏伟壮观。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HINDU_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple. [PARAGRAPH:1]The word "mandir" is used to denote all Hindu places of worship. In Civilization IV, that term is reserved for the larger and more ornate buildings; smaller mandirs are called "temples." Typically, a Hindu temple is dedicated to a primary Hindu deity and that deity's subordinates. Worshipers must maintain a certain level of ritual purity to enter a temple: they must not wear footwear; they must not smoke, eat or drink inside; their breath should not smell of garlic or onions; and they may enter only with the priest's permission. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，寺庙（或礼拜堂）被定义为宗教信徒进行宗教活动的建筑。基教徒称之为“礼拜堂”，穆斯林称之为“清真寺”，犹太人则简单地称之为“会堂”，此类建筑比大教堂更为常见，但规模及华丽程度则不及后者。甚至连最小的村庄也可能会拥有一座“寺庙”。[PARAGRAPH:1]印度教的宗教活动场所统称为神殿（“曼迪尔”）。为了在游戏中进行区分，这一名称用来专指更大型的印度教建筑；较小的印度教建筑则称为“神庙”。通常，印度教的神庙会供奉一位主神及一些次神。祭拜者进入神庙前必须做特定的净化仪式：不能穿鞋；不能其内吸烟或饮食；不能带有大蒜或洋葱的气味；而且进入前要先得到神职人员的允许。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HINDU_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a cathedral is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create cathedrals, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen. For example, the Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris, France, took over two centuries to complete. [PARAGRAPH:1]A "mandir" is the name used to describe all Hindu places of worship; used here it refers only to the larger and more important temples. Typically, a mandir is dedicated to a primary Hindu deity and other deities associated with that particular god, though in the US many different gods are worshiped in each mandir. The earliest mention of a mandir appears in the fifth century BC. The Angkor Wat, a Hindu temple built in the 12th Century AD, is one of the finest surviving Hindu mandirs in the world.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，大教堂是指规模巨大，装饰华丽的宗教性建筑。只有非常繁荣的城市才有能力建造大教堂，因为此类建筑需要消耗大量原材料，并需要大批技艺精湛的工匠经年累月的努力。例如法国巴黎的圣母大教堂（巴黎圣母院）花费了两个世纪的时间才建造完成。[PARAGRAPH:1]印度教的宗教活动场所统称为神殿（“曼迪尔”）。为了在游戏中进行区分，这一名称用来专指更大型的印度教建筑；较小的印度教建筑则称为“神庙”。通常，印度教的神庙会供奉一位主神及一些从属的次神，但在美国的印度教神殿往往会同时供奉多个神灵。最早的印度教神殿出现于公元前五世纪。建造于12世纪的吴哥窟是世界上最宏伟的印度教神殿之一。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HINDU_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A monastery is a building where monks can retreat from the world and concentrate upon the divine. Usually a monastery will have strict rules of conduct to protect its unworldly members from temptation. In some monasteries, the monks are totally silent; in others no visitors are allowed inside. Monasteries usually have many daily rituals and religious services. [PARAGRAPH:1] Throughout the ages monasteries have often been centers of learning. In remote areas the monks may be the only literate people for miles around. Monks have often been employed as scribes, copying out the words of their religion's sacred scripture. Monasteries frequently have extensive libraries, holding religious, scientific, medical and philosophical texts. [PARAGRAPH:1]Hindu monasteries have been constructed across India and Asia. Many were built in remote places, far from the ravages of war and conquest; some survive today virtually untouched by history. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>修道院是那些希望远离尘世，追求圣洁生活的宗教僧侣们的静修场所。通常修道院都规定有严格的行为准则，确保修道者免受外来的骚扰和诱惑。有的修道院要求人人保持静默；有的完全禁止访问者入内。僧侣们每日都须在修道院中举行宗教仪式。[PARAGRAPH:1]在古代，修道院往往也成为学术研究的中心。在边远地区，僧侣可能是当地仅有的有文化者。僧侣们经常担任抄写工作，负责传抄本宗教的经书文献。修道院通常会附有图书馆，用于存放神学、科学、医学和哲学书籍。[PARAGRAPH:1]印度教静修院分布于印度和亚洲其他地区。此类建筑常常位于边远地区，以避免战火的侵扰；许多古老的静修院一直存在至今。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HINDU_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Kashi Vishwanath was a temple located in Varanasi, "the oldest living city in the world," and the place most sacred to Hinduism. The origins of Varanasi are shrouded in history, but it is believed that the city is more than 3000 years old. After visiting the city, Mark Twain wrote that Varanasi "is older than history, older than tradition, older even than legend and looks twice as old as all of them put together."[PARAGRAPH:2]According to Hindu tradition Varanasi is the home of Lord Shiva and his consort, Parvati. Known as the Destroyer, Lord Shiva is part of the "trimurti" - the three aspects of God - creation, preservation, and destruction. Shiva's consort Parvati is seen as Earth Mother, and, according to tradition, the two are the parents of all living creatures. The city is also held sacred because it is here that the Ganges River gained the power to wash away sins. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Kashi Vishwanath is a golden temple standing at the city's center. The date of construction of the original temple is not known. It was destroyed in 1669 by the Mughal Emperor Aurangzeb, who built a mosque atop the ruins. The present Kashi Vishwanath was built in 1776, across the street from its original location. The newer building's spire is about 50 feet in height and covered with over one ton of gold plating, donated by Maharaja Ranjit Singh. The temple's interior consists of a mandapa (pillared hall) and a sanctum containing a silver altar. [PARAGRAPH:2]According to Hindu tradition, it was here that the first jyotirlinga, the fiery pillar of light by which Shiva manifested his supremacy over other Gods, broke through the earth's crust and flared towards the heavens. The altar contains a Shivalinga (an ancient symbol of Shiva) in its center to commemorate this event. It is believed that viewing the temple can transform a worshipper's life and put him on the path of knowledge and devotion, and each year the temple is visited by tens of thousands of Hindu faithful seeking enlightment.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>黄金殿位于印度瓦拉纳西，“世界上现存最古老的城市”，是最神圣的印度教建筑。虽然瓦拉纳西最初的建造年代已不可考，但据信它拥有超过3000年的建城史。马克吐温在访问该城之后写道，瓦拉纳西“比历史更古老，比传统更古老，甚至也比传奇更古老，后三者的年龄加起来也不及它一半古老。”[PARAGRAPH:2]根据印度教传说，瓦拉纳西是湿婆大神及其妻室巴瓦娣的居所。作为破坏之神，湿婆是“三相神”——三位一体的主神——创造之神，保护之神，以及破坏之神。而巴瓦娣则被视为大地之母，传说两者创造了世上所有的生命。这座城市之所以神圣，还因为城畔的恒河拥有洗刷所有罪恶的神力。[PARAGRAPH:2]黄金殿位于瓦拉纳亚市中心。该神殿最初的建造年代已不可考，1669年时曾被莫卧儿皇帝奥朗则布所摧毁，并在原址建造了一座清真寺。现存的黄金殿建于1776年，与原址隔街相望。新殿尖顶高50英尺，由重达一吨的黄金覆盖，系由当地王公拉吉特·辛格所捐赠。神殿由主大厅和放置银制圣坛的后厅构成。[PARAGRAPH:2]根据印度教传说，第一块“究提林迦”（意为光之圣石，湿婆用以胜过其他诸神的宝物）就是在神殿圣坛所在位置射出大地直达天界的。圣坛现放置着湿婆林迦（湿婆神的标志）以纪念这一事件。信徒们认为进入黄金殿可使人获得智慧和忠诚，因此每年都有无数印度教徒前来朝拜以寻求神的启示。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BUDDHIST_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple. [PARAGRAPH:1]Buddhist temples are places of worship, meditation and study; they can be found across the world. The oldest surviving Buddhist temples are in India, where the religion was first founded. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，寺庙（或礼拜堂）被定义为宗教信徒进行宗教活动的建筑。基教徒称之为“礼拜堂”，穆斯林称之为“清真寺”，犹太人则简单地称之为“会堂”，此类建筑比大教堂更为常见，但规模及华丽程度则不及后者。甚至连最小的村庄也可能会拥有一座“寺庙”。[PARAGRAPH:1]佛堂是佛教僧侣祈祷，冥想与研读经书的场所；佛堂分布于世界各地。现存最早的佛堂在佛教的发源地——印度。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BUDDHIST_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a cathedral is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create cathedrals, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen. For example, the Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris, France, took over two centuries to complete. [PARAGRAPH:1]Buddhist stupas are monuments holding holy relics. The first eight stupas were created to hold the Buddha's remains. During his reign, the Emperor Asoka took portions of the Buddha's ashes and spread them among the thousands of stupas he created. Stupas can now be found across Asia and the world. [PARAGRAPH:1]The oldest surviving stupa can be found in Sanchi, India. The "Great Stupa" was constructed by Emperor Asoka some time in the third century BC.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，大教堂是指规模巨大，装饰华丽的宗教性建筑。只有非常繁荣的城市才有能力建造大教堂，因为此类建筑需要消耗大量原材料，并需要大批技艺精湛的工匠经年累月的努力。例如法国巴黎的圣母大教堂（巴黎圣母院）花费了两个世纪的时间才建造完成。[PARAGRAPH:1]佛寺中的佛塔最初用来存放佛教圣物。最初的八座佛塔中安放的就是释迦牟尼的佛骨舍利。在阿育王统治时期，佛骨舍利又分散安放到他所新建的上千座佛塔中。今日亚洲及世界各地的佛寺中都有佛塔。[PARAGRAPH:1]现存最古老的佛塔位于印度桑吉。这座“大佛塔”为阿育王在公元前三世纪所建。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BUDDHIST_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A monastery is a building where monks can retreat from the world and concentrate upon the divine. Usually a monastery will have strict rules of conduct to protect its unworldly members from temptation. In some monasteries, the monks are totally silent; in others no visitors are allowed inside. Monasteries usually have many daily rituals and religious services. [PARAGRAPH:1] Throughout the ages monasteries have often been centers of learning. In remote areas the monks may be the only literate people for miles around. Monks have often been employed as scribes, copying out the words of their religion's sacred scripture. Monasteries frequently have extensive libraries, holding religious, scientific, medical and philosophical texts. [PARAGRAPH:1]Buddhist monasteries were originally created to provide places for the wandering Buddhist monks to make their annual retreats. Some Buddhist monks stay indoors during the three-month rainy season to avoid damaging new plant growth (and to avoid being stranded during inclement weather). In the past, wealthy supporters donated plots of land where the monks could retreat; over time these have evolved into monasteries, often large and wealthy structures where monks can live year round. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>修道院是那些希望远离尘世，追求圣洁生活的宗教僧侣们的静修场所。通常修道院都规定有严格的行为准则，确保修道者免受外来的骚扰和诱惑。有的修道院要求人人保持静默；有的完全禁止访问者入内。僧侣们每日都须在修道院中举行宗教仪式。[PARAGRAPH:1]在古代，修道院往往也成为学术研究的中心。在边远地区，僧侣可能是当地仅有的有文化者。僧侣们经常担任抄写工作，负责传抄本宗教的经书文献。修道院通常会附有图书馆，用于存放神学、科学、医学和哲学书籍。[PARAGRAPH:1]佛教修道院起初是为云游四方的佛教僧侣提供休憩之所。在持续三个月的雨季中，僧侣们会留在佛院之内，避免此时外出会踏伤新生的小草（而且这样的气候也不便出行）。富裕的施主也会向佛院赠送土地作为供奉；使佛院的规模不断扩大，僧侣们也开始长年居住其中而不再出外云游了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BUDDHIST_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Located near Patna, in Bihar state, India, the Mahabodhi is a Buddhist temple in Bodh Gaya, the place where, according to Buddhist tradition, Siddhartha Gautama gained enlightenment and became the Buddha while meditating under a Bodhi (Peepal) tree. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Emperor Asoka constructed the "Golden Throne" sometime around 250 BC, and over time many other buildings and statues were added. In the 12th century the area was overrun by Muslims, and the temple sacked and largely destroyed. In the 16th century a Hindu monastery was established, and the monastery's abbot was given control over the temple grounds. [PARAGRAPH:2]Eventually the area came under British control. In the 1880s they began a major restoration of the temple, much against the wishes of the Hindu abbot. In the 1940s control over the site was given to the state, which manages the site with the advice of a committee containing Buddhists from the world over. [PARAGRAPH:2]A building of remarkable beauty and grandeur, the Mahabodhi is one of the oldest surviving brick buildings in India. Standing on the ruins of an even older "stupa," the temple consists of a high central tower surrounded by four smaller towers. The central tower rises some 60 feet in height. The edifice is covered by ornate and colorful molding, pilasters (pseudo columns), and arches, many of which contain bas relief sculptures. Inside sits a very large gilded statue of the Buddha. The statue sits where, legend has it, the Buddha was sitting when he achieved enlightenment. [PARAGRAPH:2]Near to the building stands a mighty Bodhi tree, a descendant of the one under which Buddha found enlightenment. The temple stands within an extensive complex of smaller temples, statues, and pathways running through beautiful parklands and alongside peaceful lakes. The temple and its surroundings remain a focus of Buddhist worship, and people from across the world come every year to honor the Buddha and to marvel at the beauty of the Mahabodhi.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>大菩提寺坐落于印度比哈尔邦的巴特那附近，是一座佛教寺庙。根据佛教的传说，佛教创始人乔达摩·悉达多就是在那里的一棵菩提树下进行冥想时突然大彻大悟，从而成佛。[PARAGRAPH:2]阿育王于公元前250年左右建造了“黄金王座”，随后的时间里，陆续建造了许多其他建筑和雕像。12世纪穆斯林蹂躏了这里，寺庙遭到洗劫，大部分被毁。16世纪这里成了一座印度教的神庙，这一带也被印度教徒所控制。[PARAGRAPH:2]后来该地区又落入英国人之手。19世纪80年代，这座寺庙进行了大规模的修复，虽然这遭到了许多印度教僧侣们抵制。20世纪40年代，这一地区的控制权被移交给了政府。并根据来自全世界佛教徒组成的委员会的意见管理着这座寺庙。[PARAGRAPH:2]大菩提寺非常美丽庄严，是印度现存最古老的砖砌建筑。建立于一座更古老的佛塔的废墟之上，这座寺庙拥有一座中央高塔，四面还有四座小塔。中央塔大约有60英尺高。整座建筑遍布绚丽多彩的壁柱和拱顶。上面还有大量的浮雕。内部有很大的镀金佛像。这是一尊坐像，据说佛祖在得道之后就是坐化的。[PARAGRAPH:2]在建筑附近有一棵很大的菩提树，据说是佛祖得道那棵树的后代。寺庙附近有大量的小寺庙，雕像和道路，穿过那些如茵的绿地，旁边是宁静的湖泊。寺庙和其附近的建筑仍然是佛教徒们膜拜的圣地，每年有无数人从世界各地来到这里膜拜佛祖，并欣赏着大菩提寺的美丽风光。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONFUCIAN_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple. [PARAGRAPH:1]Though Confucius himself was a philosopher rather than a religious leader, over time he was accorded the status of a god and worshipped across Asia. Many temples to Confucius were constructed, some small and private, others more extensive where hundreds of worshippers could attend services. Many Confucian temples were constructed in the pagoda style of architecture.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，寺庙（或礼拜堂）被定义为宗教信徒进行宗教活动的建筑。基教徒称之为“礼拜堂”，穆斯林称之为“清真寺”，犹太人则简单地称之为“会堂”，此类建筑比大教堂更为常见，但规模及华丽程度则不及后者。甚至连最小的村庄也可能会拥有一座“寺庙”。[PARAGRAPH:1]虽然孔子本人是一位哲学家而非宗教领袖，但随着时间的推移，他的地位逐渐变得神圣起来，在亚洲的许多国家均为民众所崇拜。各处都建造了祭祀孔子的建筑（除用于祭祀外也是宣讲儒学场所），有些规模较小，称为学馆。有些则宏伟堂皇，称为学宫，所有此类建筑大都采用中国传统的飞檐斗拱的建筑形式。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONFUCIAN_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A monastery is a building where monks can retreat from the world and concentrate upon the divine. Usually a monastery will have strict rules of conduct to protect its unworldly members from temptation. In some monasteries, the monks are totally silent; in others no visitors are allowed inside. Monasteries usually have many daily rituals and religious services. [PARAGRAPH:1] Throughout the ages monasteries have often been centers of learning. In remote areas the monks may be the only literate people for miles around. Monks have often been employed as scribes, copying out the words of their religion's sacred scripture. Monasteries frequently have extensive libraries, holding religious, scientific, medical and philosophical texts. [PARAGRAPH:1]For centuries Confucianism was the state religion of China, and the Imperial Court regularly included Confucians in positions of authority and power. Thus, many Confucian monasteries were constructed under Imperial sponsorship. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>修道院是那些希望远离尘世，追求圣洁生活的宗教僧侣们的静修场所。通常修道院都规定有严格的行为准则，确保修道者免受外来的骚扰和诱惑。有的修道院要求人人保持静默；有的完全禁止访问者入内。僧侣们每日都须在修道院中举行宗教仪式。[PARAGRAPH:1]在古代，修道院往往也成为学术研究的中心。在边远地区，僧侣可能是当地仅有的有文化者。僧侣们经常担任抄写工作，负责传抄本宗教的经书文献。修道院通常会附有图书馆，用于存放神学、科学、医学和哲学书籍。[PARAGRAPH:1]在数千年间，儒学一直是中国的官方信仰，朝庭大量任用儒士担任政府官职。许多儒学书院都获得官方的资助。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONFUCIAN_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a cathedral is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create cathedrals, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen. For example, the Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris, France, took over two centuries to complete. [PARAGRAPH:1]Many of the early Confucian religious buildings were destroyed during the Qin Dynasty. When the Emperor Wu (156-87 BC) adopted Confucianism as the state religion of China, he placed many Confucian scholars in positions of power; eventually, knowledge of Confucianism became a prerequisite for anyone hoping to gain employment in the Imperial government. Private and public Confucian Academies sprung up across China, where families sent their sons to study for the civil service examinations. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，大教堂是指规模巨大，装饰华丽的宗教性建筑。只有非常繁荣的城市才有能力建造大教堂，因为此类建筑需要消耗大量原材料，并需要大批技艺精湛的工匠经年累月的努力。例如法国巴黎的圣母大教堂（巴黎圣母院）花费了两个世纪的时间才建造完成。[PARAGRAPH:1]许多早期的儒学建筑在秦朝时遭到焚毁。在汉武帝统治时期（前156-前87），儒学被尊为官方信仰，他任用了许多大儒执掌朝政；最终，熟悉儒学经典成为在朝廷和地方担任官职的基本前提。私人或官办的儒学教育机构（学宫）遍布全国，许多年轻人在其中读书求学，为通过各级科举考试而努力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CONFUCIAN_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Kong Miao, or Temple of Confucius, is located in the city Qufu in China's Shandong province. The origins of the temple date back to 478 BC, when a local ruler built a temple to honor Confucius (who had only recently passed away and was relatively unknown in most of China). As time passed and the fame of Confucius began to spread, the Kong Miao grew in stature and importance as well. The Han Emperor Wu Di offered sacrifices at the site in 205 BC, and the Kong Miao continued to be patronized by various emperors across the centuries. [PARAGRAPH:1]The actual buildings that make up the Kong Miao have been torn down and rebuilt many times over the centuries. The present layout dates to the early 16th century, when the temple was rebuilt following a massive conflaguration in 1499 sparked by lightning. Since this construction took place at the same time as Beijing's Forbidden Palace, there are many design similarities between the two complexes. The Kong Miao is known not only for its size (it comprises some 466 rooms), but also for its stone sculptures and calligraphy dating back to many different dynasties. Today it is both a holy Confucian shrine and a popular tourist attraction. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>孔庙，即孔氏宗庙，坐落于中国山东省曲阜县境内。该庙的起源可上溯到公元前478年，当时的一位地方统治者建立了这座庙纪念孔子（那时他刚刚去世，在大部分中国尚不为人知）。随着时间的流逝，孔子的盛名开始广为流传，孔庙的规模和地位也不断扩大。汉武帝于公元前205年首次在该庙献祭，此后的数百年间孔庙不断地得到各位帝王们的资助。[PARAGRAPH:1]构成孔庙的建筑在数百年里多次被毁坏而又重建。现存的建筑约建造于16世纪早期，当时寺庙毁于1499年的一次雷击引起的大火。该建筑与北京的紫禁城建于同一时期，因而两者的设计中有许多相似之处。孔庙不仅因其建筑规模宏大而著名（共有房屋466间），而且拥有大量不同时代的书法和石刻。今天这里不但是儒家的圣地，也是广受欢迎的游览胜地。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAOIST_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple. [PARAGRAPH:1]Taoist temples are often attractive, brightly-colored buildings, filled with statues of divine beings. Priests may or may not be in attendance. Taoism is a ritualistic religion, and the temple is often used for ceremonies ranging from parades to exorcisms. The ceremonies themselves tend to be loud and colorful, full of chanting, singing, clashing symbols, and firecrackers.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，寺庙（或礼拜堂）被定义为宗教信徒进行宗教活动的建筑。基教徒称之为“礼拜堂”，穆斯林称之为“清真寺”，犹太人则简单地称之为“会堂”，此类建筑比大教堂更为常见，但规模及华丽程度则不及后者。甚至连最小的村庄也可能会拥有一座“寺庙”。[PARAGRAPH:1]道教建筑称为道观，一般而言装饰精美，设有许多神仙塑像。通常会有修道之士居住其中。教道非常注重礼仪，道观经常会举行各种各样的仪式，或为传道，或为驱魔。举行此类仪式时往往钟鼓礼乐齐备，喧闹非凡。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAOIST_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A monastery is a building where monks can retreat from the world and concentrate upon the divine. Usually a monastery will have strict rules of conduct to protect its unworldly members from temptation. In some monasteries, the monks are totally silent; in others no visitors are allowed inside. Monasteries usually have many daily rituals and religious services. [PARAGRAPH:1] Throughout the ages monasteries have often been centers of learning. In remote areas the monks may be the only literate people for miles around. Monks have often been employed as scribes, copying out the words of their religion's sacred scripture. Monasteries frequently have extensive libraries, holding religious, scientific, medical and philosophical texts. [PARAGRAPH:1]Taoists began constructing monasteries during the Tang period, from 600 - 900 BC. They learned the concept of monasticism from the Buddhists, who greatly influenced Taoism during this period.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>修道院是那些希望远离尘世，追求圣洁生活的宗教僧侣们的静修场所。通常修道院都规定有严格的行为准则，确保修道者免受外来的骚扰和诱惑。有的修道院要求人人保持静默；有的完全禁止访问者入内。僧侣们每日都须在修道院中举行宗教仪式。[PARAGRAPH:1]在古代，修道院往往也成为学术研究的中心。在边远地区，僧侣可能是当地仅有的有文化者。僧侣们经常担任抄写工作，负责传抄本宗教的经书文献。修道院通常会附有图书馆，用于存放神学、科学、医学和哲学书籍。[PARAGRAPH:1]在公元7至10世纪，李唐王朝十分尊奉教道，大批道院开始兴建起来。这一时期的道教也不断借鉴佛教的经验而日趋成熟。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAOIST_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Civilization IV, a cathedral is defined as an especially large and ornate religious building where the faithful worship. Only the most prosperous cities can afford to create cathedrals, as they require huge amounts of raw material and years of dedicated labor by skilled craftsmen. For example, the Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris, France, took over two centuries to complete. [PARAGRAPH:1]Many of the most elaborate and extensive Taoist religious buildings are pagodas - tiered towers with multiple eaves. This building style originated in Nepal and has since spread across much of Asia. Unfortunately, many great Taoist pagodas were constructed of wood - wood holds special religious significance for Taoists - and have not withstood the onslaught of time. [PARAGRAPH:1]Taoist pagodas tend to be bright and colorful structures, with broad curving roofs that are adorned with divine figures and traditional symbols of luck such as dragons and carp. Taoism is not a selfish faith, and the pagodas may have rooms or shrines dedicated to Buddhist meditation and/or Hindu deities. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在文明IV中，大教堂是指规模巨大，装饰华丽的宗教性建筑。只有非常繁荣的城市才有能力建造大教堂，因为此类建筑需要消耗大量原材料，并需要大批技艺精湛的工匠经年累月的努力。例如法国巴黎的圣母大教堂（巴黎圣母院）花费了两个世纪的时间才建造完成。[PARAGRAPH:1]规模宏伟的道宫大都是重檐斗拱的多层楼阁。不幸的是，大多数道宫均用木料建造——道教信仰以林木为尊——难以经受时间的摧残。[PARAGRAPH:1]道教殿宇非常华丽精美，在屋脊和拱梁上通常装饰有大量神仙雕像以及传统吉祥图案，例如盘龙和阴阳鱼等。道教是一种兼容并蓄的信仰，在道宫中也会建有佛教僧人的禅室或是来自于印度教神灵的塑像。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAOIST_SHRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Taoist Dai Miao, or "Temple of the God of Mount Tai," is located on Mount Tai in Shandong Province, China. One of the "five sacred mountains of China," Mount Tai has been of great religious importance throughout Chinese history, and evidence suggests that pilgrims have been climbing the mountain for at least 3000 years. There are 22 temples, 97 ruins, and several thousand stone tablets and inscriptions scattered across the its rugged shoulders.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Dai Miao is the largest temple complex on the mountain, covering an area of about a million square feet. The buildings within the temple have been built and rebuilt a number of times, the most recent major overhaul occurring about 2000 years ago during the Han Dynasty. [PARAGRAPH:2]In its latest incarnation, the temple is a replica of the Imperial Palace. The complex has five major halls and many small buildings. The most important building is the Palace of Heavenly Blessings, constructed in 1008. The building contains a mural titled, "The God of Mount Tai Making a Journey." The mural is 10 feet in height by about 200 feet long. It was painted in 1009, making it 1004 years old. [PARAGRAPH:2]Next to the Palace of Heavenly Blessings stand the Yaocan Pavilion and the entrance archway, as well as the Bronze Pavilion in the northeast corner. The Dai Temple is surrounded by the 2,100 year-old Han Dynasty cypresses. Beloved as much for its rugged beauty as for its religious significance, the Dai Miao remains one of the most important religious structures in the world.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>道教圣地岱庙（或称岱岳庙、东岳庙、泰庙），即“东岳大帝（泰山之神）的庙宇”，坐落于中国山东省的泰山，该山是中国的五岳之一，在中国历史上，泰山在宗教上具有非常的重要性。朝圣者们参拜该山已经有至少3000年历史了，泰山上现有22座庙，另有97处废墟，数千座石碑和题字散布于崎岖的山间。[PARAGRAPH:2]岱庙是泰山上规模最大的建筑群，占地一百万平方英尺。庙中的建筑历经数次重建，最近一次大规模重修是在大约2000年前的汉代。[PARAGRAPH:2]它的最近一次修缮是仿照帝王宫殿的一次复制。整个建筑群拥有五座大厅和许多较小的建筑。最重要的建筑是宋天贶殿，建于1008年。殿内有一巨幅壁画:“泰山神启跸回銮图”，高约10英尺，长约200英尺，绘于1009年，已有1000年的历史。[PARAGRAPH:2]天贶殿旁边是遥参亭和一座拱门，另有一座“金阙”（铜亭）位于东南角。岱庙周围还环绕着植于2100多年前的汉柏。[PARAGRAPH:2]岱庙以其历经沧桑的美丽和宗教代表性，成为世界上最重要的宗教建筑之一。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_EPIC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An "epic" is a heroic poem celebrating the life and achievements of a heroic individual or group. Classic examples of epics include Homer's "Iliad" and "Odyssey." [PARAGRAPH:1]A "national epic" celebrates the exploits of an entire country. One of the earliest examples is the "Shahnama," (The Book of Kings), a Persian literary classic written around 1000 AD. The Shahnama chronicles the history of Persia from mythological pre-history through the reign of Khosrau II (590-628). The work contains over 60,000 couplets and is still read and enjoyed by modern readers. [PARAGRAPH:1]It is possible that the age of the literary epic is dead, and that in the future all such stories will be done as "made for TV movies." This would be a great misfortune to the world of letters - and to the rest of the world, as well.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>“史诗”是歌颂某一位或某一群人的生平和功绩的英雄诗歌。史诗中的经典例子是荷马的“伊里亚特”和“奥德赛”。[PARAGRAPH:1]民族史诗歌颂的则是整个国家的开发，最早的例子之一是“王书”（国王之书），为创作于公元1000年左右的波斯文学经典。王书记载了波斯从史前的神话时代一直到库思劳二世在位期间（590-628）。这部作品大约有60,000行，今天仍为读者们所喜好。[PARAGRAPH:1]文学史诗的时代已经永远过去了，将来这种故事将都是“为影视剧而创作”。对于文字世界来说这可能是个巨大的不幸——对整个世界来说，也许同样如此。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HERMITAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Located in St. Petersburg, Russia, the Hermitage is one of the oldest and most important art galleries in the world. The collection was begun in 1764, when Catherine of Russia purchased more than 200 paintings from across Europe. The collection was, of course, private; Catherine nicknamed her collection "my hermitage" (meaning hermit home), because only she and the mice got to see it. The New Hermitage building was built by Tsar Nicholas I; he opened it to the public in 1852. [PARAGRAPH:1]Renovated many times to hold an ever-expanding collection, the Hermitage now spans some six buildings overlooking the Neva River. The buildings themselves are extraordinarily beautiful, their huge hallways and opulent rooms fitting places for one of the world's great art collections. [PARAGRAPH:1]The art collection itself is almost beyond superlatives. It contains an extensive collection of Russian Imperial regalia and Faberge jewelry. It includes masterpieces from Greek and Roman eras and beyond into antiquity. It also houses one of the best collections of Rembrandt paintings anywhere. It has multiple works by da Vinci. In all, the Hermitage houses more than three million pieces of outstanding artwork from throughout human history.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>坐落在俄国圣彼得堡的冬宫（即爱尔米塔什博物馆），是世界上历史最悠久，也是最著名的美术馆之一。其收藏活动开始于1764年，当时沙皇叶卡捷琳娜从欧洲购买了200多件绘画作品。当然，这些收藏都是私人所有；叶卡捷琳娜把她的收藏戏称为“我的爱尔米塔什”（意即隐士的居所），因为只有她和老鼠们才能见到它们。新的冬宫建造于沙皇尼古拉一世时期；在1852年，沙皇开始允许公众参观。[PARAGRAPH:1]经过几次大的扩建和修复，爱尔米塔什博物馆已经扩大成为沿着涅瓦河畔矗立着的六座建筑组成的大型建筑群。这些建筑本身都极为漂亮，它们那巨大的门廊，富裕的房间数量都让它成为了世界上最大的美术馆之一。[PARAGRAPH:1]它的艺术品收藏是极为丰富的。拥有丰富的俄国王室礼服及费伯奇珠宝的收藏。也有古希腊和古罗马时期以及更早时代的艺术杰作。这里也是大画家伦勃朗作品收藏最多的地方。达芬奇的很多作品也能在这里见到。总之，这座博物馆拥有人类历史长河遗留下来的超过三百万件的杰作。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEROIC_EPIC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Epic of Gilgamesh documents the adventures of this Middle Eastern hero. Of special interest to biblical scholars, the document was found among the ruins of Nineveh. More than 3000 lines, scribed across 12 tablets, this tale was written around 2000 BC. Gilgamesh was a king of Uruk, which now lies within the borders of Iraq.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>史诗《吉尔伽美什》叙述了古代中东的英雄吉尔伽美什的冒险事迹。19世纪中叶，一位研究圣经的学者在古代亚述首都尼尼微城的废墟之中找到了刻写着这篇完成于公元前2000年，全长超过3000行的史诗的12块石板。吉尔伽美什是乌鲁克的国王，这个王国位于今伊拉克境内。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GLOBE_THEATRE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Most of the plays of William Shakespeare were first performed on the stage of London's Globe Theater during the 1600s. Theaters offered people a diversion from their everyday lives by allowing them to enjoy comedies, tragedies, and triumphs acted out on stage. Similar theaters, such as the Comedie Francaise in Paris, and La Scala in Milan, fulfilled similar roles by offering entertainment to the citizens of their cities. Although the original Globe Theater burned down, Shakespeare's plays are still performed in a new theater bearing his name, and in other theaters throughout the world.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>大多数威廉·莎士比亚的戏剧都于17世纪在伦敦的环球剧场首度公演。剧场使人们通过欣赏悲剧，喜剧的剧情和舞台上成功的表演从平淡无奇的日常生活中获得娱乐。类似的剧场，例如巴黎的弗兰凯斯剧场，米兰的拉斯卡拉剧场亦以类似的方式娱乐大众。尽管最早的环球剧场被大火焚毁，然而莎士比亚的戏剧却还在以他的名字命名的剧场和全世界的各大剧场中持续上演。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WALL_STREET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The location of the New York Stock Exchange, Wall Street has become the epitome of the modern financial district. A narrow street running from Broadway to the East River, it houses some of the world's most prestigious and powerful banks and commodity exchanges. In 1653 Dutch colonists erected a barricade along this route to ward off the British and unfriendly natives. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>作为纽约证卷交易所的所在地，华尔街已经成为现代世界经济状况的指标。这条从百老汇大街至东河的狭窄街道上汇集了一大批世界上声誉最盛，实力最强的银行及商品交易所。“华尔”的原意是“墙”，1653年，荷兰殖民者曾沿这条路建造高墙，以将英国人和不友好的原住民拒之墙外。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_IRONWORKS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As mankind's dependence on metals increased through the ages, it became very important to cheaply and effectively separate the base metal from impurities. The process of smelting, through the use of a structure called a blast furnace, achieved just that. Using carbon dioxide created from oxidized coke to absorb the oxygen from the molten iron, it leaves the metal slag to sink to the bottom of the furnace. This separation allows for a pure iron to be derived, which is then used for numerous purposes, including the creation of steel.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在人类致力于提高金属产量的时代里，如何将金属从杂质中廉价高效的分离出来成为一个非常重要的问题。一般是通过使用一种称为鼓风熔炉的设备使熔炼的过程达到这个要求。利用氧化反应，使用炭吸收熔化的铁中的氧而生成二氧化碳，在熔炉底便留下纯净的铁。这个分离使人们得以炼出纯铁，纯铁可用于炼钢等多种目的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WEST_POINT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Methods of passing down the tactics and arts of war from generation to generation vary based on culture and era. The United States' solution, which up to that point relied on foreign instructors, lay in creating the United States Military Academy, located at West Point, New York. Established in 1802 on the site of a 18th century fortress, West Point went on to train most of the nation's military leaders. Cadets are selected for training via a diverse number of methods, including competitive and non-competitive methods. Graduates earn the commission of Second Lieutenants and receive a Bachelor of Science degree. One paramount function of this institution is to stay current in the practice of warfare, typically by having officers from previous conflicts become instructors.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>将战术和军事艺术流传下去的方式依照地域和时代的不同而不同。美国的做法是聘用外籍教师，并设立专门的军事学院。该军事学院位于纽约的西点。以一座建于18世纪的要塞为主体建筑逐渐发展而来。始建于1802年。西点军校造就了美国的大多数军事领袖。学员在这座学院内接受多种训练。毕业后直接获得少尉军衔及理科学士学位。学校的最大特色在于不断更新教学课程以适应现代战争的要求，尤其是聘请经过多次战争考验的前任军官作为讲师。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MT_RUSHMORE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Mount Rushmore stands as one of the largest sculpted structures in modern human history. Mount Rushmore displays in granite the heads of four great US presidents: George Washington, Thomas Jefferson, Abraham Lincoln, and Theodore Roosevelt. Each head stands approximately 60 feet in height. [PARAGRAPH:2]Mount Rushmore was the vision of Doane Robinson, the superintendent of the South Dakota Historical Society. He engaged the famous American sculptor Gutzon Borglum to take charge of the project. For fourteen years Borglum and a team of 400 local miners blasted, chiseled, scraped and polished the granite mountain until the work was finally completed in 1941. Most remarkably, no one was killed during construction. [PARAGRAPH:2]Mount Rushmore has been called the "American Shrine." Each year thousands journey to the rugged mountains of South Dakota to look upon their four great leaders. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>总统山（拉什莫尔山）可以算是现代历史中最大的雕刻建筑之一。总统山以花岗岩显示了四位美国总统的头像：乔治·华盛顿，托马斯·杰斐逊，亚伯拉罕·林肯，西奥多·罗斯福。每个头像大约60英尺高。[PARAGRAPH:2]总统山的设想来自于南达科塔历史学会的负责人多安尼·罗宾逊。他让美国著名雕刻家古特松·波格鲁姆负责这个计划。波格鲁姆率领400名当地矿工队伍花了14年时间，在花岗岩上凿刮刻抛光，最后工程于1941年完工。值得注意的是，没有一个人死于工程事故。[PARAGRAPH:2]总统山被称为“美利坚圣坛”。每年都有成千上万的旅游者来到南达科塔崎岖的山地来瞻仰他们的伟大领袖。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_OXFORD_UNIVERSITY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The University of Oxford, England, is the oldest university in the English-speaking world. It is also one of the most prestigious. The exact date of the university's founding is unknown, but scholars believe it was some time around 1100 AD. [PARAGRAPH:1]Oxford is made up of 39 colleges and seven "permanent private halls" (which are religious organizations). Each is housed in a separate building usually built in a square around a quadrangle. The colleges generally consist of a great hall, a chapel, a library, a bar, several common rooms, classrooms, and lodging for around 300 students. Built in the 1250s, Balliol, Merton, and University Colleges are among the oldest. [PARAGRAPH:1]For most of its existence, Oxford has been one of the world's great universities, and it remains so to this day. Many famous people have passed through its halls, including four English and eight foreign kings, over 50 presidents and prime ministers (including US President William Clinton), 47 Nobel Prize winners, and one pope. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>英国牛津大学是英语世界中最古老的一座大学。它也有极高的声望。大学建立的确切时间无人知晓，但是学者们认为大约是在公元1100年左右。[PARAGRAPH:1]牛津大学由39个学院组成，还有七个“永久私人学院”（由教会设立）。每一个都是相对独立的，通常各拥有一个方形庭院。每个学院由主会堂、礼拜堂、图书馆、酒吧、一些普通房间、教室以及可住300名学生的宿舍组成。在13世纪50年代建成的巴利奥尔，默顿以及综合学院是其中最为古老的几个。[PARAGRAPH:1]在牛津大学建成之后，它始终位于世界上最好的大学行列中，直至今日依然如此。许多名人曾经徜徉在牛津的厅堂之间，其中包括四位英格兰国王和八位其他国家的国王，超过50位总统与首相（总理），包括美国总统克林顿，47位诺贝尔奖获得者，还有一位教皇。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RED_CROSS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>While fundamentally in conflict with the destructive goals of war, physicians must still proffer aid to those in need. The practice of repairing the personal damage of war, sometimes actually during the fight itself, has a number of benefits beyond the obvious. A paramount one is that of morale, since the soldiers of an army that contains surgeons are assured care if they fall in battle.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>虽然同“战争以毁灭为最终目的”之原则相违背，外科医生仍在战场上向那些需要帮助的人提供救治。对伤员的救助往往超出其本身的意义，其中极为重要的一点，就是对士气的鼓舞作用。因为拥有外科医生的话，士兵们会相信，哪怕他们在战场上倒下，也会有人救助他们。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SCOTLAND_YARD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Scotland Yard is the name of the British police force having jurisdiction over the Greater London area. Scotland Yard is named for the neighborhood in which the original police headquarters stood, and the force retains that nickname even though the headquarters have since been relocated (to "New Scotland Yard"). [PARAGRAPH:1]Scotland Yard was established in 1829 by act of Parliament. According to one of the new force's commissioners, "The primary object of an efficient police is the prevention of crime: the next that of detection and punishment of offenders if crime is committed. To these ends all the efforts of police must be directed. The protection of life and property, the preservation of public tranquility, and the absence of crime, will alone prove whether those efforts have been successful and whether the objects for which the police were appointed have been attained." [PARAGRAPH:1]In the early to mid-19th century Scotland Yard was the most advanced police force in the world. It gained worldwide notoriety from its pursuit of Jack the Ripper, and it was immortalized in the Sherlock Holmes stories of Sir Arthur Conan Doyle. To this day the modern Scotland Yard remains one of the finest police forces to be found anywhere.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>苏格兰场是负责管辖大伦敦地区的英国警署。苏格兰场得名于早期警察总部所处的街区名，后来当总部搬迁（“新苏格兰场”）后他们仍然保留了这个昵称。[PARAGRAPH:1]苏格兰场于1829年根据参议院法案成立。根据一个新的警察委员所说：“警察机关的主要目标是预防犯罪行为的发生，其次是当罪案发生后搜捕并惩罚罪犯。总之，警察的所有努力如能产生如下效果：保护生命与财产，维护社会治安，消灭犯罪行为。就能证明我们的努力成功了，我们所赋予的目标实现了。”[PARAGRAPH:1]早在19世纪中叶，苏格兰场就是全世界最先进的警察部门。其名声由于对“开膛手杰克”的追捕而传遍全球，而柯南·道尔爵士笔下的福尔摩斯故事更令其名垂千古。今日的苏格兰场依然是这个星球上最好的警察部门之一。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PYRAMID_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Built by the fourth dynasty of Egyptian rulers, the Pyramids represent the pinnacle of ancient Egyptian cultural achievement. Constructed on the Giza plateau outside modern-day Cairo, these structures were burial tombs and monuments for the Pharaohs, and may have taken generations and tens of thousands of workers to complete. The Pyramids are the only one of the generally accepted man-made wonders of the ancient world that remains in existence today.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>大金字塔，古埃及文化最杰出的代表作，由埃及第四王朝的统治者们建造。建筑地点位于今天的埃及首都开罗附近的吉萨高原。作为埃及法老的坟墓与纪念碑，金字塔的建造往往历尽数个朝代，并消耗成千上万的人力。埃及金字塔是仅有的仍然留存至今，并为世人所公认的古代世界建筑奇观之一。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STONEHENGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Stonehenge is perhaps the most astounding construct of pre-history still standing. Though standing in ruins, this mighty relic still has the power to insight amazement, awe and wonder. [PARAGRAPH:2]Stonehenge was built in southern England. Consisting of concentric circles of stone surrounded by a moat (called a "henge"), Stonehenge was constructed in several stages over thousands of years. The henge was dug approximately 5000 years ago; the inner ring of smaller "bluestones" were added about a thousand years later, in approximately 2000 BC; and the outer ring of huge sarsen stones was completed 500 years later. [PARAGRAPH:2]No one is sure exactly who constructed Stonehenge. For centuries it was romantically and erroneously believed that the Druids built the wonder, but in fact the edifice was completed 2000 years before there were any Druids. All we really know is that construction was begun by people of the Neolithic period and completed by those who supplanted them. [PARAGRAPH:2]Stonehenge is a wonder of engineering constructed with the most primitive tools. It appears that the outer ditch was dug with wooden and bone implements. The 80 inner bluestones, weighing about 4 tons each, were transported from a quarry over 240 miles away. Scientists speculate that the stones were dragged on logs and wooden sledges for part of the journey and carried on river barges for the rest. The heaviest of the outer ring of stones weighs in at about 50 tons; it took approximately 600 men to drag such stones from their quarry, about 20 miles away. These monster stones had to be pulled upright in exactly the correct position by men equipped with ropes and wooden levers. [PARAGRAPH:2]There is much debate about Stonehenge's purpose. Some theorize that it was built as a temple to honor earth gods, while others believe that it was a burial ground for ancient kings and noblemen. Another theory is that Stonehenge is an ancient astronomical observatory, charting the movement of the stars which men believed controlled their destinies.[PARAGRAPH:2]Whatever its original purpose, it remains today a rugged and beautiful monument to the astonishing skill and dedication of its "primitive" builders.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>巨石阵也许是遗存至今最令人感到神秘的史前建筑。虽然已经残破不堪，但是这个充满魔力的遗迹仍然令人陶醉不已。[PARAGRAPH:2]巨石阵位于英格兰南部。由圆石壕沟包围几圈巨大的同心圆石块组成，巨石阵的建造持续了数千年时间。外面的圆石壕沟大约在5000年前挖成；内环稍小的“胆矾石”约在公元前2000年时才加上；而外环的砂岩石又在此后500年才完工。[PARAGRAPH:2]没人知道究竟是谁建造了巨石阵。几个世纪以来，人们传说这是由德鲁伊教徒所建造的奇观，但事实上大致建筑在德鲁伊产生前2000年就已完工。我们所确知的一点只有：是新石器时代的人开始建造这个巨石阵，并由后来者最终完成的。[PARAGRAPH:2]对于原始的工具来说，巨石阵的确是一项工程奇迹。有迹象表明外层的壕沟是由木制和骨制的工具挖成的。80块内圈胆矾石，每块重约4吨，是从240英里外的采石场运来的。科学家推测这些石块是由原木撬和驳船运来的。外圈最重的石块有约50吨；大概要有600个人才能将它挖出来。这些巨型石块必须被竖立在正确的位置，而当时人们只有绳子和木制杠杆等原始工具。[PARAGRAPH:2]对于巨石阵的建造目的也有很大争议。有一个理论说这是供奉大地之神的庙宇，另有人相信这是古代王公贵族的陵墓。更有甚者说这是古代天文台，是那些相信星星的运动能控制自身命运的人用来制作星图的。[PARAGRAPH:2]但是无论当初原始目的为何，这个粗糙而美丽的纪念碑向我们揭示了原始人令人惊异的技术与奉献精神。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_LIBRARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Great Library of Alexandria was one of the two most important libraries of the ancient world. Ptolemy I founded it around 300 BC, and was enhanced and expanded by his successors. The library attempted to obtain copies of all scrolls of any consequence, and eventually contained over 700,000 volumes. Religious fanatics destroyed the library in 391 AD, after nearly 700 years of operation. During this period, Alexandria served as the cultural center of the Hellenistic world. Today, only part of the catalog remains, providing us with a mere hint of what treasures the library contained.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>亚历山大图书馆是古代世界最重要的两座图书馆之一。由托勒密一世于公元前300年建造。并由其继任者不断扩充馆藏。馆中收集了超过70万卷的文化典籍。在其运作的700年间，亚历山大亦作为希腊世界的文化中心而为世人所景仰。但是在公元391年，一些宗教极端分子将其付之一炬。只剩一小部分书目流传至今，让人不禁猜测，当时这图书馆究竟拥有怎样的文化财富。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_LIGHTHOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Pharos was a marble watchtower and lighthouse built in 280 BC on an island in the harbor of Alexandria, Egypt. Estimated to have been 300 feet high, the primary function of the lighthouse was to guide approaching ships to the harbor on an otherwise unmarked coast. Historians debate whether fires were burned on the top of the tower, or whether mirrors were used to reflect sunlight. Since ships rarely sailed along coasts at night, there was probably little need for the lighthouse after dark. The Pharos was destroyed in the 14th century, after having been damaged by several earthquakes.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>这是一座是全部由大理石建造的灯塔，同时也是一座了望塔。矗立在埃及亚历山大港口外的一个小岛上。其建成于公元前280年，约有300英尺高。用来指引来自其他地方的船只进入亚历山大港。历史学家一直在争论，灯塔到底是用火还是镜子来照明，因为当时很少有船只在晚上航行。在经历了几次地震后，灯塔于14世纪倒塌。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HANGING_GARDEN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Hanging Gardens were a distinctive feature of ancient Babylon. They were a great source of pride to the people, and were often described in accounts written by visitors to the city. Possibly built by King Nebuchadnezzar II in 600 BC, the gardens are believed to have been a remarkable feat of engineering: an ascending series of tiered gardens containing all manner of trees, shrubs, and vines. The gardens were said to have looked like a large green mountain constructed of mud bricks, rising from the center of the city.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>空中花园作为古巴比伦的独特建筑之一，令当地的人民为之深深自豪。并且经常出现在那些到访这城市的旅行者的笔下。它可能是由尼布甲尼撒二世于公元前600年建造。它具有无可比拟的工程设计，由一系列建筑在台阶上的花园组成，其上覆满了各种树木，灌木和蔓生植物。以至于从远处看去，像一座矗立在城市中央的巨大的砖制绿色山丘。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COLOSSUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Colossus of Rhodes was a bronze statue of Helios, the Greek God of the Sun, erected near the mouth of the city harbor. It stood over 100 feet high, about two-thirds the height of the Statue of Liberty. Unfortunately, an earthquake toppled it only 56 years after its construction. Taking the counsel of an oracle, the city elected to leave the statue where it lay. For over 900 years, people from all over the ancient world came to Rhodes to see the Colossus. It remained where it was until 654 AD when the Muslims who plundered the city sold the statue for scrap.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>罗德岛的巨像是希腊太阳神赫利俄斯的青铜铸像，矗立在城市海港的入口处。他的高度超过一百英尺，大约是自由女神像的三分之二。不幸的是，他在建成后的第56个年头，因地震而倒塌。市民们依照一个神谕的指示，将这伟大建筑的遗迹保留在原地。其后的九百年间，络绎不绝的访客由世界各地前来观赏这青铜巨像的遗迹。直到公元645年，入侵的穆斯林劫掠了这座城市，并将遗留的巨像残片变卖。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORACLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In ancient Greek religion, an oracle was a priest or priestess through whom the gods spoke in response to questions. The oracle interpreted dreams, the actions of entranced persons, and physical signs found in the entrails of sacrificed animals. The most famous oracle resided in the shrine of Apollo at Delphi, located on the slopes of Mount Parnassus. Greeks, Romans, and others consulted this oracle for centuries about public policy and private matters. A priestess called the Pythia would, for a fee, make public predictions for the future. These ecstatic pronouncements became infamous for their ambiguity.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在古希腊的信仰中，“先知”是指那些为人们传达诸神意旨的女祭司。先知负责解读梦境，着魔者的行为，以及作为祭品的动物内脏上的纹理所包含的神灵谕示。宣示神谕的先知驻所中最著名的一个是位于希腊古城特尔斐帕那萨斯山的阿波罗神殿。古希腊、古罗马和其他国家的人们时时来访，以决定从公共政策到私人事务的各种各样的问题。一个名叫派西亚的女祭司则为他们宣示关于未来的预言并收取一定费用。这些神谕最大的特点就是用词含混不清，模棱两可。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PARTHENON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Parthenon was constructed in 433 BC, in Athens, Greece, in honor of Athens' patron goddess, Athena. Measuring 100 feet by 225 feet, the Parthenon is constructed almost totally of marble. The exterior of the Parthenon is ringed with Doric-style columns more than 30 feet in height, and the center part of the temple, called the "cella," is a large open space which once held a statue of Athena. Much of the temple was decorated with beautiful marble statues and friezes celebrating Athena and the glories of Athens. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Parthenon has suffered much from the ravages of time. In the 5th century a Roman Emperor stole the statue of Athena and moved it to Constantinople, where it was subsequently destroyed. In the 13th century the Parthenon was converted to a Catholic church, which involved altering the internal structure and removing (and probably destroying) many statues dedicated to the old gods. In the 15th century Athens was captured by the Ottomans, and the temple was turned into a mosque. In the 17th century the Parthenon was partially destroyed during a war between the Ottomans and Venetians. Finally, in the 19th century, the British ambassador to Greece looted all of the surviving marble friezes from the building, which he subsequently sold to the British museum. [PARAGRAPH:2]Despite the centuries of neglect, mutilation and pillaging, the Parthenon still stands - a remarkably powerful and beautiful symbol of the glories of ancient Greece.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>位于希腊雅典的帕特农神庙修建于公元前433年，用于祭祀雅典的守护神——雅典娜。神庙长225英尺，宽100英尺，几乎全部为大理石构成。神庙四周以30余英尺高的多利安式圆柱围绕，内部则是一开阔空间，曾一度矗立着一尊雅典娜女神的塑像。神庙用精美的大理石雕像，檐壁和中楣装饰赞美雅典娜和雅典的荣耀。[PARAGRAPH:2]帕特农神庙在历史上屡遭劫难。公元5世纪时，罗马皇帝盗走了雅典娜神像，神像被搬运至君士坦丁堡，后来毁于该处。13世纪时，帕特农神庙被改建成天主教堂，这导致了内部结构的改变，而许多描绘原始信仰神祗的雕像也被移走或被破坏。雅典在15世纪被奥斯曼土耳其人征服，神庙也变作了清真寺。17世纪土耳其和威尼斯之间的战争使神庙部分被毁。最后在19世纪，英国驻希腊的大使窃走了幸存的所有大理石雕塑，并出售给大英博物馆。[PARAGRAPH:2]尽管经历了数世纪的疏于管理，毁损和掠夺，帕特农神庙依然矗立至今，成为古希腊光辉历史的美丽象征。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ANGKOR_WAT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Angkor Wat is a temple in Angkor, Cambodia. Angkor Wat was constructed in the 12th century by King Suryavaman II to serve as the royal palace and state temple, Hinduism being the state religion. Two or three centuries later Angkor Wat was converted to Buddhist use. Angkor Wat is a complex of buildings surrounded by a wall and then moat. The enclosed area measures 3000 feet by 2600 feet. [PARAGRAPH:2]Angkor Wat is constructed primarily of sandstone blocks. The complex is laid out in a rectangular pattern somewhat resembling that of an ancient fortress; the inner buildings are separated from the outer walls by a courtyard similar to a bailey one might find in a castle. [PARAGRAPH:2]At one time the courtyard was filled with wooden buildings, but these have all since perished. The inner structure is split into three galleries built on raised platforms. The outer galleys once contained libraries, while the inner was a shrine to Vishnu (and has since been converted to a shrine to Buddha). The galleries are topped with towers that resemble stylized beehives, the tallest reaching about 140 feet in height. The buildings' walls are covered with ornate and beautiful bas relief sculptures depicting scenes from Hindu mythology. [PARAGRAPH:2]Though largely neglected in the latter half of the 20th century, serious efforts are now being made to preserve and restore this wonderful and unique place of worship, and pilgrims and tourists are visiting it in ever-greater numbers each year.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>吴哥窟是位于柬埔寨吴哥地区的一座寺庙，由12世纪时的高棉国王苏利亚瓦尔曼二世修建。它是一座王宫，同时也是一座印度教寺院。2到3个世纪后，吴哥窟又改建成一座佛教寺院。吴哥窟是由城墙和护城河围绕的一组建筑群，其范围大约3000英尺长，2600英尺宽。[PARAGRAPH:2]吴哥窟大部由砂岩筑成。整个建筑群呈矩形，犹如古代堡垒；内部建筑与外墙之间有城堡外庭一般的庭院隔开。[PARAGRAPH:2]庭院里全是木构建筑，但如今已经全部朽坏。修建于凸起平台之上的内部结构可以分为三个回廊。外部的回廊曾包括图书馆，而内部回廊则是一座毗湿奴神殿（后来改为佛堂）。建筑的顶部是类似蜂巢般规整结构的佛塔，其中最高的大概有140英尺。建筑群的外墙上满是精美的浮雕，这些浮雕讲述的是印度神话里的故事。[PARAGRAPH:2]在20世纪后半叶的大多数时间中，这里被人们所忽视。但是现在，人们正努力保护并复原这一历史奇观和独一无二的圣地，而每年造访此地的朝圣者和游客也越来越多。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HAGIA_SOPHIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Hagia Sophia, or "Church of the Holy Wisdom," was constructed in 530 AD as a Greek Orthodox church. Standing in Istanbul (originally Constantinople), Turkey, it is a beautiful and ornate structure, built of stone and marble, and topped by a golden dome measuring over 100 feet in diameter. An extremely difficult engineering challenge for the time, the dome has collapsed several times during its existence. Four graceful towers stand at the corners of the building. [PARAGRAPH:2]The interior of the Hagia Sophia is a marvelous space of columns and arches extending up to the dome, which appears almost to float atop the building. The interior was sheathed in colored marble and golden mosaics depicting biblical scenes and images of Christian saints. [PARAGRAPH:2]In 1453 Constantinople was captured by the Ottoman Turks, and the Hagia Sophia was converted into a mosque. Human images are not welcome in mosques, and many of the mosaics were covered with plaster. [PARAGRAPH:2]In 1934, Turkish President Kemal Ataturk turned the building into a museum. In recent years some restoration work has been done on the Hagia Sophia, and a few of the mosaics have been uncovered. Despite the ravages of time, the Hagia Sophia remains universally acknowledged as one of the most beautiful buildings in the world.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>圣索菲亚大教堂，又名“圣智大教堂”，是一座修建于公元530年的希腊东正教教堂，位于土耳其伊斯坦布尔（君士坦丁堡）。圣索菲亚大教堂是一座华美的建筑，由大理石和花岗石建成，拥有一个直径超过100英尺的金色圆顶。修建这个圆顶在当时是一项极其困难的工程，历史上这个圆顶曾经坍塌过数次。在教堂的四角各有一座优美的高塔矗立。[PARAGRAPH:2]建筑的内部是由延伸至穹顶的柱廊和拱形结构组成的奇妙空间，这些结构使得教堂的穹顶仿佛没有基座，而是悬浮在空中一般。建筑的内墙上满是由彩色大理石和玻璃镶嵌画描述的圣经中的场景与基督教圣人的形象。[PARAGRAPH:2]1453年，君士坦丁堡被土耳其人攻占，圣索菲亚大教堂也被改建成清真寺。由于清真寺内禁止人物画像，许多镶嵌画被用灰浆覆盖。[PARAGRAPH:2]1934年，土耳其总统，国父凯末尔将清真寺改为博物馆。近年来，人们对圣索菲亚进行了复原工作，一些被灰浆掩盖的镶嵌画得以重见天日。尽管时间流逝，圣索菲亚仍以世界上最美丽的建筑之一而闻名于世。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHICHEN_ITZA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Chichen Itza is an extraordinary city of stone built in the Yucatan, Mexico. Some of the oldest buildings and pyramids date back to 1500 years ago and are of Toltec and Mayan origin. [PARAGRAPH:2]Chichen Itza consists of buildings, temples and courtyards of stone. A large "pok tap ok" or ceremonial ball court stands off to one side. (Ceremonial ball is that most interesting of games in which two sides seek to pass the ball through hoops at each end of the court. The captain of the winning team was then beheaded as a sacrifice to the gods.) Though the city is much ravaged by time (and looters), there still remain many beautiful stone carvings and statues. [PARAGRAPH:2]At the center of the city stands the mighty stepped pyramid of Kukulcan, also known as "El Castillo." Constructed around the 13th century, El Castillo is approximately 180 feet square at the base and 78 feet in height. As was the Mayan practice, Kukulcan was constructed atop an older and smaller pyramid. [PARAGRAPH:2]Chichen Itza was a thriving city until the 13th century, when revolt and civil war broke out among the Mayans, at which point the city went into a steep decline from which it never recovered. The center of the city was largely abandoned and in ruins by the time of the Spanish Conquest of the Yucatan in the 16th century. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>奇琴伊察是建造在墨西哥尤卡坦的一座非凡的石头城。其中的一些最古老的建筑和金字塔可以追溯到1500年前，由托尔泰克人和玛雅人建造。[PARAGRAPH:2]奇琴伊察由石制建筑，寺庙和庭院构成。一个巨大的仪式舞蹈场地座落在城市的一端。（仪式舞蹈是一种非常令人好奇的游戏，两支队伍需要尝试把球踢过场地两端的铁环。之后，获胜队伍的队长会作为给神的祭品而砍头。）尽管这座城市历史上遭到了时间和掠夺者的破坏，仍然有不少漂亮的石头雕像存留。[PARAGRAPH:2]在城市中央矗立着宏大的库库尔坎的金字塔，西班牙人称之为“城堡”。它建造于13世纪，占地面积大约为180平方英尺，高达78英尺。根据玛雅的惯例，库库尔坎建立在一个更古老并稍小的金字塔之上。[PARAGRAPH:2]直到13世纪，奇琴伊察都是一个繁荣的城市。此后，玛雅爆发了叛乱和内战，导致了这座城市的迅速没落，并再也没有恢复。到西班牙人在16世纪征服尤卡坦的时候，城市中心已经被很大程度地遗弃而成为了废墟。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SISTINE_CHAPEL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The beauty of Rome's Sistine Chapel has long served as a testament to the mixture of strong religious beliefs and the love of art shared by the people of Renaissance Europe. Michelangelo devoted four years to painting the mural that adorns the ceiling, a work depicting events in the book of Genesis and other Biblical stories. Few visitors to the Sistine Chapel have failed to be moved by the artist's dedication to his subject, or his feeling for the nature of human struggle, suffering, and spiritual triumph.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>罗马西斯廷大教堂作为文艺复兴时期的标志性建筑之一，集中体现了那个时代人们对宗教和对艺术的热爱。由米开朗基罗耗费四年时间绘制的穹顶壁画，描绘了创世纪中的记载及其他圣经故事。所有参观这座大教堂的人，几乎无一不为艺术家的创作热情及其作品中所表达的人类的抗争，苦难以及灵魂的胜利所倾倒。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SPIRAL_MINARET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Spiral Minaret is a massive brick and clay structure adjacent to the Mosque of al-Mutawakkil in Samarra, Iraq. The mosque was constructed in 852 AD, and at the time was the largest mosque in the world.[PARAGRAPH:2]A remarkable triumph of ancient engineering, the minaret is a circular tower 170 feet in height. A spiral exterior staircase extends up the tower to the platform where the "muezzin" called the people to prayer. It is said that the caliph al-Mutawakkil once rode up the stairs on a white Egyptian donkey. [PARAGRAPH:2]An imposing yet magnificent building, the Spiral Minaret still stands today, calling the people of Samarra to prayer at the Mosque of al-Mutawakkil. The more courageous visitors can climb the staircase to the top of the minaret, which appears to lack an outside guardrail.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>螺旋尖塔是伊拉克撒马拉的穆塔瓦基勒清真寺边上的一个砖土结构建筑物。这座清真寺建造于公元852年，是当时世界上最大的清真寺。[PARAGRAPH:2]螺旋尖塔是一座圆形的170英尺高的塔，它是古代工程学的一个奇迹。有一座螺旋状的外部阶梯从塔上延伸到一个平台，这是宣礼员通告人们进行祷告的地方。据说哈里发穆塔瓦基勒曾经骑着一匹白色埃及驴登上阶梯。[PARAGRAPH:2]作为一座令人难忘的宏伟建筑，螺旋尖塔至今仍然矗立，呼唤撒马拉的人们前往穆塔瓦基勒清真寺祈祷。如果访客足够大胆，他还可以通过阶梯登上没有任何护栏的尖塔的顶部。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NOTRE_DAME_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Notre Dame is a mighty cathedral standing on the "Ile de la Citie," an island in the Seine River in Paris, France. Built on the site of an older church, which was in turn built on the site of a Roman temple to Jupiter, Notre Dame is a magnificent example of gothic architecture and one of the greatest buildings standing. Construction of Notre Dame began in 1163 and took almost two centuries to complete. [PARAGRAPH:2]Notre Dame is a massive stone building of square towers, flying buttresses, and tall spires. The exterior of the building is decorated with delicate ribbons of arches and statues of saints and kings. The roofline of the building is festooned with gargoyles. The interior of the cathedral is a long, narrow space with columns lining each side, supporting two beautiful raised galleries. Brilliant stained glass windows shine gently down on the main altar, which contains a beautiful statue of the Virgin Mary, the cathedral's patron, holding the body of Jesus. [PARAGRAPH:2]The cathedral has suffered many periods of neglect over the years. During the French Revolution, many of Notre Dame's treasures were stolen and the building was used as a warehouse. In the early 1800s, the cathedral was in such a state of disrepair that the city planners contemplated tearing it down. In fact, Victor Hugo wrote "The Hunchback of Notre Dame" in part to raise awareness of the cathedral's plight. In 1871, during the short-lived Paris Commune, Notre Dame was almost set on fire. [PARAGRAPH:2]Fortunately the cathedral survived it all, and has now been largely restored to its original grandeur.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>圣母院是座落于法国巴黎塞纳河上的“城市岛”上的一座宏伟的大教堂。它的原址是一座由罗马的朱庇特神庙改建的古老教堂。巴黎圣母院是一座典型的哥特式建筑，也是世界上仍存在的最伟大的建筑之一。圣母院的建造从1163年开始，前后将近用了200年才完成。[PARAGRAPH:2]圣母院是一座石质建筑，由许多的方塔，飞拱和高耸的尖顶组成。其外表装饰有许多拱形带和圣徒们与国王们的雕像，屋顶的轮廓饰有怪兽状的滴水口。大教堂的内部是一个又长又窄的空间，四周的圆柱支撑着两幅漂亮的浮雕。彩色玻璃窗轻轻地照耀在主祭坛上，在这个祭坛上有一座圣母玛丽的雕像，她的怀中则抱着耶稣——这座大教堂由此得名。[PARAGRAPH:2]这座大教堂在历史上遭遇过多次劫难。在法国大革命时代，圣母院中的许多财产被窃，并被征用为仓库。在19世纪初，这座大教堂的荒废景象使得城市的规划者考虑将它拆除。事实上，维克多·雨果撰写《巴黎圣母院》的部分目的就是希望唤起人们对圣母院的困境的关注。在1871年，在短命的巴黎公社执政期间，圣母院几乎被焚毁。[PARAGRAPH:2]幸运的是，圣母院从这一系列的遭难中幸存下来，现在已经基本上恢复了原有的宏伟。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TAJ_MAHAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Taj Mahal stands in Agra, India. It was constructed in the mid-16th century at the orders of the Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan, as a mausoleum for his wife. [PARAGRAPH:2]Acknowledged as one of the most beautiful structures in the world, the Taj Mahal is constructed of rare and brilliant materials imported from across India and Asia - it is said that over 1000 elephants were employed to carry the sandstone, marble, jade, turquoise, sapphires, and other materials used in its construction. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Taj Mahal complex covers an area of approximately 1000 feet by 1900 feet and consists of a gateway, garden, mausoleum, mosque, and guest house. The first three buildings are clad in white marble and covered with geometric patterns, while the mosque and guesthouse are built of brilliant red sandstone. The buildings are topped with magnificent onion-shaped domes and minarets. [PARAGRAPH:2]Experts have debated about what makes the Taj Mahal unique and beautiful. Some suggest that it lies in the structures' marvelous proportions and symmetry, while others argue in favor of the way that the marble buildings interact with the light, giving the Taj Mahal ever-changing character as the sun rises and sets. Still others believe that its inherent beauty lies in its purpose - a man seeking to cast in stone his love for his departed wife.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>泰姬陵位于印度阿格拉。它是在16世纪中叶，依照莫卧儿帝国皇帝沙贾罕的命令而建造，作为其妻子的陵墓。[PARAGRAPH:2]泰姬陵被公认为世界上最漂亮的建筑物之一，它使用从印度和亚洲进口的各种稀有而美丽的材料建造而成。据说人们使用了1000头大象来搬运这些砂岩，大理石，翡翠，绿宝石，蓝宝石和其他的材料。[PARAGRAPH:2]泰姬陵总共占据了大约宽1000英尺，长1900英尺的广阔面积，包括一座大门，一个大花园，陵墓，一座清真寺和客房。前三个建筑覆盖着白色大理石并装饰着几何图形，而清真寺与客房在使用闪亮的红色砂岩建造。这些建筑顶部是洋葱状的圆顶和尖塔。[PARAGRAPH:2]专家们曾就泰姬陵独特和美丽的原因展开争论。一些认为这源自其不可思议的精确比例和对称，而另一些则倾向于大理石建筑在光线下的相互间的影响，这使得泰姬陵在太阳升起与落下时呈现出不断变化的景象。还有一些人相信它的美丽源于其建造的初衷：一个男人想要把他对亡妻的爱浇筑在石头中。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KREMLIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Kremlin" is a Russian word which denotes a fortified complex of buildings in the center of a city. It is most often used to refer to the Kremlin in the city of Moscow, a remarkable set of buildings which hold much of the Russian government. The Kremlin sits on a hill overlooking the Moskva River. In one form or the other, fortified structures have been in that location for almost 1000 years. The site was named "Kremlin" in the 14th century. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Kremlin is within a triangular, walled area about 68 acres in extent. The walls are of red brick, with pencil-like towers at the corners and entrances. Many of the buildings are painted white with yellow trim and green roofs that look quite cheerful from a distance. The Cathedral of the Dormition, constructed in the 1470s, is the oldest building in the complex. Two other cathedrals lie within its walls, as do a surprising number of palaces, the Kremlin Palace being the largest.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Kremlin has seen many great figures rise and fall within its walls. Ivan the Terrible built the Palace of Facets in the Kremlin. In the Great Patriotic War (WWII), Josef Stalin drove the German invaders from the gates of Moscow - perhaps the greatest service that any Russian ruler has ever performed for his country. (It was also here that Stalin planned the systematic extermination of millions of his own people.) It was here that Mikhail Gorbachev oversaw the dissolution of the Soviet Union. Today, the Kremlin holds the government of the Russian Federation.[PARAGRAPH:2]To whatever use it might be put in the future, the Kremlin will always stand as a mighty monument to Russia's past - for it has seen the best and the worst of that great nation.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>“克里姆林”是一个俄语词，它表示在城市中心的一组防御建筑群，特别指在莫斯科市中心的“克里姆林”，作为城市标志性建筑群，是绝大多数的俄罗斯政府机构的所在地。克里姆林位于可以俯瞰莫斯科河的山丘上。在这个地点，各种形式的防御建筑已经存在了近1000年。但直到14世纪时才被命名为克里姆林。[PARAGRAPH:2]克里姆林宫建筑平面图呈现一个三角形，以城墙围绕，面积将近68英亩。墙壁用红色砖块砌成，在转角和入口有像铅笔般高耸的哨塔。其中许多建筑被漆成黄檐绿顶，看上去非常的喜庆。圣母升天大教堂建于15世纪70年代，是整个建筑群中历史最悠久的。城墙内还另有两座大教堂。而“大克里姆林宫”则是城墙内众多宫殿建筑中最大的一座。[PARAGRAPH:2]许多大人物在克里姆林的围墙内沉浮。伊凡雷帝在克里姆林建造了菲赛特宫。在苏联卫国战争（第二次世界大战）中，约瑟夫·斯大林在莫斯科城下击退了德国侵略军，他这项功绩的辉煌程度超越了所有其他的俄国统治者。（但也是在这个地方，斯大林制订了杀害了上百万自己同胞的计划。）在这里，戈尔巴乔夫目睹了苏联的解体。今天，克里姆林宫仍旧是俄罗斯政府的所在地。[PARAGRAPH:2]无论克里姆林宫在将来会作什么用途，它仍会永远地象征俄罗斯的过去，因为这个国家所有最糟和最好的事件都发生在这里。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EIFFEL_TOWER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Eiffel Tower is one of the world's most famous landmarks. Built for the Universal Exposition of 1889, the tower rises 984 feet above Paris' Champ de Mars, near the Seine River. Structural engineer Alexandre Gustave Eiffel built the tower at a cost of more than $1 million to demonstrate how steel and iron could be utilized in the construction of extremely tall buildings. The tallest building in the world when it was originally completed, the Eiffel Tower drew crowds of awestruck observers from around the world. Today, it remains one of Paris' leading tourist attractions.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>埃菲尔铁塔是世界上最著名的地标之一。它屹立在塞纳河畔的战神广场，高984英尺。为了1889年的世界博览会，结构工程师埃菲尔花费了一百多万美元建造了这座铁塔，以展示钢与铁是如何在极高的建筑结构中使用。当时它是世界最高的建筑物，吸引了成群结队从世界各地慕名而来的瞻仰者。今天，它仍旧是巴黎最吸引人的景点之一。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STATUE_OF_LIBERTY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Statue of Liberty is one of the largest statues in the world. Measuring over 300 feet tall from the base of its pedestal, the statue is constructed of copper plating over an iron framework and weighs over 250 metric tons. Designed by French sculptor Frederic Bartholdi, the statue, with her upraised torch and the broken chains of tyranny at her feet, was presented to the United States by the French government in 1886 to commemorate 100 years of American independence. The statue itself, Liberty Island, and nearby Ellis Island became a national monument in 1924. For more than a century, the Statue of Liberty has stood at the mouth of the New York harbor. Often the first sight seen by immigrants arriving in America, Lady Liberty symbolizes the ideals of freedom upon which the United States was founded.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>自由女神像是世界上最大的雕像之一。连基座高达300多英尺。她建造在镀铜的铁框架上，总重量达250吨。这座雕像由法国著名雕塑家巴尔托迪设计，造型为自由女神高举火炬，脚上还残留着断裂的苛政的铁锁，是法国政府为纪念1886年美国独立100周年而赠送的礼物。1924年，雕塑本身，自由岛，以及附近的艾丽丝岛被宣布为国家历史文物。自由女神像已经在纽约港的河口屹立了一个多世纪。每一个来到美国的移民首先看到的就是自由女神像，它象征了自由的理念，这是美国建国的基础。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROADWAY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Broadway is the name of a wide street that cuts through the center of New York City, New York. It has also come to refer to the New York theatre district which straddles Broadway near Times Square in the middle of the city. Over the years, approximately 200 theatres have been built on or around Broadway, some going on to spectacular success, others failing within months. [PARAGRAPH:2]The first recorded professional theatrical performance held in New York occurred in 1732. The play was a comedy titled "The Recruiting Officer." The play was performed in an improvised space; unfortunately, the exact location of the performance has been lost. New York's first known theatre was opened in 1750; the Theatre on Nassau Street held about 280 people. The theatre lasted about four years before being torn down and replaced by a church. [PARAGRAPH:2]At present there are over forty theatres in operation. These theatres offer a selection of dramas, comedies and musicals, with musicals being in vogue at present. The competition is extremely tough, and many shows fail within weeks of opening. Clearly, Broadway is one of the two centers of American performance arts - with Hollywood, of course, being the other. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>百老汇是贯穿纽约市中心的一条大街的名字。同时它也指纽约市中心时代广场附近的剧院区，百老汇就穿过了该区。许多年来，近200家剧院在百老汇或者附近建造，有些大获成功，有些则在几个月内倒闭。[PARAGRAPH:2]纽约第一次有记录的专业戏剧演出是在1732年，是一部名叫“征兵官”的喜剧。演出在临时搭建的舞台上进行，可惜确切的地点已经无从考证。纽约已知的第一家剧场在1750年开张，该剧场坐落于拿骚街，能够容纳280人左右。四年之后该剧场倒闭，被一座教堂替代。[PARAGRAPH:2]百老汇现在有40多家剧场还在运作。这些剧场上演各种舞台剧，喜剧和音乐剧等，而音乐剧是目前最为流行的。剧场的竞争非常的激烈，其中很多在开张几周内就关门大吉。百老汇是美国两大表演艺术中心之一，当然另一处则是好莱坞。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ROCKNROLL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Elvis Presley, "The King", played a new beat that people called Rock-n-Roll. It quickly became a worldwide sensation. Elvis' home was called "Graceland" and was purchased by Presley in 1957. Presley died in 1977; the 14-acre estate was turned into a museum five years later. Presley, his parents, grandmother, and stillborn twin brother are buried on the grounds. [PARAGRAPH:2]Today Graceland stands as a remarkable testament to a man who achieved almost mythological status in American culture. Therein one can see glimpses of the young Elvis - the brilliant jeans-clad rebel who "sang like a black man," the man who seduced American teens from the clutches of British rockers and frightened parents everywhere. [PARAGRAPH:2]Overlaying these faint images is the picture of what Elvis became: the jaded overweight man, singing in Las Vegas in a white sequined jumpsuit, dodging underwear thrown by middle-aged housewives, shaking hands with Richard Nixon, and finally dying of his excesses. [PARAGRAPH:2]Today, Elvis is still beloved by millions, many of whom refuse to believe that he died. Despite this, they flock to the mansion by the thousands to lay flowers at his gravesite.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>艾尔维斯·普莱斯利，人称“猫王”，他开创了一种新的音乐形式——摇滚。它很快成为一种世界性的娱乐方式。普莱斯利于1957年购置的居所也人被称为“恩赐之地”。普莱斯利于1977年去世，5年之后，这片14英亩的土地被改建为一座纪念馆。普莱斯利，他的父母，祖母和他刚出生即死亡的双胞胎兄弟都葬在这里。[PARAGRAPH:2]今天，恩赐之地已经成为一份值得纪念的遗产，它属于一个在美国文化史上几乎拥有神话般的地位的人。今天在那里你可以看到年轻时代的艾尔维斯——穿着闪亮的夹克的叛逆者，“像个黑人似地歌唱”。这个人深深地吸引了那些喜欢英国摇滚乐的美国青少年们，也使得无数的家长们深感不安。[PARAGRAPH:2]许多艾尔维斯的照片在唤醒人们对他过去的回忆：疲惫不堪，略显发胖的男子，穿着闪闪发光的白色跳舞服在拉斯维加斯唱歌，不停地躲避着那些中年主妇们扔过来的内衣，与尼克松总统握手，最终他死于放纵无度的生活。[PARAGRAPH:2]今天，仍然有成千上万的人依然热爱着他，许多人拒绝相信他已经死去。还有无数人涌到这里，在他的墓碑前留下鲜花。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOLLYWOOD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Hollywood is a neighborhood in Los Angeles, California. Hollywood is also the center of the American film industry, making it perhaps the most potent center of cultural influence seen since Paris dominated the world of fashion, arts, and literature in the 18th and 19th centuries. Hollywood owes its existence to two important features: first, the weather is mild and pleasant for most of the year; and second, because of its distance from New Jersey. [PARAGRAPH:2]New Jersey was the first film center in the United States, owing to the simple fact that Thomas Edison lived in New Jersey and he held many patents regarding the new technology. He and other early film producers formed a powerful monopoly on the East Coast, where they spent much time and effort trying to stamp out the many small independent producers. To evade Edison and his lawyers, a number of these businesses relocated to Hollywood, Los Angeles, where they were to shortly put Edison and his cronies out of business. [PARAGRAPH:2]The period of 1927 to 1948 was the "Golden Age of Hollywood." Five major studios dominated the industry. The studios created the "star system," in which they heavily promoted their actors and actresses, making them household names while keeping them in ironclad contracts. The system was eventually broken when the actors began refusing to sign the contracts and instead created their own production companies. During this period Hollywood produced hundreds of movies, some-of which were great, many more of which were mediocre or worse. [PARAGRAPH:2]While Hollywood has diminished somewhat in power and influence, it is still home to many of the major motion picture and television production companies, and it still remains a strong exporter of American culture the world wide.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>好莱坞是加利福尼亚州洛杉矶市的一个社区，也是美国电影工业的中心。这使其成为几乎最强有力的文化中心，正如巴黎在18世纪和19世纪牢牢地统治着世界的时尚，艺术和文学潮流。好莱坞的成功应归功于两个重要因素：首先，全年的大部分时候气候都温和宜人，其次，因为这里远离新泽西。[PARAGRAPH:2]新泽西是美国的第一个电影工业中心，这只是因为托马斯·爱迪生住在新泽西，他拥有许多与这项新科技有关的专利。他和其他早期电影制片商在东海岸形成了强大的垄断集团，他们花费了大量的时间和精力来压制那些中小的独立制片商。为了躲避爱迪生和他的律师们，这些商人们选择了洛杉矶的好莱坞，在那里他们很快摆脱了爱迪生和他的那些亲信们。[PARAGRAPH:2]1927到1948年是好莱坞的黄金时期。五大主要制片商控制了这一产业。他们创立了明星体制，大力地提拔他们的男女演员，使他们家喻户晓，同时又用合同牢牢地控制着他们。这一制度最终被演员们打破，他们拒绝签这种合同，代以成立自己的制作公司。这一时期好莱坞制作了成百上千的电影，有些是伟大的杰作，但更多的只是平庸或更糟的作品。[PARAGRAPH:2]尽管好莱坞的影响力和权利在某种程度上已经削弱，它仍然是许多大电影制片商和电视出品公司的根据地，它仍然是向全世界出口美国文化的强大力量。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_DAM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Three Gorges Dam project is designed to tap the power of the mighty Yangtze River, the third longest river in the world. Construction began in Hubei Province, China, in 1994, and it is scheduled to be completed in 2009. When complete, it will be 600 feet high and run 1.3 miles, making it the largest hydroelectric dam in the world. The Chinese government estimates the final cost to be $30 billion dollars, while independent estimates put the cost at closer to $75 billion. [PARAGRAPH:2]Constructing a dam on the Yangtze was proposed as far back as 1919 by Sun Yat-sen, but the idea was shelved for 40 years due to a series of wars, revolutions, and other national calamities hitting China. The idea was resurrected in 1954, abandoned, resurrected again in 1963, abandoned, and so on until it was given final approval in 1992. [PARAGRAPH:2]There has been much debate over the project, primarily because it will dislocate almost two million people, but also because of its potentially devastating environmental impact and because it will eradicate 1300 archeological sites in the area. The Chinese government has pushed the project forward despite these objections and despite the unprecedented opposition of over 30%% of the delegates to the National People's Congress, a body which usually rubber-stamps government decisions.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>三峡大坝是一项利用长江丰富的水利资源的大型工程，长江是世界第三长河。工程建设开始于1994年，在中国的湖北省，设计竣工时间为2009年。预计在完工后，大坝将有600英尺高，1.3英里长，是世界上最大的水电大坝。中国政府估计最终投资达到300亿美元，中立方则估计投资将达到750亿美元之巨。[PARAGRAPH:2]在长江上建水坝的构想可追溯到1919年的孙中山，但这一设想被中国面临的一系列的战争，革命以及各种自然灾害耽搁了40年。这一计划于1954年曾经被提起又放弃，1963年又再度被提起又再度被放弃，直到这一计划最终于1992年被确定。[PARAGRAPH:2]对这一计划存在着很多争议，首先是这将要迁移大约两百万人，而后是将淹没1300处该地区的重要古迹。尽管存在诸多争议，中国政府还是决定实施这一计划，三峡工程项目在全国人民代表大会表决时竟出现超过30%%的反对意见，对这个向来被视为政府决策“橡皮图章”的机构来说可谓空前。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PENTAGON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Pentagon is the largest office building in existence. The structure was completed on January 15, 1943, during the height of the Second World War, after a crash building effort of only 16 months. The 83 million dollar facility covers more than six million square feet, roughly three times that of the Chicago's Sears Tower (the second largest office building). Originally a US Army facility, it soon became the nerve center for all military branches of the United States.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>五角大楼是现存最大的办公建筑。它建成于1943年1月15日，第二次世界大战最激烈的时刻。这座耗资8300万美元的建筑占地600万平方英尺。是芝加哥西尔斯塔楼（第二大办公建筑）的三倍。起初是美国陆军的设施，但很快它就成了整个美国军队的神经中枢。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UNITED_NATIONS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Created in 1945 to maintain international peace and security, the United Nations was the second of two laudable efforts to establish an international authority on law and human rights between the self governing nations of the world. Headquartered in New York City, the United Nations was established at the end of World War II in response to the apparent ineffectiveness of the League of Nations to prevent another global conflict on the scale of "The War to End All Wars".[PARAGRAPH:2]The UN was originally conceived in 1941 as the Atlantic Charter, an agreement signed between Winston Churchill and Franklin D. Roosevelt, but developed into a pact signed by 26 countries to try to stop the aggression of the Axis powers. In 1945, in a conference between "The Big Three", Churchill, Roosevelt, and Stalin, the original charter was laid down.[PARAGRAPH:2]Throughout its history the United Nations has had great success in establishing many permanent international laws on subjects from human rights, international treaties, and worldwide decolonization. Although the United Nations does not have the power to enforce decisions or compel nations to take military action, the ability to compel member nations to impose economic sanctions against countries guilty of violating security orders gives it significant power in the world stage. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>1945年成立的联合国是历史上第二个以协调各独立国家间关系，保证国际法律的权威性和人权为目标的权力机构。其总部位于纽约市。联合国成立于二战末期，部分由于之前的国际联盟在二战中所表现的低效率和无力性，目的是防止可能导致人类毁灭的战争爆发。[PARAGRAPH:2]联合国的最初构思源于温斯顿·丘吉尔，富兰克林·罗斯福于1941年发表的大西洋宪章，并随着26国间签署的试图结束轴心国的侵略战争的条约而得以进一步实现。并最终于1945年的“三巨头”丘吉尔，罗斯福，斯大林的会面中签署了基础协议。[PARAGRAPH:2]在其组建后，联合国成功地通过了一批永久性国际公约，在保护人权，确定国际谈判规章，推进全世界范围内的非殖民地化等方面作出了重要贡献。尽管联合国并不具有强制其成员国执行公约的军事力量。但它所拥有的对触犯世界安全的国家进行经济制裁的权利使它能在很大程度上影响世界政治局势。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SPACE_ELEVATOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Originally consigned to the pages of science fiction, the concept of a "space elevator" has begun to attract serious attention in the halls of academia and the space industry itself. The space elevator is a system for cheaply hauling goods and material into space. Once completed, it would quickly replace the current wasteful method of carrying everything up in dangerous and very expensive rockets. [PARAGRAPH:2]The basic concept is simple; a satellite in geosynchronous orbit is connected by cable to a stationery or mobile platform somewhere on Earth's equator. An elevator, or "climber", would ride up and down the cable at a fraction of present costs. [PARAGRAPH:2]There are a number of problems that need to be overcome before such a project could be put in place. For one, the cable would have to be made of a material stronger and lighter than anything yet known. At the moment, carbon nanotubes seem to be the best candidate, but nobody knows how to construct them in quantity, nor yet how to weave them into cable. And even these might not be strong or light enough. [PARAGRAPH:2]However, when considering the many daunting scientific and engineer challenges facing the project, it is quite useful to remember that a far less advanced world figured out how to put a man on the moon a mere ten years after it was first seriously proposed. Many sane and sober people believe that a space elevator will be constructed within this century. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>起初只是存在于科幻小说里，但现在，“天梯”的构想已经引起了学术界和航天业的注意。天梯是一种向太空运输货物和材料的廉价方式。一旦实现，它将很快取代当前向太空输送物资的危险而昂贵的运载火箭。[PARAGRAPH:2]基本的原理很简单：用一根缆线连接着一颗地球同步轨道卫星和一个地面固定或移动基站。一部电梯，或者“攀登器”将沿这根缆线上下运输物资，这将只花费现在所需运输成本的很小一部分。[PARAGRAPH:2]在这一计划实现前还有很多技术问题需要克服。比如，这根电缆需要用比任何已知的材料都更轻更有强度的材料制成。当前最有希望的材料是碳纳米管，但没人知道如何把它们连接起来，也不知道如何把它们织成缆线。即使能做到，这一材料还是不够轻，不够强。[PARAGRAPH:2]然而，不管这一项目当前面临的科学和技术难题有多少，只要想一想几十年前第一次提出把人类送到月球上去时所面对的技术难题，就会让人觉得信心仍在。许多头脑冷静的人也相信，第一部天梯将在本世纪就会投入使用。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_MANHATTAN_PROJECT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Manhattan Project was the code name for a joint project undertaken by the United States, Great Britain and Canada during World War II, the objective being to build an atomic weapon before Germany. While various laboratories had been independently studying nuclear physics for a number of years, the Manhattan Project would be on an entirely different scale; hundreds of the allies' top scientists and engineers were, along with their families, taken to various secret locations around the country where they would stay until the project succeeded. [PARAGRAPH:1]Working conditions were extremely primitive and security was incredibly tight. The United States Army was in overall charge of the Manhattan Project, while the scientists remained in control over the actual research. The scope of the Manhattan Project was immense, and it involved solving some of the most difficult scientific and engineering projects of the day. The men and women, a collection of soldiers and scientists, endured harsh conditions and physical and mental exhaustion, which were compounded by security so tight that many never saw the outside of the base on which they were stationed. They were sustained by their patriotism and by fear of what would happen to them, their families, and their countries if Germany created the bomb first. [PARAGRAPH:1]Eventually, of course, the effort paid off. By the middle of 1945 the US had two working atomic bombs. Germany, the original target, had already surrendered, but Japan was still in the fight. The two weapons were dropped on the Japanese cities of Hiroshima and Nagasaki early in August, and the Japanese Empire surrendered shortly thereafter. [PARAGRAPH:1]From our perspective some decades later, it isn't clear whether the Manhattan Project helped to save the world for democracy or brought it closer to fiery destruction. But the men and women involved believed they were fighting to stop a terrible dictatorship from gaining a new weapon and destroying everything they loved, and they were willing to sacrifice everything to succeed.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>曼哈顿工程是二次世界大战期间由美国，英国和加拿大共同进行的一项研发计划的代号，其目标是抢在德国之前制造出核武器。虽然在此之前已经有许多实验室独立开展原子物理学研究，但是其规模完全无法与曼哈顿工程相比；数百名同盟国中顶尖的科学家，工程师以及他们的家人都必须集中到与世隔绝的秘密地点，直到计划完成才得以重见天日。[PARAGRAPH:1]当时的工作条件极其艰苦，安全管制也极其严格。曼哈顿工程的管理由美国军方全权负责，科学家们则负责具体的研究工作。曼哈顿工程所涉及的领域非常广阔，需要解决数量极大且难度极高的科学和工程学问题。无数军队士兵和科学家们忍受着艰苦的环境，生理和心理上的疲惫。安全管制是如此的严格，许多人自参加该项目后甚至从未走出秘密基地一步。支持他们继续工作的动力在于他们的爱国热情，以及对于德国人首先造出核武器并危及他们的家人和国家的忧心。[PARAGRAPH:1]当然最终，所有的努力都获得了回报。到1945年中，美国已经拥有了两枚实用的原子弹。而其原定的打击目标德国则已经投降，但是日本仍然在负隅顽抗。于是在八月初，两枚原子弹分别投掷到了广岛和长崎，此后不久日本帝国即宣布投降。[PARAGRAPH:1]在数十年后的今天我们仍然无法确定，曼哈顿工程究竟是拯救了民主世界，还是会最终将其毁灭。但是对于当年的无数工程参与者来说，为了能够制止恐怖独裁者获得新式武器毁灭一切的野心，他们不惜付出任何的代价。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_THE_INTERNET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Internet is a computer network linked by hard wire, telephony and satellite. These computers share the same language, allowing for the fast transfer of information. Anyone with a computer and a modem (or other hookup) can utilize the Internet to gather information, to broadcast news and opinions, or to shoot at other like-minded folks in virtual reality galleries. In its few years of existence the Internet has dramatically changed the way that information is gathered and transmitted, and the network's full potential cannot be guessed. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Internet was first conceived of in the early 1960s.  At that time the discussion was purely theoretical, as the computers, the connections, and the common language did not yet exist. Given that it was the height of the Cold War, neither did the necessary international cooperation. But the idea had many supporters, especially in universities and research labs around the US, and by 1969 four computers located around the country were in communication with each other through ARPA-Net. [PARAGRAPH:1]By the mid-1980s, the core of the network was in place, the communications protocols had been determined, and the Internet was live. By the early 1990s the first Internet language (http) was written and the first browser was published. The World Wide Web was born. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Internet stands today as one of the few great projects constructed largely by individuals rather than by an organization such as a corporation, religion, or government. Various portions of the network were indeed created and funded by the US Department of Defense - but much of it came together organically, built in bits and pieces by professors, scientists and engineers, perhaps less for personal gain than because they thought the "information society" was an idea worth pursuing. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>因特网是由电线，电话线和卫星线路所联接起来的计算机网络。这些计算机使用同一种协议语言以进行信息的快速转换。任何一个拥有计算机与调制解调器（或其它接入设备）的人都可以利用因特网获取信息，传播新闻与观点，或与持各种相同或不同看法的人们在虚拟现实的走廊里碰面。在其诞生后的几年里，因特网戏剧化地转变了信息获取与传播的方式，而其潜力依然无法预测。[PARAGRAPH:1]因特网的设想最早出现在20世纪60年代早期。那时的讨论是纯理论式的，当时甚至连计算机，线路，和通用语言都还不存在。然而它最初却是由冷战中的思维赋予的，而非为了进行国际合作。但是这个主意有许多支持者，特别是全美的大学与研究所，到了1969年，有四台分散在各地的计算机通过“阿帕网”进行了通讯。[PARAGRAPH:1]到1980年代中期，核心网络已经建成，通讯协议也被规范了，因特网从此诞生。1990年代早期，人们发明了第一种英特网协议语言（HTTP）并且发布了最早的浏览器。万维网随即出现。[PARAGRAPH:1]今天，因特网是少数几个主要由个人建设完成的伟大工程之一，而非出于有组织的实施，比如公司，宗教，政府。网络的一部分的确曾经由美国国防部建立——但绝大部分都是由教授，科学家，工程师一字节一字节、一小块一小块地发展起来的，很少考虑到个人利益，因为他们认为建设信息化社会是值得毕生追求的目标。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_SDI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>SDI stands for "Strategic Defense Initiative," a research program implemented by the United States in the mid-1980s to provide a ground and space-based shield against incoming nuclear missiles. As proposed, the SDI is a defensive system that will spot incoming intercontinental ballistic missiles, track their courses, and then destroy them before they detonate over US cities. [PARAGRAPH:1]The concept of putting weapons platforms in space has been around for years; in fact the major space powers may have already done so in secret. Some nations have certainly built "satellite killers," satellites designed to destroy enemy satellites, disrupting the opposition's communications and intelligence capabilities. [PARAGRAPH:1]The specific method of incoming missile destruction hasn't been determined. Some have proposed creating powerful x-ray lasers powered by nuclear explosions that would melt the enemy weapons in space; others suggest ground-based anti-missile rockets on the Patriot missile model. [PARAGRAPH:1]To date the project has made little in the way of visible progress, and its future is uncertain. Some people believe that the threat of an incoming nuclear missile is extremely remote, especially when compared to the threat of a nuclear bomb being smuggled into the country by terrorists. Others believe that the entire concept is flawed and that the money would be better spent bribing potential enemies into destroying their ICBMs rather than trying to create a system to shoot them down.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>战略导弹防御系统（SDI）是一个由美国政府在20世纪80年代中期开始实施的研究项目，它致力于提供地基或空基的防护盾，以抵抗来袭的核导弹。按照预想，该系统能够发现并跟踪来犯的洲际弹道导弹，并将其在美国城市上空引爆前予以摧毁的防御系统。[PARAGRAPH:1]将武器平台置于太空的设想已有多年的历史；事实上或许几个空间强国已经秘密地这么做了。某些国家的确建造了“卫星杀手”，一种设计用来摧毁卫星的卫星，破环对方的通讯和情报能力。[PARAGRAPH:1]摧毁来袭导弹的方法还没决定。有人提议使用X射线来将导弹融化在空间；还有人建议将爱国者导弹改装成地基反导弹火箭。[PARAGRAPH:1]一些人认为来自核导弹的威胁是遥远的，特别与恐怖分子偷带核弹入境的威胁相比。另一些人相信整个计划有严重缺陷，而且与其将钱花在如何射落洲际弹道导弹，还不如想办法贿赂潜在敌人，自行摧毁他们的导弹。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_APOLLO_PROGRAM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Apollo Program was an ambitious project to put a man on the moon. The program was conceived of in the late 1950s by United State officials who were appalled at the Soviet Union's lead in the space race. In 1961, President John F. Kennedy stated before a joint session of Congress, "I believe that this nation should commit itself to achieving the goal, before this decade is out, of landing a man on the Moon and returning him safely to the Earth." [PARAGRAPH:1]There is some speculation about whether President Kennedy himself actually believed in the project; some say that he had serious questions about the cost and scientific feasibility, and that his proposal was mostly a public relations gimmick to raise America's spirits in the face of the perceived Soviet space threat. But America's imagination was fired by the project, and work proceeded with speed. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Apollo Program's managers had to overcome an incredible number of daunting scientific and engineering challenges to succeed. The journey involved many separate phases: ascent from Earth, travel from the Earth to the Moon, descent to the Moon and return to Lunar orbit, followed by the journey back to Earth, and then down to Earth's surface. This required a vehicle with many different capabilities that remained light enough to be put into orbit by the rockets available at the time. (The problem was akin to trying to create a combination submarine, all-terrain vehicle and airplane that could be towed by a Volkswagen Beetle.) [PARAGRAPH:1]That the Apollo Program succeeded and a man walked on the moon in 1969 is an incredible testament to the ingenuity, courage and persistence shown by the dedicated men and women involved. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>阿波罗计划是一个将人类送上月球的雄心勃勃的计划。这个计划于20世纪50年代后期提出，当时的美国因苏联争得了在太空竞赛中的领导地位而受到了严重的刺激。1961年，约翰·肯尼迪总统在例行参众联席会议上说，“我相信这个国家必须让自己达到这样一个目标，在这个十年结束前，将一个人送上月球，再安全地返回地球。”[PARAGRAPH:1]有一些人猜测肯尼迪总统是否真的相信这个计划；他们说他对于此计划的费用与科学可行性持很大的怀疑态度，并且他的提议更多的是一种公关技巧，意在鼓舞美国人面对苏联空间威胁时的士气与精神。但是美国人的想象力被这计划激发出来了，科学家们开始夜以继日的工作。[PARAGRAPH:1]为了成功完成阿波罗计划，参与者们不得不克服不计其数的令人退缩的科学与工程难题。登月旅程历经多个单独过程：从地球起飞，从地球飞向月球，降落在月球和返回月球轨道，然后再返回地球轨道，最终回到地球表面。这需要一种能完成全部任务的航天器，而且其重量要可以由火箭携往太空轨道。（要了解此问题的难度，可做这样一个类比：建造一艘潜水艇兼全地形越野车还兼飞行器，而且其大小不能超过一辆大众甲壳虫轿车。）[PARAGRAPH:1]最后，阿波罗计划与1969年获得了成功，人类首次得以登上月球，这一奇迹般壮举为所有参与其中的科技与工程专家们的智慧，勇气与坚强努力提供了最好的证明。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_SS_CASING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Although humankind has mastered space flight, the concept of interstellar and deep space travel presents many new problems to engineers and physicists. The Exterior Casing of the Space Ship is itself a technological marvel. Designed around a composite system of layered ceramic, zero-gee manufactured aluminum-titanium alloy, and high density polymers, the Exterior Casing is made to withstand both the dangers of debris within star systems and of radiation throughout its travel. Built into the Exterior Casing is also a complex web of electric wiring, capable of carrying a very high positive or negative electromagnetic charge, providing a shield from radiation and literally funneling electromagnetic energy and space borne hydrogen dust into the solar sail where it can be collected and used for further fuel. It is also designed with multiple levels of sensors designed to collect scientific data and to give a clear picture to the navigational computer and to the pilots of what is going on outside of the vehicle. Although this composite design for an Exterior Casing is expensive, the protection and potential scientific information that it affords is well worth the cost of manufacture.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>虽然人类已经掌握了太空飞行技术，不过星际以及超远距离太空旅行的概念，对于工程师及物理学家来说还是有相当多的问题待解决。飞船的保护性外壳本身就是一个技术杰作。飞船保护壳采用多层陶瓷，以及铝钛合金等高密度复合材料组成，可以确保飞船经得起太空旅行时所遇到的各种危险碎片或是太空射线。保护壳内部还有复杂的电子线路，能够负载高正电荷或高负电荷，用来产生一个能防止辐射线的无形防护罩，并能通过太阳帆收集飞行中所遇到的氢原子，以用做日后的燃料。保护壳还设计有多层感应器，用以搜集科学数据并提供给导航计算机，令驾驶员知晓飞船外部的情形。虽然这样的多重设计是所需花费相当昂贵，但它所提供的安全保护和大量有用信息值得人们付出这样的代价。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_SS_THRUSTERS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The massive Thrusters are, much like the Engine, designed to function in a myriad of ways. Designed in stages like the Engines, the Thrusters channel the exhaust used to propel the Space Ship through all of its phases of travel. In the initial phase, the external booster rockets channel their fuel through the Thrusters array until they run out of fuel, at which point they are jettisoned. After that, the powerful electromagnets built into the Thrusters help accelerate the charged particles of the ion drive to near the speed of light, providing a great deal of thrust for the Space Ship.[PARAGRAPH:1]Finally, in the last stages of travel, the Thrusters are responsible for maneuvering the Space Ship into the planet's gravity well and providing a counter thrust to slow the vessel to a manageable velocity to settle into a geo-synchronous orbit. In order to fulfill all of these functions, the Thrusters array had to be capable of the ultra-sensitive duty of accelerating high energy ions as well as be able to handle the hundreds of thousands of pounds of thrust produced by the solid fuel boosters.[PARAGRAPH:1]The engineers who designed the Thrusters were able to fulfill both of these functions as well as making them articulated to allow for maneuverability that is remarkable considering the mass and projected velocities of the craft.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>巨大的飞船推进器外观与应用于其他运输工具的各种喷气式引擎差不多，设计原理也类似。飞船推进器通过喷射方式来推进太空飞船，以完成航程的各个阶段。在开始阶段，由外挂副燃料箱向各组助推火箭提供燃料，直到燃料用尽时就抛弃。在此之后，再由内置推进器以强大的电磁力加速离子束，使其接近光速，这为飞船提供了绝大部份的继航动力。[PARAGRAPH:2]在航程的最后阶段，推进器负责调整飞船进入行星引力圈，并提供反向推力以缓和速度，使飞船能安然进入行星同步轨道。为了实现所有这些功能，推进器组必须具备加速高能离子的高度感应能力，又要能够操控由固态燃料推进器所产生的数十万磅的推力。[PARAGRAPH:1]设计推进器的工程师需要保证其能够同时实现这两种功能，并使其能够为质量巨大，速度极高的飞船提供足够的机动能力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_SS_ENGINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Space Ship Engine is actually a four part launch vehicle, designed to enable the Space Ship to complete its journey both within the high gravity space-time bends surrounding star systems and through the vast emptiness of deep space that separates our star from Alpha Centauri. Its first stage is the external booster rockets, which, much like the terrestrially launched shuttles of the late twentieth century, are solid fuel boosters and are jettisoned when they are no longer needed. They are crucial to build the initial impulse which will carry the Space Ship into Jupiter's gravity well, giving it the energy to slingshot to Uranus and then out into deep space. The second part to the Engine is the Space Ship's solar sail, which was designed both to use the radiation emitted from our sun and Jupiter for propulsion and to collect atomic particles for further future fuel and materials. The third part of the Engine array is the ion drive, which will harness both nuclear power and collected hydrogen to propel the craft through deep space, channeling high energy particles through the Thrusters. The fourth and most externally obvious component is the hydrogen solid fuel rocket, which will be used in the final phases of the Space Ship's travel to place it in orbit around Alpha Centauri's planetary system. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>太空飞船的发动机实际上是由四部分所组成的，其设计能使飞船顺利穿透星系周围由强大引力所造成的时空扭曲，并跨越阻隔在我们的恒星与半人马星系间浩瀚而空旷的星际空间。在第一阶段进行工作的是外部助推器，与二十世纪后期的航天飞机所用的推进器类似，这是使用固态燃料的推进器，并在其完成使命后就自动抛弃。它们能提供足够的动力，使飞船进入木星引力范围，通过借力抛射穿越天王星进入深空。第二部分是飞船的太阳帆，它依靠太阳及木星的辐射能推进，并收集原子微粒作为未来的燃料及物资。第三部分则是离子推进器，通过重核裂变或氢核聚变反应产生能量加速高能粒子，驱动飞船穿越深空。第四部分，也是飞船外部最为明显的组件即固态氢燃料火箭，用于飞船最后阶段的旅程，使飞船进入环绕半人马座阿尔法星的轨道。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_SS_DOCKING_BAY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Built entirely in space and for space travel, the Space Ship is a marvel of human technology. The Docking Bay module allows for the transfer of personnel and materials both during the initial loading of the Space Ship as well as during its final orbit, during which it will be converted to a Space Station for the first phase of the colonization and terraforming process. The Docking Bay module also holds the RCV Manned Shuttle, the main travel and transit vehicle for the Space Ship occupants, as well as providing access for the engineers to the exterior of the Space Ship during space walks. The Docking Bay is in essence a large air lock with a door large enough to release the RCV, flanked by a pair of smaller air locks for transferal of small teams of individuals. The Docking Bay also has large magnetic locks, allowing the Space Ship to join to the International Space Station prior to its departure during the final phases of supply loading before launching from Earth's orbit for its interstellar trip.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>作为人类科学技术的巅峰之作，太空飞船完全在太空轨道上建造和组装。飞船对接舱组件可在飞船的初期加载及最后入轨全过程中作为人员与货物的传送通道，在到达目标轨道后，它将被改装为一座太空站，为行星移民及地形改造的最初阶段提供相关服务。对接舱组件还配有数架太空梭（RCV），作为船员的轨道交通工具，并辅助太空工程师在飞船周围进行太空漫步。对接舱的主要结构就是一组气闸，包括足够容纳RCV进出的大型通道，以及用于宇航员进出的小型通道。对接舱还配有更大的电磁闸门，用于连接飞船和国际空间站完成最后阶段的补给工作，然后飞离地球轨道开始星际航行。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_SS_COCKPIT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The command and control center of the Space Ship, the Cockpit component is the brain of the vessel. Ergonomically designed for the comfort of the pilots, the Cockpit holds all of the advanced navigation and systems control computers necessary for interstellar travel and interplanetary colonization as well as providing for all of the long-term necessities of its occupants. A fully encased component, the Cockpit has no unshielded area, completely encasing the occupants in a protective shell of titanium, ceramic, and an electromagnetic repulsion system to shed unwanted radiation. It utilizes the latest in holographic technology for star chart navigation, heads up displays for a 360 degree range of vision around the Space Ship, and the most advanced sensors available for collision detection and avoidance.[PARAGRAPH:1]The crowning jewel of the Cockpit component, however, is the advanced CAM Computer System, an artificial intelligence system designed to evaluate the potential dangers of deep space flight that may be encountered in the regions that no human has ever before penetrated. The CAM System continually monitors radiation fields and particle positions, judging the best way to deal with any potential threat and alerting the pilots in case of an emergency. The CAM system also helps keep the pilots entertained, having full access to the libraries of the Planetary Party lounge and being the most advanced Chess computer in the known galaxy. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>飞船驾驶舱作为指令控制中心，是整艘飞船的大脑。驾驶舱采用完善的人体工程学设计，以尽可能让驾驶员感到舒适，其中配备有各种先进的导航系统和计算机系统，以满足星际旅行及外星移民全过程的各种需要。驾驶舱自成一体，具有完善的安全保护设施，其外壳由钛及陶瓷复合材料制成，并由无形的电磁效应保护罩反射危险的太空辐射。驾驶舱利用最新的全息技术来显示星际导航图，能同时完整显示360度视角，并装有最新型的碰撞侦测与规避探测器。[PARAGRAPH:1]驾驶舱中最核心的组件则是最先进的超级计算机系统（CAM），该系统能够自动分析超长距离星际航行中可能遭遇到的各种潜在危险。CAM系统通过持续监视辐射场以及宇宙粒子的位置，判断出能够规避潜在威胁的最佳航线，并在遇到紧急状况时及时警告驾驶员。CAM系统还能为驾驶员提供休闲娱乐，它拥有飞船生活舱信息资料库的完整读取权限，也是全星系最聪明的国际象棋大师。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_SS_LIFE_SUPPORT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Essential to the sustenance of human life are food, water, air, and heat, and the Life Support System provides all of these things. Recycling is the key to the Space Ship's Life Support System, and no organic component is left to waste in the vessel. Computers control the collection and recycling of waste, which is injected into large vats of algae which consume the waste or processed into fertilizer for the Space Ship hydroponics garden. Both the algae and the garden provide food and oxygen for the colonists as well as for their livestock, which consist of fish, shrimp, and a particularly hearty (and tasty) breed of Peruvian mountain llama.[PARAGRAPH:1]Extra oxygen is processed in the air filtration system, which electrically divides water into hydrogen and oxygen molecules and separates them for oxygen and fuel uses. Excess heat produced by the Fuel Cells is also absorbed into steam pipes, which are used to keep the interior of the vessel warm and to separate pure water out of waste water to a 99.44%% purity.[PARAGRAPH:1]Extraplanetary travel has never before been attempted on this scale, and the Life Support System has been carefully crafted to provide indefinitely for the needs of the colonists as well as giving them a basis for redeveloping a food chain on the eventual planet of colonization.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>维持人类生命的必需品有食物、水、空气及热能，而服务舱则提供了这些必需品。循环利用则是飞船上生命维持系统的关键所在，在星际旅行中没有任何有机物是可以被轻易浪费的。在飞船中，必须由电脑控制，归集并再利用这些废弃物，把这些废弃物注入到一个含有大量藻类的分解槽之中，将它们制成肥料然后用在飞船上无土栽培的植物园之中。这些藻类以及植物也提供了开拓者及养殖的动物维生必须的氧气，这些动物包括鱼、虾以及特别美味的秘鲁山地驼马等。[PARAGRAPH:2]多余的氧气会被空气过滤系统电解成氢，氧分子而又将氢气用在燃料用途之上。燃料电池产生的多余热量会被用于产生蒸汽并通过管线运送，使得飞船内可以保持一定的温度，最终分离出99.44%纯度的淡水。[PARAGRAPH:1]超远距离的星系旅行是过去从未尝试过的冒险，因此生命维持系统必须仔细设计、确保可靠，此系统也是提供星际开拓者在最后阶段的行星殖民时重建食物链的一个重要基石。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PROJECT_SS_STASIS_CHAMBER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>With a journey predicted to take decades, if not centuries, one of the most important considerations of the engineers was the aging of the crew. Recent advances in cryogenics and chemical therapy have enabled scientists to chemically slow the metabolic process to a virtual standstill, which enables the scientists to then deep freeze the body without harm. Sensors regulate the zero-oxygen environment to ensure that the colonists will be kept as safe as possible, and a special warming system utilizing broad spectrum electromagnetic radiation is used to quickly and safely restore warmth to the body.[PARAGRAPH:1]The radiation also has the effect of breaking down the chemical agents that slow the colonists' metabolism, making them able to be thawed out in a matter of seconds and fully aware in a little over a minute. This is essential to the survival of the craft in a situation in which the computer is unable to determine a course of action and a pilot or navigator must be roused to assess the danger, or in a situation in which a technician must be roused to effect repairs.[PARAGRAPH:1]This system has been used very effectively in tests on pigs and monkeys, and it has been shown that such animals in deep cryogenic sleep have been able to be roused after three years with absolutely no visible side effects. A couple of military volunteers have also been frozen to test the system, but only for a matter of weeks. Although scientists have not yet tested the effects of long-term freezing on human beings, they are completely confident that there will not be any problems with the Stasis Chamber on the Space Ship.[PARAGRAPH:1]Completely confident.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>如果按照预期，超远距离星际旅行需要花费数十年甚至上百年的时间，工程师们要考虑的一个重要问题就是飞船上人员年龄的老化。采用最新的低温化疗技术，可以使人的新陈代谢近乎停滞，这样科学家就可以将人体进行低温冷冻，而不会造成任何伤害。近乎无氧的环境也让这些星际移民安全地维持生命状态，而特殊的加温系统的射线则可以让他们的身体在未来迅速而安全地复苏。[PARAGRAPH:1]这种射线同时也可立即中和那些减缓新陈代谢的化学物质，使他们能够在数分钟后就能够恢复正常的作息。这项技术对太空旅行是非常重要的，例如在电脑失灵时，驾驶员必须要亲自去处理这些危险时；或者是飞船必须进行人工维护时。这个系统已经用猪以及猴子测试过，而且成效显著，进入低温休眠的这些动物们在三年后成功苏醒，并且没有任何负作用。一群军人也自愿成为这个系统的测试者，不过仅仅进行了为期数周的测试。虽然科学家们并没有经过长期测试，不过他们认为在太空飞船配备休眠舱将不会有任何问题。[PARAGRAPH:1]科学家们对此有完全的信心……</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
