<!--  Sid Meier's Civilization 4  -->
<!--  Copyright Firaxis Games 2005  -->
<!--  freesand  -->
<!--  Game Text Civilopedia CivLeaders  -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AMERICA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>The United States is young by Civilization standards, being barely more than 200 years old. The United States did not expand to reach its current borders until the middle of the 19th century, and did not become a true world power until the middle of the 20th century. America was the first European colony to separate successfully from its motherland, and it was among the first nations to be established on the premise that sovereignty rests with its citizens and not with the government.[PARAGRAPH:2]Prior to the 1770s, the American colonists were loyal subjects of the British Empire, but a combination of taxes and ministerial mismanagement of the situation led to the outbreak of revolution in 1776. George Washington, the leader of the colonial forces during the Revolutionary War and later First President of the United States, along with the other Founding Fathers, managed to win the fight for independence against all odds and lay the constitutional foundation for America's future growth. In its first century and a half, the country was mainly preoccupied with its own territorial exploration, internal development, and economic growth. American politics evolved from quasi-aristocratic beginnings to become increasingly democratic during the 1820s and '30s. But despite the nation's rapid acquisition of territory and dramatic population growth, the spectre of slavery continued to divide the country between North and South. The struggle between anti- and pro-slavery advocates eventually erupted in a bloody Civil War that lasted four years and consumed hundreds of thousands of lives. In the end, the Union was preserved and the power of the central federal government greatly strengthened compared to before the conflict.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following the Civil War, the nation entered a period of unprecedented prosperity after the long conflict and reconstruction. In the ensuing two decades industrial production, the number of industrial workers, and the number of factories all more than doubled. European immigration, westward expansion, urban growth, technological advances, and a host of American inventions - including the telephone, typewriter, linotype, phonograph, electric light, cash register, air brake, refrigerator car, and the automobile - contributed to the American explosion, while widespread use of corporate organization offered new opportunities for large-scale financing of business enterprise and attracted new capital. But despite America's growth as one of the world's leading industrial powers, the nation still remained isolationist in outlook, paying little to no attention to the world outside its borders.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Spanish-American War of 1898 marked the emergence of the United States onto the world's stage as a major power, but it was not until World War I that the country truly became invovled in world politics. Following the 1919 Versailles Peace Conference, the nation again turned its back on the rest of the world and enjoyed the prosperous decade known as the "Roaring Twenties". Unfortunately, this economic boom was not to last. Wall Street's stock market crashed in 1929 and kicked off the Great Depression of the 1930s. In the midst of constant bank failures and rampant unemployment, Franklin Roosevelt was elected president and set about to fix the country through his recovery plan called the "New Deal". The program was a mixed success economically, but helped restore hope and confidence to a people that were in serious need of both. Roosevelt then went on to lead the United States through the crucible of World War II, dying a few months before victory was won.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Allied victory at the end of World War II left the United States as one of the world's two "superpowers" along with the Soviet Union. In only a few short years the two former allies had become opponents in the Cold War, a tense diplomatic standoff that would last for forty years. Domestically, the nation enjoyed considerable prosperity in the 1950s, experienced a turbulent period of cultural and social change in the 1960s, and suffered through economic stagnation in the 1970s, with recovery taking place in the following decades. Since the collapse of the Soviet empire in 1989-91, the United States has been left alone as the world's sole remaining superpower. Rather than facing conventional armies on the field of battle, America is now threatened by terrorist groups who make no distinction between military and civilian targets. Highly trained special operations units like the Navy SEALs are often used to combat these enemies using advanced weaponry. But for all of its overwhelming economic and military strength, the United States will have to work together with other nations in order to meet the threats of the modern world.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>按照人类文明的标准，美利坚合众国是一个相对年轻的国度，自建立至今只有两百多年的历史。美国直到19世纪中叶才达到目前的疆域范围，并且直到20世纪中叶才真正成为一个世界级强国。美国是最早成功独立于欧洲母国的美洲殖民地，它也是最早将“主权在民”的理念作为立国之本的国家。[PARAGRAPH:2]在其18世纪70年代之前，北美殖民地居民是大英帝国的忠实臣民，但是一系列苛捐杂税和错误政策最终导致了1776年独立战争的爆发。乔治·华盛顿是独立战争期间的大陆军总司令，后来成为美利坚合众国的第一任总统，他与其他独立运动先驱一道战胜重重艰难险阻赢得国家独立，并为美国未来的发展奠定了宪政基础。在立国后的一百多年间，这个国家主要致力于在北美大陆的探索，扩张领土以及发展经济。到19世纪20至30年代，美国开始由最初实际上的准贵族政体转变为日益民主化的政体。但是，虽然美国的领土不断扩张，人口持续增长，对奴隶制度的不同态度却开始造成南北对峙局面的形成。奴隶制的支持者和反对者之间的斗争导致一场持续四年、伤亡无数的血腥内战最终爆发。到战争结束时，美国恢复了国家的统一，联邦政府的权力也得到极大的强化。[PARAGRAPH:2]结束内战之后的美国进入了前所未有的繁荣时期。在二十年间民族工业开始获得长足的发展，工厂和产业工人的数量都增长了一倍以上。欧洲移民的迁入、西部的开发、城市的扩展、技术的进步以及无数美国人发明创造精神的迸发——包括电话、打字机、行式排印机、留声机、电灯、收银机、气压制动器、冷冻车厢以及汽车——这一切使得美国以爆炸性的速度迅速发展，日益推广的股份公司制度使工商企业有机会获得了大量商机，并吸引新的资本不断投入。虽然此时的美国已经发展成为世界上最重要的制造业中心，但是在政治上却仍然采取孤立主义态度，对境外的事务基本上漠不关心。[PARAGRAPH:2]在军事方面，1898年爆发的美西战争历时短暂，伤亡轻微，在现代的战史上几乎不值一提，但这场战争却标志着美利坚合众国作为列强的一员开始跃上世界舞台。然而直到第一次世界大战爆发之后，美国才真正参预到世界政治事务当中。1919年凡尔赛和约签订时，这个国家又再次远离世界政治，专注于推动国内的经济繁荣，这一时期又被称为“沸腾的二十年代”。不幸的是，这样的繁荣未能持续下去。华尔街股票市场在1929年全面崩溃，从此揭开了三十年代大萧条的序幕。在银行接连倒闭，失业率持续上升的环境下，富兰克林·罗斯福当选新一届的总统，他着手实施“新政”努力推动国家复苏。这一政策在经济方面并非完全成功，但使得美国人逐渐恢复了曾经失去的希望和信心。此后罗斯福又领导美国安然度过了第二次世界大战的风风雨雨，但他在战争即将取得胜利的前夕离开了人世。[PARAGRAPH:2]盟军在二战中的最后胜利使美国成为和苏联并列的超级大国，但仅仅数年时间这对昔日的盟友就变成了冷战的对手，紧张的政治和外交对峙状态持续了四十年。而在国内，美国经历了五十年代的经济繁荣、六十年代的社会和文化动荡，以及七十年代的经济停滞，进入八十年代后又再次复苏。在1989-1991年的政治动荡导致苏联解体后，美国成为世上唯一的超级大国。今日美国所面临的最大威胁不是来自常规战场上的敌方正规军队，而是来自不断暗中袭击军事和民用目标的恐怖分子。以海豹突击队为代表、经过专门训练、装备尖端武器的特种部队经常被用于对付此类隐藏的敌人。尽管拥有压倒性的经济和军事实力，美国仍然需要与其他国家团结协作，共同消除当代世界所面临的各种威胁。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ARABIA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>Before the spread of Islam and the Arabic language, the term "Arab" referred to any of the nomadic residents of the Arabian Peninsula. When used in a modern context, "Arab" refers to any of the Arabic-speaking peoples who reside on the Atlantic Coast of Africa, Southwestern Iran, Egypt, Sudan, Saudi-Arabia, Syria, and Iraq. The earliest nomadic inhabitants of the Arabian Peninsula herded their sheep, goats, and camels through an unforgiving desert environment; while those Arabs who settled in the oases provided date and cereal agriculture as trade staples for Arab caravans that transported spices, ivory, and gold from southern Arabia and the Horn of Africa to the civilizations farther north.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the 7th century AD, Muhammad emerged as the prophet for the religion of Islam, which was widely adopted by the Arab community. Islam unified the Bedouins and the town-dwellers of the oases, and within a century, spread throughout most of the present day Arab-speaking world. The newfound social organization that followed Islam offered new possibilities for the Arabs as agricultural production and intercity trading, particularly in luxury goods, saw significant increases. Gradually, the triad of temple, court, and market formed, as well as a standardized style of writing for laws and other texts. New institutions also emerged, including coinage, territorial deities, royal priesthoods, and standing armies, which further enhanced Arab power.[PARAGRAPH:2]By proclaiming his message publicly, Muhammad gained many followers. After his death, the succeeding caliphs continued to spread the faith of Islam far beyond the religion's birthplace in Mecca. Aside from initial conquests in Iraq and Syria, the Arab conquests penetrated regions including Anatolia, Northern Africa, and Iran. Using their Camel Archers to cross difficult desert terrain, the Arabs were able to create an empire stretching from Spain to the borders of India in barely more than a hundred years. The Arab empire of the medieval period was far more advanced than contemporary Europeans; Harun al-Rashid's Baghdad may have held a million people at the same time that Charlemagne's Aachen was a "capital" of ten thousand. Centers of learning attracted scholars from across the Muslim world to great cities such as Baghdad, Damascus, and Cordoba. The Arabs of this period made many advances in medicine, astronomy, mathematics, and other areas, as well as translating many of the classics of the Ancient Greeks into Arabic, thereby saving them from destruction.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the period of the Crusades, the Arabic world came under assault from Christian Europe. The greatest of Muslim generals from this period was Salah al-Din, better known as Saladin, who successfully defeated the Third Crusade and recaptured Jerusalem for the Arabs. In addition to his military skills, Saladin was known to be a pious man and was well-respected by his enemies as well as his allies - which was very unusual indeed for the Crusades.[PARAGRAPH:2]For most of the past five centuries, much of the Arab world has been ruled by foreigners; first by the Ottoman Turks, then by the Western colonial powers. Since the onset of de-colonization in the 1950s, traditional Arab values have been modified through the combined pressures of urbanization, industrialization, and Western influence. While urban Arabs still tend to identify themselves more by nationality than by tribe, village farmers revere the pastoral nomad's romantic way of life and claim a kinship with the great desert tribes of the past. As heirs to the ancient Egyptians, Babylonians, Persians, Hebrews, even to the Greeks and Indians, the societies created by Muslims bridge time and space. The original Arab tribes, in less than 20 years after Muhammad's death, defeated the Byzantine and Persian empires, occupied a vast territory from Libya to Persia, and then developed into the Arab, or Islamic, Empire known today.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>远在伊斯兰教和阿拉伯语的大规模向外传播以前，“阿拉伯”一词仅指阿拉伯半岛上的游牧民族。但在现代文献中，则可能涵盖所有说阿拉伯语的人，他们遍布北非地中海沿岸，伊朗西南部、埃及、苏丹、沙特阿拉伯、叙利亚以及伊拉克。最早的生活在阿拉伯半岛上的游牧民族在严酷的沙漠环境中驯养绵羊、山羊、骆驼等，另一些定居者则生活于各个绿洲，种植椰枣和谷物，他们组成大规模的商队与来自阿拉伯半岛南部，东部非洲之角以及遥远北方文明的文明交换香料，象牙和黄金。[PARAGRAPH:2]公元七世纪时，先知穆罕默德开始宣讲伊斯兰教义并获得阿拉伯人的广泛接受。伊斯兰教将在沙漠中游牧的贝都因人和在绿洲里生活的居民团结在一起，仅用一个世纪时间就转遍了现今的整个阿拉伯语地区。伊斯兰教改变了阿拉伯世界的社会组织形式，促使农业生产和城市间贸易特别是奢侈品贸易更为迅速地发展。寺院、宫殿和市场大量兴建，撰写法律文书和其他各种文献的迫切需要则促成了阿拉伯书面文体的统一。一系列新的社会机构和制度也开始形成，包括：货币制度、地方与中央的专门神职机构以及常备军制度，这一切大大增强了阿拉伯人的力量。[PARAGRAPH:2]穆罕默德通过向大众宣讲教义而获得大批信徒（“穆斯林”）。公元632年穆罕默德去世之后，接替其担任穆斯林领袖的人被称为“哈里发”，历代哈里发以麦加为中心继续向四方传播伊斯兰教。在征服伊拉克与叙利亚之后，穆斯林军队又进入了安纳托利亚、努比亚、利比亚和伊朗。阿拉伯骆驼骑射手部队在沙漠地形中畅行无阻，仅用大约一百年的时间就建立了西起西班牙，东至印度边境的大帝国。中世纪的阿拉伯帝国比同时期的欧洲要先进得多，哈伦·阿尔-拉施德统治下的巴格达人口可能达到一百万，而当时查理曼帝国都城亚琛的居民不过一万而已。巴格达、大马士革和科尔多瓦等城市也成为聚集了穆斯林世界众多智者的学术中心。这一时期阿拉伯人在医学，天文学，数学及其他领域都取得了大量研究成果，他们还将许多古希腊的经典著作翻译成阿拉伯文，使其免于湮没无闻的命运。[PARAGRAPH:2]在十字军东征期间，阿拉伯世界遭遇来自欧洲基督教国家的侵扰。这一时期最著名的一位穆斯林军事领袖是萨拉赫·阿尔-丁，欧洲人称他为萨拉丁，他成功击败了第三次十字军东征，并为阿拉伯人收复了耶路撒冷。萨拉丁不但军事能力出众，而且具有仁慈宽宏的高尚人格，因而赢得了盟友甚至敌人对他的一致尊敬——这种情况在十字军东征的年代是极为罕见的。[PARAGRAPH:2]在过去的五个世纪里，阿拉伯世界的大部分地区均为异族所统治，先是奥斯曼土耳其人，然后则是西方列强。20世纪50年代非殖民化浪潮开始之后，阿拉伯人的传统价值观在20世纪随着都市化，工业化和西方文化的不断影响已经开始改变。虽然城市里的居民仍倾向与对整个阿拉伯民族的认同而不局限于本部落，乡村里的居民则趋向于回归浪漫的游牧生活，并宣称他们的血统传承自伟大的远古沙漠部落。是古埃及人、巴比伦人、波斯人、希伯来人，甚至希腊人和印度人的后代，穆斯林们创建的社会组织成为沟通如此广阔时间和空间的桥梁。当初微不足道的阿拉伯各部落在穆罕默德去世后不到20年的时间里连续击败了拜占庭和波斯两大帝国，控制了从利比亚到波斯的辽阔土地，建立起后世所称道的阿拉伯伊斯兰帝国。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_AZTEC_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>The origin of the Aztec people is uncertain, but elements of their own tradition suggest that they were a tribe of hunter-gatherers on the northern Mexican plateau before their appearance in Meso-America in the 12th century. The Aztec were so called for Aztlan ("White Land"), an allusion to their origins in northern Mexico. It is possible that their migration southward was part of a general movement of peoples that followed, or perhaps helped trigger, the collapse of the Toltec civilization. The Aztecs settled on islands in Lake Texcoco and in 1325 founded Tenochtitlan, which remained their chief city. The basis of the Aztecs' success in creating a great state and ultimately an empire was their remarkable system of agriculture, which featured intensive cultivation of all available land, as well as elaborate systems of irrigation and reclamation of swampland. The high productivity gained by these methods made for a rich and populous state. The empire the Aztecs established was equaled in the New World only by that of the Incas of Peru, and the brilliance of their civilization is comparable to that of other great ancient cultures of the New and the Old World.[PARAGRAPH:2]Under a succession of ambitious kings they established a dominion that eventually stretched over most of present-day Mexico. By commerce and conquest, Tenochtitlan came to rule an empire of 400 to 500 small states, comprising by 1519 some five to six million people spread over 80,000 square miles. Valor in war, notably in the feared Jaguar Warrior formations, was the surest path to advancement in Aztec society, which was caste- and class-divided but nonetheless vertically fluid. The priestly and bureaucratic classes were involved in the administration of the empire, while at the bottom of society were classes of serfs, indentured servants, and outright slaves. The incredible story of a wandering tribe that was able to build an empire in one century (from the beginning of the 14th century to the beginning of the 15th) can be largely explained by three main factors: the Aztec religion, the thriving trade routes centered on Tenochtilan, and Aztec military organization. In 1502 the ninth emperor Montezuma II (1502-1520) succeeded his uncle Ahuitzotl as the leader of an empire that had reached its greatest extent, stretching from what is now northern Mexico to Honduras and Nicaragua. The Aztec empire was still expanding, and its society still evolving, when its progress was halted in 1519 by the appearance of Spanish adventurers.[PARAGRAPH:2]For all its apparent strength, the Aztec Empire had vulnerabilities that the Spanish were able to exploit. Aztec rule was based upon a system of tribute and fear over the surrounding peoples; every year, they were forced to pay the Aztecs money, goods, and a supply of captives to be sacrificed on the altar. Taking advantage of this resentment of their Aztec overlords, the tiny Spanish force was able to attract a massive army of some 30,000 Mesoamericans of many different tribes. After mistaking the Spanish for gods and inviting them into Tenochtitlan, Montezuma was taken prisoner by Hernando Cortes and died in custody. Montezuma's successors, Cuitlahuac and Cuauhtemoc, were unable to stave off the force raised by the conquistadors and, with the Spanish sack of Tenochtitlan in 1521, the Aztec empire came to an end.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>阿兹特克人的具体起源尚无法确定，不过根据其本身的传说所透露的信息，可以推测他们在公元12世纪到达中美洲之前，是一个在墨西哥高原上以捕猎和采集为生的部族。“阿兹特克人”得名于“阿兹特兰”，意为“白色的土地”，似乎暗示着他们是来自于北墨西哥。他们的南迁可能与托尔特克文明的衰亡及其后大规模的民族迁徙有关，甚至可能是该古文明衰亡的直接原因。南迁后的阿兹特克人定居于特斯科科湖中的群岛，并于1325年在此建立了特诺奇蒂特兰城，此后该城的重要地位一直得以保持。阿兹特克得以成功建立强大的国家甚至后来的大帝国，一个重要的基础就是他们优良的农业技术，几乎每寸可用土地都获得精耕细作，通过建立复杂的灌溉系统，排干沼泽。这一切都提供了极高的农业生产力，足以支持富庶的城市和众多的人口。阿兹特克人所建立的帝国在新大陆上只有秘鲁的印加帝国能够匹敌，其文明的辉煌程度完全不逊色于新旧大陆上其他任何伟大的古文明。[PARAGRAPH:2]连续数代野心勃勃的国王使得帝国的疆界覆盖了现今的墨西哥的绝大部分地区。通过由商业扩张和武力征服，特诺奇蒂特兰统治着由四五百个小邦组成的巨大帝国。在1519年其人口达五百至六百万，面积超过八万平方英里。通过英勇作战，成为令人畏惧的美洲虎战士队伍中的一员，是阿兹特克人提升自己社会地位的最佳途径，他们的社会虽然等级森严，但还是可以上下流动的。祭司与官僚阶级可以参与帝国的管理，而社会的最底层则包括农奴、佣工以及奴隶。一个游牧民族居然仅用一个世纪的时间（约14世纪初至15世纪初）就能够建立这样一个庞大的帝国，是由于三个最重要的因素：阿兹特克人的宗教信仰，以特诺奇蒂特兰为中心的繁荣商路，以及阿兹特克人的军事组织。1502年，蒙特祖玛二世（1502-1520在位）继其叔父阿辉佐特尔之后成为阿兹特克帝国的第九任统治者，此时的帝国已达到了强盛的顶峰，控制范围自今墨西哥北部一直延伸到到洪都拉斯和尼加拉瓜。但是阿兹特克帝国的扩张及其社会的发展随着1519年西班牙的冒险家的到达而突然中断。[PARAGRAPH:2]阿兹特克帝国表面上虽然非常强大，但西班牙人发现其内部存在着许多弱点。阿兹特克依靠武力强迫周围民族向其纳贡。每年这些小民族都要上缴大量财物，以及用于献祭的活人。一小股西班牙武装利用这些民族对阿兹特克统治者的反抗情绪，因而召集到来自中美洲各部族的军队共三万多人。而蒙特祖玛却将西班牙人奉若神明，邀请他们访问特诺奇蒂特兰，结果被赫尔南多·科尔特斯抓获并死于狱中。他的继任者奎特拉华克和库奥提莫克均无法击退西班牙征服者，最终西班牙人于1521年攻占特诺奇蒂特兰，阿兹特克帝国就此灭亡。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BARBARIAN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>The term "barbarian" was created by the Greeks; it was originally used to denote any foreigner. Since then it has gained a more negative connotation, and it is commonly applied to civilizations deemed "inferior" to one's own. The Chinese, for instance, thought of all foreign cultures - everybody from the Manchus to the Turks to the Europeans - as barbarians. Rome applied it to the Huns and the Germanic tribes, as well as to the more advanced Gauls.[PARAGRAPH:2]In Civilization IV, the term denotes people that are not part of any organized civilization appearing in the game, but are instead old-style hunter-gatherers who prey on the "weak" civilized world. Though some barbarians may have acquired fairly advanced weaponry - swords and axes, for example - and though they may occasionally capture or even build their own cities, they remain at heart brigandic nomads, destroying everything that comes in their path. Barbarians cannot be bargained with or appeased: they must be destroyed - before they destroy you!</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>“蛮族”一词是由希腊人最先使用的，用以称呼任何外来者。从此它一直都是个相当贬义的称谓，包含对非本民族的“落后”文明的蔑视。例如中国人就认为，所有的外部民族——不论是满族人、突厥人还是欧洲人——都是一群蛮夷。罗马人则将匈人、日耳曼人，以及发展程度已相当先进的高卢人当作蛮族。[PARAGRAPH:2]在文明IV中，蛮族是指不从属于各主要文明的小部族，他们仍保持传统的捕猎和采集的生活方式，并经常袭挠“软弱的”文明世界。虽然某些蛮族可能获得更先进的武器——例如剑和斧——有时还会占据甚至建立自己的城市，但是他们在骨子里仍然是游牧民族，所到之处往往大肆破坏。文明世界无法以和平方式与蛮族交往：他们必须被消灭——免得他们消灭你！</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CHINA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>Despite political and social upheavals that frequently ravaged the country, China is unique for its longevity and resilience as a politico-cultural entity. Most of China's cultural progress has been accomplished with relatively little outside influence; even when the country was ruled by such "barbarian" peoples as the Chin or Mongols, these were soon absorbed into the fabric of Chinese culture. The casting of bronze and the development of an alphabet date from the period of the Shang dynasty - China's first, believed to have dominated north China from the mid-16th to mid-11th century BC. The overthrow of the Shang dynasty by the Chou (1111-255 BC) spanned three generations; although the vibrant Chou culture produced some of history's greatest philosophers and artists, among them Confucius and Lao-zi, the final two centuries of the dynasty saw China engulfed by a series of civil wars known as the "Warring States" period (403-221 BC). [PARAGRAPH:2]The fighting came to an end when Qin Shi Huang managed to conquer all of his rivals and establish the Ch'in Dynasty (221-206 BC). He became the first Chinese Emperor, and was the first man to unite all of China under a single ruler, but the Ch'in Dynasty was unable to outlive his death. The subsequent Han dynasty was founded by Liu Pang, who also assumed the title of emperor in 202 BC. The four centuries of the Han were ones of considerable changes in imperial, political, cultural, and social development. The Han undertook massive engineering projects (including the Great Wall), and established a Chinese identity that would survive until the advent of Communism. The Cho-ko-nu, a type of repeating crossbow, was developed during the Han period and remained in use by the Chinese for almost two thousand years.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the end of the 2nd century AD the Han Empire had virtually ceased to exist, and was followed by a lengthy period of rival kingdoms that did not end until 618 AD, when the T'ang dynasty came to power. The T'ang were followed by the Sung Dynasty (960-1279 AD), which collapsed in the face of the Mongol invasions. By securing the allegiance of the Hsi Hsia in Tibet (1209), Genghis Khan disposed of a potential enemy and prepared the ground for an invasion of China. For several years Mongol armies pillaged the country; finally, in 1214 Genghis overwhelmed the capital of the northern Chin (modern Beijing). During the next decades there was an uneasy truce between the Mongols in the north and the Sung state in the south. The Mongols resumed their advance in 1250 under Kublai Khan, grandson of Genghis. [PARAGRAPH:2]From 1267 onward, the Mongols, this time assisted by the armored horsemen and auxiliary troops of north China, attacked on several fronts. When organized resistance ceased soon afterward, foreign invaders controlled the whole of China for the only time in history. The Mongols occupied China for a century, but ineptitude on the throne, factionalism at court, and rivalries among generals weakened their rule. Out of this turmoil emerged a new native dynasty, the Ming (1368-1644), known for patronage of the arts. Before turning inward and reverting to an isolationist policy in 1424, the Ming period saw extensive trade with India and Arabia, and Ming navigators may have reached the Americas before Columbus. The Ming were followed by the Manchus (1644-1911), the last imperial dynasty of China, marked by continuous warfare, Western imperialism, rampant corruption, and bureaucratic ineptitude.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the wake of the disastrous Boxer Rebellion, the imperial court could no longer maintain support among the peasantry and army; revolution (1911-1912) followed. The first half of the 20th century saw the disintegration of the old order in China and the foundations of a new society, begun by the short-lived democratic Republic (1912-1920), which quickly degenerated into the dictatorship of Chiang Kai-shek. A new revolution, led by the Nationalist Party (KMT) and the Chinese Communist Party (CCP), erupted. Although they had been united against the Japanese invasion, by the end of World War II civil war raged in China. Nationalists and Communists raced to take over Japanese-held territories, built up their forces, and fought limited engagements while still conducting negotiations; during 1947-1948, after initial Nationalist victories, the strategic balance shifted in favor of the Communists. Four years after Japan's surrender, a profound and popularly based revolution had swept China, and, in October 1949 Mao Zedong proclaimed the People's Republic of China. In 1966, the Communists at the instigation of Mao launched the disastrous "Cultural Revolution," a ten-year assault on "traditional values" and "bourgeois thinking" which ultimately left the country in disarray. After Mao's death in 1976, his rival Deng Xiaopeng assumed power and began social and economic reforms that would see China return to world prominence. China today is one of the world's rising powers, but exactly what course its leaders will chart next remains uncertain.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>虽然经常遭受到政治和社会动乱的冲击，但是中国作为一个政治文化实体的延续性和适应力仍是举世独有的。中国的大多数文化成就都是在极少外来影响的情况下独自完成的。即便在这个国家被“蛮族”统治之时（例如满清和蒙元时期），这些异族也很快就被融入中华文化之中。中国的青铜铸造技术和文字的形成开始于商王朝（据信于公元前16世纪中期至前11世纪中期统治中国北部地区，是国际史学界认可的第一个中国王朝）。商朝被周朝（前1111-前255）历经三代统治者的努力而推翻。虽然周王朝创造了辉煌而活跃的文化，出现了许多世界历史上最伟大的哲学家和艺术家，包括孔子和老子，但后期却陷入诸侯割据纷争不断的局面，即“战国时代”（前403-前221）。[PARAGRAPH:2]诸侯争霸的最终结果是秦王嬴政扫平六国，建立了秦朝（前221-前206）。嬴政首创皇帝尊号，自称“始皇帝”，成为第一位中国皇帝。秦始皇完成了中国本部的首次大一统，但秦朝在他死后不久即土崩瓦解。代之而起的是刘邦建立的汉朝，他于前202年登上帝位。在汉朝统治的四百年间，整个帝国在政治，文化和社会发展等各个方面都发生了显著而深刻的变革，并完成了一系列规模巨大的工程（包括长城的扩建），中华文明的主体民族：汉族也就此形成并传承至今。威力强大的的中国弩也在这一时期发展完善，在汉末还出现了一种设计精巧的连发弩——诸葛弩，弩在中国历朝都是普遍使用的武器。[PARAGRAPH:2]汉帝国在公元二世纪末已不复存在，此后是漫长的分裂和战乱时期，直到618年唐朝的建立。宋朝（960-1279）继唐朝之后兴起，却因蒙古人的入侵而灭亡。成吉思汗于1209年征服西夏，并以此为基地开始对中国的入侵，几年之内即横扫整个中国北部，1214年攻占金朝中都燕京（今北京）。此后数十年间蒙古与宋朝保持南北对峙状态，直到1250年成吉思汗之孙忽必烈再次南下。[PARAGRAPH:2]自1267年起，蒙古人纠集原属金朝的铁甲骑兵和工程部队发动了多路协同进攻，至1279年最终结束了宋朝军队有组织的抵抗，这是有史以来外族入侵者第一次得以控制整个中国。蒙古人对中国的占领持续了一个世纪，逐渐因统治者的无能，宫庭内的争斗和地方军政官员的割据而衰落，最终被一个新的汉族王朝：明朝（1368-1644）所推翻，这个朝代因促进艺术的繁荣而闻名于世。而且明朝在1424年放弃积极外向转取因循守旧政策之前，与印度、阿拉伯地区的海上贸易非常兴旺，有历史学家甚至认为：明朝的航海家先于哥伦布数十年即已到达过美洲。取代明朝的是中国的最后一个王朝：满清（1644-1911）。但满清统治时期却充斥着持续不断的内外战事、西方帝国主义的入侵，以及官僚阶层极度的腐败无能。[PARAGRAPH:2]义和团运动导致的大乱局表明满清朝庭已经彻底失去了广大农民和军队的支持，不久即因辛亥革命（1911-1912）的爆发而被推翻。20世纪上半叶的中国见证了旧秩序的崩溃和新社会形态的逐步形成，先是一个短命的民主共和政府（1912-1920），此后蒋介石逐渐建立起自己的独裁统治。中国国民党和中国共产党人曾在20年代携手推进革命事业，也曾在日本入侵期间团结起来一致对外，但第二次世界大战结束后，双方又分别发展自己的力量并不断因此发生小规模的冲突，同时也在谈判桌上唇枪舌剑，最终导致国共内战的爆发。1947-1948年间，尽管国民党取得了最初的胜利，战局却逐渐向有利于共产党的方向转化。在日本投降之后的第四年，一场广受民众支持，影响深刻久远的革命取得了最后的胜利，1949年10月1日，毛泽东宣布成立中华人民共和国。1966年，共产党人又发动了灾难性的“文化大革命”，这是一场对“传统文化价值”和“资产阶级思想”持续十年的打击，结果却使国民经济面临崩溃的边缘。1976年毛泽东去世后，曾受压制的邓小平重新掌权并实施了一系列的社会与经济改革，中国终于重开民族复兴的进程，再次赢得全世界的瞩目。现在中国的实力正在持续不断地增强，虽然她的未来仍然存在着许多不确定的因素。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_EGYPT_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>Few civilizations have left such an indelible mark on history as that of ancient Egypt. Though the first settlers of the Nile valley are thought to have arrived as early as 7000 BC, it wasn't until the legendary king Menes unified Upper and Lower Egypt that the region began to develop a cohesive sense of culture and identity. This First Dynasty (2925-2775 BC), with its capital at Memphis, was followed by 26 more over the next 2700 years. Writing was the major instrument in the centralization and self-preservation of Egypt. The two basic forms of writing, hieroglyphs and the cursive form known as hieratic (used on papyrus), were invented at much the same time in late pre-dynastic Egypt (about 3000 BC). Writing was used chiefly for administration and until about 2650 BC no continuous texts were recorded; the only literary texts written down before the early Middle Kingdom (1950 BC) seem to have been lists of religious practices and medical treatises. Another strength was the Egyptian religion, which was one of the most enduring of the ancient world, through which Egypt became a highly stratified, highly efficient society. Egypt's economic strength allowed for the support of a priestly class, who were tasked with the spiritual well being of the people yet able to devote their time to the study of religion, astronomy, philosophy, and mathematics. The priesthood also served the functions of a state bureaucracy, carrying out the edicts of the Pharaoh and managing his financial and diplomatic affairs. The great organizational and economic power of Egypt allowed the rulers to accomplish unmatched works of construction. The Great Pyramids of Giza, completed in the Fourth Dynasty (2575-2465 BC), still stand as one of mankind's most impressive feats of engineering and logistics.[PARAGRAPH:2]Prior to 1700 BC, no outsiders had ever held dominion over Egypt. That changed when the Hyksos, a Semitic people, overran Lower Egypt. Thereafter, Egypt's borders were defended by capable Libyan warriors and the elite often rode into battle in War Chariots, which were able to use speed to outflank opponents and break up organized formations of troops. It was under the rule of Hatshepsut, a woman who managed to exercise power despite the prohibition that the pharaoh must be male, that the Hyksos were driven out of the country through the use of such chariots. Egypt's greatest military strength, however, lay in the employment of mercenaries from Macedonia, Greece, Nubia and many other neighboring peoples - Egyptian gold was always their most valuable military asset. However, this was not enough to guarantee the isolation of the richest land in the Mediterranean world. Egypt fell to the Assyrians, and then to the Persians yet even during the plunder of Xerxes' governors, Egyptian culture and religion survived. Alexander the Great liberated the Egyptians from Persian rule in 332 BC and established the city of Alexandria, which was to become the new capital of Hellenic Egypt under the rule of the Macedonian Ptolemaic dynasty (332-30 BC), the last Egyptian kingdom. The kingdom was one of several that emerged in the aftermath of Alexander's death and the struggles of his successors. It was the wealthiest, and for much of the next 300 years, the most powerful politically and militarily.[PARAGRAPH:2]The able Ptolemies ruled in an unbroken line until the death of Cleopatra VII in 30 BC. Her suicide marked the end of Pharaonic rule and the beginning of Egypt's centuries as a Roman and Byzantine province. Although swept by the Islamic tide in 642 AD, Egypt was to remain under foreign occupation - Arabic, Ottoman, French, and British - until after World War I, when she finally gained her independence from a British administration weary of overseas conflict. From 1922 through 1952, Egypt appeared to be one of the world's most successful constitutional monarchies. But it was ripe for revolution; the military coup of July 1952 led by Gamal Nasser, ironically, finally made Egypt an island of stability in a turbulent Middle East.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>很少有文明能够像古埃及文明那样，在历史上留下如此永难消逝的印记。虽然据信早在公元前7000年时尼罗河谷就已有人定居，不过直到传奇名君美尼斯统一上下埃及后，此地才开始发展出真正具有凝聚力的文化与民族特性。古埃及第一王朝（前2925-前2775）建都于孟斐斯的，在此后的2700年间又经历了另外26个朝代。古埃及的文字是这一文明保持强大辐射能力和文化延续能力的重要力量，它包含两种基本字体，一种是正规的圣书体（用于碑刻），另一种是简化的祭司体（用于纸草书），这两种字体都是在埃及前王朝晚期（约前3000年）发明的。文字最初只是用于行政事务，但直到约公元前2650年均无连续的文字材料流传后世。在中王国早期（前1950年）之前保存下来的文献只是一些宗教仪轨和药物方剂。古埃及的宗教则是另一股重要力量，这是上古时代延续最久远的宗教信仰，它使得古埃及社会等级分明，富有效率。古埃及经济的繁荣使得祭司阶级得以形成，祭司专门负责引导人们的精神生活，并从事宗教信仰、天文学、哲学与数学方面的研究工作。祭司还作为政府官员参与国家管理，替法老颁布敕令，处理财政与外交事务。古埃及王国组织严密与经济繁荣，使得统治者能够发起空前规模的建设工程。建成于第四王朝时期（前2575-前2465）的吉萨大金字塔至今仍是人类历史上工程学与后勤学的最伟大奇迹之一。[PARAGRAPH:2]在公元前1700年属闪米特部族的希克索斯人横扫下埃及之前，从来没有外族人入侵埃及的记载。在此之后，埃及的边界便由骁勇的利比亚战士负责守御，这些精锐部队通常乘坐轻便快速的埃及战车作战，能够凭借其速度包抄敌后，撕开对方的严密阵形。希克索斯人最终被赶出埃及是在哈特谢普苏特执政时期，能够在男性占据统治地位的古埃及成为大权独揽的法老显示了她的非凡才能。不过古埃及强大的军事力量主要还是依靠来自于马其顿、希腊、努比亚以及其它邻近民族的雇佣兵——埃及的黄金一直是他们最有价值的军事资产。尽管如此，埃及还是难以阻隔外人对这块整个地中海世界最富庶土地的垂涎。埃及先是被亚述人攻陷，后来又被波斯人占据，虽然波斯王薛西斯派遣的总督在当地大肆搜刮破坏，古埃及的文化和宗教还是顽强地继续生存。前332年，亚历山大大帝从波斯人手中解放了埃及，并建立亚历山大城，后来这座城市成为马其顿的托勒密王朝（前332-前30）统治下的希腊化埃及的新首都，这也是最后一个古埃及王朝。托勒密王朝是在亚历山大去世后由其部将分别建立的诸王国之一，也是其中最富庶的一个，在此后的三百年间保持着政治和军事上的强盛。[PARAGRAPH:2]托勒密朝王位的传承最终在公元前30年克利奥巴特拉七世死后断绝，她的自杀宣告了埃及法老统治时代的结束和作为罗马与拜占庭帝国行省时代的开始。642年来临的伊斯兰浪潮并没有改变埃及受外族奴役的地位——此后她又相继被阿拉伯人、奥斯曼人、法国人和英国人所统治——直到第一次世界大战之后，由于力量大受削弱的英国疲于处理各海外领地的乱局，埃及终于赢得独立。1922-1952年间的埃及曾是世界上最成功的君主立宪国家之一。但一场革命也在暗中酝酿，1952年7月加麦尔·纳赛尔通过军事政变上台，但他后来却使得埃及成为动乱不断的中东地区一个稳定的岛屿。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ENGLAND_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>In the classical age Britain lay on the periphery of the civilized world; Julius Caesar's visitations to the island in 55/54 BC were viewed as a daring voyage into the unknown. But in 43 AD the island was invaded by Roman soldiers under the Emperor Claudius, and it was to spend the next four centuries as a Roman province. The Romans built cities, roads, and great bathhouses, the ruins of which can still be seen today. With the collapse of Roman power under Germanic onslaught, tribal migrations into Britain began about the middle of the 5th century. The first arrivals were invited by a British chieftain to defend his kingdom against the Picts and Scots. These first mercenaries were from three tribes - the Angles, Saxons, and Jutes - which were located on the coastlands of northwestern Germany. Eventually, these peoples would themselves topple the existing order, and Britain would spend many centuries divided between various warring kingdoms such as Mercia, East Anglia, and others. The first political entity that could rightly be called "England" formed out of the efforts of the kingdom of Wessex to unite the island against the invasion of Danes and Vikings in the 9th century. But the English domination was fleeting; the subsequent Norman Conquest (1066) resulted in the subordination of England to a Frankish aristocracy, and the introduction of feudalism to the Isles.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Norman invasion reoriented England from the Scandinavian world to the Mediterranean one, and reintroduced many elements of Latin culture that had been lost in the Germanic invasions. The English Normans would eventually give rise to a purely British line of kings, the Plantagenets. Three centuries later, the Wars of the Roses was the final struggle between the Yorkist and Lancastrian descendants of the Plantagenets for control of the throne. When Henry Tudor, earl of Richmond, seized the crown in 1485, leaving the Yorkist Richard III dead upon the field of battle, few Englishmen would have predicted that 118 years of Tudor rule had begun. Elizabeth I (1558-1603) proved to be the most able Tudor monarch. No observer in 1558, any more than in 1485, would have predicted that despite the social discord, political floundering, and international humiliation of the past decades, the kingdom again stood on the threshold of an extraordinary age. Her reign ushered in two centuries of British exploration, colonization, and artistic and intellectual advances. When Elizabeth, the "Virgin Queen," died childless, Parliament offered the crown to the closest blood kin, James VI of Scotland, who became James I of England (1603-1625) and founded the Stuart dynasty. The Stuarts kings did not possess the best luck; Charles I was defeated by the forces of Parliament in the English Civil War and executed, and a scant four decades later his descendent James II was also overthrown in the "Glorious Revolution" of 1688. But despite all this turbulence, by 1700 England had merged with Scotland to become "Britain" and established an identity that would be both Protestant and Parliamentry.[PARAGRAPH:2]The British Empire was to be one based on trade and control of the seas. Using the soldiers commonly denoted "Redcoats", every major war Britain engaged in during the 18th and 19th centuries increased its colonial power. The Seven Years' War was particularly notable in this respect, and so were the Napoleonic Wars. By 1820 the total population of the British Empire was 200 million, 26%% of the world's total population. However acquired, all these acquisitions added to the crown's and the country's power and reputation. For the privileged and the rich, the Victorian era was pre-eminently one of confidence and arrogance, under the able guidance of Britain's two longtime Prime Ministers, Gladstone and Disraeli. Stretching from Australia and New Zealand through India, much of Africa, and Canada, the British Empire under Victoria was truly one on which the "sun never set."[PARAGRAPH:2]But the "long summer of peace" came to an end in the bloodbath of Flanders. Although Britain suffered far less physical damage than France and underwent no political revolution, World War I may have affected it more fundamentally than any other European power. The war was a catalyst for social and economic change. The mainstays of the early Industrial Revolution, such as coal mining, textile production, and shipbuilding, upon which British prosperity had been built, were now impoverished or redundant. Britain was slow to develop many of the newer manufacturing industries, such as those involving chemicals, electronics, and automobiles. British foreign policy for much of the postwar period aimed at rehabilitating Germany, while domestic policy focused on institutionalizing socialism to counter public concerns. In general, these movements were opposed by France and resulted in a rupture between Britain and its wartime ally, forcing France into a position of isolation that would have prodigious consequences for Europe with the rise of Hitler in the 1930s. World War II was a British victory, but left the nation bankrupt and unable to prevent the onset of decolonization in the 1950s and 1960s. Although Britons maintained a high standard of living, the British economy continued to perform poorly throughout the 1960s and 1970s. As a reaction, Margaret Thatcher (1979-1990) set out to end socialism in Britain. Her most dramatic acts consisted of a continuing series of statutes to denationalize nearly every industry that Labour had brought into public ownership during the previous 40 years. Promising that "we shall govern as New Labour," the Blair government installed in general elections in 1997 accepted some of Thatcher's foreign policies but also carried out the economic reforms it promised in its manifesto. Faced now with terrorist attacks that threaten the lives of ordinary civilians, Britain has pledged to work together with the United States and other nations to defend this attack on civilization.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>罗马时代的不列颠尚处于文明世界的边缘，朱利乌斯·恺撒在公元前55至54年登上不列颠岛的经历也被认为是一次通往未知世界的冒险之行。罗马皇帝克劳迪乌斯在公元43年征服了此地，在之后的四个世纪中，英格兰一直是罗马帝国的行省。罗马在这里建造了城市、道路、大型浴室，其遗迹至今可见。当罗马帝国在日耳曼人的冲击下分崩离析后，大大小小的部落从5世纪中期开始移居此地。最初的一批大陆移民是应一位不列颠酋长的邀请，前来帮助他抵御皮克特人和苏格兰人侵扰的。这些雇佣兵来自于如下三个部族——盎格鲁人、撒克逊人、朱特人、他们的原住地都位于今天的德国西北海滨。后来这些外来者反客为主，在不列颠岛上建立了无数的小王国，例如麦西亚、东盎格利亚等。为抵御丹麦人和维京人的入侵，公元9世纪时不列颠岛诸国在西撒克斯王国的主导下开始走向统一，首次形成一个真正可以称之为“英格兰”的政治实体。但这个英格兰人政权只维持了很短的时间，随后发生的诺曼征服（1066）使英格兰沦为法兰克贵族的领地，而封建制也就此被引入英伦三岛。[PARAGRAPH:2]诺曼征服使得英格兰从斯堪的纳维亚世界转向地中海世界，它使许多在日耳曼人入侵时丧失的拉丁文化因之复兴。最终英国诺曼王朝被一个完全本土化的王朝——金雀花朝（或称安茹朝）所取代。三个世纪之后的玫瑰战争中，为争夺王位而斗得你死我活的约克家族和兰开斯特家族其实都是源于当初的金雀花朝。1485年，约克朝的理查三世战死于博斯沃斯原野，里士满伯爵亨利·都铎乘机登上王位，当时的人们并没有料想到他所开创的都铎朝能够延续118年之久。伊丽莎白一世（1558-1603在位）是都铎朝诸王中最著名的一位英明君主。没有人能在经历了漫长社会动荡，政治混乱和对外挫败的1558年或1485年就预计到：这个王国即将进入一个空前伟大辉煌时代。在她的治下，英国开始了长达两个世纪的探险、殖民、艺术与科学进程。“童贞女王”伊丽莎白死后无嗣，国会决定将王位传给与她血缘关系最近的苏格兰国王詹姆士六世（1603-1625在位），后者便成为英格兰国王詹姆斯一世，并建立了斯图亚特王朝。斯图亚特王朝诸王运气不佳：查理一世在内战被国会党人击败并被处决，不到40年后，他的后裔詹姆斯又被“光荣革命”推翻。尽管局势是如此动荡，但英格兰仍于1700年同苏格兰合并为统一的“大不列颠”联合王国，并以新教精神和议会制度作为立国之本。[PARAGRAPH:2]发展远洋贸易和掌握制海权是大英帝国的基本国策。在18，19世纪，身着红色制服的皇家来复枪兵部队所参加的每场主要战争都加强了英国作为殖民强权的实力。其中起到最关键作用的则是七年战争和拿破仑战争。到1820年，大英帝国统治下的人口已达2亿，占世界总人口的26%。不论扩张所采取的手段如何，所有这一切成就对于富裕的特权阶层来说，由两位首相：格雷斯顿与狄士累利相继主政的维多利亚女王时代是英国自信与自傲的巅峰。帝国的领土包括澳大利亚，新西兰，印度，非洲大部分，以及加拿大等，维多利亚统治下的英国已是名副其实的“日不落帝国”。[PARAGRAPH:2]但是这一段“和平的长夏”随着在佛兰德斯地区的大血战而终结，虽然英国在战争中遭受的损失小于法国，而且也并未因此而引发政治革命，但实际上，第一次世界大战对英国的影响比对其它欧洲强国更深刻。这场战争是社会和经济变革的催化剂。曾经支撑起工业革命，为英国带来繁荣的一切，例如煤矿、纺织业与造船业，均已耗尽潜力或不合时宜。英国在化学、电子、汽车等新兴工业方面则发展缓慢。英国在战后的外交政策专注于改造德国以平衡大陆势力对比，国内政策方面则努力兑现福利社会以迎合民众的迫切要求。所有这些行动令法国十分反感，导致英国与当年的盟友关系不断恶化，并使法国陷于孤立，这也是希特勒在20世纪30年代得以迅速崛起的重要原因。英国赢得了第二次世界大战，却让国家破产，并丧失了对20世纪50，60年代非殖民化浪潮的抵御能力。尽管英国人的生活水平仍然很高，但英国经济却在六七十年代表现拙劣。为了挽救这一局面，在玛格丽特·撒切尔（1979-1990任首相）掌权后努力消除社会党人的影响。她通过一系列法令，将过去40年间工党收归国有的产业几乎全部私有化。赢得1997年大选上台的布莱尔政府许诺“我们将实施新工党政策”，他沿用了撒切尔的部份外交政策，同时推行其所承诺的经济改革。尽管现在英国的普通民众正面临着恐怖袭击的不断威胁，但英国仍然坚定地与美国等盟友站在一起，共同对抗文明世界的敌人。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_FRANCE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>Modern France has its roots in ancient Gaul. In the 2nd century BC Rome intervened on the side of Massilia (Marseilles), a Greek colony founded in 600 BC, in its struggle against the barbarian tribes of the hinterland. The result was the formation, in 121 BC, of the Roman Provincia in what is now southern France; between 58 to 50 BC Julius Caesar seized the remainder. For more than four centuries Gaul enjoyed the benefits of Roman rule, and many ruins of aqueducts and bathhouses still dot the French landscape. After 395 AD the internal problems of the Empire encouraged barbarian penetration of Gaul. By 418, the Franks and Burgundians were established west of the Rhine, and the Visigoths had settled in Aquitaine. The period of the Merovingian and Carolingian Frankish dynasties (476-887) frames the Early Middle Ages.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following his ascension, the first Merovingian king, Clovis (481-511), consolidated the position of the Franks in northern Gaul. Clovis came to believe that his victories were due to the Christian God. Clovis' subsequent conversion assured the Frankish rulers of the support not only of the Catholic Church but of the majority of their own subjects. The Frankish kingdom reached its largest extent under Charlemagne (768-814), who united modern-day France, Italy, and Germany under his rule. After Charlemagne's death, his grandsons divided the kingdom into the three parts that have largely survived to the present. France was a divided kingdom for much of the medieval period, but power gradually began to accumulate in the hands of the rulers of the Ile de France region centered around Paris. By the rise of the house of Valois in 1328, France was the most powerful kingdom in Europe. Its ruler could muster larger armies than rivals; he could tap enormous fiscal resources; and the king's courts maintained royal supremacy. The history of France in the Late Middle Ages is dominated by efforts of its kings to maintain their suzerainty, efforts that, despite French advantages, were long frustrated.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Hundred Years War was an intermittent struggle between England and France in the 14th-15th centuries over a series of dynastic disputes, including the legitimate succession to the French crown. The war's turning point was reached in 1429, when an English army was forced to raise its siege of Orleans by a relief force organized by Joan of Arc. By 1453, England retained only Calais, which it finally relinquished in 1558. The French kings of the 16th century spent much of their time fighting the Hapsburg monarchs for control of Italy, while religious conflict between Catholics and Protestants led to a series of civil wars between 1562 and 1598.[PARAGRAPH:2]The ascension of the Bourbon line of kings beginning in 1589 brought renewed stability to France, and the country soared to some of its greatest heights during the long rule of Louis XIV (1643-1715). Under Louis, France became the artistic and intellectual capital of Europe. From his magnificent palace of Versailles, Louis was truly the "Sun King", the absolute master of all he surveyed. The French military was the most powerful in Europe at this time, known for the elite Musketeer units that served as the king's personal guard. France was so strong at this time that the other European nations kept banding together to stop France from conquering them - a pattern that would be repeated in the French Revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2]These intellectual developments, although significant by themselves, gave rise to a still more momentous change: the French Enlightenment. This movement was a cultural transformation based on rationalism, empiricism, and an amorphous concept of freedom found in the influential writings of figures like Voltaire (1694-1778) and Rousseau (1712-78). Compounding the situation was the bankruptcy of the French crown, which forced the king to call upon representatives of the people for additional taxes. Hence, what began in 1787 as a conflict between royal authority and aristocrats became a triangular struggle, with "the masses" opposing both absolutism and privilege. By any standard, the fall of the Bastille to the Parisian crowd in 1789 was a monumental event, a seemingly miraculous triumph of the people. But the French Revolution soon degenerated into a reign of terror and chaos. After a decade of violence and uncertainty, Napoleon terminated the bloodshed by overthrowing the French government in 1800, at the price of suppressing freedom altogether. In utter contrast to the Revolution, militarism became the defining quality of the Napoleonic regime. The French armies under Napoleon won victory after victory against all of the other great European powers, but decades of war led to the exhaustion of the nation and eventual defeat in 1815.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, the revolutionary fervor of the French citizenry was undiminished by the Napoleonic experience, and led to further revolutions in 1830 and 1848. The latter revolution lead to the short-lived Second Republic (1848-1852), which was overthrown by Napoleon's nephew "Napoleon III" who instituted the Second Empire (1852-1870). Following defeat in the Franco-Prussia War, the Third Republic (1870-1940) was formed, which survived the First World War but collapsed in the face of the German invasion in 1940. After the war, the period of the short-lived Fourth Republic (1947-59) was succeeded by the Fifth Republic (the current one), adopted in September 1958 by popular referendum. Although shorn of its past colonial holdings and aura of military invulnerability, France today remains a major economic power and influential member of the European Union.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>现代的法国源自远古的高卢。在公元前2世纪罗马人开始到达马西利亚（马赛）附近，此城由希腊殖民者于公元前600年建立，此后一直在内陆蛮族部落的包围下挣扎求生，最终于前121年成为罗马的一个行省。前58至前50年，恺撒征服了该地残余的蛮族。在此后的四百年内，高卢地区从罗马人的统治中受益非浅，许多罗马时代的水渠和澡堂至今仍为法国的风景增色。从395年起，外来蛮族乘着帝国的内乱开始向（阿尔卑斯）山南和山北高卢地区渗透。到418年时，法兰克人与勃艮第人已在莱茵河西岸定居，西哥特人则占据着阿基坦。在中世纪早期，法兰克人建立的墨洛温王朝和加洛林王朝（476-887）相继统治此地。[PARAGRAPH:2]墨洛温朝的首任国王克洛维斯（481-511在位）继承先祖的事业，巩固了法兰克人在北高卢的统治地位。克洛维斯相信这些胜利都是基督教的神所赐予的。于是他便皈依了基督教，他的统治了不仅得到了天主教会的支持，也得到了大多数臣民的拥戴。法兰克王国的疆域在查理曼大帝统治时期达到了顶点，囊括了今法国、意大利和德国的大部分地区。当查理曼大帝去世后，他的孙子们将帝国分为三部分。在中世纪，法国实际上处于分裂状态，但居住于以巴黎为中心的“法兰西岛”的国王们努力地使权力集中于王室手。上到1328年瓦卢瓦王朝兴起之时，法兰西已是全欧洲最强大的王国。与对手们相比，法兰西君主可以召集更多的军队，也能够征用更多的财富，法王的宫廷也拥有更为集中的君权。虽然这个王国拥有众多的优势，中世纪晚期的法兰西历史却始终贯穿着国王为维护君权而进行的艰苦努力，以及这些努力所遭遇到的重重困难。[PARAGRAPH:2]百年战争是14至15世纪英格兰与法兰西之间因一系列王室纠纷（包括法兰西国王的继承权之争）所导致的一场长期军事冲突。战争形势在1429年时发生逆转，在那一年，围困奥尔良城的英军被贞德率领的援军所击退。她坚信只有在兰斯举行即位典礼，拥立神所选择的合法国王，才能领导法国迈向更大的胜利。查理三世乃于1429年7月在兰斯加冕为王。到1453年战争结束时，英国在大陆仅能控制加莱一地（后也于1558年重归法国所有）。16世纪的法国国王们则把精力花费在同哈布斯堡国王们争夺意大利的控制权上，但在1562至1598年间，由于新教与天主教间的冲突，法国国内爆发了长时的内战。[PARAGRAPH:2]当1589年波旁家族继承王位后，法国国内局势趋于稳定，法国的荣耀也在路易十四统治期间达到了顶峰。在他治下，法国成为欧洲艺术和文化的中心。路易居住于富丽堂皇的凡尔塞宫，号称“太阳王”，掌控制着整个国家的一切。法兰西军队在当时的欧洲是最为强大的武力，作为国王卫队的精锐法国火枪手则是军队的核心。这个法国是如此的强大，以致于欧洲各国不得不联合起来抵抗它的征服行动——这也是法国大革命爆发的原因之一。[PARAGRAPH:2]经济方面的成就本身即已令人瞩目，同时还推动了一项影响更为深远的历史进程：法国启蒙运动，这是一场以理性主义，经验主义及最早在伏尔泰（1694-1778）和卢梭（1712-1778）的著作中提出的自由思想为基础的，深刻的文化变革。这些因素综合起来，最终让法国君主制破产，其导火索便是法王召集人民代表以增加赋税。在此背景之下，1787年发生于王室和贵族之间的争执最终演变成为一场复杂的三角冲突，在这场冲突中，专制主义和特权主义同时成为“人民大众”的敌人。无论根据何种标准，巴黎市民攻占巴士底狱都是一项永载史册的事件，是民众所取得的奇迹般的胜利。可是这场革命很快陷于恐怖和动乱。经过了十年之久的杀戮和混乱后，流血的政治最终在拿破仑手中结束，但他同时也完全压制了自由。与革命时期形成鲜明的对比的是拿破仑统治时期的彻底军国主义。拿破仑皇帝指挥下的法国军队在同其它欧洲强权的对抗中战无不胜，但长时间的战争耗尽了法国的国力，拿破仑帝国也在1815年崩溃。[PARAGRAPH:2]然而法国市民阶层对革命的狂热并未因拿破仑的统治消退，最终又导致了1830年和1848年的两次革命，革命之后又相继建立了第二共和国和第二帝国（1852-1870），由拿破仑·波拿巴的侄子“拿破仑三世”建立）。当第二帝国在普法战争中失败后，第三共和国成立了，这个政权经历了第一次世界大战的炮火，最终因1940年德国的入侵而崩溃。其后是短命的第四共和国（1947-1959）以及1958年9月通过全民公投成立的第五共和国。尽管法国广大的殖民地和常胜的军队已经不复存在，但在今天，它仍是一个经济强国，在欧盟内部也极具影响力。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GERMANY_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>Julius Caesar's Gallic Wars brought the Germanic tribes into the spotlight of history. Although Roman efforts to establish hegemony across the Rhine continued for decades, the frontier eventually stabilized along the Rhine and Danube rivers. At that time, Germanic culture extended from Scandinavia as far south as the Carpathians. Although it was heavily fortified, the frontier was never a barrier to trade or culture. Germanic fear of the Huns eventually drove many of the tribes inside the borders of the Roman Empire in the 4th and 5th centuries, where the weakened Romans were unable to contain them. The Eastern Roman Empire survived the crisis and lasted for another thousand years, but the Germanic peoples carved out their own independent kingdoms in the West.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of the various Germanics tribes that had invaded the Roman Empire, the Franks proved to be the most successful. The Merovingian kings and their Carolingian successors eventually brought much of what would later constitute Germany under Frankish control, but the ceaseless blows from Danes, Saracens (Muslims), and Magyars in the later 9th and 10th centuries weakened the kingdom's cohesion. Because the Carolingians themselves were unable to provide effective defense for the empire, there arose in nearly all the German lands powerful lines of margraves, counts, and hereditary rulers; their intrigues and wars against each other were interrupted only briefly by the rise of strong emperors such as Frederick Barbarossa (1155-1190). The subsequent history of Germany is, despite the role of the central rule of the Holy Roman Empire, one of the rise and fall of feuding principalities. It would be a thousand years before Germany was again unified under a single ruler.[PARAGRAPH:2]Out of the hundreds of states that made up Germany, it was the kingdom of Prussia that would eventually succeed in bringing them together. Beginning as a small duchy on the shores of the Baltic Sea, the rulers of Prussia gradually accumulated more and more territory through a combination of warfare and marriage agreements. King Frederick William I (1713-40) trained the Prussian army to be one of the finest in Europe, and his son Frederick II (1740-86) - also known as Frederick the Great - used it to win a series of military victories against the larger kingdoms of Austria and Russia. Frederick was also known as a patron of the arts, his court attracting intellectuals such as Voltaire from across Europe. Ruling as an enlightened despot, Frederick was equally skilled at defeating Russian invasions and playing the flute.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following its humiliation and defeat in the wars of the French Revolution and Napoleon, Prussia managed to bounce back and reorganize itself along more modern lines. Troubled by the popular uprisings that had occurred across Germany during the 1848 revolutions, William I of Prussia (1861-1888) considered abdicating in favor of his son, who was believed to have political views close to those of the liberal opposition. He was persuaded, however, to consider forming a new government led by Otto von Bismarck, the Prussian ambassador to Paris. In September 1862, Europe was startled by the news that a statesman with a reputation for conservatism, nationalism, and [realpolitik] had become the prime minister of Prussia. Bismarck proved to be a master strategist, and the new German Empire was proclaimed in January 1871, in the aftermath of three short and decisive wars against Denmark, Austria, and France. In the span of a decade, Bismarck had unified Germany - or, as some would say, Prussia had conquered it.[PARAGRAPH:2]The same nationalism that had brought unity would also bring disaster. Ignoring the careful diplomacy that had isolated Prussia's opponent in each of Bismarck's wars, Germany rushed into World War I against a coalition of Britain, France, and Russia. Despite initial successes, the war eventually turned into a stalemate that Germany could not win, especially once the United Stated entered the war on the Entente side in 1917. Already staggering under a vengeful peace imposed by the Western Allies following World War I, the worldwide economic collapse that began in 1929 proved the catalyst for political extremism. Although bitterly opposed to each other, the Nazis and Communists during the next decade succeeded in mobilizing the political and economic resentments generated by defeat and depression. When Hitler finally became chancellor in January 1933, it was not on the crest of a wave of popular support but as the result of ruthless political intrigue. [PARAGRAPH:2]World War II is appropriately called "Hitler's War." Spearheaded by Panzer formations using revolutionary new tactics, Hitler came close to realizing his aim of establishing German hegemony in Europe. But the turning point of the war came with his decision to send his Panzers into Soviet Russia. Though at the end of 1942 an ultimate German victory still seemed possible, by spring 1945 the Third Reich was prostrate. As a legacy of surrender and the ensuing Cold War, a truncated Germany was divided into two zones of military occupation. While under Soviet rule East Germany suffered and stagnated, West Germany's recovery from total economic and political prostration at the end of World War II was of such dramatic proportions as to become a modern legend. The swift and unexpected downfall of the Soviet order in Europe led to a unification treaty, ratified by the West German Bundestag and the East German People's Chamber in September 1990. After 45 years of division, Germany was once again a united nation. Today Germany is one of the world's economic powerhouses, and a leading force in the European Union.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>朱利乌斯·恺撒发动的高卢战争第一次使日尔曼各部族的名字出现在历史舞台上。虽然罗马人为控制莱茵河以东地区而进行了数十年的努力，但最终帝国的边界还是稳定在了莱茵河与多瑙河一线。当时日尔曼文化的范围从斯堪的纳维亚向南一直延伸到喀尔巴阡山脉。虽然有重兵把守，帝国的北方边界从来都不是贸易与文化交流的障碍。公元4到5世纪，日尔曼各部对于匈奴人的恐惧驱使许多部落进入罗马帝国的疆域，而衰落了的罗马帝国无法控制住他们。东罗马帝国渡过了危机并又延续了一千年，而日尔曼人在西罗马帝国的版图上建立起了他们自己的独立王国。[PARAGRAPH:2]在所有入侵罗马帝国的日尔曼部落当中，法兰克人是最成功的。墨洛温王朝及其后的加洛林王朝历任国王经过长期努力，最终将今日德国的大部分地区置于法兰克人的统治之下，但是由于在9世纪晚期和整个10世纪不断遭受丹麦人，撒拉森人和马扎尔人的入侵，王国的凝聚力逐渐削弱。由于加洛林王朝自身不能有效地保卫其国土，在地方上崛起了许多侯爵、伯爵和其他世袭统治者，他们之间的明争暗斗只是由于个别强力选侯——比如人称“巴巴罗萨”的腓特烈一世（1155-1190在位）——的崛起才偶受遏止。尽管有神圣罗马帝国（第一帝国）名义上的中央集权统治，此后德意志历史的主导者却仍是相互之间纷争不断，此消彼长的封建诸侯。直到千年之后，才再次在统一在一个领袖的意志之下。[PARAGRAPH:2]近代以前的德意志实际上只是由上百个独立诸侯构成的地理名词，最终成功地将他们团结到一起的是普鲁士王国。从巴伦支海滨的一个小公爵领开始发迹，普鲁士的历任统治者们通过战争和联姻手段的结合逐步扩大了其版图。腓特烈·威廉一世（1713-1740在位）将普鲁士军队训练成了欧洲第一流的军队。他的儿子腓特烈二世（1740-1786在位，即著名的腓特烈大帝）凭借这支部队赢得了对欧洲列强奥地利和俄罗斯的一系列军事胜利。腓特烈还以艺术的资助人而闻名，他的宫廷吸引了全欧洲的学者，例如伏尔泰。作为一位开明君主的典范，腓特烈演奏长笛的技巧堪与他击败俄军入侵的指挥艺术相比。[PARAGRAPH:2]在经历了法国大革命和拿破仑战争中的失败和羞辱之后，普鲁士决心卷土重来并将自己改革成更现代化的国家。受到横扫全欧的1848年大革命的打击，普鲁士国王威廉一世（1861-1888在位），决定让位给他的儿子。虽然新继位的威廉二世本人的政治观点倾向于自由主义者，但最终他还是同意让时任普鲁士驻法国大使的奥托·冯·俾斯麦出面组建新政府。1862年9月，欧洲被一条新闻震惊：一个以保守主义，民族主义和实力政治而闻名的政治家成为普鲁士的首相。俾斯麦被证明是一位战略大师，在连续赢得三场对丹麦，奥地利和法国的短暂而决定性的战争之后，新的德意志帝国（第二帝国）于1871年1月宣布成立。在经过了十年的努力之后，俾斯麦使德国最终获得统一，或者说，普鲁士征服了整个德意志。[PARAGRAPH:2]给德意志带来统一的民族主义同样也给它带来了灾难。无视俾斯麦在战争中擅长的孤立普鲁士的对手的谨慎外交政策，德国一头闯进第一次世界大战，面对英、法、俄的同盟。尽管起初进展顺利，战争最终陷入德国无望获胜的僵局，特别是1917年美国加入协约国一方之后，失败无可避免。本已在一次大战后被西方联盟强加的报复性条约下艰难度日，1929年的世界性经济崩溃更成了德国政治转向极端主义的催化剂。在随后的十年里，纳粹思想成功地使遭受战争失败和经济衰退的德国人的苦难和怨恨爆发。希特勒最终在1933年1月成为德国的总理，这并非出于民众的一致拥戴，而是拜无情的政治阴谋所赐。[PARAGRAPH:2]第二次世界大战在某种程度上可以被称做“希特勒的战争”。以采用革命性新战术的德国装甲兵部队作为先锋，希特勒几乎实现了他在欧洲建立德国霸权的目标。但当他决定派遣他的装甲兵部队进攻苏维埃俄国之后，战争形势开始逆转。尽管在1942年底时德国看起来仍有可能获得最终胜利，但到1945年春天，“第三帝国”最终崩溃。作为战败者和冷战的后果，已遭压缩的德国又被分为两块军事占领区。战后的东德在苏联统治之下遭受痛苦和萧条时，西德却从经济和政治窘境中迅速全面地得到恢复，这样富于戏剧性的对比已经成为一个现代传奇。苏联意外而迅速的解体导致东欧的巨变，西德联邦议院和东德人民议会乃于1990年9月签订合并条约。历经45年分裂之后，德国再次成为一个统一的国家。今日德国是世界经济的主导者之一，也是欧盟的主导国之一。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_GREECE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>The period following the catastrophic collapse of the Mycenaean civilization in Greece (about 1200 BC) was marked by a series of migrations by barbarian peoples from the north, leading to the formation of a number of city-states - prominent among these, Sparta and Athens - and a phase of Greek colonization along the shores of the Mediterranean. For several centuries, Greek history was a provincial tale of neighbors squabbling over scarce resources. But it was also the dawn of philosophy and science, the era when the bard Homer composed his great epic poems the Iliad and the Odyssey. There seems to be no good reason why the Hellenes, clustered in isolated city-states in a relatively poor and backward land, should have struck out into intellectual regions that were only dimly perceived, if at all, by the splendid civilizations of the Yangtze, the Tigris and Euphrates, and the Nile valleys - but they did.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Persian Wars (492-449 BC) were sparked by a revolt of Greek colonies in Asia Minor and brought the Greeks onto the stage of world history. Athens and Eretria sent a small fleet in support of the revolt, which the Persian emperors took as a pretext for launching two invasions of the Greek mainland. In 490 BC a Persian army under Darius I (522-486 BC) landed unopposed on the plain of Marathon; following an appeal to the Spartans, the Athenian-led Greeks won a decisive victory. A larger second invasion ten years later, blunted by the valiant stand by the Spartans and Thespians at Thermopylae (481 BC), ended with the crushing defeat of the Persian fleet at Salamis. Sporadic fighting between Greek alliances and Persia continued for another 30 years, before the Peace of Callas (449 BC) finally ended the hostilities. The surprising Greek triumph ensured the survival of Greek culture and political structures.[PARAGRAPH:2]Growing tensions among the victors led to the Peloponnesian Wars (431-404 BC), fought between Athens and Sparta. The Athenian League was, in fact, an empire that included most of the island and coastal states around the shores of the Aegean Sea, while Sparta was leader of an alliance of independent cities that included most of the major land powers of the peninsula. The end finally came in 404 BC when, starved by an impenetrable blockade, Athens capitulated. Athens' devastation and decline was perhaps the worst casualty in a war that crippled Greek unity. [PARAGRAPH:2]By this time, a new power was growing in the north of Greece. In 353 BC, Philip I was in undisputed control of a much-enlarged Macedonia. Phalanx tactics were known from ancient Sumer and Egypt, but Philip perfected the tactical use of these spear-wielding forces in dense, massive blocks of eight or even sixteen ranks, sacrificing flexibility and mobility in order to achieve maximum protection and power. Unless Alexander (336-323 BC) was himself responsible for his father's assassination in 336 BC, he could not have foreseen the moment of his succession - but he was certainly well prepared. Educated by Aristotle and left in charge of Macedonia during Philip's attack on Byzantium, Alexander had defeated the barbarians people called the Maedi in 340 BC; two years later he had commanded the left wing at the battle of Chaeronea, in which Philip defeated the allied Greek states and became master of all Greece. Using his father's soliders to good effect, Alexander invaded the Persian Empire and began one of the greatest campaigns in history. Ten years and thousands of miles later, Alexander had destroyed the Persian Empire and carved out a kingdom stretching from Macedonia to the borders of India. By the time of his death at the age of 33, Alexander had initiated a new age by spreading Hellenism in a vast colonizing wave throughout the Middle East and created, at least economically and culturally (if not politically), a single civilization stretching from Gibraltar to the Punjab, open to trade and intellectual intercourse.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, the Greek empire could hardly survive Alexander's death. During a 40-year (323-280 BC) interregnum, the provinces became independent kingdoms, with various of Alexander's generals rising to rule through bloodshed and assassination, yet they were unable to ally against the coming of a new military power. By 350 BC, Rome was encroaching on the westernmost Greek settlements, beginning a 200-year conquest of the Hellenic world that Alexander had created. With the defeat of Cleopatra and Marc Anthony, Octavian's forces occupied Egypt and the last kingdom of Alexander's successors fell to Rome. For two millennia, Greece was part of the Roman, then Byzantine, and finally the Ottoman empires. Following an uprising supported by Britain, Russia, and France, Greece's existence as an independent nation gained formal recognition in 1832. Greece fought on the Allied side in both world wars, and was occupied by the Germans during World War II. A civil war followed the conflict, in which pro-Western forces defeated their pro-communist opponents. Greece today is a modern democracy and part of the European Union, and tens of thousands of tourists visit the country every year to see its rugged beauty and great monuments from the past.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>在希腊的迈锡尼文明毁灭性的大崩解后的一段时期中（约公元前1200年），北方的蛮族不断向南迁移并定居下来，他们建立了一系列的城邦——其中最大的两个城邦是斯巴达和雅典——这也是希腊人向地中海沿海地区殖民的时期。此后两个世纪的希腊历史充斥着各城邦之间为占有稀缺资源而不断进行的争斗。但其间也缓慢孕育着哲学和科学的萌芽。似乎没什么令人信服的理由可以使人相信，居住在这样一块相对贫瘠而且不断退化土地上，被分裂成一系列城邦的希腊人也能创造出可以与长江流域，底格里斯河-幼发拉底河流域和尼罗河流域的伟大文明相比的灿烂文明，但是，他们做到了。[PARAGRAPH:2]希波战争（前492-前449）是因为小亚细亚的希腊殖民地暴动而引发的，这个事件使得希腊人登上了世界历史的舞台。雅典与埃瑞特里亚派遣了一小支舰队支持叛军，波斯的皇帝就以此为借口对希腊本土发动了两次的侵略战争。前490年，大流士一世（前522-前486在位）麾下的一支波斯军队在没有受到任何抵抗的情况下登上了马拉松平原，雅典人赶紧向斯巴达求援，最后以雅典为首的军队赢得了决定性的胜利。十年之后第二次战争爆发，勇猛的斯巴达人和塞斯皮亚人在温泉关奋力抵抗（前481年），最终以波斯舰队在萨拉米斯湾大败而告终。希腊联邦与波斯的小规模战争又断断续续地持续了30年之久，直到卡拉斯和约（前449年）签订后才结束了这场冲突。希腊人奇迹般的胜利确保了希腊文化和政治体制的延续。[PARAGRAPH:2]此后胜利者内部的紧张关系又导致了伯罗奔尼撒战争的爆发（前431-前404），敌对双方分别是雅典和斯巴达。以雅典为首的联盟囊括了爱琴海中大部分的岛屿和沿岸城邦，而斯巴达则是半岛上大部分陆地城邦联盟的领袖。战争最后于前404年结束，雅典在无法打破的封锁之下因粮草难继而被迫投降。雅典的战败和没落也许是这场战争对希腊社会的最严重打击。[PARAGRAPH:2]就在此时，希腊北部有一新兴势力崛起。前353年，腓力二世牢固地统治了疆域大大扩展的马其顿。腓力用密集的装备着长矛的重装步兵完善了早在古苏美尔和埃及人时代就已有之的方阵战术。希腊方阵是以八人甚至是十六人密集排成纵列，虽然牺牲了作战灵活性和机动性，但是却拥有最大的防护和攻击力。不论亚历山大（前336-前323在位）本人是否牵涉其中，前336年他父亲腓力二世的遇刺促使他提前继承了这个王国。不过他当然已经准备好了，他自小受亚里士多德的教育，并在父亲出征拜占庭时掌管马其顿政局，并成功平定了麦狄人的叛乱。两年之后，他在凯罗尼亚战役中负责率领左翼部队，在此战中腓力二世击败了希腊城邦的联军，成为全希腊的统治者。继承其父军事遗产的亚历山大发动了对波斯的进攻，获得历史上空前绝后的辉煌胜利。经过历时十年的千里远征，亚历山大最终灭亡波斯帝国，将马其顿的边境一直推进到印度，当他于33岁英年早逝时，亚历山大已经开启了一个新的时代，希腊文化传遍了中东各地。西起直布罗陀，东到印度旁遮普的广阔范围都在经济和文化上同属一个文明（虽然并不存在一个同样庞大的政治实体），东西方贸易和科技的交流畅通无阻。[PARAGRAPH:2]不过这个希腊帝国在亚历山大死后就逐渐土崩瓦解了，在40年的空位期（前323-前280）中，各个行省纷纷独立成王国，亚历山大麾下的一些将领在流血冲突与暗杀事件中纷纷自立，无法团结起来面对新的军事威胁。前350年左右，罗马开始侵扰希腊西部的一些城邦，此后便开始一场历时200年的征服，亚历山大所建立的希腊化世界被逐渐并吞。在克利奥巴特拉与马可·安东尼被击败后，屋大维的军队占领了埃及，亚历山大的继承者的最后一个王国终于也落到罗马人手中。在随后的两千年中，希腊先后被罗马，拜占庭以及奥斯曼帝国所统治。后来在英国，俄国和法国协助下，希腊人发动起义宣布独立，并于1832年获得正式承认。在两次世界大战中，希腊都加入同盟国一方作战，并在第二次世界大战中被德国占领。战后希腊爆发内战，最终亲西方的力量击败了共产党的力量。今天的希腊实行民主政体，并且是欧盟的成员国，每年都有成千上万的国外旅游者访问这个国家，感受她永恒的魅力和昔日的辉煌。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_INCA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>Hundreds of years ago, a group of people calling themselves the Inca settled the Cuzco Valley high in the Andes Mountains of South America. Where they had come from was a mystery that still remains unsolved. Although their purpose for settling such a rugged and inhospitable landscape was unclear, the end result of their arrival is without doubt. In time, the Inca built an empire that spanned the Pacific coast as far south as Argentina and as far north as Ecuador, some 2000 miles of hills, mountains, valleys, and coastline. In just a short time (roughly 100 years), the Incan Empire dominated South America and is, to this day, considered one of the finest empires the world has ever known. Starting with the ninth ruler, Pachacuti Inca Yupanqui, the Inca began their expansion. Pachacuti won his first military campaign against the Chanca people, consolidated control over his cultural base of Cuzco, then turned his army south and conquered the Colla and Lupaca tribes. Though not the first Incan ruler, Pachacuti was by many accounts one of the finest Pre-Columbian persons that ever lived. It was under the rule of Huayna Capac, however, that the Incan Empire reached its greatest height. When his father died in 1483 and he became emperor in his own right, Capac continued the campaigns of the previous emperor, eventually extending the empire's borders into what is modern Colombia. A dedicated ruler, Huayna did much to improve the lives of his people. In addition to building temples and other works, Huayna greatly expanded the road network, along which he built storehouses for food so that aid could be quickly rushed to any who were in danger of starvation.[PARAGRAPH:2]Like many other groups that preceded the Inca (the Chimu, the Nazca, the Moche), Incan society was heavily dipped in the worship of powerful gods. Their pantheon contained such lofty omnipotents as Viracocha (the god of creation), Inti (the sun and father of the Inca Dynasty), Illapa (god of rain, thunder, and lightening), Pacha Mama (mother of the earth), and Mama Cocha (mother of the lakes). Grand ceremonies were held frequently to honor these gods, for the Inca believed that if one did not give thanks and obedience to the gods, bad things would happen. The world of the Andes Mountains is full of ecological wonders - and ecological disasters such as earthquakes, severe storms, and volcanic activity. The gods held sway with these events and thus the proper respect had to be paid at all times. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Inca called their empire Tahuantinsuyu (Land of the Four Quarters?), which was divided into four provinces. Each province was controlled by a local governor called the apu; below him were the local rulers - the curacas - and even lower still the district headsmen - the camayoc. Through this governmental structure, the Sapa-Inca could rule the empire with impunity. Additional structures were also put in place, such as the Imperial road system, which was built along the steep inclines of mountains, interspersing bridges and stone walkways, stone steps, and flat brick highways. In addition, way-stations known as tambos were constructed at strategic points along the roads, giving travelers and important dignitaries a place to rest and prepare for the next leg of their journey.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Incan army was also well organized. When called upon to fight, each province would muster squadrons of men armed with maces, bows and arrows, slings, darts, and spears. These fierce Incan warriors, known as the Quechua, conquered much of the Andes and coastal regions of what is now Peru and Ecuador in the period between 1440 and 1530 . During a battle, slingers would let fly a shower of rocks to soften the enemy lines. Then, archers would release their shafts, darts would fly, and then the shock troops would hit, in a torrent of screams and shouts meant to confuse and terrify the wavering opposition. Incan warfare was very successful. But nothing could prepare the empire for what was coming.[PARAGRAPH:2]After the glorious reign of Huayna Capac, the empire began to erode under a series of internal and external disasters. A bitter civil war between half brothers Huascar and Atahuallpa, the sons of Capac, stretched the empire to the breaking point. Atahuallpa won the war, quickly killed his half-brother, and declared himself king. But, in 1532 AD, Spanish Conquistadors, under the command of Francisco Pizarro, entered the Cajamarca Valley and brutally attacked Atahuallpa and his subjects, killing many and taking the Sapa-Inca hostage. Eventually, Pizarro killed Atahuallpa, pillaged the empire of its riches, and brought an end to the mighty Incan civilization. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>数百年前，一群自称“印加”的人移居到南美安第斯山的库斯科山谷。他们从何处而来不为人所知。尽管至今尚不清楚他们为何选择在如此崎岖且不宜居住的地方定居，但对于他们曾经来过这一事实却毋庸置疑。很快，这些印加人就沿太平洋海岸线建立了一个延绵2000多英里（南起阿根廷北至厄瓜多尔），遍布丘陵、高山，峡谷和海岸的帝国。在短短的时间里（大约100年），印加帝国已控制了南美洲的大片地区，并且被认为是有史以来最成功的帝国之一。从第九位统治者，帕查库提·印加·尤潘基开始，印加帝国开始了扩张的历程。帕查库提首先赢得了对查恩卡人的战争，并通过建设作为文化中心的都城库斯科加强了统治力量，随后挥师南下，征服了科拉和卢帕卡部族。尽管帕查库提不是印加的第一任统治者，但他却被很多人认为是哥伦布发现美洲大陆以前最完美的美洲人。不过印加帝国达到强盛的巅峰则是在怀那·卡帕统治时期。怀那于1483年继位为印加皇帝，他继承前代皇帝的对外征战事业，最终使帝国的领土范围扩张到今哥伦比亚。怀那还是一位勤勉的统治者，非常注重改善臣民的生活。除了修建神庙和宫室，怀那还大规模地扩建道路网，并沿建造了许多石屋以存放为附近饥民提供的食物。[PARAGRAPH:2]与许多早于印加的部族一样（奇穆人、纳兹卡人、莫切人），印加社会中充满了对强大的众神的崇拜。他们自己的万神殿中同样供奉着无所不能的维拉科查（创造之神）、印帝（太阳神和印加之父）、伊拉帕（雷雨闪电之神）、帕查玛玛（大地之母）以及玛玛哥哈（湖泊之母）。盛大的祭祀活动定期举行，以表示对诸神的敬畏，因为印加人相信一个人一旦不感谢神的赐予，违背神的旨意，必将受到天谴。这个安第斯山中的世界中充满了自然界的奇观和灾难：地震、猛烈的飓风和火山活动。人们相信众神掌控着这一切，所以必须随时表达出对于神灵的充分的敬畏。[PARAGRAPH:2]印加人把他们的帝国称作塔华廷苏育，即盖丘亚语“四方”之意。帝国分为四个行省，每个省的最高长官称为“阿普”（总督），在他们之下的是地区长官“库拉卡斯”，其下还有更低一级的头领，被称作“卡玛约克”。通过这样的行政机构，“萨帕印加”（印加皇帝）能够毫无困难地管理整个帝国。除此以外还设立有其它机构，比如皇家道路系统，这些道路有的依山而建，有的密布桥梁，包括石质人行道和平坦的砖砌路面。在道路沿线的各战略要地还建有“坦波”（驿站）,作为旅行者及出巡显贵的休息和中转场所。[PARAGRAPH:2]印加军队具有有十分严密的组织。一旦收到战争动员令，各省就会迅速集结大批配备钉锤、弓箭、投石器、标枪和长矛的部队。这些凶悍的印加山地勇士被称为“盖丘亚”，以这支部队为主力，印加人在1440至1530年间征服了安第斯山脉以及东太平洋沿岸今秘鲁与厄瓜多尔地区。在战斗中，印加的投石兵能投射雨点般的石子以削弱敌人的阵线，接着是发射弓箭和标枪，其后是突袭部队出击。在狂风暴雨般的喊杀声中，敌人往往迅速陷入混乱，并最后崩溃。印加人在战争中总是无往不利。但这一切都无法挽救这个帝国即将面临的危难。[PARAGRAPH:2]在经历怀那·卡帕的繁荣兴盛时代之后，帝国受多种内外因素的影响而逐渐走向衰落。怀那·卡帕的两个儿子，异母兄弟华斯卡和阿塔瓦尔帕之间的内战将帝国带到了崩溃的边缘。最终阿塔瓦尔帕赢得了战争，并在杀死自己的兄弟之后登上王位。然而到了1532年，弗朗西斯科·皮萨罗率领西班牙征服者进入了卡加马卡河谷，兽性地攻击阿塔瓦尔帕和他的子民。无数的印加人被屠杀，皇帝也被囚为人质。最终皮萨罗处死了阿塔瓦尔帕，并将帝国的财富洗劫一空，曾经强大的印加文明就此毁灭。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_INDIA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>The Indian subcontinent is the home of one of the world's oldest and most influential civilizations. From about 5000 BC, increasing numbers of settlements of subsistence agriculturalists began to appear throughout the Indus Valley; by 2600 BC some of these villages grew into urban centers, forming the basis for the early Harappan civilization, the peer of contemporary Egyptian and Babylonian civilizations. It was around this period that Hinduism, the world's oldest religion, began to take form. Unlike the Egyptians and Babylonians, however, a central state failed to form in India until a much later period. It was not until the Mauryan Period (325-185 BC) that the first Indian empire ruling most of the subcontinent took shape.[PARAGRAPH:2]Chandragupta Maurya was the warrior who carved out much of the territory that would form the Mauryan Empire. Using War Elephants to good effect, he defeated Alexander's successor Seleucus, the ruler of the eastern Greek holdings in Iran and India. It was under Chandragupta's grandson Asoka (272-232 BC), however, that the Mauryan Empire reached its height, covering the entire subcontinent except for the southern tip. Asoka's India possessed an elaborate administrative and tax-collecting system, and trade flourished due to his construction of roads. Asoka converted to Buddhism during his rule and gave up violent conquest in order to live a moral life. His ethical teachings can still be found inscribed on pillars and rockfaces across India today.[PARAGRAPH:2]A century later, the disintegration of the Mauryan empire gave rise to a number of feuding kingdoms, the Guptas and Pajputs in the north and Chola, Hoysalas and Pandyas in the south. These divided kingdoms were unable to stand against the coming Islamic tide. The first Arabic raids in the subcontinent were made along the western coast and in Sind during the 7th and 8th centuries, and there had been Muslim trading communities in India for decades beforehand. The permanent military movement of Muslims into northern India, however, dates from the late 12th century and was carried out by the Turkish dynasty that arose on the ruins of the Abbasid caliphate. Sultan Mahmud, who conducted more than 20 campaigns in India from 1001 to 1027 AD and established a large but short-lived empire, laid the road to conquest. By 1186 AD, the Mahmud realm had been destroyed by the Ghurids, who proceeded to conquer the Rajput kingdoms and establish a Muslim sultanate in Delhi, from which a series of able Turkish overlords ruled the north until 1526 AD.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Muslim states were themselves supplanted by the Islamic Mughul Empire (1526-1761 AD), founded by Zahir-ud-Din Muhammad Babur (1526-1530 AD). Babur was a Mongol, a fifth-generation descendant of Timur and a 14th-generation descendant of Genghis Khan. In a lightning series of campaigns commencing in 1511 AD, he overran the Punjab and Hindustan. Akbar the Great (1556-1605 AD), his grandson, continued the conquest of the subcontinent, overrunning Gujarat, Bengal and Rajasthan. At its zenith, the Mughal realm commanded resources unprecedented in Indian history and covered almost the entire subcontinent.[PARAGRAPH:2]The 16th and 17th centuries also saw the establishment and expansion of European trading organizations in the subcontinent, principally for the procurement of rare resources. By 1740, the Portuguese, Dutch, English, and French had all founded colonial trading posts, but after their defeat in the Seven Years War the French holdings were surrendered to the British East India Company. The collapsing Mughal Empire left a power vaccuum that the East India Company would step in and fill. Despite initially possessing no more than a handful of trading posts, the British soon won control of the rich province of Bengal, and continued their territorial expansion from there. Military adventurers using small numbers of British forces mixed with large numbers of Indian auxiliaries won a series of stunning victories against the dying Mughals and the independent princes of states such as Mysore, Rajputana, and the Maratha Confederacy. By 1850, the entire subcontinent was controlled by the British either directly or through alliances. The quarter-century following the bitter Indian revolt of 1857-59, which transferred the East India Company's rule to the British crown, ended with the birth of nationalist agitation.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Indian National Congress held its first meeting in December 1885 in Bombay even as Indian troops were fighting in upper Burma under the British flag. Mohandas Gandhi (1869-1948), later known as Mahatma ("Great-Souled"), was recognized throughout India as the spiritual leader of a nationwide movement for independence. The Jallianwala Bagh (1919) massacre turned millions of moderate Indians from patient and loyal supporters of the British Raj into fervent nationalists. The last years of British rule were racked by increasingly violent Hindu-Muslim conflict and intensified opposition to foreign rule. In July 1947, Britain's Parliament passed the Indian Independence Act, ordering the demarcation of the dominions of India and Pakistan by midnight of August 14, 1947, and dividing within a single month the assets of history's largest and richest colony. India today is the world's largest democracy, with a population estimated at over a billion, and despite widespread poverty is viewed as one of the world's rising powers.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>印度次大陆是世界上最早和最具影响力的文明发源地之一。从大约公元前5000年起，越来越多的以农耕为生的聚居区开始出现在印度河谷中。到公元前2600年，其中的一些村落开始发展成城市中心，并形成了早期的哈拉帕文明的基础，基本与埃及文明和巴比伦文明同时代。在此期间，世界上最古老的宗教之一——印度教已开始产生。然而与埃及和巴比伦不同的是，这一地区建立起统一中央政权的时间要晚得多，直到孔雀王朝（前325-前185）时期才形成印度历史上首个范围基本涵盖整个次大陆的帝国。[PARAGRAPH:2]孔雀王朝的创立者旃陀罗笈多（前321-前297在位）是一位出色的军事领袖。他凭借战象的强大威力，击败了亚历山大希腊化大帝国的继承者之一，控制着印度西部和今伊朗地区的塞琉古斯。到旃陀罗笈多之孙阿育王在位时（前272-前232），孔雀王朝达到了强盛的巅峰，除最南端之外的整个印度次大陆都已成为帝国的领土。阿育王时代的印度建立了完善的行政和税收体系，商业贸易也因道路的兴建而兴旺发达。在统治的后期，阿育王皈依了佛教，放弃对外征战，过着远离尘世的生活。至今印度各地许多古迹的柱石上仍然镌刻着他的哲言和警句。[PARAGRAPH:2]一个世纪之后，孔雀王朝的瓦解形成了多个彼此长期争斗的王国，笈多和帕吉甫特位于北部，殊罗，何萨拉和潘德亚在南部，因为他们无法团结一致，将无法抵挡即将到来伊斯兰狂潮。阿拉伯对于次大陆最早的入侵的是从西部沿海和信得发起的，这些区域在此几十年前就已经成为了在印度的穆斯林贸易区。穆斯林的持续军事行动可以追溯到12世纪晚期，在阿拔斯哈里发王朝的废墟上建立起来的突厥王朝的入侵行动。在1001到1027年间，马哈穆德苏丹征战印度多达二十余次，建立起了一个庞大但却短命的帝国，也为后来者铺就征服之路。1186年，古里人摧毁了马哈穆德所建的政权，随后又继续征服了拉吉普特王国，并且在德里建立了一个穆斯林苏丹国。此后这个国家多位贤能的突厥裔君主统制着印度北部地区，直到公元1526年。[PARAGRAPH:2]穆斯林国家后来被札希尔-乌德-丁·穆罕默德·巴布尔（1526-1530在位）所建立的莫卧儿帝国（1526-1761）所取代。巴布尔是一个蒙古人，他是帖木儿的第五世孙，也是成吉思汗的第十四世孙。从公元1511年开始他发起了一系列的战役横扫了旁遮普和印度斯坦。他的孙子阿克巴大帝（1556-1605在位）继续进行对次大陆之路的征服，并控制了古吉拉特、孟加拉，以及拉吉斯坦等地。在莫卧儿帝国的全盛时期，所拥有的资源是印度史上空前的，也几乎控制了整个次大陆。[PARAGRAPH:2]16和17世纪可说是欧洲的贸易组织在次大陆生根并扩张的时期，这一切主要是为了获取珍稀资源。到1740年，葡萄牙人、荷兰人、英国人和法国人都在印度设立了殖民据点。不过在七年战争之后法国人的据点被迫向英属东印度公司投降。莫卧儿帝国的衰落在印度许多地区造成的权力真空，东印度东司乘虚而入。英国人的势力很快从最初的几个贸易站发展到完全富庶的孟加拉省，并以此为基地继续扩张。由少数英国人和大量当地族裔组成的东印度公司武装力量多次大败莫卧儿王朝以及一些独立邦国（如迈索尔，拉吉普塔纳和马拉塔联邦等）的军队。到1850年，整个印度次大陆都已处在英国直接或间接（通过联盟）的控制之下。但不久即爆发了席卷全印度的民族大起义（1857-1859），东印度公司的势力被英国国王的直接统治所取代，并促使印度民族主义力量不断觉醒。[PARAGRAPH:2]1885年12月，印度国民大会党于在孟买举行首次大会并宣告成立，尽管此刻印度军队还背着英国旗帜在缅甸作战。后来被人尊奉为“圣雄”的莫罕达斯·甘地（1869-1948）开始成为一场席卷印度的独立运动的精神领袖。发生在阿姆利则市札连瓦拉园的大屠杀（1919）将数以百万计的温和派印度人由忍让而忠诚的英国总督支持者转变成激进的民族主义者。在英国印度统治的最后几年里，整个印度充斥着印度教信徒和穆斯林的激烈冲突及对外国统治的强烈不满。1947年7月，英国国会通过《印度独立法案》，下令在1947年8月14日午夜将印度分为印度和巴基斯坦两个国家，并且在短短一个月内，将有史以来最广大富饶的殖民地一分为二。今日印度是世界上最大的民主国家，人口据估计已超过十亿，虽然贫穷现象依然普遍存在，但仍被世人看做是一个正在崛起的强国。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_JAPAN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]It is not known when humans first settled on the Japanese archipelago, but the Jomon people might be called proto-Japanese, and they were spread throughout the archipelago by 250 BC. The Yayoi culture that arose in Kyushu, while the Jomon culture was still evolving, spread gradually eastward, overwhelming the Jomon. Culturally, the Yayoi represented a notable advance and flourished for some five or six centuries, from the 3rd century BC to the 3rd century AD. The unification of Japan under the Yamato court, with the tenno ("Emperor of Heaven") at its center, occurred around the mid-4th century. The 6th century reign of Kentai (507-531 AD) represented a decline of Yamato influence both at home and abroad; the period can be characterized by the growing accumulation of power by regional leaders and a weakening of royal influence.[PARAGRAPH:2]It was during this Yamato period that Japan first began to experience significant contact with the mainland. Buddhism was introduced to Japan by Korean monks around 530 and was shortly adopted by the emperor's court. Rather than displacing Japan's native Shinto religion, Buddhism would eventually merge with it to form the synthesis that characterizes modern Shintoism. Chinese influences were also particularly strong in Japan at this time; Prince Shotoku is said to have written the Constitution of Seventeen Articles promoting moral and political principles of the Chinese court. In the year 710, the first permanent Japanese capital was established in Nara, a city modeled after the Chinese capital. Buddhist monasteries near Nara became so influential that the court was moved to Kyoto in 794, which would remain the capital for the next thousand years.[PARAGRAPH:2]This Heian Period (794-1185) was characterized by a slow decline of Chinese influence in favor of the development of native Japanese customs. In the late Heian period, the more powerful of the Samurai gathered in or near the capital, where they served both the military needs of the emperor and also as bodyguards for the great noble houses. Emerging from provincial warrior bands, the aristocratic Samurai caste of the Kamakura period (1192-1333), with their military skills and deep pride in their stoicism, developed a disciplined culture distinct from the earlier, quiet refinement of the imperial court.[PARAGRAPH:2]Under the growing influence of Zen Buddhism during the Muromachi period (1338-1573), the samurai culture produced many uniquely Japanese arts that continue today. Although Japan was nominally united under the emperor and the shogun in Kyoto, the reality was that by the end of the Muromachi period the power of the government in Kyoto had declined to practically nothing. Japan disintegrated into a hodgepodge of warring feudal states, each presided over by a daimyo, or feudal lord. Many of the most famous stories of the samurai date from this "Sengoku" Period. Eventually, Japan was reunited through the efforts of three men: Oda Nobunaga, his general Toyotomi Hideyoshi, and Hideyoshi's successor Tokugawa Ieyasu. Tokugawa founded the Edo shogunate (1603-1867), which ended the incessant conflicts and brought reform and peace to the islands. The following two and half centuries of peace brought prosperity to Japan, but the isolationist policy of the shoguns left the nation backwards technologically.[PARAGRAPH:2]Although small numbers of Spanish and Portuguese traders had been in Japan since the mid-1500s, it was the arrival of a squadron of U.S. warships commanded by Commodore Matthew C. Perry in Uraga Bay in July 1853 that finally opened the nation to Western influence. The opening up of Japan brought pressure for political reforms and a national identity that the oudated shogunate was unable to meet, leading to a revolution in the 1860s. The Meiji government that followed the overthrow of the shogunate set about the task of westernization and the creation of a modern state, and moved Japan onto the world stage. Japan's stunning victories over China (1894-95) and Russia (1904-05) announced its presence as a world power, but the same nationalistic forces that led to Japan's resurgence also caused xenophobia and violent excesses against non-Japanese peoples. Japanese aggression in the 1930s and 1940s resulted in invasions of China, Vietnam, Indonesia, and eventually the bombing of Pearl Harbor. After initial successes in World War II, the summer of 1945 brought disaster for the Japanese: the Americans took Okinawa in a bloody invasion, in August the Soviet Union declared war and swept over Manchuria, and atomic bombs largely destroyed the cities of Hiroshima and Nagasaki on August 6 and 9, respectively. The Pacific War came to an end on August 14, with the formal surrender signed on September 2 in Tokyo Bay aboard the battleship USS Missouri. With postwar American aid, from 1952 to 1973 Japan experienced accelerated economic growth and social change. By the 1990s, Japan was again a first-class power, the senior partner in the emerging Asian economic bloc.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>虽然无法确定自何时起在日本列岛上开始有人类居住，不过据信日本人的前身可能是绳纹人，且在公元前250年时已散居于日本各地。在绳纹文化继续发展的同时，弥生文化又在九洲兴起并逐渐向东扩张，驱走了绳纹人。相对而言，弥生文化具有明显的优势，其繁荣持续了五六个世纪之久，即公元前3世纪到公元后3世纪。到4世纪中期，大和朝廷统一了日本，建立了以“天皇”为中心的政权。到公元6世纪继体天皇统治时期（507-531），大和朝廷的影响力开始不断下降。这一时期的基本特点是地方豪族势力的逐渐壮大，以及皇族势力的日益衰落。[PARAGRAPH:2]在大和朝廷时期，日本与亚洲大陆的联系不断加强。佛教于公元530年左右由朝鲜僧侣传入日本并被天皇的宫廷所接受。但佛教并没有彻底取代本土的神道信仰，而是与其相互融合，最终形成了现在的神道教。这一时代中国文化对日本的影响也非常巨大，圣德太子在604年颁布的十七条宪法就是中国儒家政治和文化思想的体现。710年建城的日本第一座永久性都城——奈良（平城京）也完全模仿了中国都城长安的布局。奈良近郊的佛教寺院极度兴盛，以至皇室最终于794年迁居京都（平安京），该城在此后的一千年间一直都是日本的首都。[PARAGRAPH:2]在平安时代（794-1185），中国文化对日本的影响逐渐减弱，独特的本土文化开始发展。到平安时代晚期，集中于畿内或近畿地区的武士阶层势力大增，日本武士既为天皇作战，又担任贵族门阀的护卫。最初来自地方军队的武士到鐮仓时代（1192-1333）已发展为贵族化的特权阶层，他们崇尚勇武、坚忍与自信，逐渐形成了一种更为严苛的新文化体系，与先前精致纤巧的宫廷风尚形成鲜明对比。[PARAGRAPH:2]到了室町时代（1338-1573），佛教禅宗的影响日益增强，从武士文化中派生出许多日本独有的艺术形式并流传至今。到室町时代末期，虽然日本在名义上仍是由天皇和将军所统治的统一国家，但在实际上，京都政府的力量已经极度衰落。整个日本分裂为许多彼此争斗的大小封建政权，这些封建领主即所谓“大名”。在这个“战国”时代中，涌现出了许多著名的武士，他们的英雄事迹流传至今。最终日本在三个人的努力之下重新归于统一：织田信长、他的部将丰臣秀吉，以及继秀吉之后掌权的德川家康。德川家康创立了江户幕府（1603-1867），使日本列岛结束战乱恢复和平。此后的两个半世纪里日本的经济文化持续繁荣，但幕府政权执行的闭关锁国政策使这个国家在科技方面日益落后。[PARAGRAPH:2]虽然西班牙和葡萄牙商人与传教士在16世纪中叶已到达日本，但是直到1853年7月美国海军上将马修·佩里率领的舰队驶抵浦贺湾，才最终迫使这个国家向西方敞开大门。日本的对外开放推动了政治改革的进程和民族认同感的形成，守旧的幕府政权则越来越不合时宜，最终导致19世纪20年代倒幕运动的爆发。推翻幕府之后成立的明治政府开始执行西方化政策，努力建设一个现代化国家，并使日本开始登上世界舞台。日本在中日甲午战争（1894-1895）和日俄战争（1904-1905）中的胜利震惊了世界，也使日本成为世界列强的一员，但推动日本崛起的民族主义思想也导致了日本人仇外情绪和侵略兽性的高涨。在20世纪30和40年代，日本先后入侵中国、越南、印度尼西亚，并最终导致了偷袭珍珠港事件。虽然在二战初期取得了一连串胜利，但到1945年夏天，日本已面临穷途末路：美国经过血战占领冲绳，苏联也于八月向日本宣战并横扫满洲地区，8月6日和9日，两枚原子弹分别摧毁了广岛和长崎。8月14日，天皇终于宣布投降，太平洋战争结束，正式投降文书于9月2日在停靠东京湾的美国密苏里号战列舰上签署。战后的日本又获得了美国的帮助，从1952至1973年，日本经历了经济的加速成长和社会的巨大变革。到20世纪90年代，日本已重新成为一流强国以及新兴的亚洲经济带的重要参与者。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MALI_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>Once one of the great centres of Islamic culture and wealth, Mali (which is among the continent's most ancient states outside of North Africa) owes much of its reputation to its situation as a major trading center and to the tax that is levied on its trans-Saharan route. The Mali Empire was located on the Mandinka plateau in West Africa, located in the southern part of the modern Republic of Mali. It was founded by Sundiata Keita, a Mandinka who led a revolt against the Soso Kingdom which had dominated the area. Sundiata's life is commemorated in the Epic of Sundiata, a poem of the Mandinka people. It is said that after his victory over the Soso, Sundiata Keita converted to Islam as a gesture of goodwill to the Islamic traders who brought his country wealth. After defeating the Soso, Sundiata pursued an expansionist policy, and soon the Empire covered not only modern Mali, but also extended west to the ocean across what is now Senegal. During war, the Mali often fought as "skirmishers" - soldiers who fanned out in loose formation to protect the main force's flanks or front. The Mali skirmishers were lightly-armed archers in that force, famed for their courage and their marksmanship. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Mali Empire reached its zenith under the rule of Mansa Musa (1312?1337) in the early 14th century. Previously, it had been part of the empire of Ghana, which flourished between the seventh and 11th centuries based on the trade of gold from the interior for salt from the coastal regions. Mansa Musa made a famous pilgrimage to Mecca in 1324 laden with gold and slaves to proclaim Mali's prosperity and power. It is said that he lavished so much wealth along his route that the price of gold was depressed for years afterwards. During Mansa Musa's rule Muslim scholarship reached new heights in Mali, and such cities as Timbuktu and Djenné (Jenne) became important centers of trade, learning, and culture.[PARAGRAPH:2]After the decline of the Mali Empire, the territory became part of the Songhai Empire, which occupied an area covering parts of modern-day Guinea, Burkina Faso, Senegal, Mali, Mauritania, Niger, and Nigeria. Songhai was brought to an end and its territory usurped by the Moroccan invasion of 1591. With the decline of the trans-Saharan trading routes in favor of naval commerce, the area enjoyed little strategic importance and was divided into small kingdoms for the next two centuries until the arrival of French colonists. Mali was absorbed into French West Africa in 1895. In 1960, together with what is now Senegal, it achieved independence as the Federation of Mali, although Senegal seceded after a few weeks. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>作为古代最重要的伊斯兰文化与财富中心之一，马里是北部非洲以南的广阔内陆中历史最悠久的国家，她因拥有作为主要贸易中心的优越地理位置，垄断了对穿越萨哈拉沙漠商路的征税权。马里帝国的中心位于西部非洲的曼丁卡高原（今马里共和国南部）。帝国的创立者是孙迪亚塔·科伊塔，他领导曼丁卡人反抗苏索王国对当地的统治。孙迪亚塔的生平事迹被曼丁卡人编成了一部长篇史诗“孙迪亚塔传”。传说孙迪亚塔在战胜苏索之后，为向给他的国家带来财富的穆斯林商人表达善意而皈依了伊斯兰教。击败了苏索的孙迪亚塔继续执行扩张政策，不久其帝国的控制范围不仅包括今马里全境，还一直向西延伸到大西洋沿岸（今塞内加尔）。在这一系列战争中，马里人通常担任“突击手”——采用疏散阵形，负责保护主力部队的侧翼或前沿的战士。马里突击手是使用投射武器的轻装步兵，以其过人的勇气和精准的投射而闻名于世。[PARAGRAPH:2]马里帝国在14世纪初曼沙·穆萨统治时期（1312-1337）达到力量的巅峰。马里继承了兴盛于7至11世纪的加纳帝国的大部分领土及其内陆的黄金和沿海的食盐产业。曼沙·穆萨甚至还在1324年率领满载黄金和奴隶的队伍前往麦加进行了一次著名的朝圣之旅，以显示马里的富庶和力量。据说他在沿途的大肆挥霍甚至导致此后持续多年的黄金贬值。在曼沙·穆萨统治期间，穆斯林文化在马里达到达了一个新的高度，廷巴克图、德杰恩和杰内等城市也成为重要的贸易、学术和文化中心。[PARAGRAPH:2]马里帝国衰亡后，其领地成为桑海帝国的一部分。桑海帝国的范围包括今几内亚、布基纳法索、塞内加尔、马里、毛里塔尼亚、尼日尔和尼日利亚的部分地区。1591年摩洛哥人的入侵宣告了桑海帝国的终结。随着海上商路的兴起，穿越萨哈拉沙漠的商路逐渐衰败，此后的两个世纪里这一地区的战略重要性不断下降，并分裂成为许多小王国。法国殖民者来到此地后，马里于1895年并入了法属西非。1960年，包括今塞内加尔的马里联邦获得独立，但仅仅几周之后塞内加尔即宣告分离。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MONGOL_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>The Mongol tribes entered into history with the birth of Temujin, born in c.1167 AD in the wild steppe-land of Mongolia, which is bordered by modern China and Russia. When Temujin was nine years old, tribal rivals poisoned and murdered his father Yesugei, creating a power vacuum in the tribe that resulted in the exile of young Temujin and his family as fugitives. In time Temujin would return to claim his inheritance, forge political alliances, and vanquish old rivals. In 1204 AD he summoned a kuriltai war council and proceeded to unite all local nomad tribes by force, becoming the first man ever to unite the Mongols. It was at this time he received the title 'Genghis Khan', meaning 'Great Ruler'. [PARAGRAPH:2]China, at the time, was divided into three parts: the Ch'in, who were the most powerful, reigned in the north at Beijing; the Sung occupied the South; and the Hsi-Hsia, the weakest of the 3, inhabited the western flank of the Great Wall. The Mongol conquest against China began in 1211 when the consolidated tribes of the Great Khan struck at the Hsi-Hsia, with tremendous success. Not impressed with the defeat of his weaker neighbor, the new Emperor of Ch'in insisted on a public display of servitude from Temujin. Temujin reacted by ordering a general advance against the Ch'in Empire. The resulting war lasted for approximately 23 years, and ended in the complete destruction of the Ch'in. Although the Mongols began the war as nomadic horsemen, by the time they defeated the Ch'in they had learned how to use advanced siege weaponry to capture cities. During this campaign Temujin ensured that the epic war upon the Ch'in did not occupy all of his resources and time; there were older enemies to address. [PARAGRAPH:2]Amid the war against the Ch'in the Mongols also rallied against the Kara-Khitay, one of the original Kuchlug tribes that had fled from defeat during Temujin's war of unification. Victory over the Kara-Khitay provided the Mongols a common frontier with the Shah of Khwarizm, who ruled a large Muslim state that stretched from modern day Iran to southern Russia as far as the Caspian and Aral Seas. Temujin initially attempted to establish friendly relations with the Shah Ala-al-Din, but he was contemptuously rebuffed, and the Mongol emissary killed. That was a mistake. In 1219 a Mongol horde estimated at 100,000 horsemen invaded Khwarizm and the other cities that lay along the rich Silk Way. Due to their stubborn resistance, the cities of Khwarizm were destroyed, their populations slaughtered or enslaved, and the area almost completely depopulated. Ala-al-Din fled in exile and died shortly thereafter. In many respects, this area today still has not recovered from the Mongol invasion.[PARAGRAPH:2]After destroying Khwarizm, the Mongols had access to Russia. Not content with remaining a peaceful neighbor, Temujin's successor Ogodai permitted his generals to lead an extraordinary campaign into southern Russia, which would be staged largely in the winter months. In a series of campaigns between 1237-40, the Mongols completely subjected the various principalities of Russia, destroying anyone who opposed them. From Russia, the Mongols continued their western advance by invading Poland, Silesia, and Hungary. They easily defeated the armies of Poland, Germany, and Hungary, and appeared poised to erupt into Western Europe. But the death of Ogodai, the great khan, caused the armies to retreat in order to seek new orders, thus sparing most of Europe from destruction. Less fortunate was the Muslim world, as Baghdad was sacked in 1258 by yet another Mongol army and the Caliph executed by being trampeled to death beneath Mongol horses. The destruction of Baghdad and slaughtering of its population was a blow that the Arab Empire of the Caliphs never fully recovered from. The Mongols were finally turned back for the first time by the Mameluks of Egypt in 1260.[PARAGRAPH:2]Mongol children were taught to ride on horseback from the age of three, and were given bow and arrows to use for hunting at the age of five. Horseback riding became a natural way for the Mongols to conduct war. When speed was essential, a Mongol rider could even sleep while in the saddle; and by using a system that consisted of approximately four remounts, Temujin's army was capable of traversing 130 miles in two days, with no breaks for food. Another defining characteristic of a Mongolian army was the speed and voracity with which it was able to accept and prepare for battle. The Mongols' harsh, nomadic lifestyle had prepared them well for the rigors of war; and they often thrived in conditions that would be considered intolerable by any other military of its time. When the need arose they could last up to ten days at a time without cooking food, during which they would sustain themselves by drinking the blood of their horses. Their primary weapon consisted of horse archers called Keshiks, who could fire with great speed and incredible accuracy from the back of a saddle. The mobility of the Mongol forces gave them a great tactical advantage within battles that Mongol generals would exploit over and over again.[PARAGRAPH:2]Every victory wrought by the Mongols was followed by slaughters of incredible scale. No citizens, with the exception of those who were useful to the Mongol war effort, were spared in these attacks. In 1221, the Islamic city of Merv was captured; 700,000 were murdered (this number is almost certainly exaggerated but still amazing), and a rearguard was assembled to dispatch any citizens who were fortunate enough to have escaped the original slaughter - this was routine work for the Mongol army. It is said that Temujin planned to depopulate northern China for use as a pasture for his livestock, until being told that subjects would pay more in taxes than cattle.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the end of the 13th century Mongol armies had been involved in action in countries including: Poland, Japan, Korea, Hungary, Russia, Palestine, Egypt, Persia, India, China, Cambodia, Burma, Vietnam, and Indonesia. After Temujin's death in 1227 five more Khans would follow, including Kublai Khan, whose triumph was the union of all of China under his rule. However, the death of Kublai Khan in 1294 AD marked the end of an era for Mongol conquests, and the march of Mongol armies began to decline. While many of the khanates founded by the Mongols lasted for several more centuries, the age of the great nomadic forces was over. Although their era was brief in duration, the Mongols conquered the largest empire the world has ever seen and terrorized virtually the entire Eurasian continent.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>随着铁木真1167年诞生于被现今中俄边界所围绕着的蒙古大草原，蒙古民族的历史才真正开始。在铁木真八岁时，他的父亲也速该被敌人毒死，造成部族的权力真空和内部争斗，年幼的铁木真及其家人被迫过着悲惨的流亡生活。但最终铁木真卷土重来夺回继承权，联合盟友消灭仇敌，至1204年统一了蒙古高原。1206年他召集蒙古各部在斡难河源召开忽里台大会，并被推举为“成吉思汗”，即“伟大的统治者”。[PARAGRAPH:2]而当时的中国本部正处于三个政权分立的局面：统治北方，力量最强的金朝；偏安江南，经济繁荣的宋朝；以及占据长城西翼，力量最弱的西夏。成吉思汗在1209年迫使西夏归附之后，又于1211年率军南下，意欲逐鹿中原。新继位的金朝皇帝对弱小邻国的战败并不以为然，仍坚持要求铁木真向他称臣。铁木真乃下令对金帝国发动全面进攻。这场战争持续了23年，最后以金朝的灭亡而告终。起初的蒙古军队只是精于骑射，但到他们战胜金朝之时，已经掌握了重型武器的使用和攻打城池的技术。而除了金朝进行的漫长战争，铁木真还要同时面对更多的对手。[PARAGRAPH:2]在攻打金朝的同时，蒙古人还与西辽（哈剌契丹）作战，因为在蒙古统一战争中失败的乃蛮部王子屈出律逃亡至此并夺取了西辽帝位。灭亡西辽之后的蒙古开始与信奉伊斯兰教的花剌子模接壤，当时的花剌子模国王统治着包括今伊朗及原苏联中亚里海和咸海地区的广阔土地。起初铁木真曾试图与花剌子模国王阿拉-阿尔-丁建立友好关系，但被对方轻蔑地拒绝了，蒙古的使臣也被斩杀。花剌子模国王犯下了一个巨大的错误。1219年，十万蒙古大军发动了对花剌子模及其他丝绸之路沿线城市的入侵。由于在围攻时遇到强烈抵抗，蒙古人完全摧毁了花剌子模城作为报复，所有市民被屠杀或卖为奴隶，原本的繁华城市从此成为一片废墟。阿拉-阿尔-丁本人也在不久之后死于流亡途中。可以说这片地区直到今天都还未能从蒙古人的蹂躏下恢复过来。[PARAGRAPH:2]灭亡花剌子模使蒙古人打开了通向俄罗斯大草原的通道。继铁木真之后成为大汗的窝阔台不希望与任何邻国保持和平，于是派遣部下率军入侵基辅罗斯并大获全胜，而且这场战役还是在严寒的冬季进行的。历经三年征战（1237-1240），蒙古人消灭或臣服了各个罗斯公国，随即又从俄罗斯大草原出发继续向西入侵波兰、西里西亚和匈牙利。蒙古人轻松击败了波兰、日耳曼和匈牙利各国联军，大有横扫整个欧洲之势。但窝阔台却在此时因酗酒而意外暴亡，各路蒙古大军匆忙撤退回国以推举新的大汗，欧洲才得以免遭毁灭的命运。但穆斯林世界就没有这么幸运了，另一支蒙古大军于1258年攻陷巴格达，阿拔斯朝的末代哈里发被塞进布袋，用马蹄践踏而死。强盛一时的阿拉伯帝国从此一蹶不振。此后蒙古人继续向西进攻，但于1260年被埃及马穆鲁克王朝军队击退。[PARAGRAPH:2]蒙古小孩三岁就开始骑马，五岁就要拿起弓箭去狩猎。蒙古人可以说是天生的骑兵。如果时间紧迫，蒙古骑手甚至可以在马鞍上睡觉；每个蒙古骑兵都有至少二匹甚至三四匹马，可以在行进中轮流骑乘以节省马力，这使铁木真的军队可以几乎不停顿地在两天内行进130英里。蒙古军队最大的特点就是高速机动与疯狂掠夺，对战斗充满渴求。蒙古人习惯于艰苦的游牧生活，非常适应严酷的战争环境，他们往往能够在同时期的其他军队感到无法忍受的条件下保持高昂的斗志。必要时他们可以连续十天不生火做饭，而只靠饮用马血维生。蒙古骑射手是这支大军的主力，他们能在马背上连续而精准地射击。蒙古骑射手的高度的灵活性和机动性使他们在任何情况下都能够占据主动赢得优势。[PARAGRAPH:2]蒙古人获得的每一场胜利都伴随着规模惊人的屠杀。蒙古人所俘获的人口，只有能为军队出力者才能够幸免于难。公元1221年穆斯林城市马鲁被攻陷后，70万居民全部被屠杀（虽然这个数字应该有所夸大），蒙古人专门安排了预备队。以追捕有幸在最初的杀戳中逃脱的人——这对蒙古军队来说就像例行公事。传说铁木真曾经计划屠尽中国北部的居民，并将所有农田改为牧场，直到下属告诉他征收赋税比放牧牛羊更为合算时才作罢。[PARAGRAPH:2]到13世纪末期曾经遭受过蒙古大军入侵的国家和地区包括：波兰、日本、朝鲜、匈牙利、俄罗斯、巴勒斯坦、埃及、波斯、印度、中国、柬埔寨、缅甸、越南和爪哇等。1227年铁木真去世，其后的五位大汗继续他的扩张政策，他的孙子忽必烈汗取得了征服整个中国的业绩。但1294年忽必列汗的去世标志着蒙古大征服时代的结束，蒙古大军的征战从此停止，虽然蒙古人所建立的各大汗国继续存在了几个世纪的时间，但游牧民族强盛的时代已逐渐成为历史。虽然持续的时间很短暂，但蒙古人所建大帝国的疆域之广阔是人类历史上空前绝后的，几乎囊括了整个亚欧大陆。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PERSIA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>The term Persia has been used for centuries, chiefly in the West, to designate a region of southern Iran formerly known as Persis or Parsa; the name of the Indo-European nomadic people who migrated into the region about 1000 BC, eventually supplanting the Assyrians and Chaldeans. The first mention of the Parsa occurs in the annals of Shalmanesar III, an Assyrian king, in 844 BC. Cyrus II (559-529 BC), also known as Cyrus the Great, was heir to a long line of ruling chiefs in Mesopotamia and was the founder of the Persian Empire; he was called the father of his people by the ancient Persians. In 550 BC, Cyrus, the Prince of Persia, revolted against the Median king Astyages and welded the Persians and Medes together into one powerful force. Cyrus consolidated his rule on the Iranian Plateau and then extended it westward across Asia Minor. In October 539 BC, Babylon, the greatest city of the ancient world, fell to his Persian forces. Cyrus also oversaw the construction of a series of great roads to link together the territories that he had conquered. Although Cyrus was a great military conqueror, he was also a fair ruler; he allowed the Jews to return from Babylon to their homeland in Palestine. His dynasty, known as the Achaemenids, ruled Persia for two centuries.[PARAGRAPH:2]Following the death of Cyrus' heir, Darius I (522-486 BC), a leading general and one of the princes of the Achaemenid family, proclaimed himself king following the suppression of a number of provincial rebellions and challenges from other pretenders to the throne. Darius was in the mold of Cyrus the Great - a powerful personality and a dynamic ruler. To consolidate his accession, Darius I founded his new capital of Parsa, known to the Greeks as Persepolis ("Persian City") and expanded the ranks of his personal bodyguard, the Immortals. The elite force drew its name from the fact that no matter how many men were lost, the Persian Emperor would always pay the cost to restore the Immortals back to their original strength. Although Darius consolidated and added to the conquests of his predecessors, it was as an administrator that he made his greatest contribution to Persian history. During his reign, political and legal reforms revitalized the provinces and ambitious projects were undertaken to promote imperial trade and commerce; coinage, weights and measures were standardized, and new land and sea routes explored and established. [PARAGRAPH:2]Such activities, however, did not prevent Darius from following an active expansionist policy. Campaigns in the east confirmed gains made by Cyrus the Great and added large sections of the northern Indian subcontinent to the list of Persian-controlled provinces. Expansion to the west began about 516 BC when Darius moved against the Greek colonies along the coast of Asia Minor. Xerxes (486-465 BC), son and successor of Darius I, was determined to continue the Persian conquest of the west and is best known for his massive invasion of Greece from across the Hellespont in 480 BC, a campaign marked by the battles of Thermopylae, Salamis, and Plataea. Although successful in the pacification of Egypt and suppression of a Babylon revolt, his defeat by the allied Greek city-states spelled the beginning of the decline of the Persian Empire. In Xerxes' last years, he squandered the once-enormous treasury he had gathered through trade and taxation by launching vast construction programs, most never finished. [PARAGRAPH:2]The death of Xerxes was the final turning point in Persian influence. Occasional flashes of vigor and ability by some of Xerxes' successors were too infrequent to prevent eventual collapse. The final act was played out during the reign of Darius III (336-330 BC), who was defeated at the Battle of Granicus (334 BC) by Alexander the Great. Persepolis fell to the young Macedonian conqueror in April 330 BC, and Darius, the last Achaemenid, was murdered in the summer of the same year while fleeing the Greek forces. In the struggle for power after Alexander's death, Seleucus I brought under his control the Persian provinces of Alexander's empire. But this unity was short-lived, as the Indian holdings successfully revolted and the Seleucid kingdom broke into the competing nations of Parthia and Bactria. Parts of the Seleucid kingdom lasted for two centuries, but it was eventually swept aside by the Parthians, who founded an empire that stretched almost as far as Persia under the Achaemenids. The Romans and Parthians struggled against one another for centuries over control of Mesopotamia, with the Parthians usually holding onto most of the Fertile Crescent. But in 224 AD the Parthians were themselves overthrown by a new Sassanid dynasty that revived many of the customs of the Achaemenids, such as the Zoroastrian religion. The Sassanids fought a series of debilitating wars with the Byzantine Empire in the 6th and 7th centuries, which fatally weakened the Persian Empire when the Arabs exploded onto the scene. In a series of decisive battles between 633 and 642, the Arabs conquered and destroyed the Persian Empire; since this time, Persia (modern Iran) has largely belonged to the Arab world. The customs and religion of ancient Persia were destroyed and the population absorbed into the surrounding Islamic culture; only a few remnants survive today.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>波斯一词几个世纪以来主要流行于西方，指今天伊朗南部地区。此前，这里以“波西斯”和“帕沙”而闻名，两者都是印欧游牧民族的名字。公元前1000年左右他们迁移到这里，最终取代了亚述人和迦勒底人。“帕沙”一词最早见于有关公元前844年亚述国王萨尔曼尼撒三世的史料。居鲁士二世（前559-前529在位，即居鲁士大帝），美索不达米亚一系列统治者的后裔，是位宽宏大量并受人尊敬的君主，古波斯人称其为民族之父。公元前550年，居鲁士领导波斯部族成功推翻米底亚王阿斯蒂亚格斯的统治，将米底亚与波斯结为一体。随后他巩固了在伊朗高原的统治并向西扩张到了小亚细亚。前539年10月，远古时代世上最伟大的城市巴比伦落入波斯军队之手。居鲁士还下令修建了大量驿道，以将他所征服的辽阔土地联结在一起。居鲁士不但是一位强大的军事征服者，还是一位公正的统治者，他允许被掠至巴比伦的犹太人返回他们在巴勒斯旦的家园。他所建立的阿契明王朝在此后两个世纪一直统治着整个波斯。[PARAGRAPH:2]随着居鲁士继承人的死亡，一位帝国的高级将领，同时也是阿契明家族的王子大流士一世（前522-前486在位）镇压了各省的叛乱分子和觑觎王位者后自封为国王。大流士同居鲁士大帝相似，是位强悍有力，精力充沛的统治者。为了巩固他的王位，大流士一世在帕沙建立了他的新首都，希腊人称之为波斯波利斯（“波斯之城”），并大大扩充了他的私人近卫队，即波斯长生军。这个名字是对这些战士的恰当褒奖，因为他们作战勇猛、奋不顾身，长生军在任何时候都必须保持满员状态，不论这将付出多少代价。虽然大流士巩固并扩大了前代帝王的征服事业，但他为波斯历史所做的最伟大贡献则是作为一位治国者的功绩。在他统治时期，政治和法律改革令所有省份均充满生机，很多雄心勃勃的计划得以实行，促进了帝国的贸易和商业，货币和度量衡得以统一，新的陆地、海洋贸易线路得以开拓和建立。[PARAGRAPH:2]然而，这些活动没有防碍大流士积极的扩张政策。东方的战役巩固了居鲁士大帝的成就，使北方印度次大陆的大片土地进入波斯控制的省份之列。向西方的扩张始于公元前516年，当时大流士对小亚细亚沿岸的希腊殖民地发动了进攻。薛西斯（前486-前465在位），大流士一世的儿子和继承人，决定继续波斯对西方的征服。他最著名的事迹是公元前480年越过海峡对希腊的大举入侵，期间在温泉关，萨拉米斯湾和普拉蒂亚展开了一系列的大战。虽然成功平定了埃及，并镇压了巴比伦的起义，但他却被希腊各城邦组成的联盟击败了，这标志着波斯帝国开始走向衰落。由于对这些失利感到失望，薛西斯在苏萨和波斯波利斯的宫殿中过起了引退生活。在最后的几年里，他把从贸易和税赋中获得的巨额财富全部耗费在了庞大的建筑工程上，但大多数都未能完成。[PARAGRAPH:2]薛西斯之死是波斯影响力的最后转折点。尽管他的一些继承者也偶而闪现出一些活力和能力，但毕竟极为少见，无法阻止最终的衰落。大流士三世统治时期（前336-前330）成为古代波斯帝国历史的最后一章。大流士三世在前330年的格拉尼卡斯河战役惨败于亚历山大大帝，帝国开始走向穷途末路。最终波斯波利斯于前330年4月被年轻的马其顿征服者占领。阿契明王朝的末代国王大流士也于同年在逃亡途中被谋杀。在亚历山大死后爆发的权力争斗中，由塞琉古斯一世建立的塞琉西王国控制了原属亚历山大帝国的波斯诸省。但是统一持续的时间非常短暂，印度地区很快宣告叛离，其余大部分地区也分立为帕提亚（中国史籍称为安息）和巴克特里亚（中国史籍称为大夏）两个敌对国家。日益衰落的塞琉西王国在延续两个世纪之后被帕提亚所灭，此时的帕提亚基本控制了原属波斯阿契明王朝的所有领土。罗马人为争夺美索不达米亚的统治权同帕提亚进行了上百年的战争，却几乎没有占到任何便宜。到公元224年，帕提亚又被萨珊王朝所推翻，萨珊王朝与当初的阿契明王朝有较深的渊源，且同样信仰琐罗亚斯德教（拜火教）。在公元6世纪至7世纪间，萨珊王朝与拜占庭帝国进行了长期的战争，国力因此严重削弱，阿拉伯人则乘势崛起。经过633年至642年一系列决定性的战役，阿拉伯人征服了波斯萨珊王朝，从此之后，波斯（今伊朗）成为阿拉伯世界的一部分。古代波斯的风俗和信仰被消灭了，大部分人口融入了伊斯兰文化，只剩下少量遗迹保存至今。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ROME_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>The founding of Rome on the fertile Tibur River is obscured by myth and legend, but it is generally accepted that Rome was first settled in 753 BC and that the Republic was founded in 509 BC, following the overthrow of Lucius Tarquinius Superbus, the last of Rome's seven kings. Rome was built on a site highly prized by the Etruscans, who dominated the Italian peninsula in the 6th century BC. The Etruscan king Porsenna defeated the Romans and expelled Tarquinius Superbus. Yet before Porsenna could establish himself as monarch over the unruly Romans, he was forced to withdraw. Rather than restoring their inept king, the citizens replaced the monarchy with two elected consuls, generals whose primary task it was to lead Rome's armies, and a Senate to serve as an advisory body. Where the Etruscans had failed, the people of Rome succeeded in the task of unifying the various Italian peoples into a political whole.[PARAGRAPH:2]Toward the end of the 5th century BC, the Romans, propelled by the pressures of unchecked population growth, began to expand at the expense of nearby city-states. Rome's first two wars were fought with Fidenae, an independent city near Rome, and against Veii, an important Etruscan city. In the process, the expanding Roman Republic found the Greek phalanx formation too unwieldy for fragmented fighting in the hills and valleys of central Italy; accordingly, Rome evolved a new tactical system based on flexible ranks of cohorts, organized into self-contained Legions, the means by which Imperial Rome conquered and ruled the ancient world. As Rome became increasingly powerful, the remaining city-states took up arms; the ensuing Latin War (340-338 BC) was quickly decided in Rome's favor. By 264 BC all Italy south of the Alps was united under the leadership of Rome, its members either incorporated in or allied with the Republic. Rome's growing influence led it into conflict with Carthage, an established commercial power in northern Africa. The defeat and destruction of Carthage in the three Punic Wars (264-146 BC) sustained Rome's acquisitive momentum, and the Republic set its sights on dominating the entire Mediterranean area. In short order, the Romans overran Syria, Macedonia, Greece, and Egypt, all of which had until then been part of the decaying Hellenistic empire created by Alexander the Great.[PARAGRAPH:2]But such expansion was not without costs; tensions grew and civil war erupted. The ensuing period of unrest and revolution marked the transition of Rome from a republic to an empire. The Late Republic witnessed the struggle between Marius and Sulla, the famous slave uprising under Spartacus, and saw the rise of figures such as the general Pompey, the orator Cicero, and the consul Julius Caesar. Although he was dismissed as vain and effeminate young man early in his career, Caesar proved to be a master politician and military strategist. Caesar conquered Gaul between 58-50 BC, then proceeded to crush all of his opponents in a civil war that left him the undisputed master of Rome. After Caesar's assassination in 44 BC, it was not long before civil war again erupted; but following his victory at Actium (31 BC), Octavian, Caesar's nephew, was crowned Rome's first emperor, taking the name Augustus (27 BC-14 AD).[PARAGRAPH:2]Although there were notable exceptions such as Caligula (37-41) and Nero (54-68), the Roman Empire was generally blessed with a series of able and brilliant leaders during its first two centuries who expanded the frontiers until Rome's empire reached from Britain to Egypt and from Spain to Persia. Imperial Rome was distinguished not only for its military - the foundation upon which the empire rested - but also for its accomplishments in engineering and statecraft. The Romans were gifted in the applied arts of law, record-keeping and city planning, yet they also acknowledged and adopted the contributions of earlier peoples - most notably, those of the Greeks, much of whose culture was thereby preserved. Roman law was a complex body of precedents and opinions, which were finally codified in the 6th century as the Justinian Code. The empire's road network was without match in the ancient world, designed for rapid movement of commerce, agriculture, and mail delivery as well as the needs of the army. Roman city planners achieved unprecedented standards of hygiene with their plumbing, sewage disposal, dams, and aqueducts. Roman art and architecture, though often imitative of Greek styles, was boldly planned and lavishly executed. Roman science and culture, in short, became the foundations of the European world.[PARAGRAPH:2]After the death of the emperor Marcus Aurelius in 180 AD, the empire was plagued by a series of poor rulers. The Praetorian Guard, formerly a highly respected elite unit sworn to serve the emperor, turned into a body that would sell itself to the highest bidder. During the middle of the 3rd century, Rome suffered through more than 30 emperors in a span of 70 years, and the empire nearly collapsed under the pressure of internal revolts and barbarian invaders. The Emperor Diocletian (284-305) managed to restore order, at the cost of imposing a strict authoritarian rule that left little room for individual freedom. Further chaos broke out after Diocletian's retirement, until Constantine (306-337) managed to emerge victorius from another series of civil wars. Constantine accomplished two extremely noteworthy things; first, he founded the city of Constantinople to serve as the new capital of the empire, from which the Byzantine or Eastern Roman Empire would endure for another thousand years. Secondly, Constantine legalized Christianity as a religion, allowing it to spread much more rapidly throughout the Roman world.[PARAGRAPH:2]After Constantine's death, the empire was split into an eastern and western half, the division becoming permanent in 395. When the empire again came under barbarian onslaught in the late 4th and 5th centuries, the weakened West collapsed but the East - where most of the empire's population and wealth was concentrated - managed to survive. The final emperor of the west, Romulus Augustulus, was deposed in 476, although the Western Empire had become a fiction in all but name decades earlier. Although destroyed as a political entity, the Latin culture of the Roman Empire largely survived and can still be observed today throughout the Mediterranean.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>罗马在肥沃的台伯河畔建城的史实由于神话传说已变得模糊不清，不过一般认为罗马始建于公元前753年，罗马共和国时期则是自公元前509年鲁西亚斯·塔奎尼乌斯·苏帕布斯被推翻后开始，他也是罗马七王的最后一任。罗马城是在伊达拉里亚人的根据地上建立的，他们在公元前第六世纪主宰了整个意大利半岛。伊达拉里亚国王波席那击败了罗马人，并将塔奎尼乌斯·苏帕布斯放逐。不过在波席那还来不及自立为王统治罗马人之前，他就被迫撤兵了。罗马人并不想让无能的前任国王复辟，他们选出了两位执政官取代国王（执政官同时又是负责统率军队的将领），并建立了一个“元老院”作为咨询、议事机构。在伊达拉里亚人遭到挫败之后，罗马人成功地将意大利的各民族统一成为一个政治实体。[PARAGRAPH:2]在公元前5世纪末，罗马人受到人口急剧成长的压力，便开始向附近的城邦扩张势力。罗马的头两场战事是与罗马附近的独立城市费德尼及伊达拉里亚人的重要城市维爱展开的。在战争中，势力逐渐增强的罗马共和国政府发现希腊式的方阵在意大利中部的丘陵和山谷地形中相当笨拙，不利于作战。因此他们根据罗马步兵的特性组织出一种可独立作战的罗马兵团，这也变成罗马帝国征服与统治上古世界的有力工具。当罗马变得十分强大时，其它的城邦便结盟共同抵抗罗马，在随之而来的拉丁战争（前340-前338）中，罗马很快便取得优势。在公元264年前，阿尔卑斯山南面的整个意大利都归顺罗马的统治，这些城邦不是已加入共和政府，就是与之结盟。罗马的扩张使得它与北非的商业强国迦太基发生冲突。罗马在三次布匿战争（前264-前146）中彻底击败并且摧毁迦太基。确立其霸权后，共和政府便把目标放在主宰整个地中海区域上。不久之后，罗马横扫叙利亚、马其顿、希腊、埃及诸国，这些国家都是亚历山大大帝死后逐渐衰败的希腊化帝国的一部份。[PARAGRAPH:2]不过这样的扩张并非没有代价，紧张的政治局势和内战时有发生。政局的不稳与革命使得罗马由共和政体转型为一个帝国。在内战的舞台上，才华横溢的庞培、雄辩的西塞罗以及征服高卢的（前58-前50）的朱利乌斯·恺撒竞相登场。最终，恺撒取得了胜利，并获得代表罗马最高权力的“祖国之父”称号。在他于公元前44年被暗杀身亡后不久，罗马再次陷入内战。不过当恺撒的侄子屋大维取得了阿克兴战役（前31年）的胜利后，便成为罗马的第一任皇帝奥古斯都（前27-14在位）。[PARAGRAPH:2]虽然有像卡利古拉（37-41在位）和尼禄（54-68在位）之流的例外出现，罗马帝国在它的头两百年里仍有幸拥有一系列强干而卓越的领袖，他们使得罗马的疆域北达不列颠，南抵埃及，西起西班牙，东至波斯。帝国时期的罗马不仅仅以军事成就见长——虽然这是罗马帝国兴盛的基础，在工程与治世经国的政策上也是同样高明。罗马人擅长法律、会计以及城市规划，他们也承袭了前人的知识——最明显的就是希腊人。许多希腊的文化成就都经罗马人之手保留了下来。罗马法是由众多的判例与判决所组成的复杂法律，这套法律最终在公元六世纪时被编纂成查士丁尼法典。罗马帝国道路系统之完善，在上古世界也绝对是无人能出其右，其设计目的是使商业、农业、邮件递送以及军队调动更为快捷。罗马的城市以地底的下水道、水堤以及输水道构成前所未有的卫生系统。罗马的艺术与建筑虽然承袭希腊的风格，但是却更为壮阔与华丽。简而言之，罗马人的科学与文化成就构成了欧洲世界的基础。[PARAGRAPH:2]在公元180年罗马皇帝马可·奥勒里乌斯逝世后，帝国被数位无能的皇帝弄得元气大伤。罗马禁卫军，这支当初受人尊敬，对皇帝绝对忠诚的精锐部队，现在却可以向出得起价钱的任何人服务。3世纪中期，罗马在70年内更换了30位皇帝，帝国被内部此起彼伏的叛乱和野蛮人在边界上的入侵搞得近乎崩溃。皇帝戴克里先（284-305在位）试图恢复秩序，其代价是严厉执行独裁统治，从而使个人自由丧失了空间。在他引退之后，却爆发了更大的混乱。直到君士坦丁大帝（306-337在位）通过一系列内战的胜利脱颖而出。君士坦丁留下了两件非常杰出的遗产：首先，他建立了君士坦丁堡作为帝国的新首都，在这里东罗马帝国——或叫拜占庭帝国——又延续了上千年的历史。其次，君士坦丁使基督教的地位合法化了，这使其迅速传遍了整个罗马世界。[PARAGRAPH:2]君士坦丁死后，帝国分裂为东西两个帝国。从395年起，这一分裂成为了永久性的。当帝国在4世纪晚期到5世纪再次遭到野蛮人的冲击时，衰弱的西罗马帝国灭亡了，而东罗马帝国——那里集中了帝国的大部分人口和财富——则努力生存了下来。西罗马帝国的最后一位皇帝，罗慕路斯·奥古斯都，于476年被废黜。虽然早在数十年前西罗马帝国就仅仅是名义上的存在。尽管作为政治实体已被摧毁，罗马帝国的拉丁文化则大部分保存下来并在今天的地中海地区仍可发现其踪迹。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_RUSSIA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>Indo-European, Ural-Altaic, and other races have occupied what is now the territory of Russia since 2000 BC, but little is known about their institutions and activities. Modern Russia dates from about 770 AD, when Viking explorers began an intensive penetration of the Volga region. From bases in estuaries along the eastern Baltic, Scandinavian bands, probably in search of new trade routes to the east, began to penetrate territory populated by Finnish and Slavic tribes, where they found unlimited natural resources. [PARAGRAPH:2]Within a few decades the Rus, as the Viking settlers were known, together with other Scandinavians operating farther west, extended their raiding activities down the main river routes toward Baghdad and Constantinople, reaching the Black Sea in 860. In the period from 930 to 1000, the region came under complete control by the Rus from their capital at Kiev. The lifeblood of this sprawling Kievan empire was the commerce organized by these Viking princes. Sometime around 1000 the Kievan princes were converted to Christianity by Byzantine missionaries, and the medieval Russian states would maintain close cultural ties with the Byzantines. The united Kievan state broke apart after 1054 under the pressure of attacks by nomads from the steppes, fragmenting Russia into a number of independent principalities. The devastating attack by the Mongols in 1237-40 resulted in widepread destruction of cities, loss of life, and wiped out a developing commercial middle class centered around the fur trade. This helped bring about the long rule of autocracy in Russia.[PARAGRAPH:2]Of the various Russian principalities, it was Muscovy that proved to be the most successful. Beginning as the state that collected taxes for Russia's Mongol overlords, the princes of Muscovy eventually gained a position of leadership by throwing off the yoke of their oppressors. Ivan III (1462-1505) consolidated the gains his father, Vasily II, had won in the saddle, and his warrior descendent Ivan IV (1533-84), known as Ivan the Terrible, gained enough power to take the title of "Tsar", or Emperor, in 1547. This "gathering of the Russian lands" became a conscious and irresistible five-century drive by Moscow to annex all Slavic lands, both the Russian territories and the Belorussian and Ukrainian regions. The ascension of Peter I (1694-1725), known as Peter the Great, ushered in and established the social, political, and intellectual trends that were to dominate Russia for the next two centuries. The location of his new capital, St. Petersburg, on the shores of the Gulf of Finland symbolized this shift toward a European involvement. But while the Russian aristocracy may have adopted the courtly behavior and modern military tactics of the West, the vast majority of the Russian people remained mired in a slave-like state of feudal servitude.[PARAGRAPH:2]Catherine the Great (1762-1796), though a German princess who was unrelated to Peter in any way, would prove to be his true intellectual and political heir. Catherine's reign was notable for imperial expansion. Most important were the securing of the northern shore of the Black Sea, the annexation of the Crimea, and the expansion into the steppes beyond the Urals. This permitted the protection of Russian agricultural settlements in the south and the establishment of trade routes through the Black Sea. In the process, the military democracies of the Cossack hosts along the Dnieper, Don, and Volga rivers lost their autonomy and special privileges; the wealthier officers became Russian nobles, receiving the right to own and settle serfs on their own lands, while the fierce horsemen sank to the level of peasants with special military obligations. Catherine's partitioning of Poland also helped bring Russia closer to the rest of Europe, at least geographically.[PARAGRAPH:2]Despite the heritage of Peter and Catherine, by the time of Nicholas II (1894-1917) Russia was in disarray, plagued by internal misery and oppression. Defeat in the Russo-Japanese War followed by the 1905 Revolution indicated that Russia was in need of drastic reforms, but the autocratic structure of the Tsarist state was poorly suited to adapt to changing conditions. World War I imposed stresses on the Tsardom that it could not meet, and the Russian Revolution broke out in 1917, riding on a wave of popular discontent. The Kerensky Provisional Government, a moderate attempt to resolve the problems, collapsed in the face of the Bolshevik (Communist) revolution. Given the Bolshevik desire to dominate the whole of Russia and the rest of the former Tsarist empire, civil war was inevitable, and a bitter struggle between Red (Communist) and White (Tsarist) forces lasted until the Bolsheviks were victorious in 1922. Stalin would complete the consolidation of Communist power begun by Lenin, most notably through the forced industrialization of the Five-Year Plans and the mass starvations engendered by the collectivization of agriculture. Despite an almost inhuman level of suffering imposed on the Russian people, Stalin would lead the Soviet Union through the greatest threat to its existence during the Nazi invasion of 1941-45, and help it emerge as one of the world's superpowers following the Second World War. [PARAGRAPH:2]But in the ensuing Cold War, Russia's economy tottered towards collapse. The Communist economic system worked well at producing millions of tons of iron for use in tanks, but was unable to produce simple household goods to improve the daily lives of its people. Mikhail Gorbachev attempted to revive the stagnant Soviet economy through the relaxation of economic and political controls, but the forces of free speech and a free market quickly took hold in a way Gorbachev never would have imagined. Within a few years, the Soviet satellites in Eastern Europe were declaring their independence and new politicians like Boris Yeltsin were demanding democratic elections. An ill-conceived, ill-planned, and poorly executed coup attempt to unseat Yeltsin occurred in August 1991, bringing an end to the Communist Party and accelerating the movement to disband the Soviet Union. Yeltsin dissolved the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics in December 1991, banned the Communist Party in Russia, and seized all of its property, becoming the first president of Russia. Today, as it often has throughout its history, Russia finds itself struggling between whether to follow the example of the West or pursue its own unique path of development.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>自公元前2000年以来，印欧人、乌拉尔-阿尔泰人以及其他许多民族都曾经占据这片今天被称为俄罗斯的土地，但对于他们的制度和活动我们知之甚少。现代俄罗斯的起源可以追溯到公元770年，当时维京探险者开始向整个伏尔加河流域渗透。也许是为了寻找新的通往东方的贸易路线，这些斯堪的纳维亚人从建立在波罗的海东岸各河口的基地进入芬兰人和斯拉夫人部落聚居的地区，并在那里发现了取之不尽的自然资源。[PARAGRAPH:2]数十年间，这些罗斯人——也就是当初的维京殖民者——和其他在更西边活动的斯堪的纳维亚人一道，将他们劫掠活动的范围沿着通往巴格达和君士坦丁堡的水路不断扩展，终于在公元860年抵达黑海岸边。在930年至1000年间，整个这一地区完全被基辅的罗斯人所控制。缓慢成长的基辅公国的命脉主要是倚赖这些维京领主所组织的商业活动。大约在公元1000年的时候，由于拜占庭传教士的影响，基辅的王公们皈依了基督教，由此中世纪的俄罗斯诸国与拜占庭维持了紧密的文化联系。公元1054年后，统一的基辅罗斯国家在来自大草原的游牧部落进攻的压力下逐渐分崩离析，形成诸多独立的公国。1237-1240年间，毁灭性的蒙古入侵导致大范围的城市毁灭和人口损失，并沉重打击了随皮毛贸易而发展的商业中产阶级。这些都有助于在俄国长期独裁统治的形成。[PARAGRAPH:2]在众多俄罗斯公国中，莫斯科被证明是最成功的一个。起初，莫斯科的大公们只是替俄罗斯的蒙古统治者征收税款而已。但随后他们在对抗蒙古人的过程中逐渐取得领导地位。伊凡三世（1462-1505在位）巩固了他父亲瓦西里二世在马背上获得的权势。而他武勇的继承人伊凡四世（1533-1584在位，即伊凡雷帝）更是在1547年开始自称“沙皇”。“统治全俄罗斯”成为历代莫斯科统治者的头号信条，并推动了其后长达五个世纪之久的对所有斯拉夫领地的扩张行动，包括俄罗斯、白俄罗斯和乌克兰。彼得一世（1694-1725在位，即彼得大帝）引进并建立了一整套社会、政治和文化制度，在俄罗斯其后两百年的历史中占据着主导地位。他那位于芬兰湾沿岸的首都圣彼得堡，象征着俄罗斯开始融入西方的重大转变。但是虽然俄罗斯的贵族已经接受西方的文化礼仪和军事制度，广大的俄国人民却仍然深陷于封建义务的桎梏之中，犹如奴隶一般。[PARAGRAPH:2]叶卡捷琳娜大帝（1762-1796在位）本是一位日尔曼公主，与彼得一世没有任何关系，但却被认为是他的智慧和政策的真正继承人。她统治期间最引人注目的是帝国的扩张。其中最重要的是确保了黑海北岸领土，吞并克里米亚汗国并越过乌拉尔山进入西伯利亚大草原。这些行动保护了俄罗斯南部的农业聚落和穿过黑海的商路的畅通。在这个过程中，居住在第聂伯河、顿河与伏尔加河沿岸，尚处于军事民主社会的哥萨克人逐渐丧失了他们的自治地位和特权，富有的军官成为俄罗斯贵族，他们有权利在其土地上蓄养农奴，而好斗的骑手则被降级成有特殊兵役义务的农民，由哥萨克人所组成的哥萨克骑兵部队经常被作为沙皇俄国对外征战的主力。这一时期对波兰的瓜分也使得俄国更加接近欧洲的其他部分，至少在地理上如此。[PARAGRAPH:2]尽管有彼得和叶卡捷琳娜遗留下来的丰功伟业，到尼古拉二世在位期间（1894-1917），连年的对外战争及内乱与经济萧条使得俄罗斯已是一片混乱。日俄战争的失败以及接踵而来的1905年革命表明俄国需要一次激烈的改革，但是沙皇专制政权未能调整以适应改变了的情势。第一次世界大战对这个沙皇国家产生了意想不到的影响，大众的不满导致了1917年俄国革命的爆发。克伦斯基临时政府试图缓解这些问题，但最终还是在布尔什维克革命中崩溃了。由于布尔什维克党想要控制整个俄罗斯以及沙皇俄国的其余部分，内战于是不可避免。红军（共产主义者）和白军（保皇党人）之间的艰苦战斗一直持续到1922年布尔什维克取得胜利。斯大林进一步巩固了列宁所开创的共产党政权，其中最引人注目的是因实施五年计划、强制推行工业化和农业集体化所造成的大范围饥荒。尽管俄国人民遭受了巨大的痛苦和损失，斯大林最终带领苏联挺过了对其存在最大的威胁——1941-1945年的纳粹德国入侵，并使其成为第二次世界大战之后世界上的两大超级强国之一。[PARAGRAPH:2]不过在冷战的过程中，俄罗斯的经济一步步走向崩溃。共产主义经济系统在生产成千上万吨用于坦克的钢材时运转良好，却不能生产简单的日用品以改善群众生活。米哈伊尔·戈尔巴乔夫试图通过放松经济和政治控制以激活停滞的苏联经济。但言论自由和自由市场的力量迅速转向他所不曾料想到的方向。几年内，苏联在东欧的卫星国纷纷宣布自主，而新的政治家诸如鲍里斯·叶利钦开始呼吁进行民主选举。1991年8月一场企图推翻叶利钦的失败政变宣告了共产党统治的终结，并加速了苏联的瓦解。1991年12月，叶利钦宣布解散苏维埃社会主义共和国联盟，在俄罗斯取缔共产党，查封其所有的资产，随后他成为俄罗斯的第一任总统。今天，如其过往历史中一样，俄罗斯人仍然对到底是跟随西方的模式还是坚持自己的独特发展道路争论不休。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SPAIN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>The Kingdom of Spain is located in the extreme southwest of the European continent, and occupies approximately 85 percent of the Iberian Peninsula. Spain is bordered on the west by Portugal, in the northeast by France, and by the great wall of the Pyrenees Mountains. The Iberian Peninsula that the Spanish inhabited was occupied by various other civilizations, including the Phoenicians, Carthaginians, Romans, Visigoths, and Muslims, and Spain is now associated with having a very rich, eclectic culture as a result. [PARAGRAPH:2]The development of Christian society and culture in the first 300 years following Islamic conquest in Spain was slow, but major changes occurred for the Spanish in the 12th and 13th centuries. The population grew, communication with northern Europe intensified, commerce and urban life gained in importance, and the kingdoms of Castile, Aragon, Navarre, and Portugal emerged as the governing bodies of the Iberian Peninsula. These kingdoms reached the frontiers that they would keep, with minimum amount of alteration, until the end of the Middle Ages, when Isabella I became Queen of Castile. [PARAGRAPH:2]Isabella began participating in the royal court at the age of 13; and when Portugal, Aragon, and France offered their marriage candidates, she favored Ferdinand of Aragon. Isabella ascended to the throne as Queen of Castile to rule sensibly and with a prudent political program. Her unification of the states of the Iberian Peninsula into a single entity, the maintenance and control over the Straits of Gibraltar, policy of expansion into Muslim North Africa, reform of Spanish Catholicism, and support for the exploration and expansion of the unknown were evidence of her wisdom and capabilities as Queen. In 1492 Columbus, with the blessing and financial backing of Isabella, sought a route to the legendary rich markets of China and Japan. He instead discovered what would become known as "The New World", the present day Americas. This voyage gave way to a new golden age of expeditions and conquest, as the Americas contained gold, a valuable resource that Spain happened to be desperately bereft of at the time. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Spanish explorer Hernando Cortes came to the New World with the sole purpose of seeking out new frontiers and riches in the unknown. Men like Cortes became known as Conquistadores, adventurers who undertook their expeditions in the vast landmasses of the Americas at their own expense, risking their lives without aid from the Spanish royalty. Their conquests included campaigns in Guatemala, Peru, Cuzco, Columbia, Chile, the Bay of Honduras, and as far as the Pacific coastal regions. The Conquistadors, however, were given to fighting and searching for gold, and were swiftly replaced by administrators and settlers from Spain who governed in their place.[PARAGRAPH:2]The twin forces of disease and conquest combined to devastate the indigenous peoples of the Americas, allowing the Spaniards to carve out an enormous empire comprising most of North and South America. Many of the Spanish colonies proved to yield fabulous wealth in the form of gold and sugar, but working conditions were so harsh that large numbers of Africans were brought across the Atlantic as slaves to replace the Indians who had died working on the plantations. These lucrative operations inevitably became high-profile targets of pirates and other raiders who were endorsed by European powers such as England. The Monarchy of Spain endeavored to retaliate by building an armada of warships that was dubbed "The Invincible Armada". The armada was a collection of over 130 naval warships and transport-ships, which contained approximately 8,000 seamen and 19,000 soldiers. King Philip II (1556-98) directed this armada to invade England when the various and frequent raids on Spanish commerce in the Caribbean became intolerable. England's success in repelling the Spanish fleet saved England and the Netherlands from potential consolidation into the Spanish Empire, but despite the Armada's defeat, Spain remained temporarily the strongest land power in Europe. [PARAGRAPH:2]Thereafter, Spain declined in power quickly; the enormous influx of gold and silver from the Americas debased the Spanish currency, and most of the nation's military might was wasted in the quagmire of religious conflict known as the Thirty Years War (1618-48). By the beginning of the 18th century, Spain had become somewhat marginal in international politics, even though it continued to hold vast territories in the Americas. Spain's period of imperial power and exploration left a legacy that consisted of 18 nations in Latin American, the Spanish presence in the Phillipines, and the ever-growing Spanish-speaking population in the United States today. It is also due to the work of Jesuit missionaries from Spain that hundreds of millions of people in Latin America practice Roman Catholicism to this day. In 1975 Spain transitioned into a constitutional monarchy by way of a democratic constitution and is now recognized for its eclectic culture as well as for the glory and mystique that it once possessed in its youth.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>西班牙王国位于欧洲大陆的最西南部，这个国家几乎占据了伊比利亚半岛85%的土地。西班牙的西部与葡萄牙接壤，在北边是一道由比利牛斯山组成的天然屏障，山那头是法国人。伊比利亚半岛这块土地上曾被除西班牙的很多文明占为己有，包括腓尼基人、迦太基人、罗马人、西哥特人以及穆斯林，所以今天的西班牙文化是一个多元文化融合而成的产物。[PARAGRAPH:2]在伊斯兰统治西班牙的前300年里，半岛上基督教社会和文化的发展非常缓慢。但在12世纪至13世纪间发生了革命性的变化。人口急速增长，同北方的欧洲国家间的交流日益增加，商业和城市消费的获利剧增。此时，在伊比利半岛上逐渐形成了卡斯提尔、阿拉贡、纳瓦拉和葡萄牙这几个王国。这几个王国的疆土也拓展到他们所能达到的极限，并且始终没有大的变化，直到中世纪末期伊莎贝拉一世成为卡斯提尔女王为止。[PARAGRAPH:2]伊莎贝拉13岁时就在欧洲各国的宫廷中崭露头角，葡萄牙，阿拉贡和法国都将她列为他们联姻的候选人，她最终倾心于阿拉贡的斐迪南。伊莎贝拉登上卡斯提尔王座后，在政治上表现得非常英明和谨慎。她最终将伊比利半岛统一为一个国家，并将直布罗陀海峡牢牢地掌控在西班牙手中。她将势力渗透到原来属于穆斯林的非洲北部，并在西班牙进行了天主教改革。此外她还积极支持对未知世界的探索，这一切都说明了女王的聪明才智。在1492年10月12日，哥伦布带着伊莎贝拉女王的祝愿和经济支持，开始探索传说中能到达富庶的中国和日本的航路，但他却发现了后来所称的“新大陆”：亚美利加洲。这次航行也开启了探索与征服的黄金时代，美洲富产黄金，这是那个时代的欧洲人所疯狂渴求的贵重资源。[PARAGRAPH:2]在哥伦布远航之后，一支名为“征服者”的西班牙武装集团在赫尔南多·科尔特斯率领下到达新大陆，前往遥远内陆寻找未知的财富。这些人并没有政府为他们提供资助，而是自愿前往广阔的美洲大陆进行探险。西班牙征服者的铁蹄在很短的时间里就踏遍了危地马拉、秘鲁、库斯科、哥伦比亚、智利、洪都拉斯湾以及太平洋沿岸各地区。这些给新世界带来了杀戮和掠夺的征服者最终又被来自西班牙的移民和总督所取代。[PARAGRAPH:2]在征服和瘟疫两种力量的双重打击下，美洲的原住民遭到毁灭。这使得西班牙人得以建立起包括了南北美洲大部分地区的庞大帝国。许多西班牙殖民地出产糖、黄金等贵重物资，其财富简直如同神话。但工作条件如此严酷，大批印第安劳工死于种植园，以致不得不从大西洋彼岸的非洲贩运大量黑人奴隶作为劳动力。这些回报丰厚的活动不可避免地成为了其他欧洲列强及其他们所支持的海盗的靶子，特别是英国。西班牙的君王们力图报复这些袭击，他们不断加强海军力量。“无敌舰队”因此而组建。这支舰队由130艘风帆战舰及运输船组成，舰上共有8000名水手和19000名战士。由于西班牙在通往加勒比海的贸易线不断的受到英国海盗的袭击，菲利普二世（1556-1598在位）终于无法忍受，他命令无敌舰队进攻英格兰本土。最终英国成功击败了西班牙舰队，避免了英格兰和尼德兰被西班牙吞并的潜在可能。尽管无敌舰队覆没了，当时的西班牙仍然是欧洲最具实力的陆上强权。[PARAGRAPH:2]此后，西班牙的国力急速下降。从美洲大量流入的金银造成了严重的通货膨胀，国家的大部分则军力陷入了因宗教冲突而引发的三十年战争（1618-1648）的泥沼。到了18世纪初，西班牙在国际事务中只能扮演一些陪衬的角色，虽然她在南美仍然拥有广阔的殖民地。往昔西班牙帝国的探索和征服所留下的遗产就是现今拉丁美洲的18个西班牙语国家，菲律宾的大量西班牙族裔，以及在美国不断增加的西班牙语人群。由于来自西班牙的耶稣会传教士们的长久努力，今天拉丁美洲有成千上万的人信仰罗马天主教。1975年，西班牙经由民主改革转变为一个君主立宪制国家，现代西班牙包容而多元的社会文化与其昔日曾经拥有的辉煌与神秘一样得了到世界的公认。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_WASHINGTON_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]George Washington [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]First President of the United States [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD]1732-1799[PARAGRAPH:2:1][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]George Washington was born into wealth and gentility (or what passed for it in early American history). His family owned a lot of land in Virginia, and Washington grew up as a gentleman farmer. Early on he displayed a taste for adventure, and when the French and Indian war broke out, Washington was commissioned a Lieutenant Colonel at the age of 22. His British superiors praised him for his gallantry and courage under fire. [PARAGRAPH:1]As he matured, Washington grew to dislike the protectionist policies of the British government, and he was elected one of the Virginia delegates to the Continental Congress. Being one of the few men with actual military service, when war was imminent, he was appointed Commander in Chief of the (largely theoretical) Continental Army. [PARAGRAPH:1]As a war leader, Washington faced enormous challenges. Lacking money, equipment and trained troops and hampered by the new country's inherent political problems, he had to organize, equip and recruit an army that could stand up to the finest military in the world. In his first engagement, shortly after the "battle" of Bunker Hill, his forces drove the unprepared British out of Boston. But when he next met the foe on Long Island, New York, he was totally outnumbered, outgunned, and out-generaled by the British, and he was lucky to escape the total destruction of his army. [PARAGRAPH:1]After this humiliating defeat, Washington began to employ the tactics that would eventually win the war. He realized that time was his best ally - the longer the war continued, the greater the British war weariness would grow. He couldn't hope to defeat the British war machine - but he could hope that the British would eventually give up the fight as not worth the cost. Further, the longer the war went on, the greater the chance that a foreign government would intervene on the American side. [PARAGRAPH:1]For the next six weary years Washington fought to keep his army intact. He avoided major engagements. He harried the British troops when they were vulnerable, and retreated into the mountains when they were powerful. His forces dwindled to virtually nothing in the winter, and swelled with temporary volunteers during the summer. Men went shoeless and hungry, and morale plummeted. Only Washington's iron will and strong personal magnetism kept the army alive. [PARAGRAPH:1]Finally, in 1781, the long-awaited foreign intervention occurred, and France went to war with Britain. With their invaluable naval assistance, Washington was able to capture the main British army in Yorktown, forcing Great Britain to admit defeat. [PARAGRAPH:1]Washington became the first President of the United States. Prone to pomposity, he was an "Imperial" president, giving the new office much of the stature and dignity it has maintained ever since, while strongly reinforcing its democratic underpinnings. He believed in neutrality in foreign affairs - at least until the new country was stronger - and he sought to keep the twin evils of regionalism and factionalism from infecting the federal government. In this he was largely unsuccessful, as the next several centuries would attest. [PARAGRAPH:1]Washington retired at the end of his second term. He returned to his family home and once again took up the life of a gentleman farmer. He died three months later, beloved by his countrymen and rightly recognized as the "father of his country."</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]乔治·华盛顿[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]美国总统[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1732-1799年[PARAGRAPH:2:1][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]乔治·华盛顿出生于富裕而有教养的家庭（根据美国早期历史著作的说法）。他的家族拥有弗吉尼亚的大片土地，于是华盛顿成长为一名农场主。早年的他即显示出对冒险的渴望，当对法国人与印第安人的战争爆发时，22岁的华盛顿被任命为中校。他的英国上司赞扬了他在炮火下表现出的英勇精神。[PARAGRAPH:1]年龄渐长，华盛顿开始对英国政府的贸易保护政策不满，而他作为弗吉尼亚的代表之一参加了大陆会议。当战争来临时，作为少数具有实战经历的议员，他被任命为（理论上的）大陆军总司令。[PARAGRAPH:1]作为战争领袖，华盛顿面临着巨大的挑战。缺少金钱、缺少装备、缺少训练有素的士兵，加上来自新成立国家的各种政治问题的羁绊，他必须迅速招募组织和装备一支能与世界最强战争机器对抗的军队。起初大陆军在邦克山“战役”中旗开得胜，并将缺乏防备的英军赶出了波士顿。但是当第二次在纽约长岛遭遇敌军时，他被不仅在数量上，也在武器上优于自身的英军以优越的战术打得一败涂地，但毕竟是他使得部队侥幸地避免了全军覆没的危险。[PARAGRAPH:1]自从这次羞辱性的惨败后，华盛顿开始制定了一个籍以最终获胜的战略。他意识到时间是他的最好盟友——战争拖延得越久，英国内部的厌战情绪就越强。他不寄希望于打败强大的英国战争机器——但他可以期待对方终因难以承受代价而放弃这场战争。进一步讲，战争越久，外国政府就越有可能进行干预，支持北美人民的斗争。[PARAGRAPH:1]在长达六年的战争中，华盛顿努力使军队保持完整。他避免正面作战。他在英军疲惫的时候对其进行骚扰，在他们强大的时候退却到山区。冬天的时候他将军队减员到最低限度，而在夏天靠志愿者的帮助极力扩充。士兵们因没有饭吃，没有鞋穿而士气低落。然而华盛顿钢铁般的意志与强大人格魅力保证了大陆军的生存。[PARAGRAPH:1]最终，1781年，期待已久的外国干预发生了，法国向英国宣战。靠着强大的法国海军协助，华盛顿得以在约克镇逼降了英军主力，迫使大英帝国承认战败。[PARAGRAPH:1]此后华盛顿当选为美利坚合众国第一位总统。可以毫不夸张地说，他是一位“帝皇级”的总统，他给予这个新生国家的民主基础以极大的助力，使其达到前所未有的高度。在外交方面他崇尚中庸主义——至少在美国更加强盛之前——而他致力于寻求如何避免让地方主义与党派之争这两个毒瘤感染联邦政府。但后来几世纪的历史表明，在这一点上他做得并不成功。[PARAGRAPH:1]华盛顿在他第二任总统任期结束后退休。他回到家乡重拾乡绅生活。三个月后去世，他被爱戴他的同胞们尊称为“国父”。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ROOSEVELT_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Franklin Roosevelt [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]President of the United States [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD]1882-1945[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Franklin Delano Roosevelt, the 32nd President of the United States, is best known for leading the US out of the Great Depression and to victory in WWII. Crippled by polio at 39, Roosevelt displayed indomitable courage and resolve to overcome his disability and achieve his goals. [PARAGRAPH:1]Roosevelt was a man of contradictions. Though wealthy and powerful, Roosevelt was beloved by the poor and downtrodden and despised as a socialist by the wealthy and powerful. Roosevelt ran for office on a platform of isolationism, but he hated fascism and oppression, and unceasingly worked behind the scenes to aid the UK and get America into World War II. [PARAGRAPH:1]When Roosevelt first became President in 1932, the United States was in a crippling depression. Banks had closed and businesses had failed. Millions were unemployed and falling into poverty. To counter this malaise, Roosevelt enacted a series of policies that he called the "New Deal:" a sweeping program to bring recovery to business and agriculture, relief to the unemployed and to those in danger of losing businesses, farms and homes. [PARAGRAPH:1]Meanwhile, the Depression raged across the entire planet, and much of the rest of the world was degenerating into chaos. Japan was attacking China, while the two great dictators - Hitler and Stalin - were threatening to engulf Europe. The United States had largely withdrawn from world politics after World War I and the failure of the League of Nations, and few American politicians had the stomach to call for intervention. Roosevelt didn't, either, and in fact he ran for reelection on a platform of isolationism. [PARAGRAPH:1]However, Roosevelt sincerely believed that the United States would have to become involved in the conflict one way or another - he abhorred fascism and totalitarianism - and he feared that, left unchecked, Germany, Russia and Japan would become powerful enough to overwhelm everything in their path - including, eventually, the US. Thus he did everything in his power to ready the US for the upcoming conflict by dramatically increasing the size of the US armed forces, pitifully weakened after the end of World War I. Further, he gave as much aid as was politically feasible to England, whom he rightly saw as the unprepared US's chief protection from the German war machine. Meanwhile, he did his best to turn public opinion around in favor of more direct action. [PARAGRAPH:1]It is not clear that Roosevelt would have succeeded in that, if it weren't for Japan's attack against Pearl Harbor. Though casualties were extremely heavy, Pearl Harbor did "awake a sleeping giant," and at long last the citizens of the country realized their peril. And when Germany made the huge strategic blunder of declaring war on the United States shortly thereafter, Roosevelt was able to put all of the United States' massive industrial and military might into the conflict. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the war, Roosevelt showed himself to be a masterful international politician; the UK-Soviet-American alliance was shaky at best, and his adroit handling of Stalin and Churchill did much to keep things running (relatively) smoothly. Meanwhile his "fireside chats" kept the country firmly behind him, and world opinion in the allies' favor. It has been said that Hitler hated Roosevelt even more than Stalin or Churchill - high praise indeed. [PARAGRAPH:1]As a military leader Roosevelt was less sure-footed and the US made some early strategic blunders that could have been avoided. He learned quickly, however, and by the end of his life the US military machine was the most powerful that the world had ever seen. [PARAGRAPH:1]Roosevelt died in 1945, shortly before the war ended. His legacies of social welfare and international cooperation would dominate United States policies for the next half a century.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]富兰克林·罗斯福[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]美国总统[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1882-1945年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]富兰克林·罗斯福，美国第32任总统，以领导美国走出大萧条和赢得第二次世界战而闻名与世。他的身体在39岁时残废，但罗斯福显出不屈的勇气，决心克服他的弱点并最终达到目标。[PARAGRAPH:1]罗斯福是一个充满矛盾的人。虽然富有而有权势，罗斯福却为穷人与被压迫的人民所爱戴，同时被富裕阶层视为社会主义者。罗斯福奉行孤立主义，但却痛恨法西斯主义与压迫，他始终在幕后帮助英国，并最终使美国参战。[PARAGRAPH:1]1932年，当罗斯福第一次当选总统时，美国处于萧条边缘。银行倒闭、公司关门。数百万失业人口陷入贫穷的深渊。为了对抗这种形势，罗斯福施行了一系列政策，他称之为“新政”：商业与农业的大规模恢复计划，救助失业者与处于破产边缘的个人，农场和家庭。[PARAGRAPH:1]此时，大萧条已席卷全球，其他许多国家处于混乱境地。日本侵略中国，两大独裁者——希特勒和斯大林——意欲吞并整个欧洲。美国自一战后即极少参与国际事务，加上国联的失败，没有几个美国政治家想要理会世界政治。罗斯福却不一样，不过仍然在孤立思维主导美国政治时再次当选连任。[PARAGRAPH:1]然而，罗斯福的确相信美国以无论何种方式最终必将参战——他痛恨法西斯主义和极权主义——而且他担心不受限制的德国、俄国和日本将会变得足够强大以征服任何挡道的力量——这最终也将包括美国。于是他竭尽所能地扩充在一战后规模急剧萎缩的美国军队，使美国做好面对将来战争的充分准备。此外，他还尽力在政治上给予英国帮助，他视其为在美国完成准备前对抗德国战争机器的主要屏障。期间，他还努力扭转公众的观点，以支持更直接的行动。[PARAGRAPH:1]我们现在仍不清楚，如果日本没有偷袭珍珠港，罗斯福是否能够促成美国参战。尽管伤亡惨重，但是珍珠港事件唤醒了沉睡的巨人，最终这个国家的公民意识到了他们的危险。随着德国错误地向美国宣战，罗斯福终于能够将美国所有工业与军事力量投入战争。[PARAGRAPH:1]在战争期间，罗斯福展示出强力有手腕的国际政治家风采：虽然美英苏联盟不是那么牢靠，但他在斯大林与丘吉尔之间的斡旋保证了同盟的平稳运行。而他的“炉边谈话”使美国人民坚定地作为他的后盾，并让整个世界站在同盟国一边。据说相比斯大林和丘吉尔，希特勒更痛恨的人还是罗斯福——这事实上是一种赞美。[PARAGRAPH:1]作为军事领袖，罗斯福并不那么稳当。美国参战初期犯过几个本可避免的战略错误。不过他迅速学习，在他生命终结时，美军已成为有史以来最强大的军事力量。[PARAGRAPH:1]罗斯福死于1945年，大战结束的前夕。他在社会福利与国际合作方面的遗产足以引导美国战后半世纪的政策走向。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SALADIN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Saladin [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Ayyubid Sultan of Egypt [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD]c.1137-1193[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Saladin was a Kurdish Muslim warrior and self-proclaimed Sultan of Egypt. During his life he was the Defender of Islam and great opponent to the Crusaders. [PARAGRAPH:1]Of Kurdish descent, born in Mesopotamia, Saladin grew to become a religious warrior. During his youth he studied Sunni theology for ten years and then accompanied his uncle during his battles to conquer Egypt (ca. 1167). After his uncle died, Saladin succeeded him as vizier (minister of state) of Egypt, and he eventually proclaimed himself sultan (sovereign). [PARAGRAPH:1]During his reign Saladin conquered portions of North Africa, Yemen, Syria and Palestine. He mustered a large force of Muslims to defeat the Christian occupiers and retake the city of Jerusalem. He fought off a spirited attempt to retake the city (the Third Crusade) in 1189; in 1192 Saladin signed a treaty with the Crusaders, leaving them just a small strip of land in Syria on the coast of the Mediterranean. [PARAGRAPH:1]Saladin had a richly-deserved reputation for generosity and chivalry in battle. He treated his prisoners honorably, and was a man of his word. He was greatly admired by his European opponents, who barely acknowledged other Muslims as human. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]萨拉丁[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]埃及阿尤布王朝苏丹[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]约1137-1193年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]萨拉丁是一个库尔德族的穆斯林战士，后自立为埃及苏丹。他的一生致力于抗击十字军的入侵，成为伊斯兰教信仰的保护者。[PARAGRAPH:1]萨拉丁出生于美索不达米亚地区，属库尔德族人，复杂的经历最终使他成长为一名信仰斗士。在年轻的时候，他花了十年时间研究逊尼派教义，后跟随他的叔父参加了征服埃及的战争（1167年）。在他叔父死后，萨拉丁继任为埃及的维齐尔（国务大臣），并最终自立为苏丹（最高统治者）。[PARAGRAPH:1]萨拉丁在位期间征服了非洲北部大部分地区，以及也门、叙利亚和巴勒斯坦。他聚集起一支强大的穆斯林军队，击败基督教占领者，收复耶路撒冷。1189年，他再次击退了基督徒试图夺回圣城的尝试（第三次十字军东征）。1192年，他与十字军签订了和约，仅给对方保留了在叙利亚境内地中海沿岸的一小块狭长地带。[PARAGRAPH:1]萨拉丁由于为人慷慨好义，在战斗中富于骑士精神而受到广泛的赞誉。他对俘获的敌人以礼相待，从不食言。即使是他的欧洲敌人，对他也非常钦佩，要知道那时的欧洲人几乎不把穆斯林当人看。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MONTEZUMA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Montezuma [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Aztec Emperor [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] c.1480 - 1520[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Montezuma was Emperor of the Aztec nation from approximately 1502 until its dissolution in 1520. At the start of his reign he was considered a god and was absolute monarch of the entire known world; at the end of his reign he watched a small group of foreigners destroy his empire with ease. [PARAGRAPH:1]Montezuma ruled the Aztecs at the height of their power. His empire controlled a large portion of what is now modern Mexico. They had conquered virtually all other people around them, except for a few other nations, which they deliberately left free (so that they would have somebody left to make war against and to use as sacrifices). [PARAGRAPH:1]Though extremely rich and powerful, Montezuma's nation shamelessly squandered a great portion of its wealth and might. Much like the Egyptians, the Aztecs built huge monuments to their gods and held ever-increasing numbers of expensive religious festivals in which they slaughtered tens of thousands of prisoners and their own people. Montezuma himself lived in great splendor, his clothing made of silver, gold, and brightly-colored feathers. His court was brilliant, though much riddled with corruption and intrigue. [PARAGRAPH:1]In 1519, Hernando Cortes led 600 Spanish adventurers with 20 horses and 10 cannon to the shores of Mexico on a mission of exploration. Hearing of the great wealth of the Aztecs, he took his tiny force west, determined to conquer this massive nation of five million. At the start of the march Cortes burned his ships to ensure that his men would not desert him. [PARAGRAPH:1]The natives that first faced Cortes were primitive and divided. They were terrified of the Spanish "demonic" horses and cannon and broke before their accurate musket-fire. Cleverly exploiting their political divisions, Cortes then enlisted the defeated peoples' aid by promising them revenge against the hated Aztecs. [PARAGRAPH:1]Montezuma watched Cortes' approach with fear and bewilderment. His religion told him that one day the god Quetzalcoatl would return in the guise of a light-skinned bearded man, and when that day occurred, the Aztecs were to welcome him with open arms. Surely Cortes was Quetzalcoatl, else how could he command an army of demons? On the other hand, Cortes was clearly bent on the conquest of the empire - should Montezuma not oppose him? Perhaps the sinful Aztecs needed to be punished! [PARAGRAPH:1]Eventually, at the desperate urging of his advisors, Montezuma sent an army into the field against the invaders. But they were unable to offer effective resistance and Cortes' forces quickly overwhelmed them. The invaders then marched into the capital city Tenochtitlan virtually unopposed and took Montezuma prisoner. He was eventually killed during an uprising that pushed the invaders out of the city for more than a year. [PARAGRAPH:1]One has to wonder what would have happened if Montezuma had shown Cortes' courage and resolve and mobilized his people when the invaders first arrived. Could the Spanish have conquered Mexico against determined and organized resistance? Perhaps, but perhaps the natives would have held on long enough to learn to master the horse and gun - or at least their fear of them. If so, they would have become a formidable foe indeed.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]蒙特祖玛[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]阿兹特克皇帝[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]约1480-1520年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]蒙特祖玛是阿兹特克皇帝，他在位18年，从大约1502年开始，直到帝国在1520年的瓦解。在开始统治的时候，他被人们当作是神一般看待，是整个已知世界的绝对君主；但在后来，他却看着一小股外来者轻易地将他的帝国摧毁。[PARAGRAPH:1]在蒙特祖玛统治时期，阿兹特克已达到强盛的顶峰。他的帝国控制着现今墨西哥的绝大部分土地。他们实际上已经征服了周围的所有民族，只是故意留下一些小邦，这样就可以随时与之作战，以捕获的战俘作为祭品。[PARAGRAPH:1]拥有无数的财富和强大的国力，蒙特祖玛毫不吝惜地大肆进行挥霍。与埃及人很相似，阿兹特克人也为他们的神灵建造巨大的纪念碑，不断地举办代价昂贵的宗教庆典，在庆典上屠杀成千上万的战俘和本国人民。蒙特祖玛生活在巨大的光环之下，他的衣服是用黄金，白银和绚彩的羽毛织成。他的宫庭看上去辉煌华贵，内里却充斥着腐败和阴谋。[PARAGRAPH:1]1519年，赫尔南多·科尔特斯率领600名西班牙冒险家，20匹马及10门加农炮来到了墨西哥海岸。当听说阿兹特克巨大的财富时，他带领这支小小的军队向西进发，决定征服这个拥有五百万人口的国家。在开始远征之前，科尔特斯烧毁了所有的船只，以确保他手下不会临阵退缩。[PARAGRAPH:1]科尔特斯最初遇见的只是一些散居的原始部族，他们惧怕西班牙“魔鬼”般的战马和加农炮，在火枪精准的射击下迅速溃逃。科尔特斯巧妙地利用了这些民族的政治离心倾向，许诺帮助他们向压迫他们的阿兹特克人复仇，因而获得了这些战败者的协助。[PARAGRAPH:1]蒙特祖玛既恐惧又困惑地注视着科尔特斯的到来。宗教传说告诉他，在未来的某天，羽蛇神会装扮成一位皮肤白哲、满脸胡须的人来到这里，到那时候，阿兹特克人必须敞开双臂欢迎他。看来科尔特斯就是羽蛇神，否则他怎么会带着一支魔鬼般的军队？而另一方面，科尔特斯则决意要征服这个帝国——蒙特祖玛会不会进行抵抗呢？也许邪恶的阿兹特克人接受惩罚的时刻到了![PARAGRAPH:1]最终，在大臣的极力劝说下，蒙特祖玛派出了一支军队前往阻击入侵者。但是他们很快就被科尔特斯所击溃。入侵略者毫无阻碍地进入首都特诺奇蒂特兰，蒙特祖玛也沦为阶下囚。最终蒙特祖玛死于一场反抗西班牙人的起义，起义持续了一年并一度将入侵者赶出了这座城市。[PARAGRAPH:1]后人可能会猜想，如果蒙特祖玛能坚定信心，号召他的人民进行抵抗，那么科尔特斯第一次入侵的结果会是怎样。西班牙人能否打败充分动员起来的有组织的抵抗，能否依然征服墨西哥？也许如此，但是如果这个民族已经懂得骑马和使用枪炮，或者至少克服了对这些东西的恐惧。如果是这样，他们肯定会是更难以击败的对手。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_QIN_SHI_HUANG_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Qin Shi Huang [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]First Emperor of China [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] c247-210 BC [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Born "Chao Cheng," Qin Shi Huang was the first to unify all of China. His father was ruler of "Ch'in," one of the seven dominant states in China; upon his death Cheng ascended the throne at the age of 13. However, rule was actually exercised by his prime minister until, at 22, Cheng assumed control of state affairs and stripped the minister of his powers. [PARAGRAPH:1]Chen quickly instituted a series of agricultural and military reforms that greatly strengthened Ch'in. In the next 17 years, Chen defeated the other six great powers, uniting the divided lands for the first time. He then gave himself the title "Qin Shi Huang," which means "First Emperor." [PARAGRAPH:1]The emperor was politically astute, using bribery, blackmail and espionage as much as force of arms to achieve his goals. He ruthlessly suppressed Confucianism, which set limits on the Emperor's power, going so far as to burn all books relating to China's past. [PARAGRAPH:1]While emperor, Qin Shi Huang established a centralized administration and constructed a network of roads and canals, he also fought against the steppe peoples from the northern desert, and began construction of the Great Wall of China to set limits to their incursions. Though his reign lasted but ten years, it served to unite a people who would remain united for the next two millennia and beyond. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]嬴政[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]中国皇帝[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]约前259-前210年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]嬴政出生时原名“赵政”或“赵正”，他实现了中国本部的首次大一统。他的父王是战国七雄之一——秦国的统治者。在父王去世后，13岁的嬴政登上了王位。但是实际统治权则由相国吕不韦所控制，直到22岁时，嬴政才正式掌权并罢免了吕不韦的职位。[PARAGRAPH:1]亲政之后的嬴政实施了一系列农业和军事改革，加强了秦国的实力。经过17年的战争，秦国扫平其他六国，结束了分裂的局面。此后他首创皇帝尊号，自称“始皇帝”。[PARAGRAPH:1]秦始皇是一位狡猾的政治家，他除了使用武力，还通过贿赂、敲诈与奸细等各种手段达到自己的目标。他残酷地镇压儒学，因为儒士们试图限制皇权，为此他还下令焚毁了大批古代典籍。[PARAGRAPH:1]在秦始皇统治期间，中央集权制度开始确立，道路和运河网络开始修建，他还出兵驱逐了北方的游牧部落，并筑造长城以阻止其再次南下。虽然秦始皇的统治只持续了十年，但在此后两千余年的大部分时间里，中国都保持着统一的局面。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CHINESE_LEADER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Mao Zedong [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Dictator of China (Chairman of the Chinese Communist Party)[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1893-1976[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Born of fairly well-to-do peasant stock in Hunan, Mao was trained in Chinese classics and received a modern education. Observing the oppressive social conditions besetting China, Mao became one of the original members of the Chinese Communist Party, where he worked to recruit peasants to the new party. The party was then engaged in a running guerilla war with Chaing Kai-shek, ruler of "Nationalist" China. [PARAGRAPH:1]Now a commander of one of the People's armies, Mao found himself in danger of encirclement and destruction. He famously led his ragtag force of 90,000 men, women and children on the grueling "Long March," a 6,000 mile trek through some of the most unpleasant terrain China has to offer. He arrived at the city of Yan'an having lost more than half of his force, but emerging as the undisputed leader of the Chinese Communist party. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the Second Sino-Japanese War (1937-45), Mao fought both the Chinese Nationalist forces and the Japanese until the United States forced Japan's surrender in 1945. With the Japanese now out of the way, the communists concentrated their efforts against the Nationalists, and by 1949 they drove Chaing's forces off the mainland to the island province of Taiwan. [PARAGRAPH:1]In total control of (mainland) China, Mao sought to keep his people imbued with revolutionary vigor, and in 1958 he instituted his "Great Leap Forward." This piece of political thinking resulted in the deaths of approximately twenty million Chinese, and easily set back China's development by 30 years. Not yet satisfied, in 1966 Mao and his wife initiated the "Cultural Revolution," a ten-year period in which China's artists, intellectuals, moderate politicians and other unenlightened or unlucky folk were imprisoned and killed or sent out to work the fields until they died or were judged "reeducated" by the workers. This adventure in social engineering killed perhaps one million people and further delayed China's emergence as a great world power. [PARAGRAPH:1]Mao died in 1976, beloved by his people. To summarize him as a man, it could be said that Mao was a great war leader, an exceptional political infighter, and an unbelievably brutal dictator.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]毛泽东[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]中国领导人（中国共产党主席）[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1893-1976年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]毛泽东出生在湖南的一个富农家庭，他既接受过传统的私塾教育，也接受过现代的学校教育。为了改变中国黑暗的社会现状，毛泽东加入了初建的中国共产党，成为其最早的成员之一，此后他负责组织农会，并吸收了许多农民加入共产党。不久，中国共产党发动了反对蒋介石统治的国民党政权的游击战争。[PARAGRAPH:1]作为中国工农红军的指挥者，毛泽东在强敌环伺的处境下展现出极高的军事才能。他领导九万红军（包括妇女和孩子）进行了长达6000英里的“长征”，沿途克服了重重艰难险阻。虽然损失了超过半数的部队，但最终还是成功地到达陕北建立了新的根据地，并从此确立了在中国共产党内的领导地位。[PARAGRAPH:1]在第二次中日战争时期（1937-1945），毛泽东领导共产党与国民党合作抗战，其间也多次与国民党发生冲突，直到1945年美国迫使日本宣布投降。日本被打败后，共产党继续同国民党政权作战，到1949年基本解放了中国大陆，蒋介石的军队被赶到了台湾岛。[PARAGRAPH:1]中华人民共和国成立之后，毛泽东希望进一步鼓动人们的革命热情，1958年他发起了“大跃进”，这场政治运动引发了持续三年的“困难时期”，据说造成了两千万人的非正常死亡，使中国的发展倒退了数十年。此后，毛泽东又于1966年发动了持续十年的“文化大革命”，导致大批艺术家、知识分子、温和派政治家以及其他“落后分子”以及无辜者入狱、死亡或是被迫下放劳动，接受“再教育”。这些激进的社会运动据说造成了上百万人失去生命，并使国民经济一度面临崩溃。[PARAGRAPH:1]毛泽东去世于1976年，到现在他仍然受到许多人的爱戴和怀念。如果要对毛泽东的一生进行总结，可以说：他是一位伟大的战略家，一位杰出的政治家，也是一位无情的专政者。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HATSHEPSUT_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Hatshepsut [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Pharaoh of Egypt [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] c. 1500 - c. 1450 BC[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Hatshepsut was born the daughter of King Thutmose I and Queen Ahmose. She became Queen when her father died and her husband (and half-brother) Thutmose II became Pharaoh. She and Thutmose II had a daughter together, but no son, and Thutmose II declared a son he had with a palace concubine to be his heir and successor. Thutmose II died in his early thirties while his son was still a child, and in her early teens Hatshepsut became the young pharaoh's regent, and thus ruler of all Egypt. [PARAGRAPH:1]Apparently, Hatshepsut liked the job and decided that she wanted to keep it. Declaring that the gods had appointed her as her husband's successor, she declared herself "King of Upper and Lower Egypt" and began wearing all of the trappings of a King, including a false beard. She didn't kill her husband's son, and some evidence suggests that they became co-rulers, Thutmose III in charge of the military, while Hatshepsut concentrated upon improving Egypt's commerce and infrastructure, and upon religious matters. [PARAGRAPH:1]Hatshepsut is known to have greatly expanded Egypt's commerce with Asia, Nubia and Libya, and she sent expeditions to far-off places that Egypt had never traded with before. She repaired many of Egypt's temples and secular buildings that had been severely damaged by invasion in years past. She constructed many obelisks and statues, and a striking mortuary building for herself and her father. [PARAGRAPH:1]Hatshepsut died sometime around 1450 BC, apparently of natural causes.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]哈特谢普苏特[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]埃及法老[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]约前1500-约前1450年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]哈特谢普苏特是法老图特摩斯一世和王后阿赫摩斯的女儿。在父王死后，她成为王后，她的丈夫（也是异母兄弟）图特摩斯二世成为法老。她与图特摩斯二世生有一女，但没有儿子，最终图特摩斯二世将一位妃子为他所生的儿子指定为继承人。图特摩斯去世时年仅三旬，他的儿子尚未成年，才十几岁的哈特谢普苏特也就当上了小法老的摄政，成为整个埃及的统治者。[PARAGRAPH:1]显然，哈特谢普苏特对权力非常热衷，并努力维护已有的地位。她声称众神已指定她作为她丈夫的继承人，宣布自己是“上埃及与下埃及的法老”，并开始穿着法老的服饰，戴上假胡须。但她并没有杀死她丈夫的儿子，有证据表明两者一度共同执政，图特摩斯三世负责军事，哈特谢普苏特则专注于商业贸易、国内建设和宗教事务。[PARAGRAPH:1]据记载，哈特谢普苏特大大地拓展了埃及同西亚、努比亚和利比亚地区的贸易，并向以往从无联系的遥远地区派出许多商队。她下令修复了许多因多年战争而遭破坏的神庙与世俗建筑。她主持建造了许多方尖碑和塑像，以及一座安葬自己和她父亲的巨大陵墓。[PARAGRAPH:1]哈特谢普苏特约于前1450年去世，据记载应属自然死亡。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Elizabeth [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Virgin Queen of England [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1533-1603[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Born to King Henry VIII and Anne Boleyn, who her father had executed for failing to give him a male heir, Elizabeth's early life was filled with danger. Growing up an unwanted daughter of a insane father who was destroying England's ties to the Catholic Church and engaging in civil war so that he could legally marry another woman (several other women, in fact), Elizabeth had to use all of her wits to survive. [PARAGRAPH:1]Elizabeth received an excellent education at the hands of various tutors, including the great scholars of the day. She was an outstanding student, and could speak five languages fluently. [PARAGRAPH:1]When King Henry VIII died, the throne passed to his young son, Edward. At fifteen Elizabeth was implicated in a plot to overthrow him. She came close to being executed, surviving only because she was able to convince her skeptical interrogators that she knew nothing of the plot. [PARAGRAPH:1]When King Edward died in 1553, Elizabeth's older sister, Mary, assumed the throne. An ardent Catholic, Mary was quite unpopular with a number of Protestant noblemen, who attempted unsuccessfully to overthrow her in 1554. Once again Elizabeth was implicated, but once again she talked her way out of execution. [PARAGRAPH:1]Queen Mary died in 1558, and Elizabeth became Queen. Elizabeth was an extraordinary ruler. She established the Protestant Church as the official Church of England. However, she attempted to stem the persecution of Catholics in the country - at least as much as was possible when the Catholic nobility were actively plotting her demise. She restored the debased currency of England, and she made England a center of culture, where great artists like William Shakespeare flourished. [PARAGRAPH:1]Elizabeth used all of the tools available to her to achieve her goals. She received countless offers of marriage from nobility and indeed from kings across Europe. But she accepted none of them, instead using her unmarried state to control her friends and foes alike; if one faction got too strong, she could drive them back into line by suggesting that she was considering marrying someone from an opposing faction. [PARAGRAPH:1]Militarily, Catholic Spain was England's greatest threat. Spain was the great continental power of the day, and its leader, King Philip, had upon more than one occasion expressed the intent of invading England. In 1588 he tried, building a huge armada to conquer the upstart nation. Elizabeth quickly organized the country's navy to fend off the fleet, and by a combination of superior tactics, ship design, and some foul weather at just the right moment, they defeated the Spanish foe. England was not to be seriously threatened with invasion for about 400 years. [PARAGRAPH:1]Elizabeth died in 1603, having left her country in far better state. No better words can serve to describe her than her own: "I know I have the body of a weak and feeble woman, but I have the heart and stomach of a king."</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]伊丽莎白[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]英国女王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1533-1603年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]亨利八世国王与安妮·博林之女，她的母亲因未能生育男性继承人而被丈夫处决。伊丽莎白的早年生活充满各种危险。她那患有精神病的父亲为断绝英格兰和天主教会的联系不顾陷入内战的危险，如此他便能与另一名女子（实际上不只一位）合法结婚。作为这样一个父亲的不被期望的女儿，要想生存下去就必须用上自己的全部智慧。[PARAGRAPH:1]伊丽莎白受到很好的教育，她有很多家庭教师，其中包括一些当时的大学者。她是一名优秀的学生，能流利地说五种语言。[PARAGRAPH:1]亨利八世国王死后，他的小儿子爱德华继承王位。15岁时，伊丽莎白被牵连进一起推翻爱德华的阴谋之中。要不是她极力使审讯者相信她对此事一无所知，未来的女王差点被处死。[PARAGRAPH:1]爱德华国王于1553年去世，伊丽莎白的姐姐玛丽继承了王位。作为一名狂热的天主教徒，玛丽很不受新教贵族的欢迎。他们在1554年曾试图推翻她，但失败了。伊丽莎白又一次被牵连进阴谋之中，并且又一次逃脱死刑的阴影。[PARAGRAPH:1]玛丽女王在1558年去世，伊丽莎白随后继位。伊丽莎白是一位非凡的君主。她重新确立了圣公会的英格兰国教地位。虽然她尽力阻止对天主教徒的迫害，但那些天主教贵族仍密谋推翻她。她重建了英国货币的信誉，使英国成为一个文化中心，莎士比亚等伟大的艺术家活跃一时。[PARAGRAPH:1]为达到目的，伊丽莎白可以使用任何手段。她收到过欧洲各国国王和贵族的许多求婚，但全被她拒绝。她利用自己未婚的条件来控制朋友和敌人：如果某一派系过于强大，她会通过暗示和另一派系的某人结婚来牵制这个派系。[PARAGRAPH:1]军事上，天主教西班牙是英格兰最大的威胁。西班牙当时是欧洲大陆上的强国，而菲利普国王也在多个场合表示过入侵英格兰的决心。1588年，菲利普建立了一支庞大舰队试图征服这个暴发户国家。伊丽莎白迅速组织英格兰海军拦截这支舰队。最后，在出色的战略指导，舰船设计和适时的恶劣天气等一系列因素综合作用下，英国击败了西班牙无敌舰队。英格兰在此后400年中不再有被入侵的严重威胁。[PARAGRAPH:1]女王于1603年驾崩，身后留下的国家状况远好于过往任何时代。没有什么词句能比她自己所说的更能描述其本人：“我虽身为柔弱女子，却有一副国王的心肠。”</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_VICTORIA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Victoria [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]British Queen [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1819 - 1901[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Victoria served as English monarch for 64 years - the longest reign in English history. She took the throne at 18, after the death of her uncle, King William IV. At 20 she married Prince Albert, to whom she bore nine children. The couple was very much in love and co-ruled for twenty years. She and Albert were quite interested in science, and in 1851 they inspired the hugely successful Great Exhibition in the Crystal Palace, the proceeds going to establish a number of public museums, including the Albert and Victoria museum; which remains one of the world's finest museums even today. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the early years of her reign Victoria was a quite active monarch, and she won the hearts of her people with her modesty and practicality. It was during this period that she performed her greatest service to the British people: she oversaw the transition of the British throne to a constitutional monarchy. [PARAGRAPH:1]When Albert died in 1861, Victoria was devastated. She went into permanent mourning, retiring from the day-to-day rule of her country and secluding herself on the Isle of Wight, where she was increasingly involved in somewhat dubious spiritual exploration. Her self-pity was legendary - a remarkable change from her youthful modesty and enthusiasm. [PARAGRAPH:1]Victoria's isolation and indifference to the management of her country left room for extremely talented prime ministers, such as Gladstone and Disraeli, to guide Great Britain into a golden age of prosperity and expansion. During this period the Empire came to dominate half of the world's area and population - including India and much of the Orient, as well as large chunks of Africa, Asia, North America and a goodly portion of the Pacific islands. [PARAGRAPH:1]Victoria believed that Great Britain had a mandate from heaven to bring the ignorant peoples of the world beneath the protection of the British flag. She felt that she personally had a duty to these untutored people, to educate and clothe them, and most importantly, to bring them to the church. [PARAGRAPH:1]During her reign, Great Britain grew from a moderate European power into the second greatest empire the world has ever known (exceeded only by the Mongol empire of Genghis Khan), an Empire on which "the sun never set," far overshadowing Imperial Rome in size and might. The Diamond Jubilee, celebrating Victoria's 60th year as monarch, dwarfed in pomp and majesty anything that a puny Caesar could have ever mustered.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]维多利亚[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]英国女王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1819-1901年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]维多利亚在位时间长达64年——是英国历史上在位最久的统治者。在叔父威廉四世死后，18岁的维多利亚登上王位。在20岁时与阿尔伯特亲王结婚，为他生了九个孩子。夫妇二人相亲相爱，共同统治了二十年。她与阿尔伯特都热衷于科学，1851年，他们在水晶宫举办了一次成功的大博览会，此后又建立了许多公共博物馆，包括阿尔伯特与维多利亚搏物馆，至今仍是世界上最好的博物馆之一。[PARAGRAPH:1]在统治初期，维多利亚是一位非常积极有为的君主，以其谦逊务实的作风赢得了人民的爱戴。在这一时期，他为英国人民作出了一项伟大的贡献：完成英国政体的君主立宪制转型。[PARAGRAPH:1]1861年阿尔伯特的去世对维多利亚是一个沉重的打击。她一直为他伤感不已，不再过问国事，并隐居到怀特岛，在那里寻求精神上的安宁与归宿。从当初的谦逊热忱到后来的自怜冷漠，如此剧烈的性格转变犹如传奇故事一般。[PARAGRAPH:1]维多利亚统治后期对国家政治事务的漠不关心，正好为许多杰出的首相留出了充分施展才能的空间，例如格雷斯顿和狄士累利，并将大不列颠引入了繁荣与扩张的黄金时代。在这一时期，大英帝国控制了全世界将近一半的土地和人口——包括整个印度次大陆、中东，以及非洲、亚洲、北美及太平洋诸岛的大片地区。[PARAGRAPH:1]维多利亚相信大英帝国的辉煌是出于天意，是为了将世界上弱小的人民置于米字旗的保护之下。她感到自己有义务帮助这些无助者，教育他们，供给他们衣食，最重要的是，引导他们前往教堂。[PARAGRAPH:1]在她统治期间，大不列颠从一个欧洲中等强权成长为有史以来第二大的广阔帝国（仅次于成吉思汗建立的蒙古帝国），一个“日不落”的帝国，其面积和力量都远远超过了当初的罗马帝国。为维多利亚统治60周年而举行的钻石大庆典是如此的盛大豪华，足以使曾经不可一世的罗马皇帝们相形见绌。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_LOUISXIV_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Louis XIV [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of France [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1643-1715[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Born to King Louis XIII of France, Louis XIV was raised in the most opulent court in Europe. His every need was catered to, and he was given an excellent education, even if he was too lazy and spoiled to appreciate it. Louis XIII died when his son was five, and the regency passed to the queen mother, Anne of Austria. For the next 18 years she ruled France with the able assistance of Cardinal Mazarin, who may or may not have also been her lover, while Louis lived in pampered splendor. [PARAGRAPH:1]It was upon Mazarin's death in 1661 that the 22-year-old Louis XIV began to take an active interest in ruling his country. Much to everyone's surprise, he was good at it. First he gathered all of the power into his own hands, bypassing the old bureaucratic patronage system that Mazarin and his predecessors had used. He enticed the great nobles to his court, where he heaped upon them titles, honorary positions, and financial rewards, while at the same time undermining their actual power. In Louis' court, great noblemen - whose parents had fought for the crown of France itself - fought each other for the privilege of watching Louis shave. [PARAGRAPH:1]In person Louis was said to possess a great natural dignity and bearing. He was unfailingly courteous and usually honest, but he could dissimulate with the best of them when need-be. [PARAGRAPH:1]During his early reign Louis's court was known for its debauchery, and Louis himself had several mistresses. As his reign progressed, however, Louis became more devout, and he even married his last mistress (although in secret). Louis also became a patron of the arts, and literature and painting flourished under his rule. He built many great buildings and palaces, including the grand palace at Versailles. [PARAGRAPH:1]Despite France's wealth, the country remained virtually bankrupt, not only because it had to pay for all the gifts that Louis gave his favorites, but, more importantly, it had to pay for all the wars of conquest that Louis embarked upon. Although a sound and thoughtful ruler at home, Louis had a great thirst for international "glory" - which in his terms meant victory on the battlefield. He constantly fought his neighbors, often for the most trivial reasons, gaining little but glory from the wars. Though he left the army and navy in splendid condition, he left his country's treasury bare. [PARAGRAPH:1]Louis XIV died after ruling France for 72 years.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]路易十四[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]法国国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1643-1715年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]路易十四是路易十三之子，自小生活在全欧洲最豪华的宫庭之中。他的任何需要均有人专门负责，他受到非常良好的教育，虽然懒惰和溺爱使他对所有这一切都不以为然。路易十三去世时路易十四年仅五岁，因此由其母奥地利的安妮摄政。其后18年安妮太后在红衣主教马扎林（也许也是她的情人）的得力辅佐下统治着法国，路易则继续着奢侈无度的生活。[PARAGRAPH:1]马扎林于1661年去世，此时22岁的路易十四才开始对统治国家产生兴趣。令所有人吃惊的是，他相当擅长此道。首先他将所有权力掌握到自己手中，架空了马扎林及其前任所建立的旧官僚体系。他将大贵族们集中于自己的宫庭，给予他们成堆的头衔、荣誉称号、金钱奖赏，同时减少他们的实际权力。在路易的宫庭中，大贵族们——他们的前辈曾为法王立下战功——相互钩心斗角，只是为了能够获得陪同路易刮脸的特权。[PARAGRAPH:1]路易被认为具有天生的尊贵气度。对待他人谦和有礼，并相当真诚，但在必要时也会变得非常狡诈机变。[PARAGRAPH:1]在早期，路易的宫庭以放纵的风气而闻名，路易本人拥有多位情妇。但到后来，路易的为人趋向正派，甚至决定与他的最后一位情妇结婚（虽然是秘密进行的）。路易还是一位慷慨的艺术资助人，在他统治期间，文学和绘画杰作不断涌现。他建造了许多宏伟的宫殿建筑，包括著名的凡尔赛宫。[PARAGRAPH:1]虽然法国在表面上十分富庶，但实际上已面临破产，除了路易对宠臣们大笔的昂贵赏赐，更重要的原因则是路易所发动的一系列对外战争。虽然在治理内政时很有头脑，路易在寻求国际上的“荣耀”（这一词语对他来说就是战场上的胜利）时总是贪心过度。他不断与其邻国交战，而且常常只是为了一些细小的纠纷，除了“荣耀”没有获得多少实际利益。虽然他使法国陆海军称雄欧洲，但却为此耗尽了国库的财富。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]路易十四统治法国前后达72年之久。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_NAPOLEON_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Napoleon [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Emperor of France [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1769 - 1821[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Napoleon Bonaparte was born in Corsica where he entered military school at ten, displaying a great aptitude for mathematics, history, and geography, as well as total indifference to literature and the humanities. At fourteen he was commissioned as a sub-lieutenant in an artillery regiment. When the French revolution broke out, Napoleon sided with the Revolutionaries and was appointed lieutenant-colonel of artillery, where he quickly made a name for himself as a successful commander. By 1794 he was a brigadier-general, and by 1795 he was appointed command of the French Army of the Interior. He was 25 years of age. [PARAGRAPH:1]Over the next few years Napoleon led French armies, in defense of the new Republic, to major victories over various continental foes, including the extremely powerful Austrians. In 1798 Napoleon sailed against Egypt where he won great land victories; however, the British navy destroyed the French fleet in Egypt, crippling his force. In 1800 Napoleon abandoned his weakened army and returned to France. [PARAGRAPH:1]Napoleon found Paris in a state of political turmoil, which he quickly took advantage of by overthrowing the government and making himself First Consul, with dictator-like power over all of France. An exceptional administrator, he rapidly reorganized the government, repealed the more radical and violent laws of the Revolution, and reopened the churches, gaining the love and respect of the French people, exhausted by years of revolution and chaos. [PARAGRAPH:1]However, France was still at war with most of Europe, and Napoleon once again took to the battlefields, where he won stunning victories against Austria, causing that country and England to make peace. In celebration Napoleon quickly declared himself Emperor and consol for Life. [PARAGRAPH:1]England remained nervous of France's imperial intentions, and war resumed in 1803, with England destroying French shipping on the sea and France putting together a great invasion fleet in the unsuccessful hope of occupying the British Isles. Other countries were equally alarmed by France's actions and they joined the English. France soon found itself facing a daunting alliance that included England, Austria, Russia and Sweden. Acting with amazing speed and cunning, Napoleon used his "interior lines" to concentrate his forces against the dispersed enemy. He rapidly marched across Europe, capturing the capital of Austria and then crushing the Russian forces at the battle of Austerlitz. Austria sued for peace once again, this time giving up all territory in Italy and along the Adriatic. [PARAGRAPH:1]For several more years Napoleon would defeat every foe that came against him. He moved his forces with unbelievable alacrity, and he was always able to bring them against the enemy's weakest spot. He crushed the Prussians, the Spanish, and the Austrians yet again. He tried to improve his political position by marrying his various relatives into the great families of Europe, with minor success. [PARAGRAPH:1]Eventually Napoleon decided that he would never be safe in Europe as long as Russia, aided by the perfidious English, was on his flank, so he led half a million men to Moscow. The Russian forces retreated before his advance, taking or burning anything that might be of use to the invaders, while in the rear Cossack raiders destroyed his supply lines. He did reach and capture Moscow, but once again the Russians had removed or burnt anything there that might feed his men. By September he was forced to retreat, his army reduced to 120,000 weary and starving men. By the end of November his forces had been further reduced to 20,000. Napoleon had lost 96%% of his army. [PARAGRAPH:1]Upon returning to Paris, Napoleon immediately recruited another army of 350,000, but his image of invulnerability was gone and all Europe rose against him. Prussia, Russia and Austria allied against him. England threw more troops into contested Spain. Though Napoleon was to again win famous victories, his enemies sensed victory and continued their relentless attacks. Eventually the allies drove their way into Paris, and Napoleon abdicated. For his trouble he was given ruler ship of the island of Elba, along with an income of six million francs, to be paid by France. [PARAGRAPH:1]But this wasn't enough for Napoleon. Ten months later he re-entered France. The populace immediately went over to his side and he quickly regained his power and titles. He raised an army of 125,000 and headed to Belgium, where an English and Prussian force awaited him. At Waterloo, Napoleon was finally and irrevocably defeated by the English/Prussian forces under the leadership of English general Wellington. This time he was confined for life at the island of Sainte-Hélène, a thousand miles from the coast of Africa. He died there in 1821.[PARAGRAPH:1]Napoleon was one of the most brilliant generals of all time. He moved his troops with astounding rapidity, and he always knew exactly where to strike in order to cause the most damage. He turned out to be a decent ruler and France flourished under his control (until his endless wars sapped her strength and will to fight). His only major flaw was his unending drive for conquest and domination, driving other powers to oppose him for their own preservation. In the end, he just couldn't beat everybody. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]拿破仑[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]法国皇帝[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1769-1821年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]拿破仑·波拿巴生于科西嘉岛，十岁时进入当地军事学校，在数学，历史和地理上极具天赋，对文学和人文学科则完全漠不关心。14岁那年他被委任为一个炮兵团的少尉。当法国革命爆发时，拿破仑站在革命派一边并升任炮兵中校，他迅速建立起了能征善战的名望。1794年时他还只是一位准将，到1795年就受命指挥整个法国陆军，那时他才25岁。[PARAGRAPH:1]之后的几年里拿破仑领导法国军队保护新成立的共和国，击败了许多反对者，包括非常强大的奥地利。1798年拿破仑渡海远征埃及，取得了辉煌的胜利；然而，英国海军却在埃及战胜了法国舰队，削弱了他的力量。1800年，拿破仑抛下他的军队回到法国。[PARAGRAPH:1]拿破仑发现巴黎正处于政治骚乱之中，政府已被推翻，于是他宣布自己为第一执政，成为整个法国的独裁者。作为非常时期的统治者，他迅速重组政府，废除了革命党人过于激进和暴力的宪法，重新开放了教堂，取得了被多年的革命和暴乱耗尽心力的法国人民的热爱和尊敬。[PARAGRAPH:1]但是，此时的法国仍与欧洲各国处于交战状态，于是拿破仑再次来到战场，取得了对奥地利的决定性胜利，迫使该国和英国接受和平条约。为了庆祝胜利拿破仑立刻宣布自己为皇帝和终身执政。[PARAGRAPH:1]法兰西皇帝的举动使得英国惴惴不安，战争在1803年再次爆发，英国摧毁了法国舰队，使得法国对英伦三岛的大举入侵成为泡影。其它国家也对法国的举动感到惊恐而加入英国的同盟。法国马上发现自己正面对一个包括英国、奥地利、俄国和瑞典的强大同盟。拿破仑的行动快速而巧妙，他用内线作战的方式集中部队打击分散的敌人。他迅速穿越整个欧洲，占领了奥地利首都，紧接着在奥斯特里茨战役中击溃了俄国军队。奥地利再次被迫求和，并放弃其在意大利和亚得里亚海沿岸的所有领土。[PARAGRAPH:1]在几年时间里拿破仑击败了所有敢于反抗他的国家。他的部队拥有难以置信的机动力，他总能带领他们打击敌人最薄弱的环节。他连续击败了普鲁士人、西班牙人和奥地利人。为了提升自己的政治地位，他让他的亲戚和欧洲众多高贵的家族联姻，在这方面他也略有小成。[PARAGRAPH:1]最后拿破仑坚信只要有俄国存在，又有背信弃义的英国攻击他的侧翼，他在欧洲就永远无法获得安全保障，于是率领50万大军向莫斯科进攻。俄国军队在他进军前就撤退了，烧毁了所有入侵者可资利用的东西，后方的哥萨克骑兵则不断骚扰破坏他的补给线。他到达并占领了莫斯科，俄国人却再次转移或烧毁了所有可能供应他部队的物资。到9月时他被迫撤退，他的部队大量减员，只剩下12万名受冻挨饿的老弱残兵。到11月底他的部队只剩下两万人。拿破仑损失了96%%的士兵。[PARAGRAPH:1]一回到巴黎，拿破仑立即招募了一支35万人的新军，但他不可战胜的神话已经被打破，整个欧洲都开始反对他。普鲁士、俄国和奥地利再次结盟对抗他。英国则在西班牙战场上投入更多部队。虽然他再次取得辉煌的胜利，他的敌人却从失败中恢复，继续无情的攻击。最后联军进入巴黎，拿破仑被迫退位。由于他的罪责他被流放到厄尔巴岛，由法国提供六百万法郎作为补偿。[PARAGRAPH:1]但拿破仑并没有屈服。十个月后他回到法国。人民群众立刻转投他的麾下，他迅速重获了力量和头衔。他建立起一支12万5千人的部队并向比利时进军，那里英国和普鲁士军队正等着他。在滑铁卢，拿破仑最终遭到无法挽回的失败，击败他的是英国将军威灵顿率领的英普联军。这次他被流放到距非洲海岸一千英里的圣赫勒拿岛，他的余生也在那里度过。他于1821年在那里去世。[PARAGRAPH:1]拿破仑是有史以来最卓越的军事统帅。他的部队来去如风，他总是明白攻击哪里可以给敌人造成最大损失。他也是一个不错的统治者，法国在他的治理下兴旺繁荣（直到他无尽的战争侵蚀了她的力量并激起了反抗）。他唯一的重大弱点是对征服和统治无止境的渴望，使得其他势力为了保存自己都站到了他的对立面。直到最后，他无法击败所有人。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_FREDERICK_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Frederick [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of Prussia [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1712-1786[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Frederick was born to Frederick William I, the tyrannical and cultured King of Prussia. The king held his son in great contempt, despising him for his lack of interest in leadership and war; the younger Frederick instead preferred to study literature and the arts. At the age of 18 Frederick attempted to flee to England, but he was captured and brought back to his extremely angry father, who forced him to watch the beheading of his close friend and accomplice, Lieutenant Katz. He apparently was able to get back into his father's good graces, and several years later he married a German noblewoman at his father's request. [PARAGRAPH:1]For the next several years Frederick enjoyed the life of a wealthy man of letters. He maintained an active correspondence with various scholars from around Europe, including the brilliant French writer; Voltaire. He wrote "Anti-Machiavel," a lively refutation of Machiavelli's; "The Prince." Frederick assumed the throne of Prussia upon his father's death in 1740. [PARAGRAPH:1]Once in power, Frederick showed himself to be both a ruthless pragmatist and a brilliant campaigner. Seeking to increase the size of his empire, over the next 23 years he fought a series of wars against his neighbors, notably Austria, who was often allied with Russia and France. With the support of England he won a series of significant battles against his foes, but he was eventually worn down and soundly defeated, and Berlin was occupied by an allied Austrian-Russian army. [PARAGRAPH:1]Reportedly on the verge of suicide, Frederick was saved by the timely death of the Russian Tsarina, who was replaced by the pro-Prussian Peter III. Facing the combined power of Russia and Prussia, Austria was forced to accede to Frederick's demands and give up all claims to Upper and Lower Silesia. The two European monarchs then dismembered Poland, making Prussia the most powerful force in Europe for many years to come. [PARAGRAPH:1]Domestically, Frederick was the model of an "enlightened despot." He instituted important legal and penal reforms, created new industries, improved education, and accomplished internal improvements such as drainage projects, roads, and canals. He improved the lot of his own serfs (but did nothing to curtail the nobility's power over them). [PARAGRAPH:1]During his rule Frederick maintained his friendship with the enlightened men of Europe. His midnight soirees in Potsdam were famous for the great men they attracted. Frederick was quite famous for his sharp wit and caustic tongue; he more than held his own in their company. [PARAGRAPH:1]Frederick died in 1786, leaving Prussia more powerful and prosperous than when he first gained power. Upon his death, Frederick's nephew Frederick William II inherited the throne of Prussia.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]腓特烈[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]普鲁士国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1712-1786年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]腓特烈是生性残暴而又富有文化修养的普鲁士国王腓特烈·威廉一世的儿子。年轻的腓特烈丝毫不热衷于权术和战争，却对文学和艺术很感兴趣，这使得国王对他的儿子很不以为然。18岁时腓特烈企图逃到英国去，却被抓回到他盛怒的父亲身边，命令他看着他的密友和同谋卡茨中尉被斩首。后来他又重获父亲的宠爱，几年后在父亲的授意下娶了一位德国贵族小姐。[PARAGRAPH:1]之后的几年里腓特烈通过书信享受着丰富的精神生活。他和来自全欧洲的学者们保持通信，包括才华横溢的法国作家，伏尔泰。他反对马基雅弗利，写了一篇生动的文章驳斥马基雅弗利的“君主论”。1740年腓特烈在父亲死后继承了普鲁士王位。[PARAGRAPH:1]大权在握后，腓特烈就显现出了与生俱来的无情的实用主义和超群的军事能力。为了扩张他的王国，在接下来的23年里他不断与邻国征战，尤其是对奥地利，这个国家经常与俄国和法国联盟。在英国的支持下他赢得一系列辉煌的胜利，可是最后还是被彻底击垮了，连柏林也被俄奥联军占领。[PARAGRAPH:1]据说在腓特烈绝望得快自杀时，俄国女沙皇的突然去世挽救了他，继位的彼得三世曾经是普鲁士人。面对俄国和普鲁士的联合力量，奥地利被迫接受普鲁士的条件，放弃了对上下西里西亚的领土要求。然后这两位欧洲国王瓜分了波兰，使得普鲁士在之后许多年里成为欧洲最强大的力量。[PARAGRAPH:1]在国内政策上，腓特烈是一个标准的“开明君主”。他制定了重要的法律并修订了刑法，新建了许多工业，改善了教育体系，完成了许多公共设施的建设，包括排水工程，道路网和运河。他改善了许多农奴的生活（不过在缩减压在他们头上的贵族的权力方面并没有多少作为）。[PARAGRAPH:1]腓特烈在位期间和很多欧洲开明人士保持了友谊。他在波茨坦的午夜晚会吸引了很多社会名流参加。腓特烈以他出众的智慧和善辩的口才出名，在他们的圈子里很受欢迎。[PARAGRAPH:1]腓特烈死于1786年，留下一个比他刚掌权时强大得多，繁荣得多的普鲁士。他去世后，其侄腓特烈·威廉二世继承了普鲁士的王位。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_BISMARCK_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Bismarck [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Chancellor of the German Empire [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1815 - 1898[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Otto von Bismarck, also known as the "Iron Chancellor," is perhaps the most significant figure in German history. During his long political career, Bismarck unified Germany and founded the German Empire. During his 30-year chancellorship, Germany was transformed from a weak and loose confederation of states into a powerful united country that would come to dominate continental Europe. [PARAGRAPH:1]Descended of a noble Prussian family, Bismarck certainly inherited the arrogance of the Prussian Junker class. He was a poor student who excelled at dueling and was quite a historian and linguist. However, he spent much of his time drinking with the other aristocrats in their exclusive fraternity. [PARAGRAPH:1]Unable to accept the discipline required for military service, Bismarck instead entered the Prussian diplomatic corps, where his skill quickly brought him to the attention of the Prussian Kaiser. Appointed to the German Federal Diet (congress), Bismarck worked to increase Prussian status and power within Germany. Eventually he would rise to the rank of Prussian Prime Minister, where after years of long struggle, he succeeded in unifying Germany under Prussian rule. Bismarck would accomplish this through crafty diplomacy, aided by a series of successful wars. [PARAGRAPH:1]Once Germany was unified, Bismarck's main foreign policy aim was to keep the peace in Europe, mostly by isolating France, Germany's historic enemy. In this he was largely successful. He engineered a war with France in 1870 in order to draw several German states (Bavaria, Baden, and others) into the German empire. In the war, France was quickly defeated. [PARAGRAPH:1]Having achieved his objective of acquiring the German states, Bismarck argued for fairly lenient terms, but the German people and military wanted more, and he was forced to annex the French provinces of Alsace and Loraine. Bismarck knew that this would be trouble in the long run - before the war he had told a colleague, "Supposing we did win Alsace, we would have to maintain our conquest and to keep Strasbourg perpetually garrisoned. This would be an impossible position, for in the end the French would find new allies - and we might have a bad time." This, of course, is exactly what happened in World War I, where Germany had a very bad time indeed. [PARAGRAPH:1]Although an ardent conservative and monarchist, Bismarck was the first European leader to promote a system of social security for workers. He rebuilt the German monetary system, introducing for the first time a single currency. He also helped fabricate the new country's code of civil and commercial law. His benevolence was not universal, however; while emancipating the Jews, Bismarck also enacted laws aimed at restraining Germany's Catholics. [PARAGRAPH:1]As a diplomat, Bismarck's greatest weakness was his single-minded desire to weaken France. He was largely successful during his lifetime, but in doing so he made France into an implacable enemy, which would have dire consequences in the next century. Domestically, Bismarck's great flaw was his indifference to the lives of the German people. As Germany grew in power and stature, the people's lives improved but little. His social security system did some good, but he enacted that mainly to avoid having to make greater concessions to the German Socialists. [PARAGRAPH:1]In total, Bismarck was a great leader, perhaps the greatest European leader of the 19th Century. His triumphs greatly outweighed his defeats, and he almost single-handedly turned a group of bickering kingdoms in to a mighty state. The disasters in Germany's future were not so much a result of his policies, but of his successors' inability to adjust to the changing geopolitical climate in Europe.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]俾斯麦[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]德国首相[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1815-1898年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]人称“铁血宰相”的奥托·冯·俾斯麦也许是德国历史上最重要的人物。在他长期的政治生涯中，俾斯麦完成了德国的统一，建立了德意志帝国。在他30年的首相任期中，德国从一个弱小而松散的王国联盟转型为一个强大的统一国家，并在中欧占据绝对统治地位。[PARAGRAPH:1]作为一个普鲁士贵族家庭的后裔，俾斯麦毫无疑问继承了普鲁士容克阶层的傲慢自大。他曾是一位精于决斗的穷学生，还是一位不错的历史学家和语言学家。不过，他也花了不少时间参加其他贵族孤高排外的酒会。[PARAGRAPH:1]由于无法忍受在军队服役时必须遵守的严格制度，俾斯麦加入了普鲁士外交界，在那里他的才能很快引起了普鲁士国王的注意。进入德意志联邦议会（国会）后，俾斯麦致力于提升普鲁士在德意志地区的地位和实力。最终他登上了普鲁士首相的位置，在多年的努力后，他成功使得整个德意志处于普鲁士的领导下。俾斯麦种种诡计多端的外交手腕和一系列战争的胜利帮助他完成了这一伟业。[PARAGRAPH:1]德国统一之后，俾斯麦的首要外交政策是维持欧洲秩序，这就必须孤立德国的世仇——法国。在这点上他大获成功，在1870年他发动了一场对法战争，并成功的把几个德国固有省份（巴伐利亚、巴登等）并入德意志帝国的版图。在战争中，法国被迅速击败。[PARAGRAPH:1]达到取得德意志省份的目标后，俾斯麦希望给与法国宽大的和平条约，但德国人和德国军队希望得到更多，他被迫吞并了阿尔萨斯和洛林这两个法国省份。俾斯麦明白最后这会带来麻烦——在战争之前他对同僚说过：“假如我们赢得了阿尔萨斯，我们可以确保我们的战利品并保证斯特拉斯堡的防卫。但这会使我们处于很不利的地位，最后法国会找到新的盟友——这样我们就麻烦了。”这一预言在第一次世界大战中被证明是非常准确的，那时德国经历了一段艰难岁月。[PARAGRAPH:1]尽管俾斯麦是一个强烈的保皇派和君权主义者，他也是第一个建立起一套工人的社会保障系统的欧洲领袖。他重建了德国的货币结构，第一次引入了单一货币体系。他还帮助制定了新的民法和商业法。但他的宽容气度并不针对所有人群，解除犹太人禁令的同时，俾斯麦也颁布了旨在限制德国天主教徒的法令。[PARAGRAPH:1]作为一个外交官，俾斯麦最大的弱点是专注于削弱法国的政策。他在他活着的时候取得了很大成功，但也因此与法国结下世仇，在下个世纪造成了可怕后果。在国内政策上，俾斯麦最大的缺陷是他对德国人民生活的忽略。在德国逐渐发展壮大的同时，德国人民的生活却没有多少改善。尽管他的社会保障体系有不少优点，但俾斯麦制定这项法规的最大目的却是避免向社会主义者做出更大的让步。[PARAGRAPH:1]总的来说，俾斯麦是一位伟大的领袖，也许是19世纪欧洲最伟大的领袖。他的成功远大于失败，他几乎凭一己之力把众多纷争不断的王国变成一个统一国家。未来德国遭遇的灾祸和俾斯麦的政策并无多大关系，而是他的继任者们无法适应欧洲地缘政治形势改变的结果。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALEXANDER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Alexander the Great [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of Macedonia, Greece [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 356 - 323 BC[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Alexander was the son of King Philip II, an extremely successful king and warlord who had rescued his kingdom from the verge of extinction and then led his people to triumph by conquering Athens, Illyria, and Thrace - the three powers who, a few short years before, had been on the verge of conquering Macedonia. As the son of the most powerful monarch in the "civilized" world, Alexander got the best of everything, including education - the scholar Aristotle, the great thinker of Western Civilization, was his tutor. [PARAGRAPH:1]Taught by his mother that he was descended from Hercules and Achilles, Alexander did not lack for self-confidence, even at a very young age. At 16 he led an army to quell a Thracian rebellion while his father was away. Alexander stormed the rebel stronghold and broke the back of the rebellion. [PARAGRAPH:1]Several years later, Alexander's father was assassinated while in the process of mounting an invasion of Persia. Alexander immediately took power, and within two years he carried out his father's interrupted invasion of Persia. Alexander's force consisted of 30,000 foot soldiers and 5,000 cavalrymen, a huge army for the day, and was accompanied by engineers, surveyors, scientists, and even historians. [PARAGRAPH:1]Alexander had amazing success against the Persians. He repeatedly beat their best soldiers, routinely fighting against odds of 10-to-1. His success can be attributed to his military genius, his force's superb training and equipment, and their magnificent esprit de corps, largely engendered by their faith in Alexander's invincibility. [PARAGRAPH:1]Having secured Persia's surrender, Alexander then moved south, conquering Syria, Palestine, much of modern Iraq, and eventually Egypt herself. He returned to Persia, destroyed the last of the Persian forces and took over the entire country. He continued east, eventually coming into contact with the great Indian King Porus, who fought him to a standstill. Alexander eventually won the conflict, but at such a heavy cost that his men begged him to end the campaign and let them return to their families. Alexander himself returned to rule his empire from the captured city of Babylon. [PARAGRAPH:1]In eight short years of fighting, Alexander had conquered more territory than any other living being. He successfully led his forces into battle against all of the great nations of the day, but none could stand against him. He was the absolute ruler of the largest empire the world had ever seen. [PARAGRAPH:1]Apparently he found this boring. [PARAGRAPH:1]Once in Babylon, Alexander began an inexorable decline. He began drinking heavily and engaging in all kinds of available debauchery (and there was much debauchery to be found in Babylon). He became subject to fits of anger and bouts of paranoid delusion. One night, in a fit of blind rage and under the influence of alcohol, Alexander murdered Clitus, his closest associate. This barbaric act was to haunt Alexander for the rest of his life - which wasn't very long. [PARAGRAPH:1]In June of 323 BC, his body weakened by his excesses, Alexander died of malaria. He was 32 years old. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]亚历山大[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]马其顿、希腊国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]前356-前323年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]亚历山大是腓力二世之子，作为一位伟大的国王和将军，他拯救了处于毁灭边缘的马其顿王国，并领导他的人民击败并征服了几年前几乎灭亡马其顿的雅典，伊利里亚和色雷斯。作为“文明”世界最强大君主的儿子，亚历山大在各方面都很出色，并受到了良好的教育——他的老师是学者亚里士多德，西方世界最伟大的思想家。[PARAGRAPH:1]他的母亲告诉他，他是赫拉克勒斯和阿喀琉斯的后代，即使在亚历山大年纪很小的时候，也从不缺乏自信。在父亲因事外出时，16岁的他率领一支军队镇压了色雷斯人的叛乱，亚历山大亲自攻入叛军城堡并将其夷为平地。[PARAGRAPH:1]几年后，亚历山大的父亲在准备入侵波斯时被暗杀。亚历山大迅速获得了权力，在两年里他就完成了父亲征服波斯的未竟事业。亚历山大的军队包括三万名步兵、五千名骑兵，即使在今天这仍是一支庞大的部队，这支部队还包括工程师、测量员、科学家甚至历史学家。[PARAGRAPH:1]亚历山大在波斯获得了一系列令人惊异的胜利。他多次击败了对方最好的士兵，在一比十的战斗中取胜仿佛是例行公事。他的胜利归功于他的军事天赋，他的军队良好的训练和装备，以及他们对不可战胜的亚历山大的无比信任而形成的团队精神。[PARAGRAPH:1]波斯的投降使得后方安全获得保障，亚历山大于是继续率军南进，征服了叙利亚、巴勒斯坦、以及现今伊拉克的大部分土地，最终平定埃及。然后他回到波斯，消灭了波斯的残余部队并接管了整个国家。他继续东进，与强大的印度国王波拉斯交上了手。尽管亚历山大取得了最后的胜利，但也付出了沉重的代价，他的士兵请求他停止东征并允许他们回家。于是亚历山大回到其占领下的巴比伦开始治理他的帝国。[PARAGRAPH:1]在短短的八年征战中，亚历山大征服的土地比他之前所有的人都多。他成功率领他的军队击败了当时所有强大国家，没有人可以反抗他。他是前所未有的庞大帝国的绝对统治者——但很快他就感觉这很无聊。[PARAGRAPH:1]在巴比伦的亚历山大走上了人生的下坡路。他开始酗酒，并热衷于种种放浪的活动（巴比伦城中有很多这样的地方）。他变得易怒而偏执妄想。有一晚，在狂怒和大量的酒精刺激下，亚历山大杀了他最亲密的助手克利图斯。这类野蛮行径在亚历山大剩下的并不太长的生命里时有发生。[PARAGRAPH:1]公元前323年6月，无节制的生活摧垮了亚历山大的身体，最终他死于疟疾，享年33岁。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HUAYNA_CAPAC_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Huayna Capac [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Leader of the Incan Empire [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1493 - 1527[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Huayna Capac was the son of the Incan Emperor Iupanqui. Under his father, Capac led armies against his nation's neighbors to the north. When his father died in 1483 and he became emperor in his own right, Capac continued the campaigns, eventually extending the empire's borders into what is modern Colombia. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Inca Empire reached the height of its size and power under his rule, stretching over much of Bolivia, Peru, Argentine, Chile, Ecuador, and Colombia. It included varying terrain, from the high, frozen Andes to the densest swamps, and over 200 distinct ethnic groups, each with their own customs and languages. [PARAGRAPH:1]Despite the geographical and cultural challenges, Inca - or Tawantinsuys, the "Realm of the Four Quarters" - was sophisticated for its time and place. At its height it had "monumental cities, temples and fortresses of stone, marvelously engineered roads cut through granite mountain slopes, and massive agricultural terraces and hydraulic works." A dedicated ruler, Huayna did much to improve the lives of his people. In addition to building temples and other works, Huayna greatly expanded the road network, along which he built storehouses for food so that aid could be quickly rushed to any who were in danger of starvation. [PARAGRAPH:1]Huayna contracted smallpox while campaigning in Colombia. Smallpox had been introduced to South America by the Spaniards, and the Native Americans had no defense against it; Huayna and about 200,000 other South and Central Americans died in that one epidemic. Before his death Huayna divided his country, leaving the newly-conquered north to his favorite son, Atahualpa, and the rest to his legitimate heir, Huascar. The two brothers fought a long and debilitating war to reunite their country. Atahualpa eventually won, but the victory left his country exhausted and prostrate, unable to withstand attack from the Spaniard; Francisco Pizarro. [PARAGRAPH:1]Very little is known about Huayna the man. As was their established practice, the Spanish conquerors did their best to obliterate Incan history in order to detach their subject people from their places in history and make them easier to enslave (and to be converted to Christianity). We know that Huayna was bloodthirsty and vindictive in war, but in his private life he was affectionate, even tender. We can assume that Huayna was smart enough to hold his empire together, ambitious enough to seek to extend its borders, ruthless enough to crush those in his path, and foolish enough to divide his empire to try to satisfy both of his sons.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]怀那·卡帕[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]印加领袖[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1493-1527年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]怀那·卡帕是印加皇帝尤潘奎之子。在其父统治时期，卡帕曾率军攻打北方的敌国。在1483年父皇去世后他继承了皇位，此后他继续进行征服事业，将帝国的领土扩展到今哥伦比亚地区。[PARAGRAPH:1]在卡帕统治下，印加帝国达到了强盛的巅峰，包括今玻利维亚、秘鲁、阿根廷、智利、厄瓜多尔和哥伦比亚的大部分地区。帝国境内地形复杂，从高耸而寒冷的安第斯山区到潮湿而闷热的沼泽低地，并有超过200个不同的族群，每个族群都有自己的风俗和语言。[PARAGRAPH:1]虽然存在着如此巨大的地理和文化差异性，印加——或称“塔华廷苏育”（意为“四方之国”）——仍建立了那个时代最完善的统治体系。在其盛时曾拥有“宏大的石质城池，庙宇和要塞，设计精巧，穿山越岭的道路，广阔而充分灌溉的农田。”怀那是一位勤勉的统治者，他非常注重改善臣民的生活。除了修建神庙和宫室，怀那还大规模地扩建道路网，并沿建造了许多石屋以存放为附近饥民提供的食物。[PARAGRAPH:1]怀那在今哥伦比亚地区作战时感染了天花。天花是被西班牙人带入美洲的，美洲原住民对其完全没有免疫力，怀那本人及约20万南美和中美居民死于这场瘟疫。在去世前，怀那将他的帝国划为两部分，将新征服的北部地区分给他最钟爱的儿子阿塔瓦尔帕，其余地区则分给他的合法继承人华斯卡。结果这对兄弟为重新统一国家进行了长期的战争。最终阿塔瓦尔帕获胜，但这场内战将帝国带到了崩溃的边缘，无力再抵抗弗朗西斯科·皮萨罗率领的西班牙人的进攻。[PARAGRAPH:1]现在人们对怀那的为人和生平事迹知之甚少。西班牙征服者致力于抹去印加的历史，以使当地人民失去自己的传统，便于统治和奴役（以及使他们改宗基督教）。我们只知道怀那在作战时极为凶悍狂暴，但在个人生活中则相当感性甚至仁慈。我们相信怀那有足够的智慧统治他的帝国，有足够的野心扩展他的疆土，有足够的残忍消灭他的对手，也有足够的愚蠢将他的帝国分为两半，以使他的两个儿子都满足。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ASOKA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Asoka [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Emperor of India [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] c.299 - c.232 BC[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Asoka was one of the greatest rulers of ancient India. He brought nearly all of India (plus Afghanistan and Baluchistan) under one rule for the first (and thus far, only) time in history. Despite his great military prowess, Asoka grew weary of war; and over time he became disgusted at its stupidity and pointlessness. [PARAGRAPH:1]A popular young general and statesman, Asoka ascended to the Mauryan throne upon his father's death in 273 BC, at the approximate age of 26. He began his rule as a conqueror, seeking to expand his nation's power across the Indian subcontinent and beyond. He was quite successful, and his empire grew. [PARAGRAPH:1]However, after his bloody conquest of the Kalinga state in which over 100,000 people died and another 150,000 were injured, Asoka underwent a great spiritual change. Deeply remorseful for all of the suffering he had caused, he abandoned wars of conquest and accepted Buddhism. He turned from expansion and instead concentrated upon improving the spiritual and physical well-being of his people. He modified many of his country's harsh laws, and he advocated tolerance of all faiths. He built many Buddhist monasteries throughout the land, and the arts flourished under his rule. He sent Buddhist missionaries across the known world, including to faraway places like Greece and Egypt. Despite his fervent belief in Buddhism, Asoka demanded religious tolerance in his kingdom, saying, "Beloved-of-the-Gods, King Asoka desires that all religions should reside everywhere, for all of them desire self-control and purity of heart."[PARAGRAPH:1]Asoka died in 232 BC, and the empire he built lasted only fifty years after his death. His name would be virtually lost to history now, if it weren't for the discovery of a large number of columns and boulders inscribed with his words and teachings. These "Edicts of Asoka" contain not only a fount of information about King Asoka, showing him as a wise and thoughtful ruler, but they also provide invaluable knowledge of the early teachings and beliefs of Buddhism. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]阿育[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]印度皇帝[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]约前299-约前232年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]阿育王是古代印度最伟大的统治者之一。他首次（也是迄今为止仅有的一次）完成了几乎整个印度次大陆（包括阿富汗和俾路支地区）的统一。但是作为一位伟大的军事家，他却逐渐厌倦了战争，他对战争的愚蠢和无意义有了越来越深刻的理解。[PARAGRAPH:1]阿育在年轻时就展现出出色的军事和政治能力，并在公元前273年他的父王死后继位，年约26岁。起初他立志成为伟大的征服者，努力将其统治领域扩展到整个印度次大陆甚至更遥远的地区。这一事业相当成功，他的帝国日益壮大。[PARAGRAPH:1]然而，在对喀林加国的血腥征服中，有10万人死亡，15万人受伤，这样的惨象对阿育的思想造成了极大的冲击。他为自己对人们所造成的巨大痛苦感到深深的悔恨，因而决定放弃战争和征服，并皈依了佛教。他中止了扩张政策，转向专注于臣民的精神与物质福祉。他修改了许多严苛的法律，允许所有信仰共存。他在全国各地兴建了许多佛教寺院，文化和艺术也日益繁盛。他还向世界各地派遣僧侣传播佛学，最远到达过希腊和埃及。虽然本人是一位狂热的佛教徒，但阿育宣布他的国家包容所有的信仰，“天所眷顾的阿育王，希望所有宗教均能和平共处，因所有宗教均旨在规范自律与纯洁心灵。”[PARAGRAPH:1]阿育王与公元前232年去世，此后他的帝国仅继续维持了五十年。如果不是因为镌刻着其事迹和教诲的柱石大量被发现，阿育王的名字也将涅没于历史之中。这些“阿育谕令”不仅记载了阿育王的生平事迹，体现了他的治国智慧，同时也保存了有关早期佛教思想的珍贵信息。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_GANDHI_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Gandhi [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD]1869-1948[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Mohandas Gandhi was born in an India under British rule. The son of the Prime Minister of the small state of Porbandar, in his youth Gandhi displayed none of the brilliance that would mark him as an adult; in fact the young man was a mediocre student and quite shy. He entered into an arranged marriage at the age of 13, the usual custom of the period. Apparently he did not enjoy the experience, later calling the practice "the cruel custom of child marriage." [PARAGRAPH:1]Upon graduating from high school, Gandhi decided to follow his father into state service. To this end he decided he would go to England to study. His father having just died, Gandhi's mother did not want him to go, allowing him only after he had promised to abstain from wine, women, and meat. His caste looked upon traveling over the ocean as unclean; when he persisted they declared him an outcast. He learned much about England and the English during his time in that country, knowledge which was to prove invaluable later in his career. In 1891 Gandhi passed the bar and set sail for India. He attempted to set up practice in Bombay, but was unsuccessful and shortly relocated to South Africa. [PARAGRAPH:1]Gandhi enjoyed more professional success in South Africa, but he was appalled by the racial bigotry and intolerance he found there. He would spend the next twenty years of his life in South Africa looking after the interests of all under-classes, not just the Indians. It was here that Gandhi began to refine and teach his philosophy of passive resistance. He was jailed several times for his resistance to the so-called "Black Acts," by which all non-whites were required to submit their fingerprints to the government. When the government ruled that only Christian marriages were legal in South Africa, Gandhi organized and led a massive non-violent protest, which eventually caused the government to back down. It was here that Gandhi acquired the title of "Mahatma," which means a person venerated for great knowledge and love of humanity. [PARAGRAPH:1]In 1915, Gandhi returned to India. He shocked the world when he expressed his humiliation that he had to speak English in his native land, and he shocked the Indian nobility when he chided them for their ostentatiousness, telling them that they should hold their jewels and wealth in trust for their countrymen.[PARAGRAPH:1] Thus Gandhi began his long campaign to free his country from English rule. He followed two paths - he shamed oppressors and he demanded sacrifice from his people. For the next thirty years Gandhi was to tirelessly exhort his people to passive resistance, leading strike after strike, march after march, fasting himself to the point of incapacity, enduring innumerable beatings, and months and even years in prison. At one point he made a historic trip to England, where he won over much of the English working and middle classes, to the great irritation of the government. Despite innumerable setbacks and years of endless toil, he persisted. In 1946, exhausted and virtually bankrupt by World War II, the English agreed to vacate India, but in doing so divided the country between Hindu and Muslims, which Gandhi abhorred. [PARAGRAPH:1]The partition sparked an outbreak of religious violence, in which Muslims were massacred wholesale in India, and the same fate awaited Hindus in Pakistan. The countries were in chaos. In response, Gandhi went on a fast, refusing to eat again until the violence ceased. Astonishingly, his fast worked: the peoples of India and Pakistan were unwilling to see their great hero die, and they sent him letters and representatives promising to stop the killings and begging him to end the fast. He did so, to the relief of millions. Twelve days later, Gandhi was assassinated.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]甘地[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1869-1948年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]莫罕达斯·甘地出生于英国统治之下的印度。是一个小邦国（博尔班达）的首相之子，少年甘地并没有表现出过人的才能，他只是一位成绩中等，性格内向的普通学生。他在13岁时接受了一桩家人包办的婚姻，这是当时印度很普遍的做法。他显然不喜欢这一经历，并在后来将其称为“残忍的幼儿婚姻”。[PARAGRAPH:1]中学毕业后，甘地决定子承父业进入政界。为了实现这一目标他前往英国继续求学。他的父亲恰在此时去世，甘地的母亲并不希望他远离自己，只是在甘地承诺禁绝饮酒，肉食和美色后才同意其成行。他所处的种姓认为远洋旅行是不洁的行为，因此宣布将坚持远行的甘地除名。他在英国期间对这个国家的社会和人民有了充分的了解，这使他在后来的政治生涯中受益匪浅。1891年，甘地学成回国。他尝试在孟买开创事业但没有成功，不久便转往南非。[PARAGRAPH:1]甘地在南非获得得了事业上的一定成功，但当地的种族隔离制度令他难以忍受。他在南非的二十年中，产生了对所有下层人民，而不仅对印度人民的利益的深切关注。在那里他开始完善自己的非暴力不抵抗主义哲学。他因对所谓“黑人法案”的抗议而多次入狱（该法案禁止任何有色人种在政府任职）。南非政府规定只有基督徒的婚姻才受法律保护，为此甘地组织了一次大型的非暴力抗议活动，最终使政府作出妥协。甘地就是在此时获得了“圣雄”的称号，这一词汇意味着智慧和仁爱。[PARAGRAPH:1]1915年，甘地返回印度。他因在自己祖国的土地上却必须说英语而感到羞耻，并为此向世界大声疾呼；他斥责印度上层阶层的软骨病，敦促他们珍视和尊重印度广大人民的利益。[PARAGRAPH:1]就这样，甘地开始了为英国统治下的祖国赢得自由而进行的长期努力。他在两方面采取措施——让压迫者感到羞愧，也让人民作出牺牲。此后的三十年间，甘地不知疲倦地鼓动人民加入非暴力不合作运动，领导了一次又一次的罢工，一场又一场的游行，他自己也经历了长时间的绝食，无数次的殴打，成年累月的牢狱之灾。在对英格兰的历史性访问中，他赢得了大批英国劳动人民和中产阶级的支持，并使英国政府感到非常恼怒。虽然不断遭受挫折和伤害，他仍然坚持斗争。1946年，英国已因第二次世界大战而筋疲力竭，财政面临破产，只得允许印度殖民地独立，但令甘地愤怒的是，英国人却同时将印度按印度教和伊斯兰教信仰不同分为两个国家。[PARAGRAPH:1]国家的分裂导致宗教冲突不断爆发，在印度地区，大批穆斯林遭到屠杀，在巴基斯坦的印度教徒也面临同样命运。局势一片混乱。为此甘地再度宣布绝食，在暴力冲突平息之前不再进餐。令人惊异的是，他的绝食取得了效果：印度和巴基斯坦的人民不愿他们心目中的英雄死去，他们发出了无数声援信件，各方代表也纷纷承诺停止杀戳。在数百万人的呼吁下，他停止了绝食。但是在十二天后遇刺身亡。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_TOKUGAWA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Tokugawa [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Shogun of Japan [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1543 - 1616[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Tokugawa Ieyasu was the daimyo ("great person") of a province of Japan. Life as a Japanese feudal lord was not easy. The lords fought each other constantly, using deception, treachery, seduction, blackmail and poison in addition to bloody war to achieve dominance. At one point Tokugawa's wife and son were implicated in a plot to overthrow him; under intense pressure from his friends and allies, Ieyasu ordered their deaths - his son by ritual suicide, and his wife by execution. Despite this mishap, by all accounts Tokugawa was a master of this most dangerous game. A great general, a master tactician and an excellent liar, he did to others what they would do to him - except that he usually did it faster and better. [PARAGRAPH:1]As Tokugawa rose in power and prominence, he became an important personage in the court of Toyotomi Hideyoshi, a powerful general who had conquered most of Japan. Eventually he was given the great responsibility of looking after the general's son. However, upon Hideyoshi's death Tokugawa assembled an "eastern army" to take on Hideyoshi's successor. The two forces met in the battle of Sekigahara (1600). Aided by treachery of one of the enemy's generals, Tokugawa was victorious. [PARAGRAPH:1]After his victory at Sekigahara, Tokugawa had himself declared "shogun" (which translates approximately as "generalissimo"). In Japan, the Emperor is the titular head of the country but with little real power. The real power resided in the shogun. [PARAGRAPH:1]Tokugawa's rule was a time of peace and stability for Japan. He stopped much of the interminable fighting between the various feudal lords. Contrary to popular myth (as portrayed in the novel "Shogun"), Tokugawa actually welcomed foreign traders - Chinese, Portuguese, Dutch, English, Spanish and Siamese - in Japanese ports, and Japan's trade net expanded greatly during his rule. (The ban on foreign trade and travel was put in place by his descendants.) [PARAGRAPH:1]Tokugawa was always preoccupied with ensuring that he would not suffer the same fate that had befallen so many of his predecessors, and he took draconian measures to protect himself. For example, he forbade all wheeled vehicles from using Japan's fine road network. This made gathering an army to rise against him more difficult, of course, but it also crippled Japan's internal commerce, as all goods had to be carried on the backs of animals or people, rather than in far more efficient carts. [PARAGRAPH:1]In 1605 Ieyasu abdicated in favor of his son, Hidetada. His family would rule Japan until 1868.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]德川家康[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]日本幕府将军[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1543-1616年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]德川家康起初是日本一国的“大名”（领主）。日本战国时代领主的处境是很艰难的。他们要不断同其他人争权夺利，除流血战争以外，还有尔虞我诈、背信弃义、美色诱惑、巧取豪夺、下毒暗杀等种种手段无所不用其极。一次德川的妻子和儿子牵连进了谋反阴谋，在好友和同盟者织田信长施加的压力之下，德川下令将他们处死——最后他的儿子切腹自杀，他的妻子则被处决。除去这些灾祸，德川被公认为这场危险游戏的大师。他是一位伟大的将军，一位高明的战术家，也是一位卓越的阴谋家，他以其人之道还治其人之身——通常他做的更快更好。[PARAGRAPH:1]随着德川的脱颖而出，他逐渐成为几乎征服整个日本的伟大将军——丰臣秀吉面前的红人。最终他担负起了辅佐秀吉幼子的责任。然而，在秀吉死后，他聚合起“东军”对抗秀吉的继承人。双方在关原展开大战（1600年），对方一位将军的背叛使得德川获得胜利。[PARAGRAPH:1]关原之战胜利之后，德川宣布自己为“幕府将军”（“总司令”）。日本天皇有名无实，真正的权力掌握在幕府将军手中。[PARAGRAPH:1]德川统治时期的日本和平而稳定。他结束了各领主之间无尽的争战。与传统看法相反（正如小说“幕府将军”中所描写），德川热情欢迎外国商人——中国人、葡萄牙人、丹麦人、英国人、西班牙人以及暹罗人——来到日本港口，日本的贸易网络在他的统治下大大扩张。（后来的禁海令是由其继承者颁布的）。[PARAGRAPH:1]德川经常专注于确保自己免受先辈遭遇的灾祸，他采取严峻的手段保护自己。比如，他禁止任何轮式车辆通行于日本良好的道路网。这使得聚集一支反抗他的军队很艰难，当然，这也阻碍了日本国内的商业发展，所有的货物运输只能靠人和动物来背负，而不是效率更高的车辆。[PARAGRAPH:1]1605年，家康把将军的头衔传给儿子秀忠。之后他的家族统治日本直到1868年。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MANSA_MUSA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Mansa Musa [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Leader of the Mali Empire [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] ? - 1337[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Musa was the grandson of Sundiata Keita, the Muslim founder of the Mali Empire, which existed on the Mandinka plateau in West Africa from the 14th to the 17th centuries. At the time Mali was the source of over half of the world's gold, and Musa was fabulously wealthy. During his famous hajj (pilgrimage to Mecca) in 1324, Musa gave away so much gold in Cairo that the price of gold there was depressed for the next twenty years. He gave away so much treasure, in fact, that he had to borrow money to pay for his return trip. Legend has it that Musa was accompanied on his journey by a huge retinue and honor guard, not to mention 60,000 porters to carry the supplies. [PARAGRAPH:1]Called "Musa the Magnificent," Mansa was celebrated for his enlightenment and piety. He added the important towns of Timbuktu and Gao to his kingdom. Upon reaching the throne, Musa became a feverish Muslim, and he built countless mosques across the country and made Islam the state religion, though he did not persecute other religions in his country. [PARAGRAPH:1]Musa encouraged trade between Mali and the world beyond, using his country's vast resources of kola nuts, ivory, salt, and gold to attain goods from three continents. A believer in knowledge, Musa made the city of Timbuktu into a center of learning and craftsmanship, and Sankore University was one of the great schools in the Muslim world. Students came from all over to receive a free education there. [PARAGRAPH:1]Musa died in 1337, after ruling Mali for twenty-five years. A contemporary historian said of Masa Musa, that, of all of the leaders in West Africa, he was, "the most powerful, the richest, the most fortunate, and the most feared by his enemies and the most able to do good for those around him."</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]曼沙·穆萨[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]马里领袖[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]?-1337年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]穆萨是孙迪亚塔·科伊塔之孙。孙迪亚塔信仰伊斯兰教，是马里帝国的创立者。马里帝国在公元14至17世纪统治着今西非曼丁卡高原地区。当时的马里的黄金产量占全世界的一半，统治马里的穆萨因而拥有惊人的财富。穆萨在1324年前往麦加进行了一次著名的朝圣之旅，据说他在开罗的大肆挥霍甚至导致此后当地持续二十年的黄金贬值。他花掉的财富如此之多，事实上，他回国的旅费不得不向他人暂借。传说一路上穆萨的随行人员不计其数，仅货物搬运工就达6万名之多。[PARAGRAPH:1]人称“神奇的穆萨”，曼沙也因其聪慧和虔诚而闻名于世。他将位置显要的廷巴克图和加奥并入了马里。在继位之后，穆萨成为一位狂热的穆斯林，他下令在各地建造了无数清真寺，并将伊斯兰教定为官方信仰，但他也并不压制国内的其他宗教。[PARAGRAPH:1]穆萨致力于拓展马里与世界的贸易，利用本国丰富的可乐果、象牙、食盐与黄金资源与三大洲各国交换各种物资。穆萨也非常尊重知识，他将廷巴克图建成为重要的学术与艺术中心，当地的桑科雷大学是穆斯林世界最著名的学府之一。各地的学生可以在此免费获得教育。[PARAGRAPH:1]穆萨于1337年去世，在位25年。一位当时的历史学家曾经这样评论曼沙·穆萨：在西非各国的领导人中，他是“最强大、最富有、最幸运的人，也是最能使敌人感到害怕，最能为朋友提供帮助的人。”</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_GENGHIS_KHAN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Genghis Khan [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Khan of the Mongol Empire [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1152/1167 - 1227[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]The Khan who founded the world's largest empire was given the name Temujin at birth. At his death, Temujin's empire encompassed over 13.8 million square miles and 100 million people, about half of the world's entire population. [PARAGRAPH:1]Temujin was born into a family of the minor Mongol nobility. His father was murdered when he was nine, leaving his mother to teach Temujin how to ride a horse, shoot a bow, and tend the animals. She also taught her son that allies were crucial to one's survival, and Temujin took this lesson to heart. By the time Temujin had reached his late teens, he had gathered to him a group of very loyal vassals, with whom he shared the spoils of his wars. He also became blood brothers with men from the leading Mongol families. However, Temujin was first and foremost a pragmatist; he would remain friends with these leaders as long as it suited him and he would discard or betray them at need. [PARAGRAPH:1]Temujin grew in power and prominence, and he was eventually accepted as leader of all of the Mongols. He reorganized the military, promoting men of competence rather than men of good breeding. This gave him the unwavering backing of the common soldiers and the officers. After defeating his last internal foe, Temujin was named "Genghis Kahn," meaning either "Oceanic Ruler" (or possibly "Fierce Ruler"). After fully securing his position at home, Kahn began his extraordinary series of conquests across Asia and Europe. [PARAGRAPH:1]Genghis Khan was far more interested in victory than he was in glory in battle. Before attacking a city or country, Genghis Khan sent the local rulers "orders of submission," in which he demanded immediate surrender. If the rulers did so, they were allowed to continue governing as long as they provided him tribute in money and labor. If the rulers did not surrender, they could expect little mercy once defeated. [PARAGRAPH:1]As a political leader, Genghis Kahn adopted a policy of religious tolerance, which eased tensions with the local priests. He recruited foreigners to serve as officers in his army and in his government, allowing them to rise to prominence according to their abilities, thus giving the ablest men reason to support him rather than to plot against him. He issued a set of laws for his conquered lands, which among other things punished horse theft with death and imposed severe punishment on disobedient soldiers. He also allowed full trade with Europe, and for the first time it was possible for European merchants to travel all the way to China in (relative) safety. [PARAGRAPH:1]As a military leader, Genghis Khan was exceptional. He maintained tight discipline among his troops, punishing them severely for infractions. He developed a sophisticated intelligence network across Asia, and he used the intelligence to craft clever military campaigns that fully exploited his enemy's weaknesses. Genghis Khan's troops were extraordinary, as well. The Mongols were superb light cavalrymen, and their ability to shoot arrows from the saddle was unbelievable. At first his armies were ignorant of the arts of siege warfare, but as more and more armies refused to meet his forces in the open field; his men grew skilled with catapults and the other tools for fighting men behind walls. [PARAGRAPH:1]Genghis Khan's first campaigns were against the Tanguts, who controlled the lucrative trade routes between the East and West. After subduing them, he conquered other foes in Central Asia and Northern China. No one could stand against him. During his last and most extraordinary campaign, he set out with 200,000 warriors and captured Bukhara, Samarkand, Balkh, Nishapur and Herat in succession. After remaining in Central Asia for four years, Genghis Khan headed back home, only to die en route. [PARAGRAPH:1]Something more than a barbarian and something less than an enlightened ruler, Genghis Khan remains one of the most extraordinary warrior-kings of all time.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]铁木真[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]蒙古大汗[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1152或1167-1227年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]铁木真建立了人类历史上面积最广阔的一个帝国。在他死的时候，这个帝国覆盖了1380万平方英里土地，统治着着将近一亿人口，约占当时世界总人口的一半。[PARAGRAPH:1]铁木真出生于一个蒙古小贵族家庭，在他九岁时，他的父亲死于谋杀。他的母亲教会她骑马，射箭和放牧，并告诉铁木真，生存的关键就是团结盟友，他也一直用心记着。铁木真在十七八岁时已经聚集了一批非常忠诚的臣属，他们共同分享战利品。铁木真同时也成为许多蒙古部族统治者的结拜兄弟。然而，铁木真首先是一个实用主义者，如果符合他的利益，他就与那些统治者保持友好，一旦需要，他也会抛弃背叛他们。[PARAGRAPH:1]铁木真的权力声名不断增长，并且最终成为整个蒙古的领袖。他重组军队，根据才能而非血统任用文武官员。这使他获得了普通士兵和官员们坚定的支持。在打败内部最后一个敌人，统一蒙古之后，铁木真被尊称为“成吉思汗”（“大海一般的统治者”抑或“勇猛的统治者”）。在巩固了国内的地位后，成吉思汗开始了他横跨亚欧大陆的伟大征服之路。[PARAGRAPH:1]成吉思汗喜欢战斗带来的荣誉，但是对胜利更感兴趣。在攻打城市或国家之前，他先会给当地统治者送出一封“劝降书”，如果统治者照做了，提供给他财物和人口作为贡礼，他将会允许其继续统治。如果对方拒绝投降，那么他们在战败后就不会得到丝毫的怜悯。[PARAGRAPH:1]作为政治领袖，成吉思汗采取了相当宽松的宗教政策，这相当程度的缓解了各国宗教界的紧张情绪。他允许外国人在军队和政府里任职，只要拥有才华，就可以获得高官厚禄。这样能人们就有理由支持他而不是反对他。他在征服的土地上颁布一系列的法律，从处死盗马贼到严惩不服从命令的战士。他还允许与欧洲的开展全面贸易，使欧洲商人在历史上第一次得以（相对）安全地前往中国。[PARAGRAPH:1]作为军事领袖，成吉思汗达到了独一无二的成就。他的军队纪律严格，违反军纪者将严惩不贷。他在全亚洲布置了精密的情报网络，充分利用所收集的情报寻找和利用敌人的弱点，组织了许多成功的战役，同时，成吉思汗麾下的战士也超乎寻常。蒙古人是天生的骑射手，在马背上具有不可想象的高超箭术。起初他的军队并不重视攻城战，但是随着越来越多的军队拒绝与其在开阔地带作战，他们也掌握了投石车和其它重型武器的运用，熟练地打击躲藏在城墙之后的敌人。[PARAGRAPH:1]成吉思汗的第一次对外征战是进攻唐古特人，以夺取着东西方之间收益丰厚的贸易路线。在收伏他们之后，他又陆续征服了中亚及中国北部的许多政权。无人能与他对抗。在他最后一次，也是规模最大的一场远征中，他率领20万大军先后占领布哈拉、撒马尔罕、巴尔克、内沙布尔和赫拉特等地。在中亚征战四年之后，成吉思汗胜利凯旋，却病死于回家的途中。[PARAGRAPH:1]超越普通蛮族的领袖，不及宽仁智慧的明君，成吉思汗就是一代天骄，古往今来绝无仅有的勇士之王。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_KUBLAI_KHAN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Kublai Khan [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Khan and Emperor of China [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1215 - 1294[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]The grandson of the great Mongol leader Genghis Khan, Kublai oversaw the transformation of the Mongol people from nomadic warriors to sedentary farmers and townsfolk. He also captured the southern half of China, reunifying the country under one rule and taking for himself the title of "Emperor." [PARAGRAPH:1]Ascending to the throne in 1260 at around the age of 45, Kublai was revealed to be a shrewd and skilled political leader. As Emperor of China, he followed his father's precepts of being gentle with the subject peoples in order to keep them happy; he restored many of the Chinese traditions and institutions that his predecessors had banned. Further, Kublai returned much political control back to the native people, and he reinstated numerous Confucian rituals and ceremonies at court. He also commissioned many public works, including the repair of the Grand Canal and extending China's highway system. Through these actions he secured his throne, allowing him to turn his attention to conquering the southern half of China, which was under the control of the Sung dynasty. [PARAGRAPH:1] Southern China was a tough shell to crack. Her terrain was unsuitable for the Mongol light cavalry; the heart of its army, the climate was cold and wet; and its huge cities were quite difficult to take by the Mongol's usual siege tactics and weapons. Kublai considered the problem and eventually came up with an innovative solution, particularly for the leader of nomadic horse warriors; he decided that he would attack the Sung Empire from the sea. As quickly as possible he trained his forces in the ways of naval warfare. He grouped his troops with native Chinese sailors, and he actively recruited deserters from the Sung naval forces. When the time was right he opened a series of campaigns against the coastal cities, and then moved inland to the Sung capital, Lin-an, which fell in 1276. The contest was decided in a sea battle, in which the final Sung emperor drowned as his forces were destroyed. [PARAGRAPH:1]Kublai Khan's later campaigns were rather less successful. Seeking to conquer Japan, in 1281 Kahn assembled two invasion fleets carrying about 140,000 troops to take on the islanders. The ships rendezvoused off of the Japanese coast as planned, but before they could offload the troops they were hit by a major typhoon, causing the loss of about half the men and ships. The expedition ended in failure as the dazed survivors limped home. A similar venture in 1292 to subjugate Java suffered a similar fate; this time the invaders landed safely and managed to capture and hold the island, but the occupiers were prostrated by the heat and ravaged by tropical disease. Many died, and within a year most of the survivors fled for the cooler climes of home. [PARAGRAPH:1]Kublai died in 1294, shortly after the Java campaign came to its dismal end. His record is mixed; he is usually judged to be a fair and able administrator who conquered China and improved the lives of many of his subjects. Militarily, he succeeded in his most important campaign, the conquest of southern China, but failed miserably in others. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]忽必烈[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]蒙古大汗，中国皇帝[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1215-1294年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]忽必烈是强大的蒙古领袖成吉思汗之孙，他引导蒙古人民从游牧战士转变为定居的农民和市民。他还征服了中国南部，重新统一了中国，并自封中国皇帝。[PARAGRAPH:1]忽必烈在1260年登基时年约45岁，他很快显现出他灵活而熟练的政治才能。作为中国皇帝，他谨记父亲的箴言，善待顺从的子民，让他们保持快乐。他恢复了前任蒙古统治者所禁止的许多中国传统制度，并进而将许多政治权力还给当地的人民，儒家礼仪制度因此得到恢复。他还大量开展公共建设，其中包括修复大运河以及完善驿站道路网这两项工程。通过这些举措，它确保了自己的皇位，进而可以集中精力对付宋朝，征服中国南部的半壁江山。[PARAGRAPH:1]南部中国是个难以打破的坚果，复杂的地形和潮湿的气候使作为蒙古大军主力的轻骑部队无法体现威力，巨大的城市使蒙古常规的围攻战术及武器无法发挥作用。经过仔细的考虑，忽必烈对传统的马上民族作战方式进行了大幅改革。他决定从海上发动对宋朝的进攻，以最快的速度训练适应海战的军队，征召中国的本地的水手，收留宋朝海军的逃兵。时机成熟之后，他首先攻击沿海城市，随后深入内陆，终于在1276年攻占宋朝都城临安。在1279年决定性的崖山海战中，宋朝的末代皇帝同他的舰队一起湮没于茫茫的大海。[PARAGRAPH:1]忽必烈此后进行的战争则并不成功。1281年，忽必烈集结了两支舰队共14万大军向日本列岛进发，试图征服日本。按计划，舰队要在日本海岸会师，但是在他们上岸之前，遭到了威力巨大的台风的袭击，损失了近一半的船只和人员。幸存者失魂落魄地逃回大陆，远征宣告失败。1292年，相似的冒险经历，相似的命运，忽必烈对爪哇的远征也失败了。这一次，蒙古舰队成功地登陆爪哇岛，但是占领者却遭受酷热和疾病的折磨，许多人相继死亡，在一年之后，幸存者多数逃回了自己凉爽的家园。[PARAGRAPH:1]忽必烈于1294年去世，即远征爪哇失败后不到两年。对他的评价毁誉参半。通常他被认为是一个公正而有能力的统治者，征服了中国，并且改善了臣民的生活。军事上，他征服了中国南部，这是他所进行的最成功，也是最重要的一场战役，但其他的征战却都以失败告终。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CYRUS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Cyrus the Great [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of Persia [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] c.576 - July, 529 BC[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Cyrus was the first Emperor of Persia (which occupied about the same land upon which Iran now stands). He is known as a great warlord and a great ruler. He created one of the largest empires the world had seen, and he ruled his subjects with fairness and compassion. Cyrus also founded Pasargade, the capital city of Persia. [PARAGRAPH:1]At the time of Cyrus's birth, Iran was divided between two major tribes: the Persians and the Medes. Ascending to the Persian throne, Cyrus conquered the Medes. He joined the two tribes together, creating the country of Persia. To ensure full cooperation of the newly-conquered Medes, he allowed their nobles to become government officials and gave them equal status with the Persian nobility. [PARAGRAPH:1]Once he had secured Persia, Cyrus turned his attention to the east. He conquered Drangiana, Arachosia, Margiana, and Bactra. He built a series of fortified towns along the border to secure his flank and protect his empire from the nomads of Asia. He then turned west, conquering mighty Babylon. [PARAGRAPH:1]As a civil leader, Cyrus was progressive far beyond his time. He left the institutions in conquered lands alone, allowing the people to largely govern themselves. He didn't meddle with local religions, and he tried to put an end to religious persecution - when he conquered Babylon, the Jews there welcomed him as liberator. In fact, he freed about 40,000 Jews from bondage in Babylon, allowing them to return to their homes in Palestine. [PARAGRAPH:1]During the early part of his rule, Cyrus issued a decree on his objectives. This decree is now recognized as the first declaration of human rights. When he died, Cyrus was mourned by millions, including his conquered subjects. The Hellenes called him "Law Giver," and the Jews named him the "Anointed of the Lord."</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]居鲁士[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]波斯国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]约前576-前529年7月[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]居鲁士是第一位波斯国王（古代的波斯地区今属伊朗）。他是位杰出的军事家，也是位伟大的统治者。他建立了历史上面积最广阔的帝国之一，他对臣民的统治则公正而仁慈。居鲁士也是波斯都城帕萨尔加达的建立者。[PARAGRAPH:1]在居鲁士出生的时代，今伊朗地区分为两个主要部族：波斯和米底亚。在成为波斯人的领袖之后，居鲁士征服了米底亚人。他将这两个部族结为一体，成为统一的波斯王国。为了巩固在新征服的米底亚的统治，他允许米底亚贵族担任政府官职，给予他们与波斯贵族同等的待遇。[PARAGRAPH:1]完成波斯的统一之后，居鲁士的目光转向东方。陆续征服了德兰格亚那、阿拉霍西亚、马吉安那和巴克特里亚。此后居鲁士沿东方边境建造了许多城池要塞，确保他的帝国免受亚洲游牧民族的侵扰。接下来他的目标又转向西方，并征服了强大的巴比伦。[PARAGRAPH:1]在治理国家方面，居鲁士的思想超越了他的时代。他允许被征服地区保留原有制度，允许各族臣民自己进行管理。他从不干涉当地人的信仰，并努力制止各种宗教迫害行为——在他征服巴比伦时，当地的犹太人将他视为解放者。事实上，他释放了被掳到巴比伦为奴的40000名犹太人，并允许他们返回巴勒斯坦故乡。[PARAGRAPH:1]在执政初期，居鲁士向全体臣民颁布了一道法令。这道法令被人们称作是最古老的人权宣言。居鲁士去世后得到了无数人的哀悼，包括被他所征服的民族。希腊人称他为“立法者”，犹太人称他为“受主眷顾的人”。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_JULIUS_CAESAR_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Julius Caesar [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]First Roman Emperor [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] c.100 - 44 BC[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Gaius Julius Caesar was born - according to legend by Caesarean section - to a noble family. His father was a praetor, a mid-level functionary in the Republic. His family was respected, but not especially rich or influential. His father died while Caesar was still a teenager. At 19, Caesar married Cornelia, daughter of a prominent member of the popular political faction. The dictator of Rome at the time was Sulla, who belonged to the rival Optimate (pro-aristocrat) faction. He ordered Caesar to divorce Cornelia, and when he refused, Sulla ordered him to be executed. Caesar went into hiding until his influential friends got him a pardon. [PARAGRAPH:1]During his early manhood, Caesar had a varied career. He served on the staff of a military officer, where he was awarded oak leaves for saving a man's life in battle. He was sent on an embassy to Bithynia, where he persuaded the king to provide Rome with a fleet of ships. He worked as an orator/lawyer in the courts of Rome, where he honed his skills as a public speaker. [PARAGRAPH:1]During a trip to Greece, Caesar was captured by pirates and held for ransom. When the pirates told him that they planned to ask for 20 talents for his release, he indignantly insisted that he was worth 50 talents at least. He maintained friendly relations with his captors, at one point jokingly informing them that upon his release he intended to hunt them down and crucify them. Imagine their surprise when, after they released him, he did just that. The pirates had treated Caesar well during his captivity, however, so he mercifully slit their throats before nailing them to the crosses. [PARAGRAPH:1]Caesar began his climb to power. He was elected to the Senate, where he gave his support to Gnaeus Pompeius (Pompey the Great), who with Caesar's help was given command of the war against King Mithridates. He spoke at funerals, including the one of his wife, Cornelia, dazzling the crowds with his oratory skill and personal magnetism. He married the granddaughter of his old enemy, Sulla. He later divorced her because of rumors that she had had an affair, saying famously, "The wife of Caesar must be above suspicion." He spent lavishly on games to win popular support. [PARAGRAPH:1]In 60 BC, at the age of 40, Caesar entered into an alliance with Pompey and Crassus, two very important and influential men of Rome. He agreed to support their aims if they, in turn, would help him get elected to the consulship of Rome (at the time, Rome was ruled by two consuls, each elected for one-year terms). Upon being elected, Caesar pushed through measures that helped the other two men achieve their goals. At the end of his term, he strong-armed the Assembly into giving him a five-year term as the powerful proconsul of Gaul, and thus leader of a large portion of Rome's best troops. [PARAGRAPH:1]Caesar was to remain in the field of battle for the next nine years. During that time he conquered most of what is now Central Europe, adding "great general" to his already formidable reputation. During his absence, however, Crassus died in battle against the Parthians, and Pompey took sole control of Rome. Worse, Pompey was siding with Caesar's enemies, the Optimates. When Caesar was informed that the Optimates intended to prosecute him for his illegal actions in forcing the Assembly to give him the Gaul proconsul, he broke relations with Pompey. [PARAGRAPH:1]Having earned his legions firm loyalty and support, in 49 BC Caesar led them "across the Rubicon" and to Rome. Most of Pompey's legions at the time were in Spain, so he and the Senate abandoned the city to Caesar's legions. In a lightning campaign, Caesar destroyed Pompey's Spanish troops before his enemy could consolidate his forces, and Pompey retreated to Greece, where there remained forces still loyal to him. Caesar pursued as quickly as possible. [PARAGRAPH:1]Caesar's sea transportation was limited, and he could only support about 20,000 troops in Greece. He left behind his trusted lieutenant Marc Antony, ordering Antony to rectify the supply situation and get him more troops as soon as possible. Knowing, however, that Pompey was using every moment's delay to gather allies and increase his forces, Caesar couldn't wait; at the head of his now 21,000-strong army he marched to battle. [PARAGRAPH:1]The two armies met on the plains of Pharasulus, with Pompey's army outnumbering Caesar's by more than two-to-one. Despite the odds, Caesar was victorious, his brilliant generalship making up for his disadvantage in numbers. Pompey fled the field, and shortly thereafter was betrayed and murdered by the Egyptians. Now undisputed ruler of Rome, Caesar went to Egypt, where he set his lover Cleopatra upon the throne after a short but bitter fight. [PARAGRAPH:1]Back in Rome, Caesar began an extensive program of reforms. He began to resolve the Roman debt problem; he settled his veterans abroad, giving them the land they craved but not dispossessing others (other Romans, that is). He reformed the Roman calendar, regulated public assistance and strengthened the middle class. His actions greatly improved life for the average citizen, but angered the aristocracy, the remnants of the Optimate party. [PARAGRAPH:1]In February of 44 BC, the puppet Senate voted Caesar "dictator perpetuus," or dictator for life. For the first time he began wearing purple garb, a color associated at that time with kings and emperors. Further, he allowed his statues to be adorned like the statues of the gods. On March 15, Caesar was murdered, stabbed at least 23 times by a coalition of aristocrats and senators.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]朱利乌斯·恺撒[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]罗马统治者[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]约前100-前44年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]盖乌斯·朱利乌斯·恺撒传说是经由剖腹产而出生的。他父亲是罗马共和国的中级官员，并没有太多的权势或金钱。当恺撒的父亲去世时，他还是只是个十多岁的少年。他19岁那年娶了科妮莉亚为妻，而后者的家族属于罗马城里的一个政治派别。而当时罗马的独裁者苏拉却正好属于与之敌对的派系。他命令恺撒与科妮莉亚离婚，恺撒拒绝了，苏拉便下令处死恺撒。恺撒不得不逃进山中，直到他那些有权有势的朋友为他求得了独裁者的宽恕。[PARAGRAPH:1]在恺撒刚成年时，他作过各式各样的工作。他担任军官时，因为在战斗中营救同僚而获得奖励。他被派往卑斯尼亚，并成功地劝说那里的国王向罗马提供一支舰队。他还在罗马法院中担任律师，并由此锻炼了自己的雄辩术。[PARAGRAPH:1]在一次去希腊的旅行中，恺撒被海盗所绑架。当海盗要求他交出20塔伦作为自己的赎金时，他却愤怒地坚持他至少值50塔伦。他同这些海盗结交，还开玩笑地说一旦他获得自由，必将带人来这些海盗全部干掉。果不其然，在获得自由后，恺撒履行了自己的诺言。尽管海盗在恺撒被俘期间对他很好，但恺撒仍在处死海盗之前凶残地切开了他们的喉咙。[PARAGRAPH:1]在此之后恺撒一路顺风，首先是在格涅乌斯·庞培的支持下当选参议员，后者通过恺撒的协助获得了米特拉达梯战争的指挥权。他的演讲在此时已经可以让听众疯狂，在自己妻子科妮莉亚的丧礼上也是如此。之后，他娶了自己曾经的敌人苏拉的孙女。但他不久后又与之离婚，理由是传闻她私生活不检点，这就像一句谚语所说的那样，“身为恺撒妻，必须无可疑。”他为了争取公众的支持不惜一掷千金。[PARAGRAPH:1]在公元前60年，恺撒40岁时，他与罗马另外两个强势人物庞培及克拉苏结盟。恺撒答应支持他们的行动，其报酬是后两者必须支持自己当选罗马执政官（在那时，罗马由两个执政官统治，其任期为一年）。在自己当选后，恺撒就要尽其所能为庞培和克拉苏提供帮助。在恺撒任期最后一段时间，他运用铁腕手段为自己争取到了担任五年高卢总督的机会，这意味着他成为了罗马一大批精锐部队的长官。[PARAGRAPH:1]恺撒在接下来的九年里不停地作战。在此期间他征服了中欧的绝大部分地区，并因其赫赫威名而被称为“伟大的将军”。但是在他远离罗马的这段时间里，克拉苏在同帕提亚人的战争中丧命，庞培乘机控制了罗马城。更为糟糕的是，庞培现在同恺撒的敌人站在了一起。当恺撒得知到政敌将就自己使用不正常手段谋求高卢总督职位一事提起控告后，便决心同庞培决裂。[PARAGRAPH:1]恺撒在公元前49年率领自己忠心耿耿的部下“穿越共和国”向罗马进军。庞培手下的绝大多数军团当时正在西班牙作战，所以他和他的同盟者不得不将一座座空城留给恺撒。在一次奇袭中，恺撒趁庞培的西班牙军团尚未巩固战线前就打跨了他们，庞培接下来又撤往希腊，他在那里有着许多死忠者。恺撒也马上展开了追击。[PARAGRAPH:1]但恺撒的海上运输能力很有限，他只能将2万人运往希腊。他将自己可靠的部下马可·安东尼留在意大利，命令他维持补给线，并尽可能多的把部队提供给自己。但庞培正在利用对方的延误集结军力，恺撒知道自己不能再将战事无限拖延下去了，于是决定率领现有的2万1千人迅速投入战斗。[PARAGRAPH:1]两军在帕拉苏卢斯平原相遇，庞培和恺撒军队的数量之比是二对一。尽管处于劣势，恺撒仍然取得了胜利，他以自己的才略弥补了数量上的不足。庞培战败后逃到了埃及，但不久又被当地人谋杀。而作为罗马唯一统治者的恺撒来到了埃及，他在那里邂逅了自己的情人克利奥帕特拉，并将她抬上了埃及国王的宝座。[PARAGRAPH:1]在回到罗马后，恺撒开展了轰轰烈烈的改革。他着手解决罗马的债务问题，让自己手下的老兵移民海外，并给予他们一直渴望的土地，而且也没有以牺牲他人（仅指罗马人）的土地为代价。他改革了罗马的历法，调整官方补助，使中产阶级的实力得以扩大。他的一系列措施极大地提高了罗马市民的生活水准，但却触怒了贵族阶级保守派的残余势力。[PARAGRAPH:1]公元前44年2月，已成象征性傀儡的元老院任命恺撒为“终身执政官”。他开始穿着代表帝王身份的紫色长袍，甚至还允许象塑造神像那样塑造自己的雕像。3月15日，恺撒被共和派贵族和议员阴谋刺杀，政敌们在他身上留下了至少23道伤口。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_PETER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Peter the Great [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Emperor of Russia [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1672 - 1725[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Peter was born the fourth son of the Tsar Alexey I. After the death of his father and older brother, at the age of 10 he became co-tsar with his sickly half-brother, Ivan, under the regency of their sister Sophia Alexeevna. Apparently Peter was quite the terror in his teens. He had utter contempt for religious and political ceremony, combined with almost limitless energy and a capacity for alcohol. At 17 he had the regent (his elder sister) arrested on charges of conspiring against him and had her locked in a convent, where she would stay for the rest of her life. He took total control of the empire, his brother Ivan no more than a figurehead. [PARAGRAPH:1]In addition to drinking, carousing, and political intrigue, young Peter was also fascinated by military affairs. In 1695, he ordered the army to move against the Turks. Astonishingly, he didn't command his forces in the field, instead choosing to act as an lowly artilleryman. The Russian forces emerged victorious and within a year had captured the vital port of Azov. [PARAGRAPH:1]Several years later, Peter set off on a tour of Europe. He spent 16 months traveling incognito through Germany, Holland, England and Austria, at one time working as a shipwright in England and Holland. Peter learned a lot during his trip, and he later hired many western craftsmen, engineers, soldiers, sailors, architects and artists to help modernize Russia. Once home, Peter adopted many European customs, including a mandate that beards were to be shaved off at court, which was a great controversy that nearly caused a revolt with the Boyars. [PARAGRAPH:1]Despite his love of European culture, Peter remained a drunken, overbearing bully, whose practical jokes stopped just short of outright torture. (Or perhaps went a little over the line.) Foreign observers noted with horror that at a state dinner Peter had one of his cronies hold another tight, pinning his arms and forcing his mouth open. The victim was known to hate salads and especially vinegar; Peter jammed salad into his mouth and down his throat and then poured vinegar up his nose until it bled. [PARAGRAPH:1]Peter liked to force his guests - including foreign diplomats - to drink until they passed out, then wake them up an hour later and force them to drink more. He once woke a group of extremely inebriated men up in the middle of the night, gave them axes and demanded that they help him cut down trees to make a path to the seashore. [PARAGRAPH:1]In 1700 Russia went to war against Sweden. But, Gustavus Aldolphus, the Swedish King, proved more cunning to him, striking Peter's army before it was prepared, capturing much of the Russian artillery in the process. In response Peter demanded that all of the bells in Moscow (including church bells) be melted down to make cannons. He also confiscated church treasure to fuel the war effort. The war dragged on, but in 1709 the Swedish forces were decisively defeated, and Russia gained parts of Finland, Estonia, and Latvia. [PARAGRAPH:1]Peter's home life did not go particularly well. In 1698 his wife was implicated in a plot to overthrow him; he divorced her and sent her off to yet another convent. In 1712 he married his mistress, Martha Skavronsky, a former Lithuanian servant and previously the mistress of a bevey of other Russian nobles. She gave him four children. In 1718 the tsar's oldest son Alexey was imprisoned for suspected treason and died under torture. [PARAGRAPH:1]Upon his death Peter was buried in Saint Petersburg, the vital port and Russian capital, which he established in 1703, in the Peter and Paul Cathedral. Presumably under the heaviest rock they could find.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]彼得[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]俄国沙皇[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1672-1725年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]彼得是沙皇阿列克谢一世第四个儿子。他的父亲和兄长去世后，十岁的他和病弱的同父异母哥哥伊凡共同继位为沙皇，由他们的姐姐索菲亚·阿列克谢耶芙娜摄政。在他十几岁时彼得就显现出令人惊恐的一面。他完全蔑视传统的宗教和政治仪式，他还拥有旺盛的精力和无穷的酒量。十七岁时彼得以谋反为由逮捕了摄政（他的姐姐），并把她关在一家修道院里，她在那里度过了她的余生。他完全掌控了整个帝国，他的哥哥伊凡则有名无实。[PARAGRAPH:1]在乐衷于饮酒狂欢和政治阴谋同时，彼得还醉心于军事。1695年，他率军进攻土耳其人。令人吃惊的是，他并没有在战场上指挥军队，而是作为一名低级的炮手参与作战。一年后俄罗斯人获得了胜利，并夺取了性命攸关的亚速海出海口。[PARAGRAPH:1]几年之后，彼得开始了他的欧洲巡游。他花了十六个月微服私访了德国，荷兰，英格兰和奥地利，曾在英格兰和荷兰做过一段时间造船工人。在他的旅途中彼得学到很多东西，雇佣了许多西方工匠，工程师，士兵，水手，建筑师和艺术家来帮助他实现俄罗斯的现代化。回到祖国后，彼得采用了很多欧洲习俗，包括制定法令命令所有进入宫廷的人必须刮去胡子，这几乎引起了一场特权贵族的叛乱。[PARAGRAPH:1]除去他对欧洲文化的热爱外，他依旧酗酒蛮横，恃强凌弱，他的恶作剧只有当他直率的秉性抑制不住时才会揭穿。有个外国观察着惊恐的记录道，在一次晚宴上，彼得命令自己的一个亲信把另一个紧紧绑住，钉住他的手臂迫使他张开嘴。知道这位可怜人讨厌色拉和一种特制的醋后，彼得把色拉塞进他嘴里，压进他的喉咙，接着把醋灌进去，直到他的鼻子开始流血。[PARAGRAPH:1]彼得喜欢灌醉他的客人——包括外国的外交官，一个小时后弄醒他们再逼着他们喝。有一个午夜他弄醒了一群酩酊大醉的人，交给他们斧子命令他们帮他砍树，来铺一条通往海岸的道路。[PARAGRAPH:1]1700年俄国开始和瑞典作战。可是，瑞典国王古斯塔夫·阿道夫比他更诡计多端，在彼得军队准备就绪之前就击溃了他，并俘获了很多俄国人的大炮。作为回应彼得下令莫斯科所有的大钟（包括教堂的钟）必须融掉铸成大炮。他还没收教堂的财产充作军费。战争得以继续，到了1709年瑞典人的军队被彻底击败，俄国获得的土地包括芬兰，爱沙尼亚和拉脱维亚。[PARAGRAPH:1]彼得的家庭生活并不如意。1698年他的妻子受到一次阴谋造反的牵连，他和她离婚并把她送入另一家修道院。1712年他和他的情妇玛萨·斯卡荣斯基结婚，她曾是一位立陶宛人女仆，也曾是另一个俄国贵族的情妇。她给他生了四个孩子。1718年沙皇的长子阿列克谢被囚禁，他涉嫌参与谋反，后来死于严刑拷打。[PARAGRAPH:1]彼得死后葬在圣彼得堡，一个重要的港口，也是俄国的首都。他的墓碑系用人们所能找到的最大岩石雕凿而成。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CATHERINE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Catherine the Great [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Tsarina of Russia [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1729 - 1796[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Catherine was born in Szczecin in 1729, a princess of Pomerania, a small kingdom in Prussia. At 16 she was married to Carl Peter Ulrich, the heir to the Russian throne. Catherine quickly learned Russian and joined the Russian Orthodox Church. Largely self-educated, Catherine immersed herself in the literature of the time. Endowed with both beauty and intelligence, she became strong friends (if not more) with the great thinkers of the day, including the brilliant French philosophers Rousseau and Diderot. [PARAGRAPH:1]Catherine did not lack political ambition, however. At the age of 33, with the support of the Imperial guard, she overthrew her husband, the Emperor Peter III, who was soon killed "in a hunting accident," leaving Catherine the sole ruler of Russia. As Empress, Catherine pursued an expansionist policy, fighting two successful wars against the Ottoman Empire and acquiring vast territory in southern Ukraine and the Crimea. She undertook a wide range of political reforms, attempting to shape up the notoriously corrupt and incompetent Russian bureaucracy. She curried favor with the aristocracy, expanding their already-great power over the Russian peasants. [PARAGRAPH:1]A patron of the arts, Catherine commissioned many statues and paintings. Under her rule St. Petersburg was transformed from a primitive and forbidding city into one of the most beautiful and impressive European capitals. [PARAGRAPH:1]Despite her many public successes, Catherine is best known for her private excesses. Her affairs are legendary; it has been suggested that she slept with a fairly large fraction of the Russian officers corps, not to mention her many well-publicized dalliances with a horde of well-known European politicians and artists. [PARAGRAPH:1]Catherine died at the age of 67, having lived longer than any other Romanov monarch. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]叶卡捷琳娜[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]俄国沙皇[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1729-1796年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]叶卡捷琳娜原名苏菲，是日耳曼小诸侯国——波美拉尼亚的公主，1729年出生于什切青。叶卡捷琳娜在16岁时嫁给了俄国皇位继承人卡尔·彼得·尤里奇，很快学会了俄语并皈依东正教。叶卡捷琳娜热爱新知，倾向当时的启蒙主义思潮。她既有美貌，又具智慧，并与当时的许多大思想家保持着良好的（或是更亲密的）友谊，包括著名的法国哲学家卢梭和狄德罗。[PARAGRAPH:1]叶卡捷琳娜也富有政治野心。在她33岁时，凭借近卫军的支持发动政变，废黜了他的丈夫彼得三世，不久这位沙皇即死于“打猎时的意外”，从此叶卡捷琳娜成为俄国的最高统治者。叶卡捷琳娜在位期间执行积极扩张政策，两次赢得对奥斯曼帝国的战争，夺取了乌克兰南部和克里米亚的大片领土。她还在许多领域实施了一系列政治改革，试图消除俄国官僚阶层的腐败无能。她努力维护大贵族的利益，而对俄国的农奴进行极其残酷的压迫。[PARAGRAPH:1]作为艺术资助者，叶卡捷琳娜收集了大量雕塑和绘画。在她统治期间，圣彼得堡由一座原始封闭的城市变为全欧洲最美丽的都市之一。[PARAGRAPH:1]虽然在政治上非常成功，叶卡捷琳娜在私生活方面的放纵却更惹人关注。关于她有许多传奇般的风流韵事。传说她曾与一大批俄国军官有染，她与欧洲一些著名的政治家和艺术家的暧昧关系则更是广为人知。[PARAGRAPH:1]叶卡捷琳娜享年67岁，比任何其他罗曼诺夫王朝的君主都更长寿。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISABELLA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Isabella [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Queen of Spain [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1451 - 1504[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Isabella was the daughter of King John II of Castile. At the time of her birth, Spain was divided into a number of smaller kingdoms, with Castile, Portugal and Aragon being three of the largest. The southern part of the country was under Arab rule, the "Moors" having conquered much of Spain in the 8th Century. For Christian Spain, there were two major objectives: unite the country and drive out the Moors. Isabella accomplished both. [PARAGRAPH:1]After her father's death, Castile was ruled by Isabella's older brother, King Henry IV. At eighteen, and against her brother's express wishes, Isabella married Prince Ferdinand, heir to the throne of Aragon. Henry was furious at her - he had wanted her to marry the King of Portugal - but eventually he forgave her and made Isabella his heir. Upon his death in 1474, Isabella became Queen of Castile, and, after a brief war, made an alliance with Portugal, thus uniting much of Spain. [PARAGRAPH:1]Isabella and Ferdinand worked surprisingly well together. They co-ruled their two kingdoms equally (according to many historians, Isabella was the better ruler of the two). [PARAGRAPH:1]Once they were enthroned, the couple set about weakening the Spanish nobility, which Isabella believed had become overly powerful. They created a special military force known as the "Holy Brotherhood" for the express purpose of protecting people and property from attacks by the nobility. They also redistributed some of the nobles' lands and destroyed several of their castles. In other internal matters, Isabella and Ferdinand reorganized the courts and the justice system, and they more closely regulated the country's coinage. [PARAGRAPH:1]Some of Isabella and Ferdinand's other programs were less appealing. The two rulers were Catholic zealots and they had a rabid hatred for non-Catholics, and especially for Jews. In 1478 they petitioned the Pope to establish the Spanish Inquisition. Under Chief Inquisitor Torquemada, the Inquisition tortured and murdered thousands across Spain, driving the heretics out of the country or underground, or forcing them to convert to Catholicism. [PARAGRAPH:1]Interestingly, when they conquered Granada, the last Muslim stronghold in Spain, Isabella and Ferdinand treated those Muslims quite well, allowing them to freely practice their religion in Spain. The Jews of Granada, however, were treated as barbarously as their cousins in other parts of Spain. [PARAGRAPH:1]Perhaps Isabella's most famous act as monarch was her decision to fund Columbus's voyages of exploration. Christopher Columbus was an Italian navigator who was looking for a western route to India; after getting Isabella's backing, he set out to cross the Atlantic to find Asia. Instead, Columbus discovered America. [PARAGRAPH:1]As a ruler, her record is mixed. She did unite her country along with the help of her husband, Ferdinand. She did drive out foreign powers who had occupied Spain for 700 years. She did bring peace and stability to Spain. She did fund exploration which would bring vast new territory and vast wealth to her kingdom. On the other hand, she did launch a terrible campaign of torture and murder against the most vulnerable population in her lands. To her Christian subjects, then, Isabella probably was the best thing that had ever come their way. However her Jewish subjects probably had a somewhat less positive opinion of Her Majesty. Isabella died in 1504, leaving the kingdom to her daughter.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]伊莎贝拉[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]西班牙女王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1451-1504年[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]伊莎贝拉是卡斯提尔国王约翰二世之女。在她刚出生的年代，整个伊比利亚半岛分为数个小王国，卡斯提尔、葡萄牙和阿拉贡是其中最大的三个。半岛南部则为阿拉伯人（“摩尔人”）所控制，他们在8世纪曾经征服了西班牙大部分地区。西班牙各基督教政权有两个主要目标：统一西班牙和驱逐摩尔人。而伊莎贝拉做到了这一切。[PARAGRAPH:1]在父王去世后，卡斯提尔由伊莎贝拉的兄长亨利四世统治。在18岁时，伊莎贝拉不顾兄长的反对，嫁给了阿拉贡的储君斐迪南王子。亨利起初十分愤怒——因为他希望妹妹同葡萄牙国王结婚——但最终还是认可了，并将伊莎贝拉指定为自己的继承人。1474年亨利去世后，伊莎贝拉成为卡斯提尔女王，并在一场短暂的战争之后同葡萄牙结盟，就这样完成了西班牙的基本统一。[PARAGRAPH:1]伊莎贝拉与丈夫斐迪南的配合惊人完美。他们共同统治卡斯提尔与阿拉贡王国（许多历史学家认为在两者之中，伊莎贝拉的能力更为出色）。[PARAGRAPH:1]伊莎贝拉与斐迪南夫妇掌权后，开始着手削弱西班牙贵族集团过于强大的势力。他们创立了一个名为“圣兄弟团”的军事修会，其宗旨是保护人民大众不受贵族的欺压。他们还没收部分贵族的土地，拆毁其城堡。在国内其他事务方面，伊莎贝拉和斐迪南重组了宫庭和司法系统，并建立了完善的货币制度。[PARAGRAPH:1]伊莎贝拉和斐迪南的另外一些作为则遭到了史家的抨击。两位统治者都是狂热的天主教徒，对非天主教信徒，特别是犹太人充满仇恨。在1478年，他们获得教皇准许而创立了西班牙宗教裁判所。在大裁判官托克玛达的领导下，宗教裁判所在西班牙各地迫害并屠杀了数千人，大批异教徒被驱逐出境，转入地下，或被迫皈依天主教信仰。[PARAGRAPH:1]有趣的是，在攻陷摩尔人在西班牙最后的据点格兰纳达之后，伊莎贝拉和斐迪南对当地穆斯林表现出相当的善意，允许他们留在西班牙并保持原来的信仰。但格兰纳达的犹太人却同他们在西班牙其他地方的同胞一样遭到野蛮的迫害。[PARAGRAPH:1]伊莎贝拉在位期间最重要的一项决定，也许就是资助哥伦布进行远洋探险。克里斯多弗·哥伦布是一位意大利航海家，他提议向西寻找通往印度的新航路。在伊莎贝拉的资助下，他率领船队横渡大西洋，虽然没有到达印度，却发现了美洲。[PARAGRAPH:1]伊莎贝拉是一位充满争议的统治者。她确实在丈夫斐迪南的协助下实现了国家的统一，她确实驱逐了统治西班牙700年之久的异族势力，她确实为西班牙带来了和平与稳定，她确实资助了为她的王国带来广阔领土和无限财富的远洋探险事业。但在另一方面，她也确实对一个弱小无助的族群实施了极其残酷的迫害与屠杀。对信仰基督教的臣民来说，伊莎贝拉也许是他们最理想的统治者。但西班牙的犹太人则不可能对这位女王产生敬意。伊莎贝拉于1504年去世，王位由她的女儿继承.</Chinese>
</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>