<!--  edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by lcollins (Firaxis Games)  -->
<!--  Sid Meier's Civilization 4  -->
<!--  Copyright Firaxis Games 2005  -->
<!--  freesand leo  -->
<!--  Game Text - New  -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HOLY_ROMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Holy Roman Empire is a nightmare in the Medieval Era. That is, for anyone playing against them. Say goodbye to city maintenance thanks to the Rathaus building, the Holy Roman replacement for the Courthouse, which cuts city upkeep by seventy-five percent. The Landsknecht, the Holy Roman Pikeman replacement, is possibly the best melee unit of the Medieval Era, with a one-hundred percent bonus against other melee units as well as an equivalent bonus against mounted units. Under the rule of Charlemagne, a "Protective" and "Imperialistic" leader excellent at setting up and holding far-reaching empires, the Holy Roman Empire is one of the most formidable foes in Civ.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Holy Roman Empire was created in 800 AD by Charlemagne. Covering much of central Europe from the Netherlands to Hungary, the Empire was both a political powerhouse and a hotbed of political intrigue and military conflict. In some ways "Emperors" in name only, the rulers of the Holy Roman Empire were rarely able to exert real control over any territory that was beyond the reach of their personal armies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Although the Holy Roman Empire was not referred to as such until late in the reign of Otto I (962-973), it came into being as a political entity in 800 AD when Pope Leo III, in an effort to break ties with the weakening Byzantine Empire, crowned Charlemagne the "Emperor of the Romans." A keen military strategist and devout Catholic, Charlemagne managed to keep the empire united until his death in 814, upon which the empire steadily dissolved into separate warring states until reunited under the rule of Otto I. While Otto I managed to reunite the empire, his downfall, and that of many successor emperors, was his fixation on Italy. Although Italy was not formally part of the empire, Otto I repeatedly invaded that country in order to secure holdings for the Germanic empire. However, the majority of his military ventures into Italy were unsuccessful, and Otto I only succeeded in eroding his power base in Germany.[PARAGRAPH:1]Throughout its history, the Holy Roman Empire was the stage for conflicts between its Emperors and the Church. Initially it was only the Pope who could designate the Roman Emperor, however over time - especially during the reign of Otto I - it became instead the Emperor who named the next Pope, providing the throne with enormous religious power. During the reign of the Salian Emperors (1024-1125) this practice again changed. A council of churchmen, known as Cardinals, was formed and given the power to nominate and elect popes. This practice has continued with only minor changes to the present day.[PARAGRAPH:1]Charles VI ruled with perhaps the most pragmatic view of his empire. Voted by the Cardinal Council as Holy Roman Emperor in 1355, Charles immediately gave up all imperial ambitions in Italy and instead focused on consolidating power in the Germanic lands and the eastern half of his empire. Accepting that the German cities and territories were the political and military domains of their local rulers, Charles worked with these local leaders to establish a combined dominance instead of attempting to wrest away their power. Unfortunately, upon Charles' death his son Sigismund fell back into the historical fallacy of attempting to control Italy, and the Empire once again continued its decline into irrelevancy.[PARAGRAPH:1]Despite the internal power struggles wracking the Holy Roman Empire, local rulers banded together in order to face the Napoleonic threat from France. From 1792 to 1802, Austria, Prussia and the other German states combined forces with the hope of defeating the invading French, but to no avail. With little territory left under his control, Emperor Francis II resigned the title of Holy Roman Emperor. The Empire was formally dissolved on the sixth of August, 1806.[PARAGRAPH:1]Over its history, the Holy Roman Empire existed more as an idea than an actual administrative organization. The empire's leaders rarely had actual control over their lands, and constant squabbling between fiefdom holders, as well as the church and state, kept the empire from solidifying any real control over its domain. Its recreation has, however, served as a goal which many would-be conquerors in history have strived to achieve, including Otto von Bismark, King William I, and Adolf Hitler.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[BOLD]策略提示:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]神圣罗马文明是其对手们在中古时代的梦魇。神圣罗马替代法庭的特色建筑——议会厅可将城市维护费降低百分之七十五，使其几乎不必受维护费问题的困扰。而神圣罗马替代长枪兵的特色单位——自由佣兵可以说是中古时代最强的肉搏兵种，对其他肉搏单位及骑乘单位作战时均拥有百分之百的奖励加成。帝国领袖查理曼的特质是“保国”加“霸权”，擅长建立并维持庞大的领土，使得神圣罗马帝国成为游戏中最强大的文明之一。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]“神圣罗马帝国”是在公元800年时由查理曼所创立。帝国的传统疆域西起尼德兰，东达匈牙利，覆盖了中欧大部分地区，它既是改变欧洲历史之走向的强大实体，又是滋生阴谋和冲突的政治温床。从某种意义上来说，“神圣罗马皇帝”仅是这个庞大帝国名义上的最高统治者，历代皇帝往往只能调遣数量有限的军队，掌控范围有限的土地。[PARAGRAPH:1]虽然神圣罗马帝国上述地理疆域和形态特征是直到奥托一世统治时期（962-973）才真正成形的，但其作为一个政治实体的历史则开始于公元800年，当时罗马教皇利奥三世为了孤立业已衰落的拜占庭帝国（“东罗马帝国”），加冕查理曼为“神圣罗马皇帝”（塞爱维小提示：许多历史学家将这个政权称为“查理曼帝国”或“法兰克帝国”以同后来只包括中欧地区的“神圣罗马帝国”相区别）。查理曼是一位杰出的军事战略家和虔诚的天主教徒，他使帝国保持统一状态，但当他于公元814年去世后，帝国迅速分裂为几个彼此征战的邦国，直到奥托一世再次完成统一。虽然奥托一世成功重建了帝国，但他和他的继任者们都在对意大利的执意征伐中吃了苦头。意大利在当时已不属于帝国的正式版图（虽然查理曼曾对其实施有效的控制），可是为了壮大这个日耳曼帝国的实力，奥托一世不断率军南侵。奥托一世在意大利的军事冒险毫无收获，反而削弱了他在日耳曼地区的权力基础。[PARAGRAPH:1]皇帝与教会之间的争斗贯穿了神圣罗马帝国的整个历史。起初，只有教皇才能为皇帝加冕，然而随着时间的推移——特别是在奥托一世统治时期——反而是由皇帝来任命教皇，皇帝集世俗和宗教权力于一身。在萨利安王朝时期（1024-1125）情况再次改变，由教会人员组成的“红衣主教团”（Cardinals）掌握了提名和选举教皇的权力。这一制度经历微小调整，一直延续至今。[PARAGRAPH:1]查理六世也许是帝国历史上最为务实的一位皇帝。1355年查理六世经由红衣主教团推举成为皇帝之后，立即宣布放弃对意大利的领土要求，专注于巩固对日耳曼地区和帝国东半部分的控制。查理六世允许日耳曼地方诸侯在各自所属城市和领地上实施政治和军事统治，同他们分享帝国的利益，而不是图谋剥夺他们的权力。不幸的是，查理六世死后，他的儿子西吉斯蒙德又开始重复尝试控制意大利的错误，帝国也再度陷入历史潮流的对立面。[PARAGRAPH:1]尽管后期的神圣罗马帝国饱受内乱的困扰，但诸侯们还是团结起来，共同对抗法国皇帝拿破仑的威胁。从1792年到1802年，奥地利、普鲁士和其他日耳曼邦国怀着击退法国入侵的希望结成联盟共同战斗，但却屡遭挫败。眼看领地已经所剩无几，最后一任皇帝弗朗茨二世被迫退位。1806年8月6日，帝国正式宣告解体。[PARAGRAPH:1]历史上的“神圣罗马帝国”在大多数时候都只是一个名不副实的虚幻理想，皇帝很少能够真正掌控归属在其名下的疆土，总是不断与封臣、教会和城邦进行着明争暗斗，使其对帝国的有效统治变成不可能的任务。重建这个欧洲大帝国成为后世许多征服者追求的目标，包括奥托·冯·俾斯麦，包括威廉一世，也包括阿道夫·希特勒。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_CHARLEMAGNE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Charlemagne[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Emperor of the Holy Roman Empire, King of the Franks[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c.747 to 814 AD[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Charles the Great, Emperor of the Holy Roman Empire, fathered a kingdom that encompassed France, Germany, Italy and much of Eastern Europe. Legends of his conquests are pervasive throughout history, and he is considered one of the great figureheads of European Chivalric society.[PARAGRAPH:1]During his lifetime Charlemagne successfully campaigned in many countries. Some wars he completed personally and others were left for his sons to finish. His first campaign was against Desiderius of Lombardy who, soon after the succession of Pope Hadrian I, marched on Rome. Charlemagne pressed into Lombardy, and after a lengthy siege (772-774), he accepted Desiderius' unconditional surrender. Desiderius would live out the remainder of his life confined to a monastery.[PARAGRAPH:1]The longest lasting and most challenging conquest of Charlemagne's reign would be that of Saxonia. It would be a theater that he would continually revisit during his lifetime. After Charlemagne's initial push into Saxonia he was continuously forced to retake previously conquered land which had rebelled against his authority. Weary of war and losing more rights and freedoms with every capitulation, the Saxons eventually accepted Charlemagne's terms, including renouncement of their national religious customs and adoption of the Christian faith and its associated Frankish customs.[PARAGRAPH:1]Charles was both a highly religious man and a philanthropist. He often built friendly relationships with other countries, such as Egypt and India, so that he could later send money in an effort to assist struggling Christians in those regions. Although much more of a conqueror than an economic or social reformer, Charles often contributed money to relieve the poor and sick in his kingdom.[PARAGRAPH:1]Charlemagne, despite being unable to write well himself, had a vast love of literature and education. Due to his conquests, Charlemagne came into contact with many different cultures and learning institutions. Having contributed considerable funding to existing monastic schools and institutions of learning, Charlemagne's era became known as the Carolingian Renaissance, with a blossoming of the arts and sciences.[PARAGRAPH:1]As a member of the Nine Worthies, a group of both fictional and real people that represented the pinnacle of chivalry during their eras, Charlemagne was the embodiment of honor in both person and position. A conqueror, a philanthropist, lover of the arts and a highly devout Christian, Charlemagne stands as one of the important figures of the first millennium, and the forefather of Central Europe as it stands today. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]查理曼[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]神圣罗马帝国皇帝，法兰克国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]约747-814[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]“查理曼”（Charlemagne）意即“查理大帝”，他是神圣罗马帝国皇帝，这个帝国的范围涵盖今法国、德国、意大利以及东欧大片土地。他传奇般的征服业绩影响遍及欧洲历史的方方面面，被世人誉为欧洲骑士精神的伟大典范。[PARAGRAPH:1]查理曼的一生之中对许多国家进行了成功的征伐。许多征服由他亲自完成，有些战争则延续到他的子孙统治时期。他的第一场战争是针对伦巴第的德希迪里乌斯，此人在教皇哈德良一世即位后进军罗马挑起战端。查理曼挥师攻打伦巴第，经过一场漫长的围城战（772-774），迫使德希迪里乌斯无条件投降。后来德希迪里乌斯被软禁在一所修道院中度过余生。[PARAGRAPH:1]查理曼在位期间最漫长也最艰难的战争是对萨克森人的征服，这场战争在他有生之年持续不断。起初查理曼顺利攻占了萨克森地区，但萨克森人一再发动叛乱，使他不得不重复出兵，以夺回这些领地的控制权。萨克森人看到自己的权利和自由一次次被剥夺，逐渐失去了反抗的勇气，最终接受了查理曼的和平条件，包括放弃旧有信仰皈依基督教、认同法兰克人的社会制度等。[PARAGRAPH:1]查理曼既是一位热忱的宗教信徒，又是一位仁慈博爱的领袖。他与远方的国家例如埃及和印度建立了友好关系，以便能够向在当地挣扎求生的基督徒们提供资助。虽然查理曼更多地是作为一位征服者而非经济与社会的改造者，但他也经常出钱帮助国内的穷困者和患病者。[PARAGRAPH:1]查理曼本人虽不擅舞文弄墨，但却十分热爱文学和教育事业。在他的征战生涯中，查理曼接触了许多不同的文化族群和学术机构。查理曼给予各个教会学校和学术机构大笔的金钱资助，促进了艺术和科学的繁荣，后人因此称查理曼时代为“加洛林文艺复兴”（加洛林是查理曼家族的姓氏）。[PARAGRAPH:1]查理曼位列代表完美骑士精神、来自真实历史和神话传说的“九大英雄”之一（塞爱维小提示：这九位中世纪欧洲人心目中“最值得歌颂的英雄”是指赫克托耳、恺撒、亚历山大、亚瑟、查理曼、布戎的戈弗雷、约书亚、大卫、马卡布的犹大），被视为性格鲜明、地位崇高的荣耀化身。查理曼是开疆拓土的统帅、爱民如子的仁君、文化艺术的热情赞助者、基督教的虔诚信徒，是第一个千年最重要的历史人物之一，他对中欧政治与文化格局的深刻影响一直延续至今。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOLY_ROMAN_RATHAUS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]In German towns and cities the Rathaus was a central location used primarily for town council meetings and other official business. It was also used as a large meeting space for interest groups as well as for other activities, depending on the town's policies.[PARAGRAPH:1]Germany has several famous rathauses, including the Rathaus Schöneberg. The Rathaus Schöneberg was built in the Berlin borough of Tempelhof-Schöneberg between 1911 and 1914 before Schöneberg was absorbed by Berlin. After World War II, the Rathaus Schöneberg served as the temporary seat of government for West Berlin. Upon the destruction of the Berlin wall in 1989 the Rathaus reverted once again to its original function as City Hall of Schöneberg.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]在德国的城镇中，议会厅是一种主要用于举行地方议会和开展其它官方活动的重要场所。它也曾被一些利益集团用作基于城镇政策而举行其他活动的大型会议场所。[PARAGRAPH:1]德国有几座著名的议会厅，这其中包括勋伯格议会厅。勋伯格议会厅建于1911年至1914年间，坐落于柏林市的一个名叫特培尔霍夫-勋伯格的自治镇，那时这个自治镇还没有被吸收进柏林市。二战之后，勋伯格议会厅还一度为西柏林政府提供临时席位。在柏林墙倒塌之后，这座建筑被重新恢复了它的原始职能，即成为了勋伯格区的市政大厅。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HOLY_ROMAN_LANDSKNECHT_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Landsknecht were a Renaissance style of German mercenary (although the individual members came from all over Europe) which were renowned for employing a tactic known as the "pike square." In the pike square, each soldier would be equipped with an eighteen foot long pike, and would stand in a tight, and sometimes hollow, box formation. If attacked from any side, the pikemen would simply lower their weapons and brace their pikes into the ground. This tactic was devastating to enemy cavalry and infantry. Surpassing the Swiss mercenaries organizations on which they based their tactics, the Landsknecht eventually became one of the most successful style of mercenary in Europe due to their willingness to integrate newer technology such as arquebuses and gunpowder artillery into their military formations.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]“自由佣兵”（Landsknecht）指启蒙时代的日耳曼佣兵（实际上其成员来自欧洲各地，并不限于日耳曼人），以其“长枪方阵”战术而闻名于世。长枪方阵中的每位士兵手持18英尺的长枪，组成密集的方阵（有时是空心方阵）。当阵形的某一方向受到攻击，所有长枪手就会将手中的武器指向攻击方，这种战术对付敌方骑兵和步兵均非常有效。日耳曼佣兵从瑞士佣兵那里学会了方阵战术并积极引入新军事技术（例如火绳枪和火炮），逐渐抢走了“师傅”的生意，最终成为全欧洲最好的雇佣兵。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_PERICLES_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Pericles[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]General of Athens[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c.495 BC - 430 BC[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Pericles was a model statesman, a beloved citizen, and a determined general, leading Athens during its golden era of prosperity. Pericles was born in 495 BC in the Greek city state of Athens to the wealthy Alcmaeonid family. Though he later went on to lead Athens through the Peloponnesian war, he spent the majority of his early life in quiet study. It is believed that his studies in philosophy greatly influenced his later political career, and Pericles would use his influence with the Athenian people to further promote the arts and literature.[PARAGRAPH:1]Pericles debuted on the political stage in 472 BC when he sponsored the Persae of Aeschylus, a popular tragedy, during the spring festival of Dionysus. This cemented his position as a wealthy and influential man in the minds of the citizens, and gave him the influence necessary to assist in breaking up the Areopagus, a traditional council of wealthy landowners that ruled over Athens, and later to banish Cimon - one of his key political rivals.[PARAGRAPH:1]Some scholars have attributed several of the democratic institutions created by Pericles to the eventual downfall of Athens. The Athenian democratic structure was fundamentally flawed - in order to sustain their high quality of life the Athenians would need to subjugate other city states for the tribute they could provide. In the short term, however, this system helped create a powerhouse economy that threatened Sparta and eventually sparked the Peloponnesian war.[PARAGRAPH:1]Following a heavily defensive strategy, Pericles convinced the people to avoid direct confrontation with Sparta and its allies in favor of quick raids and overseas attacks which would make use of Athens's superior navy. The end result of the campaign would never be seen, as in 430 BC, just two years after the start of the war, a plague broke out in Athens, decimating the population and claiming the lives of Pericles' legitimate children and, eventually, his own.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]伯里克利[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]雅典将军[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]约前495-前430[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]伯里克利是模范的政治家、受宠的公民和决断的将军，雅典繁荣的黄金时代的领导者。公元前495年伯里克利出生于希腊城邦雅典富裕的阿尔克迈翁家族。虽然后来他在整个伯罗奔尼撒战争期间一直领导着雅典人民，但他早期的主要生活是安静的学习。据信他对哲学的研习极大的影响了他以后的政治生涯，而伯里克利也利用他对雅典人民的影响进一步提升了雅典的文学和艺术成就。[PARAGRAPH:1]伯里克利在政治舞台上崭露头角是公元前472年，在酒神狄俄尼索斯的新年祭期间，他出资承办了埃斯库罗期所著的传世悲剧《波斯人》的演出。这巩固了他在市民头脑中身为一名富有和有权势人士的地位，并给予他所必需的影响力，从而打破由传统贵族势力把持的战神山议事会对雅典的统治。后来他还放逐了西蒙——他的主要政治对手之一。[PARAGRAPH:1]一些学者将伯里克利创立的数种民主制度归结为雅典最终衰败的原因。伯里克利的民主结构有着基础上的缺陷——为了维持雅典人高品质的生活，必须征服其他城邦来获得他们提供的贡品。就目前所知，这套系统所帮助建立的强大经济威胁到了斯巴达，并最终点燃了伯罗奔尼撒战争。[PARAGRAPH:1]伯里克利以防御策略为重心，说服民众避免直接面对斯巴达人，他的盟友赞成快速奇袭并利用雅典优势的海军出海迎击。战役的最终结果永远也无法目睹了，因为在公元前430年，也就是战争开始后仅两年，雅典突然爆发了瘟疫。居民大量死亡，他的嫡子也失去了生命，最终——还有他自己。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLEM_VAN_ORANJE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Willem van Oranje[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Prince of Orange, Stadtholder of Holland[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] April 25, 1533 - July 10, 1584 AD[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Willem van Oranje, also known as "William the Silent," was born in 1533 into the House of Nassau, a prominent noble family in what is today modern Germany. In 1544, the young Count of Nassau, but 11 years old, became the Prince of Orange through an inheritance, with new holdings in the Netherlands waiting for young Willem to come of age.[PARAGRAPH:1]Oranje was raised in the lap of luxury, his family a favorite of the Spanish monarch in control of the Netherlands, Charles V. Oranje received his education in France at the behest of the Spanish King and proved to be both a precocious student and a charismatic leader. With the completion of his education, Oranje took control of his estates in the Netherlands. Thanks in part to his calm demeanor, which was a welcome change during an age of rising tensions, Oranje was appointed to a number of important posts within the Dutch government, eventually reaching the position of stadtholder, the highest rank open to a Dutchman. His selection to this auspicious rank came thanks to Phillip II, Charles' son and the new King.[PARAGRAPH:1]By 1559, enforcement of the law of Placaten, which made Protestantism not only a religious crime, but a civil one as well, increased bloodshed between Protestants and Catholics throughout the Netherlands. Oranje, taking a stance against the persecution of Protestants in the Netherlands, gradually found himself on the wrong side of the Catholic Spanish monarchs. Catching word of an imminent assassination attempt, Oranje was forced to retreat to his castle in Nassau, hoping to keep himself alive and free of the growing Dutch rebellion.[PARAGRAPH:1]When Phillip II sent Fernando de Toledo, the Duke of Alva, to deal with the uprising and arrest its leaders, Oranje was included in the list of outlaws. After failing to defeat Alva with his meager army, Oranje again fled, fortifying himself in the states of Holland. The Prince of Oranje, universally recognized for his ability and cunning, now found himself embroiled in the heart of the sweeping Dutch rebellion, which would continue to grow in size and scope into what became known as the Eighty Years' War.[PARAGRAPH:1]Due to sudden changes in Spanish leadership within the region, a number of provinces, taking advantage of the ensuing havoc, allied themselves with Oranje and the rebellion. With the signing of the Union of Utrecht in 1579, the five northern provinces of the Netherlands, along with much of Flanders and Brabant, previously separate, united in their opposition to Spain.[PARAGRAPH:1]To support the insufficient Dutch forces, Oranje had sought foreign aid and in 1581 received word from Francis, Duke of Anjou, brother of the French king, that if the struggling provinces declared independence from Spain and appointed Francis their sovereign, he would aid them in defeating their Spanish foe. So, on July 26, 1581, the United Provinces declared their independence from Spain.[PARAGRAPH:1]Oranje, unfortunately, was unable to enjoy his country's new independence for long. Unhappy with the restrictions the Dutch nobles had placed on his powers, the Duke of Anjou turned against Oranje and his peers. And while Anjou was defeated not long after, an assassin hired by King Phillip gunned down Willem van Oranje in 1584, bringing to an end the leader's grand struggle for Dutch freedom.[PARAGRAPH:1]While Oranje had passed on, the want for an independent Netherlands did not. Struggles would continue with the Spanish, but in 1648, the Treaty of Westphalia would end the Eighty Years' War and finally grant the country the self-determination that Willem van Oranje had died trying to institute.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]威廉·奥兰治[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]奥兰治亲王，尼德兰总督[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]1533年4月25日-1584年7月10日[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]威廉·奥兰治，人称“沉默者威廉”，生于1533年，来自拿骚家族（当时的一个名门望族，领地在今德国境内）。1544年，年仅11岁的拿骚伯爵威廉又继承了奥兰治亲王的头衔（领地在今荷兰境内），从此以奥兰治为家族姓氏。[PARAGRAPH:1]奥兰治自小在富贵奢华的环境中成长，他的家族很受当时统治着尼德兰诸省的西班牙国王、神圣罗马皇帝查理五世的垂青。国王安排奥兰治在法国接受教育，掌握了丰富的学识和出色的领导能力。在完成学业之后，奥兰治开始统治这块尼德兰领地。奥兰治生性平静沉稳，这种气质在那个冲突不断的年代里十分引人关注，地位不断上升，最终被任命为尼德兰总督——这是一个尼德兰人在帝国政界所能达到的顶峰了。奥兰治能够有幸获得任命，是由于继查理五世之后成为西班牙国王的腓力二世对他非常赏识。[PARAGRAPH:1]根据1559年开始实施的“安抚法令”，信仰新教是不仅违反宗教教条、而且违反世俗法律的严重罪行，这使得尼德兰诸省新教徒和天主教徒的流血冲突进一步加剧。由于奥兰治反对迫害新教徒，因而逐渐走向信奉天主教的西班牙王室的对立面。西班牙人暗中计划刺杀他，奥兰治觉察到危险，被迫逃往拿骚的城堡闭门不出，远离尼德兰的乱局以保全性命。[PARAGRAPH:1]当腓力二世派遣阿尔瓦公爵费尔南多·德·托莱多镇压尼德兰叛乱并逮捕领导者，奥兰治也被列入了黑名单。奥兰治的军队被阿尔瓦击败，但他撤至荷兰省坚持战斗。奥兰治亲王从置身事外到卷入风口浪尖，尼德兰起义波及的范围越来越大，牵涉的势力越来越多，最终演变为八十年战争。[PARAGRAPH:1]西班牙军队激烈的镇压行动导致局势的进一步混乱，促使多个尼德兰省份与奥兰治率领的起义者走向联合。1579年尼德兰各方代表签署协定，由北方五省及弗兰德斯省、布拉邦特省的大部组成“乌特勒支同盟”，共同对抗西班牙。[PARAGRAPH:1]为加强尼德兰一方的力量，奥兰治努力寻求外来援助。1581年，法国国王的兄弟，安茹公爵弗朗西斯向奥兰治提议：如果尼德兰诸省宣布独立于西班牙并推举弗朗西斯为领袖，他愿意协助出兵击败西班牙。于是在1581年7月26日，“尼德兰联合省”正式宣布独立建国。[PARAGRAPH:1]不幸的是，国家的独立给奥兰治带来的快乐并不长久。由于不满尼德兰贵族对自己权力的诸多限制，安茹公爵又开始与奥兰治为敌。安茹军队的进攻被挫败了，但腓力二世派遣的刺客却在1584年枪杀了威廉·奥兰治，他为独立自由而努力奋战的一生就此结束。[PARAGRAPH:1]刺杀奥兰治并未阻止尼德兰的独立进程，与西班牙人的战争仍在继续，到1648年，八十年战争随着威斯特伐利亚条约的签署宣告结束，尼德兰人终于赢得了威廉·奥兰治为之付出生命代价的国家主权。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NETHERLANDS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]With bonuses to Production, Culture and Commerce, the Dutch are the most balanced Builder civilization in the game. Willem van Oranje, a "Financial" and "Creative" leader, gives a major boost to Culture and Commerce in every city under his reign, while the Dike, the Dutch replacement for the Levee, provides a Production bonus from any water or river tile in a city radius. Throw in the most powerful transport ship until the discovery of the Transport - the East Indiaman - and you've got a civilization that can spread from horizon to horizon with ease.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Originally several separate territories under the control of the Holy Roman Empire, and then united into one state under Habsburg rule (16th century), the Netherlands did not acquire national independence until the conclusion of the Eighty Years' War (1568-1648 AD) when the Spanish formally renounced all claims to Dutch sovereignty in the Treaty of Münster.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Eighty Years' War was sparked by Spanish religious oppression and an occupation by Spanish forces led by the Duke of Alba, during which over one thousand people were sentenced to death, including two prominent and popular Dutch nobles; these actions caused dissention among the Dutch people. In 1568 Willem, Prince of Orange, returned from a self-imposed exile (in order to avoid prosecution by the Duke of Alba) and led the uprising against the Spanish occupation.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Dutch fight for independence can be seen as a war against religious oppression, with the Pacification of Ghent treaty being a written representation of this sentiment. Signed on November 8th, 1576 the document specified an alliance between the Dutch provinces, in which religious differences would be put aside for the purposes of expelling the Spanish and restoring local provincial control to the Netherlands.[PARAGRAPH:1]During the seventeenth century the Dutch began using their large military and merchant navies to both create their own trading posts along the African coast and rob those of the Portuguese in an effort to reach valuable markets in India and Indonesia. The inrush of treasure, trade and knowledge from these trading and military expeditions was extremely beneficial, and during this first half of the seventeenth century the Dutch experienced a Golden Age of cultural and economic growth. This Golden Age would soon come to a crushing end.[PARAGRAPH:1]In 1795, France, under Napoleon I, conquered the Dutch mainland. The Netherlands quickly declined in influence and power, locally and internationally, with the British taking most of their colonial possessions. After Napoleon was defeated a few colonial territories were restored to the Dutch and remained under their control until the decolonization of the twentieth century.[PARAGRAPH:1]Many historians regard the Dutch empire as the first truly capitalist country. In addition to developing the first stock exchange, many modern services such as corporate insurance and retirement funds were attributed to Dutch inventiveness.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Netherlands is also the birthplace of one of the world's early democratic institutions - the Dutch Water Boards. Due to the unique topography of the Netherlands - about half of the mainland is a foot or more under sea level - the country's waterways must be constantly monitored and controlled in order to prevent flooding that would result in tremendous loss of life and property. Each Water Board is in charge of one of the nation's 27 water districts and all matters pertaining to local water management. The creation of these water boards predates the Netherlands itself. [PARAGRAPH:1]The modern Netherlands, with a diverse population and liberal laws towards drugs, prostitution, abortion, same-sex marriage, and euthanasia, has been a constant haven for refugees from other countries. Cultural minorities are encouraged to protect their own cultural identity while at the same time integrate into Dutch culture at large, further reinforcing the open-minded ideals for which Dutch ancestors fought and died.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[BOLD]策略提示:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]荷兰拥有工业、文化和商业等方面的奖励加成，是游戏中最具平衡发展能力的文明。威廉·奥兰治作为一位“擅长理财”和“崇尚创新”的领袖，可为他统治下的每座城市带来文化兴盛和商业繁荣。而荷兰替代防洪堤的特色建筑——海堤则为城市范围内所有水域及沿河地块提供额外工业加成。荷兰的特色单位——东印度商船是运输舰出现之前最强大的运输工具，可帮助你轻松建立并维持一个覆盖全球的海洋帝国。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]（塞爱维小提示：荷兰是个约定俗成的称谓，其正式名称是“尼德兰”，意为“低地之国”，“荷兰”仅是当初尼德兰的七省之一。中文史籍通常在其独立前称“尼德兰”，独立后称“荷兰”以作区分。）[PARAGRAPH:1]荷兰起初是从属于神圣罗马帝国的几个省份，在16世纪（西班牙）哈布斯堡王朝统治时期逐渐融为一体。经过八十年战争（1568-1648），西班牙人最终签订了明斯特条约，正式放弃对该地的主权，荷兰至此赢得独立。[PARAGRAPH:1]八十年战争的起因是阿尔瓦公爵属下的西班牙驻军所进行的残酷宗教压迫，当时有上千名新教徒被处死，其中包括两位德高望重的贵族，激起尼德兰人的强烈不满。1568年，因遭阿尔瓦公爵迫害而自我流放的奥兰治亲王威廉返回尼德兰，发动了一场旨在推翻西班牙统治的起义。[PARAGRAPH:1]尼德兰人争取独立的战争同时也是争取信仰自由的战争，这一理念在根特协定的条文中明确地体现出来。根特协定于1576年11月8日签署，其中申明尼德兰诸省将团结一心，抛开彼此之间宗教信仰的差异，而将驱逐西班牙占领军、争取国家主权作为首要目标。[PARAGRAPH:1]在17世纪，年轻的荷兰已拥有强大的海军和商船队，在非洲沿海建立了一系列贸易据点，同时不断与葡萄牙人进行明争暗斗，控制了前往印度和印度尼西亚利润丰厚的航线。荷兰人通过一系列商业和军事冒险活动获得了大量金银财宝、商业资源和地理知识，使国家进入了文化繁荣和经济增长的黄金时代。但这样的好时光并未维持长久。[PARAGRAPH:1]法国皇帝拿破仑一世于1795年征服了荷兰本土，同时英国也在不断蚕食她的海外殖民地，荷兰在欧洲和全球的力量和影响迅速衰落。拿破仑被击败后，荷兰人恢复了部分海外领地的控制权，直到20世纪非殖民化浪潮的兴起。[PARAGRAPH:1]许多历史学家认为荷兰是世界上第一个真正的资本主义国家。荷兰人不但建立了最早的证券交易所，许多现代的金融服务——例如商业保险和退休基金——也都是荷兰人的发明。[PARAGRAPH:1]荷兰还产生了世界最早实行民主体制的公共机构之一——“水理事会”。由于荷兰独特的地理环境——半数国土均低于海平面一英尺以上——人们需要持续严密地监控其境内的所有水域，以防海水淹没土地，造成生命和财产的巨大损失。荷兰全国划分为27个“水区”，每个水区的相关事务都由该区的水理事会负责管理。这些水理事会的历史比荷兰的建国史更悠久。[PARAGRAPH:1]现今的荷兰生活着多种多样的文化族群，在对待麻醉剂、性交易、堕胎、同性婚姻和安乐死等问题上采取非常宽容的政策，因此成为不见容于其他国家的边缘性群体的避难天堂。国家鼓励各少数民族保持其独特的文化，同时又能与整个荷兰的文化融为一体，这些政策将荷兰开国先驱们曾经为之战斗牺牲的开放包容理念进一步发扬光大。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEVEE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The earliest human civilizations all grew up along the banks of rivers. Yet when rains grew heavy, the Nile, Indus, Tigris or Yangtze became a danger to those on their shores. The Levee, also known as a dam, is a wall of earth or stone, constructed to hold back encroaching waters. The ancient Egyptians were among some of the most sophisticated levee builders, channeling the Nile in order to provide water for cities and crops. Today levees provide hydroelectric power to populations throughout the world.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]最初人们都是沿着河岸来修筑河堤。然而每当大雨如注时，尼罗河，印度河，底格里斯河或扬子江对河两岸的人们来说都是个巨大的威胁。防洪堤，也称为大坝，是个由土或者岩石构筑而成的大墙，专门建来阻止洪水。古埃及人是最杰出的水利建筑师之一，凿渠令尼罗河水为城市供水和灌溉农作物。今天，大坝为世界各地的人们提供水电。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NETHERLANDS_DIKE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Dikes are walls of earth or stone, used to entrap or hold back water. Often built as a protection against flooding, the dike has come to characterize the Netherlands, with significant portions of the country actually lying below sea level. Dikes, while a necessity for the country's continued survival (and independence from foreign towel imports), were occasionally used as a clever tactic for self-defense. During the Siege of Leiden in the midst of the Eighty Years War, Dutch leader Willem van Oranje's men cut the dykes around the city, flooding the positions of the opposing Spanish and driving the invaders back before the sea.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]海堤是石头或泥土筑成的长墙，用于引入或阻止水流。荷兰的许多国土实际上都处于海平面以下的位置，为了抵御海水泛滥，海堤成了这里的象征。大堤，当然首先是为了保证国家命脉的延续（还从对外国的纺织品进口依赖中独立出来），偶尔也被用在一条精明的自卫计策里。在八十年战争中期的莱顿围城战中，荷兰领袖威廉·奥兰治的部队打开了环城大堤的一角，大水淹没了西班牙敌军的阵地，从而在海上就将侵略者据之门外。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NETHERLANDS_OOSTINDIEVAARDER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The term "East Indiaman" describes a vessel designed to transport goods between Europe, India, Indonesia and China during the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. The East Indiaman was an armed merchantman; although primarily designed for the transport of goods and passengers, it was nevertheless outfitted with cannon in order to protect itself against pirates or to open up hostile ports of call. In fact, the East Indiamen were among the most heavily armed ships of their time, and were sometimes acquired by state navies for use as warships.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because the East Indiaman was designed to carry cannon, the East Indiaman was inevitably slower than its descendants: the Ship of the Line and the Frigate. Yet the strengths of the East Indiamen ensured that the European trade companies that employed them could protect their profitable monopolies on all trade between Europe, the Americas, Africa and India.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]“东印度商船”是指18、19世纪在欧洲、印度、印度尼西亚和中国之间往来运送货物的专用船只。东印度商船是一种武装商船，虽然它在最初设计时是用于运送货物和客商的，但仍然配备有加农炮以对抗来自海盗或敌对港口的突然袭击。事实上东印度商船是当时武装最完备的船只，有时还被所在国海军征用作为战船。[PARAGRAPH:1]由于船型设计本身的关系，东印度商船的航速比在其之后发展起来的主力战舰和三桅战舰都慢。但其强大的战斗力已足够使欧洲贸易公司确保其对欧洲与美洲、非洲、印度之间利润丰厚的商路的垄断。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_PACAL_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Pacal II[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of Palenque[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] 603 - 683 AD [NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Pacal II, also known as Pacal the Great or "The Shield," was successor to the lineage and Mayan city today known as Palenque. Born in 603, Pacal II became King of Palenque in 615 and ruled it until his eightieth birthday, dying in 683. During Pacal's youth, the city of Palenque came under continual raids from the neighboring states of Pomona and Calakmul to the south. Palenque's male population was decimated, as men were taken prisoner or sacrificed by the various raiders, leaving Pacal's mother, Lady Sak K'uk, at the reins of the city until Pacal came of age. Taking the throne at the age of twelve, Pacal's reign suffered another decade of raids and even the kidnapping of a noble family member. [PARAGRAPH:1]Several victorious campaigns to subjugate minor city-states would mark the turning point for the young ruler and Pacal gradually found himself in command of a powerful and respected city. Taking revenge on those that once preyed upon his own, Pacal led raids against Pomona, securing his city's hegemony among the Mayans. [PARAGRAPH:1]Once an established power, Pacal began construction of numerous great structures, like the Palace of Palenque, one of the most exceptional examples of Mayan architecture visible today. [PARAGRAPH:1]Despite his success in saving his people from the raids of Pomona, Pacal was always looked down upon for inheriting the throne from his mother, rather than from a male predecessor. To combat this, the Mayan ruler engaged in a grand retelling of his Palenque family lineage, proclaiming the divinity of his mother, himself and his son, Kan Balam. This grand history of the Palenque lineage can be seen today lining the walls of the Temple of the Inscription, Pacal's massive burial pyramid. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]帕卡尔二世[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]帕伦克国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]603-683[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]帕卡尔二世，也被称为伟大的帕卡尔或者“神盾”，是玛雅帕伦克王室血统的王室成员。生于公元603年，于公元615年成为帕伦克国王，一直统治到八十岁寿终正寝为止。帕卡尔幼年时代，帕伦克经常被南方的邻居波莫娜和卡拉科姆鲁突袭。帕伦克的男性被大量屠杀，因为男人都被掠夺成为俘虏进行祭祀活动，帕伦克人逃难期间，帕卡尔的母亲，赛卡-克尤卡夫人统治着帕伦克，直到帕卡尔长大成人才让出王位。坐上了王座的十二岁的帕卡尔，遭遇了十年被打劫的统治期，甚至还被一个贵族成员给绑架过。[PARAGRAPH:1]几场战役的胜利，征服了一些小城邦，标志着这位年轻统治者的转折点，帕卡尔逐渐建立了自己的威信，掌握了帕伦克的权力。报复那些欺压自己的行动开始了，帕卡尔率领军队突袭了波莫那，保卫了自己人民的安全，并树立了在玛雅中的霸权地位。[PARAGRAPH:1]掌权后，帕卡尔开始兴建不计其数的建筑，比如帕伦克宫殿，是今天触目可见依然存在的历史遗产。[PARAGRAPH:1]尽管他成功挽救了被波莫那突袭的人民，帕卡尔始终被人看不起，因为他是从母亲那里继承来的王位，而不是从一个男性那里继承的。作为回击，这位玛雅的统治者郑重申了他的家族血统，宣称他的母亲是神的化身，他自己和他的儿子坎-巴拉姆也是神的化身。帕伦克的这段伟大历史依然在今天历历在目，它就记载于帕卡尔大陵墓铭文神庙的墙面上。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MAYA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Mayan Empire is wealthy, healthy and happy. Pacal's "Financial" trait adds a bonus to any plot producing 2 commerce, while his "Expansive" trait not only provides extra health to your cities, but also allows Workers to quickly improve new plots to take advantage of the "Financial" trait. Have your Workers build a few Hamlets and watch the money roll in. And while money can't buy happiness, the Ball Court certainly can, making your newly wealthy citizens jubilant. Even without the Holkan, a spearman that requires no copper, the Mayans would surely be an early game powerhouse.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Mayan Empire blossomed within the thick jungles and volcanic hills of Belize, Guatemala and the Yucatan Peninsula of Mexico. Creators of the most advanced civilization in the Americas from 700 BC until 900 AD, the Mayan population in its age was second only to the Chinese T'ang dynasty in sheer numbers.[PARAGRAPH:1]Often referred to as the "Greeks of the New World," the Mayans were similarly organized into a series of feuding city states, although these cities served more religious and administrative purposes than as populations centers. Uniting the Maya culture was a common language, religion and artistic style, but each city state remained fiercely independent, often uniting only at the point of a Holkan spear. [PARAGRAPH:1]Every city-state was governed by its own royal family, whom often claimed full or semi-divinity. During the Mayan Classical Period from roughly 250 to 900 AD, these cities became vast complexes of pyramids, causeways and plazas. Nakbe, the first city-state to grow on a grand scale, began its expansion around 700 BC. By 300 BC, Nakbe had been transformed into an impressive city, with four grand step pyramids and a seven mile stone causeway linking it to the nearby city of El Mirador. [PARAGRAPH:1]Nakbe was only the first of many vast cities. Chichen Itza, Tikal and Palenque all became massive population centers. With myriad pyramids and religious structures, Tikal grew to become a city of the grandest scale and the largest of the Mayan population centers, dwarfing Palenque and Copan.[PARAGRAPH:1]Palenque, a significantly smaller settlement to the West, reached its zenith in the seventh century AD under the reign of Pacal II, whose subjugation of neighboring cities ensured the hegemony of his own. Much is known about Pacal and his city thanks to the intricately-carved history left to us within Pacal's tomb, "The Temple of Inscriptions," entire walls of which were filled with the Mayans' distinctive pictographic language, the only written language developed in the Americas. [PARAGRAPH:1]Language was not the only realm in which Mayan minds excelled. Their calendars were nearly on par with those of the modern era, but were created without the use of the telescope or other tools. Independent development of the number zero, an accomplishment that eluded both the Greeks and Romans, was yet another of the impressive feats of the Mayans. [PARAGRAPH:1]Most of these discoveries grew out of the Mayan religion. And while certainly interested in knowledge, the Mayan religion was ensconced in the belief of the power of blood. Many wars among the Maya were fought simply to provide prisoners to be sacrificed in intricate religious ceremonies, thought necessary to ensure the safety and advancement of the people. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Mayan civilization came to a surprisingly abrupt end, and the cause of this fall is still a hotly debated topic. One of the most widely-accepted theories is that the delicate ecology of the Yucatan rainforests simply could no longer support the growing population of the Mayan people. A peasant revolt is also a likely cause of the fall of Mayan priestly caste, as belief in brutal Mayan rituals fell to the wayside. [PARAGRAPH:1]But the popular notion that the Mayans simply disappeared is false. While the grand temple building, intricate carvings and sacrifices ceased, the Mayan language and people continued to survive in their former homeland, even after the conquest of their country by Spanish conquistadors. The Mayan languages, Yucatec being the most common, are still spoken to this day and armed resistance by the Maya continued into the twentieth century. The Maya remain a living people.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[BOLD]策略提示:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]玛雅是个富裕、健康又快乐的文明。其领袖帕卡尔的“理财”特质使所有商业收入为2的地块额外+1商业，而他的“开拓”特质不但可提升所有城市的健康度，还能加快工人建造区域设施的速度，更有效地发挥“理财”特质的作用。记得让你的工人建造农舍，金钱很快就会滚滚而来。虽然金钱买不到幸福，但玛雅的特色建筑——人祭球场却可以让在你统治下富裕起来的人民感到快乐无比。替代矛兵而无需铜资源的特色单位——霍坎武士更使玛雅如虎添翼，确保其在游戏早期即成为世界强权。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]玛雅帝国兴起于今伯利兹、危地马拉和墨西哥的尤卡坦半岛，那里是被火山环绕的遍布着深深丛林的地方。在公元前700年到公元900年期间，玛雅是美洲大陆最高度文明的缔造者，期间，玛雅的人口数量仅仅亚于中国的唐朝，居世界第二。[PARAGRAPH:1]玛雅常被称为“新大陆的希腊”，尽管更多的用宗教方式来管理这些人口中心，玛雅还是同样存在着城邦不和谐的系列问题。尽管用统一语言、统一宗教、统一艺术形式的手段去试图统一玛雅文化，但是各个城邦依旧存在着强烈的独立情绪，因此将这些城邦结为一体就成为玛雅“霍坎武士”（Holkan）的重要职责。[PARAGRAPH:1]每个城邦都由各自的王族所统治，这些王族通常宣称自己是半神之身甚至神的化身。大约公元250年到公元900年期间的玛雅古典时代，这些城邦遍布金字塔，铺石路和花园广场。从大约公元前700年，纳克贝城，成长为第一座具有巨大规模的城市，并开始向周边扩张。到了公元前300年，纳克贝城已经俨然一座具备重要影响的城市，拥有四座巨阶金字塔，并用豪华的铺石路一直铺到埃尔-米拉多，足有七英里长。[PARAGRAPH:1]纳克贝城仅仅是众多大城市之一。奇琴伊察城，蒂卡尔城和帕伦克城都是具有众多人口的城市。拥有无数金字塔和宗教建筑的蒂卡尔城逐渐成为了规模最大的人口中心，而帕伦克城和科潘城逐渐退出了竞争。[PARAGRAPH:1]帕伦克城是座落于西面的一座稍小些但是引人注目的城市，在公元七世纪帕卡尔二世统治时期到达顶峰。帕卡尔二世镇压了周边城市的暴动，确保了自己的霸权地位。我们对帕卡尔的了解，要归功于帕卡尔墓——铭文神庙，庙墙上面书写着玛雅文化的沧桑历史。而书写用的文字则是玛雅独一无二的象形文字，唯一一种由美洲原住民所创造的文字。[PARAGRAPH:1]语言并不是玛雅王国唯一骄傲的东西。她的历法跟现代历法具有同等价值，但是玛雅历法的制订并没有使用过天文望远镜或者类似的工具。完全从零开始，丝毫没参考过希腊和罗马的历法，这是另一个让人刮目相看的玛雅成就。[PARAGRAPH:1]绝大多数的发现演变成玛雅宗教。但是出于对这些发现的认知程度，玛雅宗教认为都是因为“血的力量”。所以，很多玛雅的战争仅仅是为了掠夺俘虏，用来进行各种形式的祭祀活动，以确保自己人民的安全和优势地位。[PARAGRAPH:1]令人不解的是玛雅文明却突然消失了，这一直是人们谈论的热点话题。比较广泛接受的观点是，尤卡坦半岛的雨林生态环境无法支撑那么多人口的玛雅人。农民起义也极为可能是诱因之一，他们反对残酷的玛雅宗教仪式，导致了玛雅僧侣阶级的垮台。[PARAGRAPH:1]然而说玛雅人消失了的说法肯定是不正确的。当西班牙征服者的铁蹄征服了玛雅王国后，纵然巨庙建筑，精美的雕刻品和祭祀活动不再，玛雅语言和人民却依旧生存在他们从前的土地上。玛雅的一些语言，比如尤卡坦语至今仍然被广泛使用，而且玛雅人民的抵抗一直没有间断，一直持续到二十世纪。玛雅人至今仍然生活着。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MAYA_BALL_COURT_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Mesoamerican "Ball Game" (no native name has ever surfaced for the sport) originated in Southern Mexico, roughly two thousand years before the Common Era. By the time of the arrival of the Spanish, the game had become popular throughout Mexico, Guatemala and Belize, drawing crowds from both the upper echelons of society and the masses.[PARAGRAPH:1]While much of the game is still not understood, what is known is that two teams of two to four players each took to the field with the goal of keeping a small, rubber ball in the air by bouncing it off arms, hips and thighs. How the winner was decided is not known, but we do know that the losers often became the next sacrifice to the gods.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Ball Court held a deep religious significance for the Maya. Mayan Kings would often reenact a famous game between the God of the Underworld and the Heroes from the Popol Vuh, a Mayan sacred text. The King's victory on the Ball Court was said to be an omen of the continued survival of his city.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]中美洲土著的“球赛”（不是这项运动原始意义上的名字）起源于墨西哥南部，大约距今已有两千年历史。到西班牙人到达时，这种比赛已经风靡墨西哥、危地马拉和伯利兹等地，并且吸引了众多上层社会和基层民众的踊跃参与。[PARAGRAPH:1]这项运动的很多部分还不为人所知，已知的只是两队各两到四名队员，各占一方场地，需用手臂、臀部和腿部将一个胶制小球不落地的送入对方球门。怎样决出胜利一方无从知晓，但是失败者却将成为下一批献给众神的祭品。[PARAGRAPH:1]人祭球场对玛雅人来说有着至关重要的宗教意义。玛雅人的国王们经常从玛雅族圣经中汲取灵感，创造一个英雄对阵地下世界之神的比赛。国王一方的胜利会被认为是他的城市延续生存的预兆。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MAYA_HOLKAN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Warfare among the Mayans was a bloody and constant affair, serving both economic and religious purposes. Most leaders demanded tribute from conquered city-states in order to increase their own standing. Yet equally important was the capture of victims for sacrifice. This was the domain of the dreaded Holkan. Elite warriors armed with slingshots, stones and razor-sharp spears, the Holkans were trained specifically to capture enemies alive, to provide fodder for ever-hungry sacrificial altars.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]玛雅各部族间战争血腥而又频繁，有时是由于利益纠葛，有时是由于宗教冲突。胜利一方的领袖除了要求被征服的城邦缴纳大笔贡奉以进一步增强自己的实力，还需要捕获大量人口作为对神灵的献祭——这些任务均由令人畏惧的“霍坎武士”（Holkan）来承担。霍坎武士的装备是弹弓、石子和锋利的长矛，他们通过专门的训练，特别擅长将敌人生擒活捉，以便源源不断地向嗜血的祭坛提供牺牲。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ZARA_YAQOB_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Zara Yaqob[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of Ethiopia[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c.1399-1468 AD[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Zara Yaqob was Emperor of Ethiopia from 1434 until 1468. A member of the Solomonic Dynasty, which traced its heritage back to the Biblical King Solomon, Zara Yaqob was an extremely devout, if occasionally draconian, ruler. Confined to the Amba Geshen prison for the early years of his life due to being a potential threat to his brother Tewodros's grip on the throne, Zara Yaqob only gained monarchal power in 1434 after his brother's death.[PARAGRAPH:1]As a highly religious leader, Zara Yaqob introduced many reformations and innovations in daily living based off his beliefs. Christmas was celebrated monthly in addition to many other feasts and celebrations. All thirty three festivals to the Virgin Mary were celebrated as if they were on the Sabbath, regardless of the actual day of the week on which they fell.[PARAGRAPH:1]Zara Yaqob was strict in his religious beliefs. Citizens who did not rigidly follow the prescripts of the Christian Church and adorn themselves with religious markings were put to death. If a person admitted to, or was accused of, worshipping the devil (or another non-Christian god), they were put to death. Even Zara Yaqob's own family was not sheltered from these punishments. Several were beaten and put to death, including his own wife, in an effort to give credibility to his harsh punishments, which were widely criticized.[PARAGRAPH:1]After a conspiracy organized by one of his subordinates came to light early in his reign, Zara Yaqob started exhibiting signs of paranoia. He began replacing all of his higher officials with female family members whom he felt he could trust. The emperor eventually attempted to appoint his own sisters, daughters and nieces to various governorships. Due to this paranoia, Zara Yaqob's reign is distinguished as being uniquely female dominated in a time when men traditionally held the majority of social power.[PARAGRAPH:1]Zara Yaqob also sent several diplomatic missions into Europe and India in both an attempt to create alliances against the rising Middle Eastern Islamic powers and to bring skilled workers and artisans into his country.[PARAGRAPH:1]Known mostly for his draconian religious laws, Zara Yaqob none the less was a practical leader and managed to protect Ethiopian interests from outside influence for the duration of his reign. Several of his progressive writings on religion, including the Mashafa Berha and the Mashafa Milad, are still available today.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]札拉·雅各布[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]埃塞俄比亚国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]约1399-1468[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]扎拉·雅各布是从1434年到1468年统治埃塞俄比亚的皇帝，属于所罗门王朝，这个家族可以上溯到圣经中的所罗门王。扎拉·雅各布是一位极其虔诚甚至严苛的统治者。早年时，由于雅各布对他的哥哥特沃德罗斯取得王座有着潜在威胁，因此他被囚禁于安巴监狱，直到1434年，他的哥哥死后，扎拉·雅各布才取得了国王的权利。[PARAGRAPH:1]作为一名十分虔诚的领导人，扎拉·雅各布基于他的信仰，在日常生活中引入了许多改革和创新。圣诞节每月都要举行一次，再加上许多其它的盛宴和节日。所有的33个纪念圣母玛利亚的节日都要被庆祝，就好像它们总是在安息日一样，而不管它们具体是在哪一个星期。[PARAGRAPH:1]扎拉·雅各布对他的宗教信仰的执行十分严格。没有严格执行基督教堂指示或没有用宗教标志装饰自己的市民都要被处死。如果一个人承认，或是被指控崇拜恶魔（或是其他非基督教的神灵），也要被处以死刑。即使是扎拉·雅各布的族人，也不能免于惩罚，一些人被责打并处死，包括他自己的妻子，这种行为是为了给他的这种广受指责的惩处措施一种公信力。[PARAGRAPH:1]在他早年的时候，一起由下属发起的针对他的阴谋被曝光，使得扎拉·雅各布开始表现出一种偏执狂的状态。他将所有的高层官员都替换为他认为值得他信赖的女性。这个皇帝甚至打算任命他的妹妹、女儿和侄女成为各种政府官员。因为这种偏执狂的表现，扎拉·雅各布的政府同其他的政府截然不同：女性占据了本来由男性主导的全部统治地位。[PARAGRAPH:1]扎拉·雅各布同时也向欧洲和印度派去了几个外交官员，试图寻求联盟，以对抗日益崛起的中东伊斯兰势力，并将熟练工人和艺术家带到他的国家来。[PARAGRAPH:1]尽管更多的是因为他严厉的宗教法令而闻名，扎拉·雅各布同时也是一位有作为的领导人，在他的统治期间，他在外来势力的影响下努力保护着埃塞俄比亚的利益。他的一些宗教上的进步著作，包括《光书》和《诞生书》，现在我们仍然可以读到。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ETHIOPIA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Expert in quick combat and civil society, the Ethiopian Empire draws its strength as a city-building empire from the reduced upkeep costs for civics and speedily-expanding borders of leader Zara Yaqob's "Organized" and "Creative" traits. The Stele building, the Ethiopian replacement for the Monument, spreads happiness as well as culture among Ethiopian cities. But when it comes to lightning combat, few can compare to the Oromo Warrior, a Musketeer replacement that is immune to first strikes and starts with the Drill I and Drill II promotions.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ethiopia is believed by many historians to be the birthplace of the human race. Lucy, a 3.2 million year old human skeleton, was discovered in Ethiopia's Afar Depression. However, beyond Lucy, there is little evidence to suggest (one way or another) that Ethiopia was settled until roughly the eighth century BC, when it is theorized that Jewish settlers fleeing Egypt, Sudan, and southern Arabia settled there.[PARAGRAPH:1]The first recorded government in Ethiopia was the Kingdom of Axum in the first century AD. Information on this kingdom is scarce; its founder remains unknown. But under Axum rule, Ethiopia became the first Christian nation in Africa. In roughly 330 AD, Frumentius, a Greek from Tyre, was consecrated the first bishop of Ethiopia by Saint Athanasius. Frumentius spread Christianity in Ethiopia through the construction of churches on land given to him by the Axum emperor. Although Christianity did not become a widespread religion in the region until much later, Frumentius can be considered the originator of Christianity in Ethiopia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Although Ethiopia had traditionally been the target for Muslim raids in the region, it was not until 1528 that a full scale invasion was successful. Under the leadership of Imam Ahmad ibn Ibrihim al-Ghazi, Muslim forces swept through Ethiopia, routing the emperor's forces and sending him into hiding. Unable to re-secure his homeland with Ethiopian forces alone, Emperor Lebna Dengel Dawit II petitioned the Portuguese to assist defeating the invaders. In 1541 the Portuguese deployed an army of 400 musketeers to assist the emperor, and while these forces were defeated at the Battle of Wofla, the Muslims were ultimately forced to retreat when their leader was killed the following year at the Battle of Wayna Daga.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ethiopia had been wracked by a series of internal conflicts throughout the sixteenth and seventeenth century. While not splintering the nation, these conflicts eroded the empire's central power until the feuding families were ultimately defeated by Tewodros II, who ruled Ethiopia between 1855 and 1868. Despite a prestigious military career, Tewodros II committed an egregious political faux pas when, in 1867, he imprisoned several British nationals after Queen Victoria of the England failed to answer a letter he had sent to her. The British swiftly sent an army to rescue the British citizens, and upon the Ethiopian army's defeat, Tewdros II committed suicide.[PARAGRAPH:1]Soon after, in 1870, the Italians, who had bought the Ethiopian costal city of Eritrea from a local Sultan, claimed that the Treaty of Wuchale (1889), an agreement between Italy and Ethiopia on the official boundaries between Ethiopia and Eritera, granted them sovereignty over all of Ethiopia, though in reality it only specified a very small portion of Northern Ethiopia near Eritrea. The Italians sent an army to conquer Ethiopia, but were repelled by Emperor Menelek II at the Battle of Adowa. After their defeat, the Italians signed the Treaty of Addis Ababa (1896) which recognized Ethiopia as an independent state. As it turned out, the Italians would be back.[PARAGRAPH:1]In 1936 the Italians once again invaded and occupied Ethiopia, this time under the fascist dictatorship of Mussolini, forcing the emperor to flee to England. The Italians were eventually defeated in 1941 by combined British and Ethiopian forces.[PARAGRAPH:1]Perhaps the most influential Ethiopian Emperor of the modern era was Haile Selassie I. Ruling from 1930 until his death in 1974 (with the exception of the brief Italian occupation), Selassie made great strides in modernizing his nation. New tax programs were implemented and the constitution was revised under his rule.[PARAGRAPH:1]In 1972, an enormous drought hit Ethiopia resulting in the deaths of over 200,000 citizens. Local rulers conspired to keep this information from Emperor Selassie, and when the information was finally revealed, the government's credibility with the common citizenry was seriously undermined. Combined with a major economic recession, the chaos within the government due to the drought provided the opportunity for officers within the Ethiopian military to stage a coup and take over the government. Haile Selassie I died on August 27th, 1975 when it is believed that he was suffocated in his sleep while imprisoned by the military government.[PARAGRAPH:1]In 2005 Ethiopia underwent its second multiparty election. Despite claims of corrupted vote counting, much of the international community saw this election as a positive step for Ethiopia's future.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[BOLD]策略提示:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]埃塞俄比亚帝国擅长速战速决与和平发展，其力量来自于札拉·雅各布“组织”加“创新”特质所带来的内政法令维护费降低和文化边界快速扩张。埃塞俄比亚替代纪念碑的特色建筑——纪念石柱可为城市带来额外的快乐与文化点数。而在实施闪击战的能力方面，很少有其他兵种能与埃塞俄比亚替代火枪手的奥罗莫战士相比，这种特色单位对先发打击免疫，并可自动获得操练一级和操练二级晋升。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]埃塞俄比亚被很多历史学家认为是人类的诞生地。考古学家在阿法尔洼地发现了露西，一具有着320万年历史的人类骨骼。然而除了露西之外，几乎没有其它的证据能够证明人类定居埃塞俄比亚的历史可以追溯到约公元前8世纪以前——历史记载中犹太移民从埃及、苏丹和阿拉伯南部地区逃难出来并在此定居的年代。[PARAGRAPH:1]最早有记录的埃塞俄比亚政权是公元1世纪的安瑟姆王朝，有关这个王朝的信息大多已经丢失，它的建立者是谁也不清楚。但是在安瑟姆王朝的统治下，埃塞俄比亚成为非洲最早的一个基督教国家。在大约公元330年，弗鲁盟提乌斯，一个来自泰尔的希腊人，受圣徒亚沙拿修斯的派遣，成为埃塞俄比亚的首任大主教。弗鲁盟提乌斯通过在安瑟姆皇帝送给他的土地上建造教堂的方式，开始传播基督教，尽管直到很长的一段时间之后，基督教才开始流行，但弗鲁盟提乌斯仍然被看作是基督教在埃塞俄比亚的鼻祖。[PARAGRAPH:1]尽管埃塞俄比亚经常成为穆斯林的侵略对象，但直到1528年穆斯林才真正实现了成功的全面入侵。在伊玛目·艾哈迈德的领导下，穆斯林的军队横扫埃塞俄比亚全境，击溃埃塞俄比亚军队并迫使皇帝本人逃亡。认识到单靠他自己的力量无法收复领土，埃塞俄比亚的皇帝大卫二世向葡萄牙乞求帮助以击败入侵者。葡萄牙遂于1541年派遣了一支由400名火枪手组成的军队前来帮助他，尽管这支部队在沃弗拉战役中败北，但由于次年穆斯林领袖战死于维纳·达加战役中，因此穆斯林军队最终还是被迫撤退了。[PARAGRAPH:1]在16世纪和17世纪时，埃塞俄比亚遭到了一系列的内乱，使得它的实力大减。尽管国家并未由此分裂，但这些冲突削弱了王权。这种情况一直持续到特沃德罗斯二世最终打败了那些割据的封建领主。特沃德罗斯二世于1855到1868年间统治着埃塞俄比亚，他尽管有着声名显赫的军旅生涯，但他却犯下了一个严重的错误：1867年时，仅仅是因为维多利亚女王没有回他的一封信，他就监禁了数名英国人作为报复。英国很快派出了一支军队来解救被囚禁的国民。在败给了英国的军队后，特沃德罗斯二世自杀身亡。[PARAGRAPH:1]不久之后的1870年，从一名当地苏丹手上买下了海岸城市厄立特里亚的意大利人，宣称1889年签订的《乌查里条约》——一份规定了意大利与埃塞俄比亚在厄立特里亚附近正式边界的条约——给予了他们管理埃塞俄比亚全境的权利，尽管这份条约的实际范围上只包括了在厄立特里亚附近的很小一部分埃塞俄比亚领土。意大利于是派遣了一支军队试图征服埃塞俄比亚，然而他们却在阿杜瓦战役中被皇帝孟尼利克二世打败，最终不得不签订了《亚的斯亚贝巴和约》，承认埃塞俄比亚是一个独立的主权国家。然而事实证明，意大利人还会再回来的。[PARAGRAPH:1]1936年，意大利人再度入侵并占领了埃塞俄比亚，这次是在法西斯独裁者墨索里尼的统治下，迫使埃塞俄比亚的皇帝逃亡英国。最终意大利人于1941年败给了英国和埃塞俄比亚的联军。[PARAGRAPH:1]现代最有影响力的埃塞俄比亚皇帝应该是海尔·塞拉西一世了。他的统治从1930年起直到1974年他去世止（中间有一个短暂的被意大利统治时期），塞拉西做了相当多的努力以使他的国家更加现代化，在他的统治下，新的税法被颁布，并且议会也作出了改革。[PARAGRAPH:1]在1972年，一次严重的旱灾袭击了埃塞俄比亚，导致了超过20万人身亡。当地的政府官员阴谋隐瞒这个消息，但当这个消息最终曝光时，政府的公信力被严重的削弱了，再加上当时严重的经济倒退和政府部门的混乱，这给了埃塞俄比亚军方一个可乘之机，他们策划推翻了政府并控制了权利。海尔·塞拉西死于1975年8月27日，据信他是在被军政府囚禁期间死于睡觉时的窒息。[PARAGRAPH:1]2005年埃塞俄比亚经历了它的第二次多党派选举，尽管有消息称选举中存在贿选和舞弊的情况，但国际社会的大多数成员还是把这次选举看作有利于埃塞俄比亚未来发展的一个积极步骤。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ETHIOPIAN_STELE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]A Stele is a monument made of either wood or rock, erected for commemorative, funerary, or official purposes. In addition, Stelai would sometimes be used as territorial markers. Stelai have often provided some of the best historical records of a civilization, due to the lasting nature of the materials with which they were made.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Kingdom of Aksum, which encompassed Ethiopia, Yemen, southern Saudi Arabia, northern Somalia, Djibouti and northern Sudan, erected some of the largest Stelai in the world. These Stelai, located in the city of Aksum in Ethiopia, mark the graves of Aksum's kings and nobles.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]纪念石柱是一种木制或石制的纪念碑，一般由于纪念仪式、葬礼或是其他正规仪式而树立。另外，纪念石柱有时会被用作划分区域的标志。纪念石柱经常能提供某个文明最具历史性的记录，制作石柱的材料也理所当然的是耐久度很高的材料。[PARAGRAPH:1]阿克苏姆的王国版图，包括了埃塞俄比亚、也门、沙特阿拉伯南部、索马里北部、吉布提和苏丹北部的地区，那里树立着一些世界上最巨大的纪念石柱。这些位于埃塞俄比亚境内的阿克苏姆石柱，标志出了阿克苏姆国王与贵族的陵寝。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ETHIOPIAN_OROMO_WARRIOR_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Oromo are a cultural group that has lived for centuries in the area today known as Ethiopia. Historically defined by their unique democratic caste system, each age group within the Oromo was assigned to a specific position within society. As an Oromo citizen aged, they progressed through these age groupings to assume different positions within the Oromo hierarchy. Young men between the ages of sixteen and thirty-two were traditionally assigned to the warrior caste. Young Oromo men were not fully considered men until they had killed a man or, in times of peace, a fierce animal.[PARAGRAPH:1]Bravery in combat was paramount among Oromo culture, and many of their customs required retelling the histories of great warriors. These storytelling traditions reinforced the warlike attitude prevalent throughout Oromo society. In addition to this focus on military achievement, the Oromo also heavily stressed the importance of harmony and peace amongst their people. This unifying ideal ensured that if any outside military force attacked an Oromo tribe, they could expect a united Oromo counterattack. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]“奥罗莫人”（Oromo）指的是许多世纪以来一直生活在今埃塞俄比亚地区的一个文化族群，以其独特的“民主等级制度”而闻名于世。奥罗莫人根据不同的年龄段归入不同的社会阶层，随着年龄的增长，进入所在年龄段所对应的更高社会等级。在奥罗莫人的传统中，16至32岁的青年都属于战士阶层。一位奥罗莫青年必须杀死一个敌人（在和平时期则须杀死一只猛兽）才会被视为真正成年。[PARAGRAPH:1]奥罗莫文化非常强调英勇无畏的品质，有许多著名勇士的故事在奥罗莫人中代代相传，这些英雄故事不断强化着整个社会的尚武传统。奥罗莫人不但重视军事成就，而且重视本族群内部的和谐共荣。这种理念使得任何敢于侵犯单个奥罗莫部族的外来军事力量均将面临所有奥罗莫人团结一致的反击。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SULEIMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Suleiman I[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Sultan of the Ottoman Empire[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] November 6, 1494 - September 6, 1566 AD[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Suleiman I, known as "The Magnificent," "The Legislator" and "The Grand Turk," was the caliph of Islam and the sultan of the Ottoman Empire, taking the reigns of the Turkish kingdom in 1520 and ruling until his death in 1566.[PARAGRAPH:1]The only heir still breathing when his father Selim I passed on, Suleiman continued his father's tradition of expansion throughout the Middle East, creating a new level of prosperity within the empire. Suleiman's conquests reached from Baghdad to Egypt, making the Ottoman Empire the main channel through which the riches of the east could reach Europe. Ottoman naval supremacy in the Mediterranean further aided Suleiman's economic empire, the corsair Barbarossa sending innumerable European ships to the sea floor.[PARAGRAPH:1]It was this penchant for expansionism that struck fear into the heart of Europe. The Sultan's push northward took him as far as Hungary, where he found his progress stalled by the Hapsburg ruler Archduke Ferdinand I.[PARAGRAPH:1]While his territorial accomplishments were impressive, the Sultan did not ignore the culture of his homeland, Suleiman himself a skilled poet and fervent Muslim. Towards the end of his reign, Suleiman commissioned numerous new mosques of a previously unseen grandeur, designed by master architect, Sinan.[PARAGRAPH:1]Suleiman became well known in both the Christian west and the Muslim east, but for strikingly different reasons. Most Europeans envied the Sultan for the sheer opulence in which he lived. Celebrations of a previously unheard of grandeur were held at the Hippodrome in Istanbul. Rooms covered in gold, gems and the finest tapestries could be seen throughout the Sultan's palace at Topkapi.[PARAGRAPH:1]Muslims, on the other hand, respected the Sultan for his belief in the rule of law. The Sultan adopted Islamic sacred law to compliment the traditional law already in place from his predecessors. Both Christian and Muslim recognized the renewed strength and sense of honor that Suleiman brought to the Ottoman Empire, deeming him worthy of the title "The Magnificent."</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]苏莱曼一世[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]奥斯曼帝国苏丹[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]1494年11月6日-1566年9月6日[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]苏莱曼一世，以“大帝”，“立法者”和“大土耳其之君”闻名，是伊斯兰教的哈利发和奥斯曼土耳其帝国苏丹，于1520年继位统治土耳其王国直至1566年逝世。[PARAGRAPH:1]作为其父塞利姆一世身故之际仍在世的唯一继承人，苏莱曼既在中东各地发扬他父亲的扩张传统，又将帝国内部的繁荣提升至新的高度。苏莱曼的征服从巴格达直至埃及，使奥斯曼帝国成为东方财富得以进达欧洲的主要通道。奥斯曼在地中海的海上霸权更进一步加强了苏莱曼的经济帝国，巴巴罗萨的海盗船将无数欧洲船只葬送海底。[PARAGRAPH:1]其扩张主义倾向令欧洲从内心里感到恐惧。苏丹向北推进至匈牙利，直到他发现自己前进的步伐受阻于哈布斯堡王室的统治者费迪南一世大公。[PARAGRAPH:1]在他开疆拓土的成就令人印象深刻的同时，苏丹没有忽视祖国的文化，苏莱曼本人是熟练的诗人和虔诚的穆斯林。苏莱曼在统治后期委托建筑大师锡南设计了许多空前壮观的新清真寺。[PARAGRAPH:1]苏莱曼在基督教西方和穆斯林东方皆广为人知，但显然出于不同原因。大多数欧洲人因其奢华的生活而羡慕苏丹：前所未有的豪华的庆祝活动在伊斯坦布尔的赛马场举行。覆盖黄金的殿堂，珠宝和最好的挂毯在苏丹的托普卡匹宫比比皆是。[PARAGRAPH:1]而另一方面穆斯林因其在立法原则中体现出的信仰而尊敬苏丹。苏丹采用伊斯兰宗教法以向其先辈已实行的传统法律表达敬意。基督徒和穆斯林都承认苏莱曼带给奥斯曼帝国复兴的实力和荣誉感，认为他是当之无愧的“大帝”。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_LINCOLN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Abraham Lincoln[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]16th President of the United States of America[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] February 12th, 1809 AD - April 15th, 1865 AD[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]"A house divided against itself cannot stand. I believe this government cannot endure permanently half-slave and half-free. I do not expect the Union to be dissolved - I do not expect the house to fall - but I do expect it will cease to be divided. It will become all one thing or all the other." (House Divided Speech, June 16, 1858)[PARAGRAPH:1]President Abraham Lincoln was born in 1809 on the American frontier in Hadrin County, Kentucky. While not poor, Lincoln certainly had more in common with the average American than his more affluent political counterparts. An almost entirely self-made man, Lincoln's formal education included only 18 months of unofficial schooling which he supplemented with his own studies. Teaching himself law, he was admitted to the bar in 1837 upon which he became a well known and successful lawyer.[PARAGRAPH:1]Lincoln is best known for his Emancipation Proclamation, which declared the end to slavery in the United States, and his refusal to permit the secession of the South. His reasons for fighting the Civil War are often misconstrued, however, as being motivated by his desire to end slavery. Lincoln's motivations behind fighting the civil war were the preservation of the Union and, to an extent, the protection of the larger democratic ideals represented by an unshattered Union. "[A]nd that government of the people, by the people, for the people, shall not perish from the earth." (Gettysburg Address)[PARAGRAPH:1]Few public speakers in American history have spoken in a manner that at once appealed to the desires of their constituents while at the same time addressed the larger issues outside the purview of an average citizen. This was Lincoln's gift. A brilliant orator and public speaker, he was able to convey the larger political picture to his constituents in a way that was at once easy to understand and implored action for the greater good of the country.[PARAGRAPH:1]Largely criticized and ridiculed for his policies before and during the war, Lincoln's greatness was only fully acknowledged by the public after his assassination by John Wilkes Booth on April 15th, 1865.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]亚伯拉罕·林肯[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]美国第16任总统[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]1809年2月12日-1865年4月15日[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]“分裂之家不能持久。我相信我们的政府不可能永远容忍半奴隶制半自由人的状态。我不希望这国家分崩离析──我不希望这家庭灭顶倾覆，但我的确期望它不再四分五裂。它终将完全变为其中一种或是另一种。”（“家庭纠纷”演讲，1858年6月16日）[PARAGRAPH:1]亚伯拉罕·林肯总统1809年出生于美国边境附近的肯塔基州哈定县。若非贫穷，林肯和他富有的政治对手相比，显然和普通的美国人没什么两样。做为一个差不多完全是自力更生的人，林肯所受的正式教育仅包括18个月的由非执业教师教授的学校课程，他通过自修来弥补知识的不足。自学法律后，林肯在1837年取得律师执照，此后他成为一位知名和成功的律师。[PARAGRAPH:1]林肯因他那篇宣布了美国奴隶制度终结的《解放宣言》而享有盛名，并且也没有放任南方脱离美国联邦。他对内战的动机常被误解，然而受期望驱使的动机是要结束奴隶制度。林肯在南北战争背后的目地是为了联邦的生存和发展，由一个团结一致的联邦所扮演的更广泛的民主理想的保护者。“要使那民有、民治、民享的政府不致从地球上消失。”（盖茨堡演讲）[PARAGRAPH:1]从某种意义上说，美国历史上几乎没有那个公开演讲者曾说出过这样的话，不但立刻对公众的愿望产生吸引力，同时也讲出了普通民众视野之外的重大问题。这是林肯的天赋，一个才华横溢的雄辩家和公众演讲者。他能用简洁而立刻就懂的方式向听众传递重要的政治意图，并为了更有利于国家恳请大众为之行动。[PARAGRAPH:1]在战前和战中对他的政策有着众多的批评和嘲弄，林肯只是在1865年4月15日被约翰·威尔克斯·布思暗杀后才得到公众的一致认同。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SURYAVARMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Suryavarman II[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of the Khmer[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c.1095 - 1150 AD [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Suryavarman II was king of the Khmer Empire from 1113 to 1150 AD. Encompassing much of what is today modern Thailand, Laos and Cambodia, the Khmer Empire had been wracked with internal feuding and chaos for fifty years before Suryavarman's reign. Born in the last quarter of the eleventh century, Suryavarman would grow to become a skilled general, statesman and patron of the arts.[PARAGRAPH:1]After overcoming his rivals for the throne, Suryavarman began a series of successful invasions into neighboring states and occupied what is now Thailand and Myanmar, extending the borders of the previously stagnant Khmer kingdom. Through his efforts, the empire re-established contact with China to the north and formed a powerful alliance with Champa to the east. Together with his Champa allies, Suryavarman launched an attack against the neighboring state of Dai Viet.Yet when their continued campaigns against Dai Viet ended in loss, the Champa King broke with the Khmer empire. Not one to lightly accept treachery, Suryavarman invaded neighboring Champa, but the brutal campaign ultimately cost the Khmer leader his life.[PARAGRAPH:1] Yet Suryavarman's impressive legacy would reach far beyond his territorial gains. The massive temple to Vishnu which was constructed under his reign - Angkor Wat - remains the largest religious structure in the world. Considered the epitome of Khmer architecture, Angkor Wat acted as the heart of Suryavarman's expanded kingdom. And while stunning as a work of art, Angkor Wat also served as a masterful propaganda piece for the lord of the Khmer. Numerous bas-reliefs of the ruler cover the temple. Many of the sculptures depict Suryavarman among his court or in combat, but above all, they portray him as a calm and talented ruler. Suryavarman's wondrous temple complex remains one of the a central symbols of Khmer heritage and today appears on the modern Cambodian flag.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]苏耶跋摩二世[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]高棉国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]约1095-1150[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]苏耶跋摩二世在公元1113至1150年间统治着高棉帝国。古代高棉帝国的疆域包括今泰国、老挝和柬埔寨大部分地区，但在苏耶跋摩登基前的五十年间，这个国家一直饱受内乱的困扰。苏耶跋摩在12世纪末出生，在新世纪逐渐成长为一个经验丰富的军事家、政治家和文化艺术资助人。[PARAGRAPH:1]在消灭所有内部敌人之后，苏耶跋摩对临国发动了一系列成功的入侵，占据了今属泰国和缅甸的大片土地，显著拓展了高棉帝国的边界。在他的努力下，帝国与北面的中国重建邦交，又同东面的占婆结成强势同盟。苏耶跋摩与盟友占婆并肩作战攻打邻近的大越，但随后遭遇挫败，占婆国王也中止了与高棉的盟约。没人会轻易忍受背叛，苏耶跋摩为此亲自率军进攻占婆，不幸在残酷的战斗中付出了自己的生命。[PARAGRAPH:1]苏耶跋摩留给后世的遗产不仅仅是大片新征服的领土。他下令为保护神毗湿奴所修建的巨大神庙——吴哥窟——至今仍是全世界最大的宗教建筑。吴哥窟被视为高棉建筑艺术的集大成者，也是苏耶跋摩统治之下庞大帝国的中心。吴哥窟不但是一件艺术杰作，也是高棉统治者宣扬国威的强大工具。这座神庙的墙壁上无数的浮雕均表现了国王的形象：苏耶跋摩或是在他的宫廷中，或是在指挥作战，人们将他描绘成一位沉静而富有智慧的统治者。苏耶跋摩所建的伟大神庙至今仍是高棉文化遗产的象征，并出现在柬埔寨的国旗之上。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KHMER_BALLISTA_ELEPHANT_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Used as weapons of war from Rome to China, nowhere did the War Elephant become a more essential part of battle than in Southeast Asia. The animals' massive size allowed them to trample infantry and their unsettling smell caused horses to panic and flee, giving the beast a stunning tactical advantage in the field. But it was the sheer strength of the War Elephant that proved to be its greatest asset.[PARAGRAPH:1]While towers and howdahs were an essential part of a War Elephant's accoutrement across the world, it was the Khmer that perfected the deployment of the great siege crossbow, the ballista, deployed on the back of a mountainous pachyderm. This made both elephant and ballista more deadly than ever: the panic-inducing character of the elephant granted the ballista protection from flanking cavalry, while the elephant suddenly became a fearsome ranged implement of destruction.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]西起罗马，东至中国均将大象用于作战，而在东南亚，战象在战场上发挥的作用更是超过其他任何地区。象的体形巨大，能够轻易践踏步兵，象身上的特殊气味又能使马惊惶奔逃，这些都使战象获得极大的战场优势，而战象作为一种武器更为重要的是其本身所具备的强大战斗力。[PARAGRAPH:1]除了“象塔”和“象轿”这些在古代世界各国战象的必备配置，高棉人还将用于攻城战的“重弩”（ballista）装到巨象身上。大象和重弩相辅相成，发挥出前所未有的可怕威力：大象能惊吓战马使重弩不受骑兵的威胁，重弩则能将战象的打击距离大幅度地提升。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KHMER_BARAY_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]First built under the reign of the Khmer King Yasodharapura, Barays were massive reservoirs designed to provide sustenance and clean water for the surrounding populace. The first Baray, known as the East Baray, was constructed in the late ninth century. The above-ground levee relied on a series of huge earthen walls to catch falling rain water in the reservoirs, which were capable of holding over 60 million cubic meters of liquid.[PARAGRAPH:1]A second Baray, the Western Baray, was built under the reign of Suryavarman I. The Western Baray was similar in design to the first, if a bit larger, to provide for the increased Khmer population. This new Baray would become an invaluable source of sustenance as the kingdom of Khmer reached new heights under the reign of Suryavarman II.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]人工湖是在高棉国王耶输跋摩一世统治时期被首次建造的，这是一种巨型的水库，它的设计目的是给周围民众提供食物和净水。第一座人工湖名叫“东湖”，建于9世纪末。地上大坝依靠一系列土质巨墙来使雨水向水库当中汇集，墙体就这样围起了超过六千万立方米的水资源。[PARAGRAPH:1]第二座人工湖名叫“西湖”，在苏耶跋摩一世统治时期建造完成。“西湖”的设计与与“东湖”相似，但是更加巨大，以满足大幅增长的高棉人口的需要。这一新人工湖后来成为了取之不尽的食物来源，那时在苏耶跋摩二世治下的高棉王国繁荣兴盛，达到了新的高度。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KHMER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Khmer Empire, under the command of Suryavarman II, is a city-building civilization. Not only does the Baray, the Khmer's unique building, provide the health benefits of an aqueduct, it also provides an extra food, boosting the growth of cities in which it is built. Suryavarman's "Expansive" trait will quickly expand the population of these blossoming cities, while his "Creative" trait will give the security of ever-expanding borders. Finally, the Ballista Elephant, with its high strength and massive bonuses against Mounted Units, will make any foe think twice before trying to take one of your stunning Khmer metropolises.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Khmer Empire was a kingdom located in Southeast Asia from 790 until 1431 AD. At its height, the Khmer Empire covered fully one half of Southeast Asia, encompassing what is today Cambodia, Laos, Thailand and parts of Myanmar.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Khmer Empire was founded on the remnants of the kingdom of Chenla, which had spread itself across much of Cambodia and Laos, but had become fractured and weakened by the eighth century AD. A former Chenla prince, Jayvaraman II, returned to the area after his education in Java and created the base of power for the Khmer Empire in the region that is today central Cambodia.[PARAGRAPH:1]The fractured state of Southeast Asia after the collapse of Chenla made the unified strength of the Khmer a welcome presence in the region. The new nation quickly annexed many of its smaller neighbors, sometimes peacefully, sometimes less so.[PARAGRAPH:1]As their prominence grew, the Khmer kings initiated many grand public works projects. King Yasovarman I, ruling from 889 to 915, built Yasodharapura, the first major capital of the Khmer, on a site that would remain important throughout Khmer history. Yasovarman also constructed the East Baray, a massive raised reservoir that was capable of holding over 60 million cubic meters of water.[PARAGRAPH:1]Not long after Yasovarman's reign, internal struggles began to sweep the Khmer Empire. And while a number of impressive works of construction were completed during this period, it was not until the reign of Jayavarman V, from 968 to 1001 that the Khmer Empire could again find itself in relative peace. And it would still be another century until Suryavarman II would again make the Khmer a force to be reckoned with.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ascending to the throne in 1113, Suryavarman II established himself as a firm ruler over the squabbling princes that wreaked havoc on the reign of his father, Suryavarman I. Wisely guiding the forces within his nation, Suryavarman the younger would turn the Khmer Empire into the most powerful kingdom in southeast Asia. Extending his domain over much of neighboring Thailand and Myanmar and constructing Angkor Wat, a monumental temple complex erected not far from the site of the original Khmer capital of Yasodharapura, Suryavarman would guide his Empire to its greatest heights.[PARAGRAPH:1]Shortly after the death of Suryavarman in 1150, relations would sour between the Khmer and the Champa Empire, former allies of the Khmer, and would lead to the sacking of Angkor Wat in 1177, nearly drawing to an end the reign of the Khmer kingdom. The kingdom would be given one last flourish under the reign of Jayavarman VII, whose keen military insight brought the Champa under Khmer control. A devout Buddhist, Jayavarman also littered the Cambodian countryside with new temples.[PARAGRAPH:1]Jayavarman's reign would mark the end of the powerful rulers of the Khmer. A Thai uprising established the kingdom of Ayutthaya in 1350, which would eventually absorb all that once was the Khmer Empire within its borders by 1431.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[BOLD]策略提示:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]苏耶跋摩二世领导的高棉帝国是一个擅长建设城市的文明。高棉的特色建筑——人工湖不但能象其所替代的引水渠那样提升健康度，还能额外+1食物，加快所在城市的成长速度。苏耶跋摩二世的“开拓”特质则可促进所有城市人口规模的提升，他的“创新”特质又保证了文化边界的持续扩张。还有高棉的特色单位——重弩战象不但力量极强，而且拥有对骑乘单位的巨大战斗加成，使得任何对手在对高棉城池下手前都必须三思而后行。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]位于东南亚地区的古代高棉王国存在时间从公元790年起至1431年止。在其鼎盛时期，高棉王国的疆域覆盖了半个东南亚，包括今柬埔寨、老挝、泰国和缅甸的部分地区。[PARAGRAPH:1]高棉王国是在原真腊王国的废墟之上建立起来的，真腊王国曾占有今柬埔寨和老挝的大部分地区，但到公元8世纪时已分崩离析。此时真腊国的一位王子闍耶跋摩二世从爪哇求学归来，在今柬埔寨中部建立了高棉王国最初的统治中心。[PARAGRAPH:1]在真腊王国崩溃之后，东南亚地区小国林立，纷争不断，拥有统一力量的高棉符合人们的诉求。这个新兴国家迅速合并了许多邻邦，有时是通过和平方式，有时则是通过战争手段。[PARAGRAPH:1]随着实力的增强，历任高棉统治者启动了许多大型公共工程。耶输跋摩一世（889-915在位）建造了耶输陀罗补罗（耶输陀罗城），这是高棉的第一座大型都城，在整个高棉历史中均保持着重要的地位。耶输跋摩还建造了“东湖”——一座巨大的人工湖，能够蓄水6千万立方米。[PARAGRAPH:1]耶输跋摩去世之后，高棉王国迅速陷入内乱。虽然在这一时期仍完成了许多巨大的工程，但直到阇耶跋摩五世（968-1001在位）统治时期，高棉王国才逐渐恢复和平安定。又过了一个世纪，高棉才在苏耶跋摩二世的领导下重新强盛起来。[PARAGRAPH:1]苏耶跋摩二世于1113年登上王位，他迅速终结了其父苏耶跋摩一世统治时期国内诸侯纷争的局面，建立起稳固的统治。年轻的苏耶跋摩明智地实施因势利导的政策，使高棉发展成为东南亚第一强国。他将疆域拓展到今泰国和缅甸地区，并建造了吴哥窟，这座巨大的神庙建筑群位于高棉旧都耶输陀罗补罗附近。在苏耶跋摩治下，他的帝国进入了全盛时期。[PARAGRAPH:1]苏耶跋摩于1150年去世，此后高棉王国与原先的盟友占婆王国之间的关系迅速恶化，占婆军队于1177年攻陷并劫掠了吴哥窟，高棉几乎因此而亡国。阇耶跋摩七世统治下的高棉经历了最后的繁荣，他通过出色的军事才能控制了占婆全境。阇耶跋摩是一位虔诚的佛教徒，他建造的许多佛寺至今仍散布于柬埔寨各地。[PARAGRAPH:1]阇耶跋摩七世是高棉最后一位强势统治者。泰人于1350年发动起义建立了大城王朝，到1431年时这个政权已将原高棉王国的全部领土置于其统治之下。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_DARIUS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Darius I[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Emperor of Persia[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c.550 - 486 BC[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Darius the Great, as he became known, was recognized as a great organizer, builder, and financier. Ruling Persia during the first century, Darius both consolidated control of his kingdom and substantially expanded its borders, creating one of the largest empires in history.[PARAGRAPH:1]During the early years of his reign, Darius focused on quelling the various rebellions that had sprung up in the wake of his predecessor's fall. After retaking Persia, Media, Babylonia and sections of Western Asia back from the rebels, Darius focused on creating an efficient and effective bureaucracy within his empire.[PARAGRAPH:1]Darius devised a system in which each region would be the responsibility of a Satrap who would rule the region in his name. To prevent any individual Satrap from gaining too much power and challenging Darius' rule, the king implemented a series of checks and balances that effectively kept power from accumulating with any one man (besides Darius himself). Each region not only had a Satrap who was in charge of civil affairs, but a general who controlled the military, and the subtle presence of Darius' own secret police, who watched over them all. This system of government was so successful, it later became the inspiration for the governments of Alexander the Great and the Parthians.[PARAGRAPH:1]Darius I conducted two historically important military campaigns against the Greek mainland. During the first, around 500 BC, he invaded Greece in retaliation for their support of the rebelling Ionian cities within Persian territory. Unfortunately, his ships were caught in a storm off the Athenian coast and were wrecked. In the second campaign Darius I managed to successfully land on the Athenian coast, but was defeated in the now famous battle of Marathon in 490 BC.[PARAGRAPH:1]Despite his failures on the Greek mainland, Darius I conquered much land in Europe, North Africa and India. His military campaigning and sophisticated organizational designs ensured Darius' place as one of the greatest leaders of the ancient world.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]大流士一世[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]波斯皇帝[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]约前550-前486[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]大流士大帝，以伟大的组织者，建筑者和理财专家而闻名于世。在一世纪统治波斯期间，大流士既巩固了对其王国的统治又切实扩大了它的疆域，建成历史上最大的帝国之一。[PARAGRAPH:1]在其统治之初，大流士致力于平息由于其前任的暴死而引发的的各种各样的叛乱。在从那些叛乱者手中夺回波斯、米底亚、巴比伦和西亚的一些部分之后，大流士将主要精力集中于在他的帝国内建立一套高效和实际的官僚机构。[PARAGRAPH:1]大流士设计了一套行省体系，每个行省由以他的名义管理该地区的总督负责。同时他采取一系列制衡措施防止任何一个总督获得太多权力并挑战大流士的统治从而避免大权旁落。每个行省不仅安排了负责民政事务的总督，还设有一名将军专司控制军队，以及隶属于大流士自己的秘密警察，监视他们全体。这种如此成功的政体成为后来亚历山大帝国与帕提亚王国的所效仿。[PARAGRAPH:1]在历史上大流士一世对希腊发动了两次重要的战争。第一次大约在公元前500年，他为报复他们对波斯境内叛乱的爱奥尼亚人城市的支持而侵入希腊。不幸的是他的舰队在雅典近海遭遇风暴并被摧毁。在第二次战争中大流士一世设法在雅典海滨成功登陆，但于公元前490年在如今非常著名的马拉松平原被击败。[PARAGRAPH:1]尽管大流士一世在希腊遭遇失败，但他在欧洲，北非和印度征服了大片土地。大流士的赫赫战绩以及复杂的官僚机构设计足以保证他进入古代最伟大的领袖之列。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_DE_GAULLE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Charles de Gaulle[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Prime Minister of France, President of the French Fifth Republic[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] November 22, 1890 - November 9, 1970 AD[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Charles de Gaulle was President of the French Fifth Republic, Prime Minister of France and leader of the French resistance during World War II. Born in Lille, France, de Gaulle would fight in both World Wars and guide his country through reconstruction before his death in 1970.[PARAGRAPH:1]As a young man, Charles de Gaulle was drawn to the life of a soldier. In 1912, de Gaulle graduated from Saint-Cyr, the premier military academy in France. Two years later the precocious, young soldier found himself in the midst of the carnage of World War I. Captured by the Germans after the Battle of Verdun in 1916, de Gaulle was held for nearly two years before being released when the War to End All Wars finally came to a close.[PARAGRAPH:1]After a brief stint fighting with the Polish during the Polish-Soviet War, de Gaulle returned to France and began publishing numerous papers on the state of modern warfare. His most prophetic, "The Army of the Future," published in 1934, argued that the static defenses of the Maginot Line, France's key protection against another German invasion, would not last in the face of a modern mobile assault.[PARAGRAPH:1]His words would go unheeded.[PARAGRAPH:1]With the German invasion of France and the capitulation of French leadership, de Gaulle escaped to Great Britain, firm in his belief that while the government had folded, France was not defeated. From England, de Gaulle broadcast a message of resistance back to his homeland, stating "France has lost a battle, but France has not lost the war." Leaving Great Britain, de Gaulle traveled towards the French colonies in Africa, now under the control of the Nazi-sympathizing Vichy government. Creating the new base for his "Free French" movement in the Congo, de Gaulle won a series of key victories against the Vichy and German forces, steadily increasing his strength and renown. [PARAGRAPH:1]When France was finally liberated by the Allies, the Free French forces were there to take control of the country. De Gaulle became the interim Prime Minister as the Fourth Republic was created, but disagreements with the nascent government ended in de Gaulle's resignation.[PARAGRAPH:1]In 1958, economic struggles and political infighting in the Fourth Republic drew de Gaulle back into power and would mark the beginning of the French Fifth Republic. With a strong hand, de Gaulle began a period of driven, some would say bullheaded, modernization and redirection of the French state. Ushering in France's nuclear age and breaking ties with the problematic French colony of Algeria, de Gaulle ensured that France would remain among the premier nations of the world.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]夏尔·戴高乐[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]法国总理，法兰西第五共和国总统[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]1890年11月22日-1970年11月9日[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]夏尔·戴高乐曾任法兰西第五共和国总统，法国总理，也是第二次世界大战中法国抵抗运动的领袖。戴高乐生于法国里尔，他经历了两次世界大战，并在其后一直引导着祖国的复兴进程，直至于1970年逝世。[PARAGRAPH:1]年轻时，夏尔·戴高乐就向往戎马生涯。1912年，戴高乐毕业于圣西尔军校，这所法兰西的最高军事学府。两年之后这名少年老成的军人发现自己被淹没在一战的成河血流之中。在1916年凡尔登战役后戴高乐遭德军俘获，被关押近两年，直到这场“止战之战”接近尾声才获得释放。（塞爱维小提示：凡尔登战役因其惨烈被称为“绞肉机”。戴高乐在凡尔登作战曾三次负伤被俘，也三次在战报中受到表扬。“止战之战”即指第一次世界大战。讽刺的是，人类搏杀的游戏并未就此终结）[PARAGRAPH:1]戴高乐在短暂的波苏战争中与波兰人并肩作战，随后返回法国并撰写了多部关于现代作战理论的著作，其中最具先见之明的作品——《未来的陆军》出版于1934年，戴高乐批驳了马其诺防线式的静态防御策略，认为这一法国赖以抗击德国下一次入侵的核心策略，将在现代化机动突袭中面临穷途末路。——言者有意，然听者痴。[PARAGRAPH:1]由于德国的入侵以及法国领导层屈膝投降，戴高乐逃往英国，政府的软弱更加坚定了他的信念，法兰西抵抗的火焰决不会熄灭。戴高乐从英国对他的祖国发表抵抗声明：“法国输掉了这场战役，但法国没有输掉这场战争。”戴高乐随后离开英国前往法国在非洲的殖民地（当时尚处于亲纳粹的维希政权控制之下）。在刚果为其“自由法国”的建立新根据地的同时，戴高乐赢得了一系列对维希政权和德国的关键性胜利，他的实力和声望与日俱增。[PARAGRAPH:1]法国被盟军解放之时，三股势力都试图支配起这片土地。第四共和国建立时，戴高乐受任为总理，但这个政府一直为内斗所困扰，最终戴高乐递交了辞呈。[PARAGRAPH:1]1958年，第四共和国的经济和政治乱局促使戴高乐重返权力舞台，第五共和国宣告诞生。通过高超的政治手腕，戴高乐坚定地——有人称之为强硬地——推动法国的现代化与社会转型。戴高乐使法国进入核能时代，使法国从原殖民地阿尔及利亚的乱局中脱身，并使法国继续保持她对全球事务的重大影响力。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HAMMURABI_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Hammurabi[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of Babylonia[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c.1728 BC - 1686 BC[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Hammurabi ruled over Babylon, quite possibly the largest metropolis in the ancient world, during the height of the Babylonian empire. He is most famously known for his Code of Laws, set in stone and mounted in the middle of ancient Babylon for all to see. Although not the first Babylonian emperor to implement a structured system of laws, Hammurabi was the first to coherently organize and standardize them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Punishments for breaking these laws were varied. Smaller crimes and business infractions were typically dealt with via fines. Crimes dealing with theft or crimes of a more physical nature (assault, battery, murder) typically had harsher penalties involving death, slavery, or banishment. If proven guilty of a crime, the defendant could expect to receive a punishment nearly equivalent to the crime itself. This is quite possibly where the ancient idea of an Eye for an Eye, and the modern variation of A Tit for a Tat, came from.[PARAGRAPH:1]But decisions were not draconian, and took into account circumstance. If a man was to kill another while defending himself, he might only be fined a small fee depending on the social stature of the deceased, instead of facing a sentence of death himself.[PARAGRAPH:1]With a recorded set of responsibilities and consequences for any given action, punishment was no longer left up to the whim of those in power, and people could conduct their business with the assurance that they would not inadvertently commit a serious crime to which the punishment was unknown. This gave the Babylonian empire the much needed stability it required to flourish.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hammurabi further covered his land with strongholds, police garrisons and civilian administrators. His intent was to enforce his laws so that a citizen in his empire could travel from Babylon to the coast of the Mediterranean without fear of harassment or unfair persecution. Safety, stability, and prosperity were to be Hammurabi's gift to his people. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]汉谟拉比[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]巴比伦国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]约公元前1728-公元前1686[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]汉谟拉比，在巴比伦帝国的鼎盛时期统治着巴比伦城，那座远古世界中最大的城市。他因其所制定的法典而闻名于世；这部法典被刻在石柱上，矗立于古巴比伦城的中心，好让所有人都看得见。虽然汉谟拉比不是第一个实行系统法律制度的巴比伦君主，但他确实是第一个将这些法律清晰地组织在一起并使之标准化的人。[PARAGRAPH:1]对于不同的违法行为，“汉谟拉比法典”规定了不同的处罚方式。对某些轻微犯罪和商业违约的典型处置是判以罚金；而盗窃和一些伤及人身的罪行（如人身侵犯、殴打、谋杀）则会遭到更严厉的惩罚，包括死刑、贬身为奴和流放。如果被告被证明有罪，他受到的刑罚将会与其所犯罪行的分量相当。很可能，古人“以牙还牙”的信条和这话的现代版本——“针锋相对”，就是从巴比伦人那学来的。[PARAGRAPH:1]然而判决并不总是严酷的，特定案件的具体情况也会被加以考虑。一个人若是在正当防卫时将他人致死，就不会被判处死刑，而是代以一小笔罚金；罚金的具体数额要依死者的社会地位而定。[PARAGRAPH:1]“汉谟拉比法典”对于其中所提到的每一种行为，都规定了相应的责任与后果。如此一来，罪名的判定与刑罚的量取，就不会再由着掌权者一时的异想天开了。因此，无意间触犯一条尚未被定义的法律，这种情况是不存在的。有了这层保证，人们就可以放心地开展商业活动了。这为巴比伦帝国带来了其走向繁荣所必需的稳定环境。[PARAGRAPH:1]汉谟拉比还在他的国土上部署了许多要塞和卫戍部队，安排了许多管理平民的行政官员，其目的是以强制手段来保障他的法典得以通行。这样，人们可以从巴比伦城下一直旅行到地中海边，而不必担心遭到袭击或不公正的迫害。安全、稳定和繁荣，正是汉谟拉比送给他的人民的礼物。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BABYLON_BOWMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Bowman was a cornerstone of the Babylonian military. The Babylonians, similar to their Sumerian predecessors, fielded highly trained and well-equipped bowmen. These archers were instrumental in siege warfare; they cleared enemy walls of troops, and sowed terror into the populace by launching volleys of fire arrows into the cities. Once a city had been captured, these bowmen became the key to defending their newly acquired prize. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]弓手是巴比伦军队的主力。巴比伦人与他们的先辈苏美尔人一样，组建有大批训练有素、装备精良的弓手部队。巴比伦弓手擅长围城作战，通过密集的箭雨迅速破坏敌军阵线，使敌城的居民陷入恐慌。而当城市被攻占后，这些弓手又成为巴比伦人保卫其胜利果实的中坚力量。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BABYLON_GARDEN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]In modern, developed countries, gardens are often more valued for their aesthetic qualities than for their food growing functionality. However, in ancient civilizations such as Babylonia, gardens were an important source of nutrition for city dwelling families who otherwise could not purchase an adequate variety of food.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]在现代的发达国家中，花园大多是为了实现审美价值而不是为了寻求食物增长点。然而在像巴比伦这样的古文明中，花园则是城市家庭中重要的营养食品来源，如若没有花园，这些家庭就无法得到足够多样的食物。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BABYLON_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Babylonians don't just walk the line between Builder and Warmonger: they've settled down to raise a civilization on it. Hammurabi's "Organized" trait and the health-yielding Garden building, the Babylonian replacement for the Colosseum, make Babylonian cities fast-growing affairs. But Hammurabi's "Aggressive" trait and the Bowman's significant bonus against melee units allow Babylonian players to wreak impressive early-game havoc.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Babylonian Empire was, rather than a new idea, a reinvigoration of the old Sumerian Empire, which had also occupied what is today Southern Iraq. Babylonia was formed from a collection of roughly a dozen city states and was named for its capital city of Babylon. Originally a disorganized region, Babylon and Babylonia began to grow as a center for culture, trade, and religion under the rule of Hammurabi in 1728BC. Location of one of the seven ancient wonders - the Hanging Gardens - Babylonia became the jewel of the ancient world.[PARAGRAPH:1]Hammurabi was the first known ruler of united Babylonia as well as its greatest lawgiver. Hammurabi's Code of Laws regulated Babylonian life in such a way as to make the consequences of most criminal acts publicly known. Citizens could then structure their behavior based on these laws leading to a more organized society. So comprehensive was the Babylonian Code that little about its laws or governmental system changed in the entirety of its 1,200 years of existence. Babylon was so revered for this system that cities and states as far as the Mediterranean would emulate it for centuries.[PARAGRAPH:1]After the death of Hammurabi (1750 BC), the empire slowly declined in power and influence until it was eventually conquered by the Kassites (around 1600 BC) from what are now the mountains of Iran. The Kassites ruled over Babylonia for 576 years, reinvigorating the empire under their reign. Although Hammurabi ruled over Babylonia as a series of interconnected city states, the Kassites were the first rulers of Babylonia to transform the country into an organized territory. The Kassites created trade routes to countries as far away as Greece, Armenia and Turkey. Trade with these nations brought further wealth and status to Babylonia.[PARAGRAPH:1]Towards the end of the Kassite era of rule, Babylonia once again began to fall into decline, in part due to external political and military pressure. In 627 BC, the last Kassite ruler died, and Babylonia revolted under the command of a new leader, Nabopolassar. Nabopolassar's son, Nebuchadnezzar II, ruled Babylonia and brought about another golden era. During his rule, Babylonia became a military power, invading and taking territory in Egypt and Assyria. Not long afterwards, in 539 BC, Cyrus of Persia invaded Babylonia, conquering it, and forever ending Babylonia's existence as an independent territory.[PARAGRAPH:1]Despite numerous regime changes, education reached exceptional heights among the Babylonians. Technical achievements such as the creation of a base 60, "sexigesimal," system of mathematics, are still used to this day. Sixty seconds per minute, sixty minutes per hour: modern time, is in fact, Babylonian time.[PARAGRAPH:1]Much like the Sumerian Empire from which they were descended, Babylonia was a nation of fanatical record-keepers. Starting with Hammurabi and continuing down until the empire's dissolution at the hands of Cyrus and the great Persian emperors, every financial transaction, every court verdict, every contract, and just about anything that could be written down, was - on clay tablets. With laws pertaining to almost every aspect of daily living, a significant amount of data was recorded, and much of this has been uncovered and excavated during the modern era. Researchers have even found several optical devices, similar to magnifying glasses, which were used to allow record keepers to write in smaller cuneiform, in order to fit more information on each clay tablet.[PARAGRAPH:1]Babylonia played an important role in the development of law throughout the world. The creation of Hammurabi's Code of Laws, and the zeal with which his successors, both blood-related and not, upheld those laws, demonstrated for all of history how successful and wealthy a nation could become by following an organized system of government. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[BOLD]策略提示:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]巴比伦并不仅是介于建设者和战争狂之间的中间派，而是一个能够全面发展的强大文明。汉谟拉比的“组织”特质配合提供额外健康、替代竞技场的巴比伦特色建筑——花园，可以帮助巴比伦的城市快速成长。而汉谟拉比的“好斗”特质加上擅长克制肉搏单位的巴比伦弓手，又使其成为游戏早期最可怕的军事强权。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]巴比伦，与其说是一个新文明，不如说是——包括今伊拉克南部地区的——原苏美尔文明的复兴。巴比伦是由好几个城邦联合组成的，并以它们的首都巴比伦城的名字命名整个国家。公元前1728年，在汉谟拉比的统治下，巴比伦和巴比伦城开始从最初的无组织地区，发展成为当地文化、贸易和宗教的中心。作为古代七大奇观之一——空中花园的所在地，巴比伦成了古代世界的明珠。[PARAGRAPH:1]巴比伦统一后，汉谟拉比是其第一个为今人所知的统治者，同时也是它最伟大的立法者。“汉谟拉比法典”以这样一种方式控制着巴比伦人的生活，即把大部分犯罪行为的后果都公之于众。人民根据这些法律来组织自己的行为，并且在这些法律的引领下，共同构建一个更有组织的社会。巴比伦人的法典是如此包罗万象，以致于其中规定的法律和政府体制在巴比伦存在的整整1200年间都罕有变动。这一套制度为巴比伦赢得了极大的尊崇，远达地中海世界的许多城市和国家都对其进行效仿，有几世纪之久。[PARAGRAPH:1]公元前1750年汉谟拉比去世后，帝国的力量与影响开始衰退，直到最后被来自今伊朗高原的加喜特人所征服（公元前1600年左右）。加喜特人统治了巴比伦576年，并使帝国在他们的统治下得以复兴。虽然早在汉谟拉比时代，巴比伦就在许多城邦的联合下形成了，但是加喜特人却第一次使它变成了一块有着统一组织的土地。加喜特人还开辟了一些商路，通达像希腊、亚美尼亚和土耳其这样遥远的地方。国际贸易给巴比伦带来了更多的财富和更崇高的地位。[PARAGRAPH:1]到加喜特人统治的末期，巴比伦文明再次走向衰落，部分原因是来自外部的政治和军事压力。公元前627年，最后一位加喜特统治者死后，巴比伦人在他们的新领袖——纳博波拉撒领导下发动了起义。纳搏波拉萨的儿子尼布甲尼撒二世的统治使巴比伦再次进入黄金时代。当时的巴比伦成为一个军事强权，先后入侵并占领了埃及和亚述。但不久之后的公元前539年，巴比伦又被波斯王居鲁士所征服，她作为一个独立国家的历史就此永远地结束了。[PARAGRAPH:1]尽管政权多次变动，巴比伦人的教育水平却异常地达到了很高的程度。一些科技上的成就，比如六十进制计数法的创造，一直到今天仍然被使用着。一小时有六十分钟，一分钟有六十秒。事实上，现代的通行计时法就是巴比伦人的计时法。[PARAGRAPH:1]与其所继承的苏美尔帝国很相似，巴比伦是一个狂热的资料记录者的国家。这种状况从汉谟拉比开始，一直持续到帝国在居鲁士和伟大的波斯帝国手中解体为止。每一笔财务帐目、每一次法庭判决、每一份合同，几乎每一个可以被写下来的事情，都被记在了泥板上。由于有着和日常生活中差不多每个方面都相称的法律，因为它们的作用，极大量的资料被记录了下来，而且其中很多已经在现代被发现、被挖掘了出来。研究人员甚至还找到了一些和放大镜很相似的光学仪器；那些资料记录者可以用它们写出更细小的楔形文字，这样就可以在一块泥板上记下更多的信息了。[PARAGRAPH:1]巴比伦曾在全世界的法律发展进程中起了十分重要的作用。“汉谟拉比法典”的创立，还有汉谟拉比的——无论是同族的还是异族的——继任者们的热忱，支持了那些法律，并为整个历史作出了示范，告诉人们，一个有着良好组织的政府体制能使一个国家变得多么的成功和富裕。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_GILGAMESH_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Gilgamesh[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of Uruk[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Living approximately 2500 years before the Common Era, Gilgamesh was King of Uruk, the largest city of its time in Sumeria. Said to be two-thirds divine (his mother was thought to be the goddess Ninsun), Gilgamesh's history will forever be intertwined with his legend, vividly portrayed in the "Epic of Gilgamesh." Because the earliest written texts of the Epic date from 1700 BC, roughly a millennium after the death of the great king, it is difficult to judge what is truth from what is tall tale. Yet the epic remains the clearest demonstrator as to the caliber of ruler that was King Gilgamesh.[PARAGRAPH:1]"Iron-fisted" would be the best description of Gilgamesh as a ruler. His policy towards young maidens on their wedding nights had much of the populace of Uruk enraged at their leader, calling for aid from the heavens. Yet under his reign, Uruk thrived. The author of the epic describes Uruk as an impressive feat of construction, specifically the grand temple dedicated to Ishtar, the Sumerian goddess of love. But Gilgamesh's greatest work was the construction of the massive walls of Uruk, considered a masterwork of masonry.[PARAGRAPH:1]The adventures of Gilgamesh were varied, from traveling through a great forest of cedars to kill the monstrous Humbaba to finding the key to immortality. Even though many of Gilgamesh's journeys are steeped in magic, a number of claims from the epic are generally accepted as credible. The most prominent is that the walls of Uruk were actually built under the reign of the King Gilgamesh. And while much of the truth of the great King of Uruk has been lost to the ages, his name will always be remembered as the hero of man's first epic.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]吉尔伽美什[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]乌鲁克国王[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]吉尔伽美什约生于在公元前2500年左右，他是苏美尔当时最大城市乌鲁克的王。据说他有三分之二神的血统（他母亲是女神南松），因而有关他的历史总是和传奇故事纠缠在一起，其中形象最鲜明的就是《吉尔伽美什史诗》。这部史诗最早的抄本写于公元前1700年，差不多是这位圣君去世一千年之后的事了，因此我们很难分辨哪些内容是史实，哪些是演义。不过，《吉尔伽美什史诗》还是描绘出了英雄吉尔伽美什最清晰的影像。[PARAGRAPH:1]说吉尔伽美什是个铁腕君主就再合适不过了。他曾立下法令，将全城少女的初夜权据为己有。这触怒了乌鲁克的臣民，人们祈求神灵惩治他的恶行。但是吉尔伽美什治下的乌鲁克非常繁荣。史诗的作者称，乌鲁克有众多宏伟的工程，其中的佼佼者就是伊什塔尔（苏美尔神话中司爱情的女神）大神殿。然而，吉尔伽美什最伟大的功绩还数他修建了环绕乌鲁克的高大而厚实的城墙。这道城墙成为砖石结构建筑史上的绝唱。[PARAGRAPH:1]吉尔伽美什经历过种种险境。他曾只身穿越一片广袤的杉树林，还曾为了寻求长生不老的秘密而杀死怪兽洪巴巴。尽管吉尔伽美什的旅程满溢着魔幻色彩，人们还是普遍认为史诗的有些内容是可信的，其中最突出的就是吉尔伽美什主持乌鲁克城墙的修建工作。况且，就算吉尔伽美什的真实面貌从此消失在历史长河中，这位乌鲁克圣王的英名也将和这人类的第一部史诗一起永垂世间。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SUMERIAN_VULTURE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Vulture was not a specific type of troop within the Sumerian army, but rather a symbol. Warfare was a fact of life between the city-states of lower Mesopotamia, but it was during a battle between the King of Lagash and the King of Umma in 2525 BC that something exceptional occurred.[PARAGRAPH:1]After a resounding victory over the King of Umma, the King of Lagash erected a stele to commemorate the occasion. In commissioning this monument to his victory, the King of Lagash created the first known depiction of war ever created by humanity. The stele's carvings display the troops of Lagash: spearmen arranged in a phalanx formation, with eight men to a row, six rows deep. (As a phalanx arrangement would require strict training and discipline, this suggests that the Sumerians had one of the earliest professional armies.) Elsewhere on the stele, vultures can be seen carrying away the heads of the fallen Umman warriors. As a result, these Sumerian soldiers have become known as the "Vultures of Sumer."</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]“兀鹫战士”并非苏美尔军队中实际存在的兵种，只是个象征性的词汇。古代美索不达米亚南部各城邦之间的战争司空见惯，但公元前2525年的拉加什王国对乌玛王国的战争却因一件不寻常的事而成为后世的研究对象。[PARAGRAPH:1]在决定性地击败乌玛国王之后，拉加什国王下令竖立一座石碑作为纪念，在这座庆祝胜利的石碑上留下了人类历史上最早的战争画面。石碑表面的浮雕表现了拉加什军队的形象：许多矛兵组成密集阵形，每排八人、纵深六排。（组成密集阵形需要有充分的训练和严格的纪律，这表明苏美尔人拥有最早的职业化军队。）在石碑的其他地方刻有许多兀鹫，叨着死去的乌玛士兵的首级。因此人们就把浮雕上的战士称为“苏美尔兀鹫”。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SUMERIAN_ZIGGURAT_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Ziggurats were religious centers dedicated to the gods of ancient Sumeria. Each was comprised of a temple built upon of a series of tiered, earthen platforms, raising the building atop and dwarfing the surrounding structures. Every city's Ziggurat was dedicated to one specific god. These individual dedications sprung from the Sumerian belief that each temple was not a place of worship, but the actual home of the god. Belief held that the gods originated from the distant mountains, and it is thought that the ziggurats were raised in order to make the new dwellings of the gods a little more like home.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]神塔是古苏美尔人献祭神灵的核心宗教建筑。每座神塔都是由一系列土制台阶和修建在它上面的神庙构成，这样使得抬高后的整座建筑在周围别的建筑中鹤立鸡群。每个城市的神塔都献祭各自的神灵。这种独立献祭的方式源自苏美尔的信仰，这种信仰认为神庙并不是一个供人礼拜的场所，而是神灵真正的居所。他们的信仰认为众神来自远方的群山，所以使神塔隆起是为了让神的新居所看起来更像它们的故乡。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_SUMERIA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Sumerian Empire is a balanced nation. Gilgamesh's "Creative" trait provides Sumerian cities with extra culture and extra-large borders, while his "Protective" trait makes life difficult for any enemies foolish enough to cross them. This is especially true once they encounter the "Vulture," the powerful Sumerian replacement for the Axeman. Finally, the Sumerian Ziggurat, an easily-produced Courthouse, will bring speedy stability to Sumerian cities.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Sumerian Empire was founded along the banks of the Tigris and Euphrates Rivers, in modern day Iraq, in roughly 3000 BC. Sumeria was the world's first civilization and created the world's first historians through the invention of cuneiform, the original written language. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Sumerian people were organized into a series of carefully irrigated city-states, each with its own ruler and local deities. The surplus of wheat grown from the verdant fertility of the Tigris and Euphrates allowed the Sumerians to create an exceptional urban civilization. Never numbering more than a dozen or so, the cities of Sumeria were major centers of commerce, culture and defense, and the Sumerians were the first truly metropolitan population. In fact, the Sumerian creation myth states that first there was nothing; then there was a city - Eridu.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sumerian cities were seas of sun-cooked brick, rushing irrigation ditches and mountainous ziggurats (the Sumerian temples to the gods). Facing near-constant warfare, each city was defined by a series of intimidating walls and well-placed canals. Indeed, the Sumerians are the first people known to employ a professional army, necessary to fight the perpetual skirmishes that characterized Sumerian daily life.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unity in Sumeria was only established at the end of a spear. The first Sumerian King to lay claim over a number of cities was Eannatum of Lagash. Initiating a campaign against the city of Umma (Lagash's ancient rival) over a border dispute, Eannatum followed up his victory by sweeping over and conquering the remainder of Sumeria. An uprising within Umma would later shatter this new empire, but a mutual treaty would again bring peace to Sumeria.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, the Sumerians were not alone in the Fertile Crescent. Their competitors included the Akkadians, a Semetic people to the North. In 2334 BC, Sargon, a highly skilled military strategist, was born in Akkadia. Upon reaching maturity, Sargon would found his own dynasty - the Akkadians - bringing all the peoples of the Fertile Crescent, including the Sumerians, under his rule.[PARAGRAPH:1]In roughly 2250 BC, a new people, the Gutians, thundered into the Fertile Crescent, deposing the Akkadians and establishing themselves as the new rulers of the land. But the rigors of invasion severely weakened the new overlords of Mesopotamia, allowing the long-dominated Sumerians the chance for rebellion. With the rise of a new leader, Utu-khegal, the Sumerians threw off their Gutian overlords and reestablished the supremacy of Sumerian culture throughout the Fertile Crescent.[PARAGRAPH:1]Under Ur-Nammu, a successor of Utu-khegal, order was restored in the fractured state, and the period of The Third Dynasty of Ur began. Ur-Nammu was a reformer and builder as well as a warrior, and he created roads and walls throughout his new empire. This golden age would last until 2004 BC, when internal feuding fractured the Sumerian nation decisively.[PARAGRAPH:1]The story of Sumeria comes to us through the many cuneiform tablets that have been discovered. Unfortunately, many of these tablets aren't especially evocative: tireless record-keepers, the Sumerians would just as often record the season's flock of sheep as the reign of ancient kings. Several tablets, though, have been of a religious nature and have provided great insights into the foundation of Judeo-Christian beliefs. Tales of a great flood abound in Sumerian myth. Man, they said, was formed from clay.[PARAGRAPH:1]Although the first great empire vanished from history, Sumerian culture would survive to influence the next great civilization to spring from the Tigris-Euphrates Valley - Babylon.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[BOLD]策略提示:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]苏美尔是一个非常平衡的文明。吉尔伽美什的“创新”特质为苏美尔城市提供文化加成，快速扩展文明边界；他的“保国”特质则能使任何胆敢侵犯其边界的敌人感到痛苦不堪，特别是当他们要面对苏美尔替代斧兵的强大特色单位——兀鹫战士的时候。最后，苏美尔的特色单位是替代法庭而更易建造的神塔，因而能使苏美尔城市更有效地保持稳定。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]公元前约3000年，苏美尔帝国在两河流域（今伊拉克）兴起。苏美尔文明是人类最早的文明，他们发明了楔形文字。正因为有了书写系统，苏美尔也最先拥有了自己的历史学家。[PARAGRAPH:1]苏美尔人分属几个沟渠密布的城邦，他们各有各自的首领，膜拜本族的神灵。底格里斯河和幼发拉底河沿岸富饶的土壤带来小麦的丰产。苏美尔人不必忙于农事，从而得以建立一个高度城市化的文明。苏美尔仅有的十几座城市是他们的主要商业枢纽、文化中心和防御基地，而古苏美尔人也当之无愧是最早的“都市人”。事实上，苏美尔人的创世神话就这样说：起初，世界上什么都没有；后来就有了一个城市——埃利都。[PARAGRAPH:1]苏美尔城市建筑多用泥砖砌成，城中有完备的灌溉渠系统和众多巍峨的神殿。由于战事频仍，每座城市都筑有险峻的城墙和精巧的运河网。苏美尔人的日常生活几乎就是不停地打仗。为此，他们首创了职业军队制度。[PARAGRAPH:1]苏美尔城邦最后是通过武力统一的。来自拉格什城的安纳图姆是第一位苏美尔王。安纳图姆趁着一次边境纠纷对温马城出兵，接着就势如破竹地扫平了整个苏美尔地区。后来在温马境内爆发了起义，把初生的帝国搅得分崩离析。事后各方签订了一份和约，苏美尔才重归和平。[PARAGRAPH:1]然而苏美尔人并不是两河“肥沃新月”地带的唯一居民。属于闪族一支的阿卡德人，就是他们在北方的劲敌。公元前2334年，天才军事家萨尔贡在阿卡德降生。当萨尔贡成年之时，他统一了新月地带众多邦国，建立了自己的王朝——阿卡德帝国。连苏美尔人都归于他治下。[PARAGRAPH:1]公元前约2250年，库提人以迅雷之势攻入两河新月地带，推翻了阿卡德人的统治，成为这片土地的新主人。猛烈的进攻大大消耗了这些入侵者的力量，这就给了美索不达米亚历来的统治者苏美尔人一个卷土重来的机会。在乌图-赫加尔的领导下，苏美尔人赶走了库提领主，重新确立了苏美尔文化在肥沃新月地带的强势地位。[PARAGRAPH:1]乌尔-纳姆继承乌图-赫加尔的遗志，把四分五裂的国家带向新秩序。吾饵第三王朝时代就这样开始了。乌尔-纳姆不仅弓马娴熟，而且锐意改革，注重建设。他下令在全国铺设道路，建筑城墙。吾饵的黄金时代一直持续到公元前2004年，苏美尔最终毁于内乱，再度分裂。[PARAGRAPH:1]我们对苏美尔的了解主要来自出土的楔形文字泥板。不幸的是很多泥板上提供的信息并没有多大意义：苏美尔人真是不知疲倦的记录员，他们连每一季羊群的数量都要记录，就好像记载古代君王的事迹一样。但有几块泥板却是宗教文本，为我们了解犹太－基督教信仰的根源提供了深层次的资料。苏美尔神话中有很多关于大洪水的故事。而且他们也说，人是用泥土造的。[PARAGRAPH:1]虽然这世界最早的帝国已经湮没在历史的尘埃中，苏美尔文化却保留了下来，影响施及继之而起的另一个伟大文明——同是位于两河流域的巴比伦王国。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SITTING_BULL_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Sitting Bull[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]War Chief of the Hunkpapa Sioux[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c.1830 - 1890 AD[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Sitting Bull, whose name in Lakota, Tatanka Yotanka, roughly translates to "an Obstinate Bull Buffalo at Rest," was born into the Hunkpapa Sioux branch of the Lakota tribe around 1830 AD. Rising to the position of Chief in 1856, Sitting Bull was a key member of the native resistance against American encroachment into the Black Hills of the Dakota Territory.[PARAGRAPH:1]Sitting Bull was a precocious youth, taking to warfare and hunting like a fish to water. At ten, he slew his first buffalo. By the time he had reached middle adolescence, Sitting Bull had been inducted into the prestigious societies of the Strong Heart Warrior and the Silent Eater. A most dangerous and powerful warrior - despite walking with a limp from a bullet wound he suffered as a youth - Sitting Bull became a feared name among the Lakota, the young Chief leading his fellow Hunkpapa into numerous victories over other tribes.[PARAGRAPH:1]His expertise in warfare did not keep Sitting Bull from signing the Fort Laramie Treaty of 1868, which called for the halting of American expansion into Sioux territory beyond the Powder River. But with the discovery of gold in the Black Hills in 1874, a new rush of colonists from the East began violating the treaty. Sitting Bull is said to have had a prophetic dream regarding the American expansion - an American military officer and his men, plummeting from the sky into a Sioux village - which was interpreted as a portent of the Americans' imminent doom. Not long after Sitting Bull's vision, General George Custer and his seventh cavalry launched an attack on a native village, only to be decimated by the assembled Sioux and Cheyenne fighters. [PARAGRAPH:1]American wrath quickly fell upon Sitting Bull and his people, and they were forced to flee to Canada where, despite a reception worthy of a foreign dignitary, they were to remain but briefly. A dearth of resources in their new lands threatened the Lakota with starvation, forcing Sitting Bull to guide his people back to the United States in 1881, with the understanding that they would receive land, sustenance and peace in America.[PARAGRAPH:1]Upon his return to the United States, Sitting Bull and a number of his followers joined Buffalo Bill Cody's Wild West show. Cody was able to provide a better standard of living than Sitting Bull and his Sioux brethren could expect to receive on the reservations to which they were now assigned, and a strong friendship formed between Cody and the native leader.[PARAGRAPH:1]In the final decade of the nineteenth century, the "Ghost Dance," a ritual promising to rid the natives of American influence once and for all, began to spread among the Sioux. Tensions again grew between the Lakota and the American military, who had expressly forbade native religious rituals like the "Ghost Dance." Buffalo Bill stepped in to try and negotiate a peaceful truce, but none was to be had. Fearing Sitting Bull's involvement in the growing ritual, the Chief was arrested and assassinated by Indian policemen in 1890, just days before the American opposition to the "Ghost Dance" would bring about the infamous Massacre at Wounded Knee.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]坐牛[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]苏族洪克帕帕部落酋长[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]约1830-1890[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]坐牛的名字在拉科塔语中念作塔坦卡·约塔克，大致的意思是“一头顽固的雄性水牛在休息”。他在公元1830年左右出生在拉科塔部落的洪克帕帕族中（苏族分支）。坐牛在1856成为了酋长，而且是土著抵抗运动的关键人物，土著们在他的领导下抵抗美国对达科他地区的黑山领地的侵犯。[PARAGRAPH:1]坐牛是个很早熟的年轻人，他在战斗和打猎中简直是如鱼得水。年仅十岁的时候，他就猎杀了第一只水牛。而且在他还只是个少年的时候，坐牛就进入了很有威望的社会阶层，强壮之心战士和静食者。作为一个最危险而强大的战士——尽管由于年轻的时候受过枪伤，使得走路的时候有些步履蹒跚——坐牛成为了拉科塔人中令人敬畏的名字。年轻的酋长率领着他的洪克帕帕族追随者们在与其他部落的战斗中获得了众多的胜利。[PARAGRAPH:1]但是坐牛在战争上的经验没能阻止他在1868年的拉勒米堡条约上签字。该条约要求美国停止向粉河另一边的苏族领地扩张。不过随着1874年在黑山发现了黄金，新一轮来自东部的殖民狂潮来临，条约成了一纸空文。据说坐牛曾经做过一个预言关于美国扩张的梦——一个美国军队指挥官和他的士兵们从天而降，掉入一个苏族村庄——这被认为预示着美国人即将面对毁灭的命运。在这个梦之后不久，乔治·库斯特将军和他的第七骑兵团对一个土著村庄发动了进攻，但是他们却被联合起来的苏族和夏安族战士们歼灭。[PARAGRAPH:1]美国的愤怒很快降临到了坐牛和他的人民头上，他们被迫逃到加拿大境内。尽管被当作外来权贵一样接待，他们也只是暂时得以苟延残喘而已。在他们的新领地上，资源的匮乏使这些拉科塔人面临着饿死的威胁。这迫使坐牛带领他的人民在1881年又回到了美国境内。他们希望能够在美国得到土地、食物以及和平。[PARAGRAPH:1]在他回到美国后，坐牛和他的一些追随者加入了“水牛”比尔·科迪的狂野西部演出。比起坐牛和他的苏族同胞们留在他们分到的保留地上所能获得的，科迪给他们生活条件要好得多了。于是科迪和这个土著领袖之间建立了深厚的友谊。[PARAGRAPH:1]在19世纪的最后十年，“鬼舞”，一种旨在彻底消除美国对土著人影响的宗教仪式在苏族人当中流传开来。而美国军队则明令禁止类似“鬼舞”这样的土著宗教仪式。这使得拉科塔人与美国军队之间的局势再次变得紧张起来。水牛比尔介入并努力促使双方达成和平协议，但是最后还是徒劳无功。由于担心坐牛与这个逐渐壮大宗教仪式有牵连，美国政府在1890年派印第安警察逮捕并暗杀了这个可怜的酋长。就在事后数日，由于美国政府对“鬼舞”仪式的反对，导致了臭名昭著的伤膝河谷大屠杀。（塞爱维小提示：伤膝河谷大屠杀是印第安人与美国政府的最后一次大规模武装冲突。1890年12月29日，300多名北美土著人——其中有200多名是手无寸铁的妇孺，在逃亡途中于南达科他州松树岭的伤膝河谷时遭遇美国军队，在实力悬殊的状况下，战斗变成了单方面的屠杀。）</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_NATIVE_AMERICA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Troy can't hold a candle to the Native American Empire. As a defensive powerhouse with a focus on archery units, the Native American Empire has a myriad of methods to defend itself. Sitting Bull's "Protective" trait allows the speedy construction of Walls and grants Archery and Gunpowder Units bonus promotions. The Totem Pole, the Native American replacement for the Monument, gives an experience bonus to all Archery Units. And if that weren't enough, the Dog Soldier, a replacement for the Axeman, can be produced without Copper or Iron and receives a big bonus against melee troops. Combine these defensive advantages with the plethora of Great People created by Sitting Bull's "Philosophical" trait and you've got a defensive force that would make Priam blush.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Native Americans were the original inhabitants of North America, emigrating roughly 16,000 years ago. The term "Native American" most often refers to the people who settled in the northern continent of the Western Hemisphere, in the land that is today owned by the United States and Canada. At the time of the arrival of Columbus, thousands of Native American tribes populated the furthest reaches of North America, with somewhere between two and 18 million Natives living in this region. (The "Native American" civilization in the game represents the empire that would have formed had these disparate people ever united.)[PARAGRAPH:1]The northern Native Americans never developed a system of writing (the Mayans to the south were the only Native Americans to do so), so the history of the Native Americans before the arrival of the Europeans is difficult to piece together. It is known, however, that these original inhabitants had crossed a land bridge (since gone) connecting Siberia with Alaska. As these Siberian immigrants spread south and east across the continent in search of sustenance, they encountered many different climates, ecologies, and geographies. Settling from within a stone's throw of the Arctic Circle to the most desolate regions of the American Southwest, the Native Americans were a testament to human adaptability. [PARAGRAPH:1]Given the diversity of lands which they inhabited, not to mention the vast distances separating them, the Native Americans never formed a unified nation. Powerful local entities - such as the Six Nations (also known as the "Iroquois Confederacy") - would appear periodically, but for the most part tribes remained the largest political organization. [PARAGRAPH:1]With the arrival of the Europeans in the New World, the Native American tribes would be forced to adapt to yet another hostile environment. As the United States established itself as a nation, the Native Americans were perceived as a roadblock to American supremacy - a roadblock which needed to be removed. Andrew Jackson, before his election as the seventh President of the United States, waged total war against the Seminoles in Florida and obliterated the Creek Indians at the Battle of Horseshoe Bend. As President, he signed into effect the "Indian Removal Act" of 1830, the precedent to numerous future "relocation treaties." The Treaty of New Echota, one such relocation treaty, was signed between the United States government and a tiny fraction of the Cherokee people. The march of the Cherokee from their homeland in the eastern United States to new territory in Oklahoma and Arkansas cost the lives of some four thousand natives, and would later become known as the "Trail of Tears." [PARAGRAPH:1]The continual pushes westwards by American settlers further displaced the Natives, resulting in a series of conflicts known as the "Indian Wars." However, the Native Americans were never able to unify on a grand enough scale to stop the Europeans or their descendents. A common scenario began to occur. Various individual tribes would fight tooth and nail against the invaders and be nearly defeated. These tribes would then be enticed into signing treaties that would often be ignored by the Americans and the tribe would once again be pushed on at the point of a bayonet. The state of Oklahoma was originally given to Native Americans who had been forced from the east, but then in the 1890s, was opened in chunks for American settlement. [PARAGRAPH:1]By the beginning of the twentieth century, between 75 and 95 percent of the Native American population had been destroyed by starvation, disease or warfare. The reservation system had consigned most survivors to usually undesirable land throughout the United States, and over the next several decades, the rates of alcoholism and suicide among the Native American population skyrocketed. But during the 1960's, a revival of Native American heritage began to emerge. Today, over two million Native Americans live in roughly 563 tribes across the United States. Native American artists such as author Sherman Alexie have beautifully conveyed the travails endured by modern Native Americans in poetry and prose, and proud peoples once forced onto reservations have again begun to spread throughout the United States.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[BOLD]策略提示:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]特洛伊人能在敌人围攻下坚持十年之久，但和北美土著相比却只能说是小巫见大巫。北美土著文明是擅用投射武器的顽强防御者，拥有许多保护自己的有效手段。北美土著领袖的“保国”特质可以加速城墙的建造，并使投射类及火器类单位自动获得特定晋升。北美土著替代纪念碑的特色建筑——图腾柱又可给予投射单位额外的经验奖励。有了这些还不够，北美土著替代斧兵的特色单位——猎犬战士拥有对其他肉搏兵种的高额战斗加成，而且无须铜铁资源即可组建。如此之多的防御优势再加上坐牛的“思辨”特质催生的历史伟人，你强大的帝国卫队足以令特洛伊国王普利阿摩斯感到自愧不如。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]北美土著是北美洲的原住民。他们在大约16000年以前就迁到北美洲定居了。“北美土著”这个专有名词多用于表示以前定居于西半球北部大陆上的人（现在，这些土地属于美国和加拿大）。当哥伦布到达的时候，数以千计的北美土著部落散布在北美洲的每个角落。大约有2百万到1千8百万之间的土著生活在这个地区。（在游戏中，“北美土著”这个文明表现的是一个由这些迥异的部落联合起来所组成的虚拟帝国。）[PARAGRAPH:1]由于北部的北美土著一直都没有发展出一套书写系统（南部的玛雅人是唯一发展出书写系统的美洲原住民）。所以，在欧洲人到达之前的北美土著历史难以一窥全貌。尽管如此，公认的是这些原住民是穿越了连接西伯利亚和阿拉斯加两地的大陆桥（现在已经不存在了）而来的。这些西伯利亚移民迫于生计向南部和东部迁徙，足迹遍布整个北美大陆。在这期间，他们遇到了各种各样的气候条件，生态环境和地理环境。这些北美土著的居住地从距离北极圈一箭之遥的地方一直扩展到北美西南部最荒凉的地区，他们是人类强大适应能力的一个证明。[PARAGRAPH:1]由于他们居住地之间的差异，所以北美土著部落从来就没有形成过一个统一的国家（即使不考虑他们之间的距离之大）。虽然强大的区域性势力——比如说六族（也被称为“易洛魁联盟”）——周而复始地出现。但是，很大程度上来说，部落依然是最大的政治组织。[PARAGRAPH:1]随着欧洲人抵达新大陆，北美土著部落不得不去适应另一个充满敌视的环境。当美国建国的时候，北美土著就成了美国霸权的阻碍，而且是必须被排除掉的阻碍。安德鲁·杰克逊在当选为美国第七任总统之前，曾经对佛罗里达的米诺尔人发动了全面战争，还在马蹄弯战役中灭亡了克里克族印第安人。1830年，他以总统的身份签署生效了“印第安人移居法”。该法案开了后来众多“移居条约”的先例。比如美国政府和少数切罗基族人签订的新艾克塔条约就是一条典型的移居条约。切罗基人从他们美国东部的故土迁移到了俄克拉荷马州和阿肯色州的新领地。在这次长途跋涉中，大约四千土著人失去了他们的生命。这就是后来有名的“血泪之路”。[PARAGRAPH:1]美国移民持续不断的西进活动使得土著人流离失所的情况进一步加剧，并最终导致了一系列的流血冲突，史称“印第安战争”。但是，北美土著一直无法团结起足够大的力量来阻止欧洲人及其后裔。一幕常见的情景开始上演。各个部落与侵略者孤军奋战，最后独力难支，几乎溃败。然后这些部落被诱使着签署了一些条约。当然，美国人经常会“忘掉”他们曾经签署过的条约，而这些部落也经常再次被推到刺刀前。例如：俄克拉荷马州最初划给了那些从东部强制迁来的北美土著。但是在19世纪90年代，该州却向美国移民全面开放。[PARAGRAPH:1]在二十世纪初，有百分之七十五到百分之九十五的北美土著人死于饥饿，疾病或者战争。美国的保留地制度中分配给幸存者的土地通常都是整个美国中无人问津的土地。而在接下来的几十年里，北美土著人中酗酒和自杀的比率暴涨。不过在20世纪60年代，北美土著传统的复兴运动开始出现。现在，有超过2百万的北美土著生活在大约563个部落中，横跨整个美国。许多像作家谢尔曼·亚历克西一样的北美土著艺术家们用诗歌和散文巧妙地表达了现代北美土著所经受的苦难。同时，也表达了土著人们的自豪——虽然曾经被迫迁移到保留地上，但是今天再次开始发展壮大起来，遍布美国各地。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIVE_AMERICA_TOTEM_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Totem Poles were a tradition of the Native American tribes of the Pacific Northwest. Built from Oregon to Alaska, the Totem Pole is a visual representation of various tribal legends or important occurrences. [PARAGRAPH:1]While not worshipped, Totem Poles were often revered as symbols of wealth and common heritage. Yet some Totem Poles acted as warnings, rather than testaments. "Shame Poles" could be constructed to remind a tribe of a particular debt or offense. One particularly controversial pole, now found in the Alaska State Museum, bears the image of President Abraham Lincoln. Some claim that the "Lincoln Pole" was built to honor the passage of the Emancipation Proclamation, while many believe that it was built to mourn the wealth lost by the Tlingits tribe when forced to free their slaves.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]图腾柱是美洲西北部太平洋沿岸土著部落的一种传统建筑。从俄勒冈到阿拉斯加的各式图腾柱成为了各部落传奇或重要事件的最直观表现。[PARAGRAPH:1]图腾柱并非是用来被崇拜，而只是作为财富的象征和公共遗产为人们所崇敬。然而有些图腾柱也会担当警示作用，而不仅仅是被当成遗嘱。有一种“耻辱柱”，一个部落建造它是为了铭记犯下的一次罪孽。在阿拉斯加州立博物馆的藏品中，有一支备受争议的图腾柱，它上面竟印有总统亚伯拉罕·林肯的形象。一些人断言这支“林肯柱”是为了彪炳奴隶解放运动中的功勋，同时也有许多人相信修建它是为了怀念特林吉特部落被迫释放自己的奴隶而失去的财富。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_NATIVE_AMERICA_DOG_SOLDIER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Dog Soldiers were the elite of the Cheyenne warriors and some of the most feared fighters in the American West. Members of a prestigious fraternal society, the Dog Soldiers each received a "Dog Sash" upon entrance into the group. While at first merely emblems of membership, the "Dog Sash" soon became a symbol of iron will in combat. This reputation stemmed from the Dog Soldier habit of, during particularly brutal combat, staking themselves to the ground by way of their "Dog Sash" and not moving from the spot until victory or death had overtaken them.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]猎犬战士是居住于北美西部地区的夏安族精锐战士。猎犬战士享有极高声望，彼此团结友爱，他们在加入团队时将获得一条“猎犬腰带”，起初这只是作为团队一员的标记，但日后它将会成为坚强战斗意志的象征。因为猎犬战士在面临最残酷战斗的时候，习惯用“猎犬腰带”将自己固定在某个位置绝不后退，直到赢得胜利或是被死神带走。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PORTUGAL_FEITORIA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Feitoria is a Portuguese trading post. During the colonial era Feitorias were essential to the Portuguese in expanding their trade network between Europe, the Far East, and eventually the Americas. They afforded ships with limited range a safe port of call to refill depleted supplies and give their crews much needed rest.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]商站是葡萄牙人的贸易驿站。在殖民地时代，商站在扩张位于欧洲、远东直至美洲的贸易网络时对于葡萄牙人来说是不可或缺的。商站能为提供船只一个安全的停泊位置和足够的必需品给养，还能为船员提供他们最需要的休息场所。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PORTUGAL_CARRACK_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]These four-masted sailing ships were the first European ships able to reliably navigate the open ocean. Although small by modern standards, the Carrack afforded enough space for crew, cargo and small cannons. Because the ship rose high out of the water it was near impossible for smaller ships to board a carrack. This size was a double edged sword, and due to its height Carracks were prone to capsize in strong winds. The Carrack was used most prominently by the Portuguese and Spanish during their explorations in the 15th and 16th centuries. The Santa Maria, the ship that carried Columbus to the New World, was a Carrack.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]“卡拉克帆船”（Carrack）拥有四根桅杆，是第一种能够比较安全地在大洋中航行的欧洲船舶。虽然按照现代标准，卡拉克帆船只能称为“小船”，但它的空间足够容纳远洋航行所需的船员、补给品及数门轻型加农炮。卡拉克帆船的甲板高出水面很多，人员很难从小艇上靠帮登船。这样的船型有利也有弊，例如在强风下容易侧翻。葡萄牙人和西班牙人在15、16世纪远洋探险活动中大量使用卡拉克帆船。哥伦布远航新大陆时所乘的圣玛利亚号就是一艘卡拉克帆船。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BYZANTINE_HIPPODROME_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Hippodrome of Constantinople (literally "Horse Path" in Greek) was constructed in 203 AD by the Emperor Septimius Severus. The building was a massive venue for chariot races. While the art of charioteering saw great advances in the Hippodrome - the first four-horse races were held here - much of the venue's renown would stem from it involvement in one of the most terrible massacres in Byzantine history. During the Nika Revolts, a brutal uprising between rival racing factions, nearly 30000 rioters were slain by Byzantine troops within the Hippodrome.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]君士坦丁堡的赛马场（希腊语的字面意思是“跑马之地”）是由皇帝谢普提米乌斯·塞维鲁在公元203年兴建的。这座建筑是一圈用于马拉战车竞赛的宽大场地。当时这种驾驭战车在赛马场中驰骋的艺术是一种巨大的进步，第一场四匹马的赛马会就在这座赛马场举行，但是这座建筑的多数名声是因为与拜占庭历史上一宗著名的血腥大屠杀有关。在尼卡叛乱中，一批近30000人的赛马竞争对手之间爆发了野蛮的暴动，但都被拜占庭军队屠杀在了这座赛马场中。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_BYZANTINE_CATAPHRACT_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]While not a Byzantine invention, heavy cavalry reached a new level of perfection under Byzantine command. Until the sixth century AD, Byzantium had relied on Teutonic and Hunnish mercenary cavalry, but under Emperor Nicephorus II - known as "The Pale Death" - native heavy cavalry, the Cataphracts, became the cornerstone of Byzantine warfare. The heaviest cavalry of its age, the Cataphract shielded both rider and mount with thick protective armor, making them a terror on the battlefield. The effectiveness of the Byzantine heavy cavalry made the Cataphracts one of the key models for later European knights.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]虽然拜占庭帝国并非重甲骑兵的发明者，但确实使重甲骑兵战术发展至接近完美。在公元6世纪以前，拜占庭主要雇佣条顿人和匈人骑兵为其作战。但到人称“白面死神”的尼斯弗鲁斯二世皇帝统治时期，“重甲骑兵”（Cataphract）开始成为拜占庭军队的中坚力量。拜占庭重甲骑兵是当时护甲最厚重的骑兵，战马和骑手均穿戴着坚固的铠甲，凭借强大的冲击力在战场上所向披靡。实际上后世欧洲骑士的装备主要也是仿效拜占庭重甲骑兵发展而来。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_BYZANTIUM_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Byzantines are a multi-faceted empire. Justinian's "Spiritual" trait means anarchy is a thing of the past and makes it in their Empire's interest to found an early religion. But the combination of Justinian's "Imperialistic" trait and the high-powered Cataphract unit make the Byzantines a formidable martial civilization, as well. Be sure to claim any horses you may encounter. The Cataphract requires them and the Hippodrome, the Byzantine replacement for the Theatre, provides an extra happiness with access to horses.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD] [PARAGRAPH:1]The Byzantine Empire, centered around the city of Constantinople, was the successor to the Roman Empire. At its height, the Byzantine Empire reached from Persia to Spain, controlling nearly all the territory that felt the lap of the Mediterranean's warm waters. [PARAGRAPH:1]When the Byzantine Empire began and the Roman Empire ceased is a point of much contention. Some historians place the beginning of the Byzantine Empire in 300 AD, when Constantine I moved the capital of the Roman Empire from Rome to a city called Byzantium (later know as Constantinople). Others place the birth of the Byzantine Empire at the end of the reign of Theodosius I, who at his death split the Roman Empire into the Western Empire, ruled from Rome, and the Eastern Empire, ruled from Constantinople. [PARAGRAPH:1]Regardless of historic debate, after the sacking of Rome in 476 AD, the Byzantine Empire was to become the foremost European nation in art, trade and stability - although not necessarily all at once. Taking the throne in 527 AD, Justinian I extended the grip of the Byzantine Empire from Constantinople to the furthest coasts of the Mediterranean Sea. However the Empire would not be able to enjoy the benefits of such territorial expansions for long, as Justinian's successor, Justin II, would begin a trend of placating the various enemies of the Empire - the Sassanid Persians, the Bulgars, and the Arabs, newly organized under Mohammed - with territory in exchange for peace. [PARAGRAPH:1]Territorial losses would continue to weaken the Byzantines until a new lineage of emperors, known as the Macedonian Emperors, arose to invigorate the Empire once again. Basil I founded the Macedonian line in 869. Under the Macedonians, the Byzantine Empire once again began to reach outwards, solidifying its hold on much of the territory neighboring Constantinople. Art flourished in their roughly two centuries of rule, as did the Greek Orthodox Church. [PARAGRAPH:1]The new millennium would be a painful one for Byzantium. Relations between the Roman Catholic Church and the Eastern Orthodox Church had been deteriorating for many years, and the conflict came to a head with the Great Schism (1054), which finally split the two religions. Militarily, increased assaults by the Seljuk Turks culminated in a resounding defeat for the Empire at the Battle of Manzikert, the Empire losing much of its freshly-gained holdings.[PARAGRAPH:1]But once again, the rise of a powerful new dynasty reversed the Empire's decline. This new dynasty, the Comnenius, sent the call to Western Europe for aid in fighting the Seljuk Turks. Pope Urban II, seeing a chance to reconquer the Holy Lands of Antioch and Jerusalem, as well as halt the squabbling of the European Kings, spread the word for the First Crusade. [PARAGRAPH:1]Through the Crusaders' efforts, the Byzantine Empire regained a portion of its lost territory. But the holy warriors of Western Europe became difficult to control, often threatening to assault the very Empire that had requested their aid. John II and Manuel I, the two most prestigious of the Comnenius emperors, held off the Crusaders and safeguarded the empire from a host of external foes, while ushering in a new era of Byzantine artistic and economic prowess. [PARAGRAPH:1]Manuel I Comnenius was the last great emperor of the Byzantines and the last Comneni. The Angeloi dynasty, successors to the Comneni, proved unable to halt the Empire's slow collapse. In 1204, the knights of the Fourth Crusade, summoned by a disposed Angeloi prince, sacked Constantinople and split the Byzantine Empire into three smaller kingdoms. Nicaea, one of these ex-Byzantine states, recaptured Constantinople years later, but all hopes of reviving the Byzantine Empire would be ended with the capture of the city by the Ottoman leader Mehmed II in 1461.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[BOLD]策略提示:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]拜占庭帝国可以说是一个多面手。查士丁尼的“虔信”特质意味着与无政府状态告别，并有利于快速创立一个早期宗教。而查士丁尼的“霸权”特质配合强大的重甲骑兵单位又使拜占庭成为可怕的军事化文明。请确保控制你所发现的所有马匹资源，这是组建重甲骑兵部队的必要条件，而且马匹资源还能使替代剧场的拜占庭特色建筑——赛马场额外+1快乐。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD] [PARAGRAPH:1]以君士坦丁堡为中心的拜占庭帝国（塞爱维小提示：或称东罗马帝国，实际上“拜占庭帝国”是后世史家为强调其与罗马帝国的区别而生造的称谓）是罗马帝国的继承者。在全盛时期，拜占庭帝国从波斯伸延到西班牙，几乎控制了所有包围着地中海温暖海水的土地。[PARAGRAPH:1]拜占庭帝国何时开始和罗马帝国何时终结是一个备受争议的问题。有些历史学家把拜占庭帝国的开始放在公元300年，那一年君士坦丁一世把罗马帝国的首都从罗马迁到一个叫拜占庭的城市（后来更名为君士坦丁堡）。有些则把拜占庭帝国的开始放在狄奥多西一世统治的结束，狄奥多西一世逝世后罗马帝国分裂为以罗马为中心的西罗马帝国和以君士坦丁堡为中心的东罗马帝国。[PARAGRAPH:1]不管历史争议如何，公元476年蛮族洗劫罗马之后，拜占庭帝国成为欧洲艺术最兴盛、贸易最繁荣、政局最稳定的地方——虽然并非总能三者兼具。公元527年查士丁尼一世登基，他进一步扩大了拜占庭帝国从君士坦丁堡到地中海最远海岸的控制。然而帝国却没有充分获得长期领土扩张带来的利益，作为查士丁尼的继承人，查士丁二世便开始倾向安抚各个敌对国家——包括萨珊王朝统治的波斯人、保加利亚人和后来由穆罕默德团结起来的阿拉伯人，用土地换得和平。[PARAGRAPH:1]领土的减少不断削弱拜占庭，直到一个新的王族血统，著名的马其顿王朝的兴起再次刺激了帝国。869年巴兹尔一世建立马其顿王朝。在马其顿王朝的统治下，拜占庭帝国再次开始向外扩张，巩固掌握了君士坦丁堡邻近的大部分领土。在他们近两个世纪的统治下，艺术和希腊东正教同样蓬勃发展。[PARAGRAPH:1]新千年对拜占庭来说将是个痛苦的时期。罗马天主教和东正教之间的关系已恶化多年，并且因大分裂（1054）使冲突达到白热化的阶段，基督教世界就此分裂成两大教会。军事上，塞尔柱突厥人加强攻击，最终在曼兹克尔特一役决定性地击败了帝国，帝国失去了许多刚得到的土地。[PARAGRAPH:1]但是一个强大新王朝——科南尼王朝的崛起再次挽回了帝国的衰落。科南尼王朝为抵抗塞尔柱突厥的攻击而向西欧求助。教皇乌尔班二世看到再次夺回圣城安提俄克和耶路撒冷的机会，成功暂停了欧洲国王的争论并发起第一次十字军东征。[PARAGRAPH:1]在十字军的帮助下，拜占庭帝国夺回了部分失地。但是西欧的圣战者变得难于控制，经常威胁要对向他们求助的帝国发动进攻。科南尼王朝最高声望的两位君主约翰二世和曼纽尔一世努力控制住十字军，抵御外敌入侵，同时使拜占庭的艺术和经济影响力迎来新纪元。[PARAGRAPH:1]曼纽尔一世是科南尼王朝乃至拜占庭历史上最后的一位大帝。继科南尼王朝而起的安吉利王朝无法阻止帝国的缓慢衰败。1204年，一位被废黜的安吉利王子怂恿第四次东征的十字军洗劫了君士坦丁堡并将拜占庭分裂为三个小国家。原为拜占庭下属省份的尼西亚王国在多年后重新夺回君士坦丁堡，但在奥斯曼领袖穆罕默德二世攻陷该城之后，所有恢复拜占庭帝国的希望终于在1461年完全破灭。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_JUSTINIAN_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Justinian I[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Emperor of the Byzantine Empire[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] May 11, 483 - November 13, 565 AD[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Justinian the First, known as Flavius Petrus Sabbatius Iustinianus in Latin, was emperor of the Byzantine Empire from 527 until his death in 565. His four decades of rule marked the greatest expansion of the Byzantine Empire since its split with the Roman Empire and a sweeping revival in the Christian religion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Born in a small village in modern Macedonia, Justinian had little connection to power in Constantinople as a youth. It was the rise of his uncle, Justin, a Byzantine general who succeeded the Emperor Anastasius, which drew young Justinian from the Macedonian pastures into cosmopolitan Constantinople. Justinian served his uncle as a close advisor for a decade before the passing of Emperor Justin transferred the diadem to Justinian.[PARAGRAPH:1]With Justinian's rise to power, two other important faces rose to prominence. Belisarius, a close friend of Justinian, became the leader of Justinian's armies and proved himself as a brilliant tactician. The second face belonged to his beautiful and savvy wife, Theodora, who took on the role that Justinian himself once filled, that of the emperor's closest advisor.[PARAGRAPH:1]One of Justinian's first actions as Emperor was to order a collection of all Roman law, the Corpus Juris Civilis. But not long after the first issuing of the Corpus, an uprising among two rival chariot racing factions, the Blues and the Greens, engulfed Constantinople in a wave of violence and conflagration. Enterprising powers within the city allied against Justinian, using the chaos to declare a new Emperor, Hypatius, a nephew of Anastasius. Justinian, unsure of the strength of usurpers, decided to flee the city, but his brave wife refused. Instead, Belisarius was ordered to take two divisions and quell the uprising, which he did with ruthless ability, trapping rioters in the Hippodrome and killing nearly 30,000 before the riot was finally put down.[PARAGRAPH:1]The damage done to the city after the riots was substantial. Among the smoldering ruins lay the Hagia Sophia, Constantinople's greatest cathedral, burnt to the ground. Justinian thus began a monumental campaign to expand and restore the building. With its completion five years later, the reconstructed Hagia Sophia was christened as the world's largest cathedral, a title it would hold for a millennium. Under Justinian's order, twenty-five cathedrals were built in Constantinople alone, with many more built outside the capital city.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Empire thrived under Justinian. Thanks in no small part to the able command of Belisarius, Emperor Justinian's reach spread from Constantinople to Southern Spain, with North Africa and Italy all falling under the Byzantine grasp. Justinian's reign marked a high point for the Byzantine Empire, as shortly after his death, much of the land conquered in his name was lost. War with powerful Germanic tribes and neighboring Persia would cost the empire much of its hard-fought gains.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]查士丁尼一世[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]拜占庭帝国皇帝[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]483年5月11日-565年11月13日[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]查士丁尼一世，拉丁文全名是弗拉维乌斯·菲特鲁斯·萨巴提乌斯·查士丁尼乌斯，是拜占庭帝国的皇帝，自527年执政到565年逝世，他四十年的统治标志着拜占庭自罗马帝国分裂和基督教兴起以来最伟大的扩张。[PARAGRAPH:1]出生在马其顿中部的一个小村庄，年少的查士丁尼跟君士坦丁堡的权力中心没什么关系。正是他的叔父查士丁，一位继承国王阿纳斯塔修斯的拜占庭将军，使年轻的查士丁尼从马其顿的牧场走进了大都会君士坦丁堡。查士丁尼作为顾问为他叔父服务了十年，查士丁逝世后权力被交给了查士丁尼。[PARAGRAPH:1]随着查士丁尼上台，有两个重要的面孔在政坛浮现。贝利撒留，查士丁尼的一位亲密好友，成为查士丁尼军队的领导并且展现出自己是一位出色的战术家。第二位则是他美丽而机智的妻子，西奥多拉，扮演查士丁尼他曾亲自担任的角色，即皇帝最亲密的顾问。[PARAGRAPH:1]当上皇帝的查士丁尼做的第一项行动是下令收集所有的罗马法律整理为《查士丁尼法典》。但第一版的法典出版后不久，蓝绿两个赛车竞争派别之间的争斗使君士坦丁堡卷入一波血腥的动乱。反对派联合起来对抗查士丁尼，利用混乱拥立阿纳斯塔修斯的侄子海帕提斯为新的皇帝。查士丁尼无法估计篡位者的力量，决定逃离城市，但他勇敢的妻子拒绝了。贝利撒留奉命分化并镇压两个派别，他设计在竞技场诱捕乱党，在暴动最终平息前有将近三万人被屠杀。[PARAGRAPH:1]暴乱对城市的伤害是很大的。君士坦丁堡最大的教堂圣索菲亚也被彻底烧毁。此后查士丁尼致力于城市的发展和重建。五年之后完工的新圣索菲亚被称为世界最大的教堂，这个名衔保持了一千年之久。在查士丁尼的命令下，有25座教堂建在君士坦丁堡城内，还有更多的建在首都的外围。[PARAGRAPH:1]帝国在查士丁尼的统治下繁荣兴旺。很大程度上归功于贝利撒留出色的指挥，查士丁尼的势力从君士坦丁堡伸展到西班牙南部，包括北非和意大利都归到拜占庭的统治之下。查士丁尼的统治标志着拜占庭帝国达到一个新的高度，但他死后不久，这些新近征服的土地逐渐流失。和强大的日尔曼部族以及邻国波斯的战争消耗了太多来之不易的收获。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_JOAO_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Joao II[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of Portugal[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived:[\BOLD] c.1455 - 1495 AD[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]King Joao II of Portugal was a statesman that supported the exploration and exploitation of the undiscovered world. Arguably the first nation to discover America, under Joao's reign Portugal made several other important discoveries while also advancing the field of nautical navigation.[PARAGRAPH:1]"I am the lord of lords, not the server of servants." These words, originally a castigation of rebellious nobles by Joao, would come to define the Portuguese king's reign. Joao's dislike of court intrigue and the inability for political opinion to influence his decisions made him an unpopular king amongst his peers. The King's early rule was defined by his efforts to curtail, and eventually crush, all internal corruption and opposition to his rule. After having intercepted conspiratorial letters between the Duke of Braganza and Queen Isabella I of Castile in 1483, Joao had the Duke executed, his family banished from Portugal, and his lands and wealth confiscated. [PARAGRAPH:1]Joao II's policies focused primarily on the exploration and exploitation of maritime trade routes, particularly with India. The full extent of Portugal's explorations and discoveries remain largely unknown due to the government's secrecy, born of a fierce competition with its neighbor Castile. It is, however, argued that Portugal had already reached North America and Brazil by 1470 and 1480, respectively. This places their discovery of North America in advance of Christopher Columbus's voyage.[PARAGRAPH:1]Portugal, under the reign of Joao, was also credited with the 1484 discovery of the Congo River, the 1488 rounding of the Cape of Good Hope (Africa's southern tip), and the 1493 settlement of the São Tomé and Príncipe Islands.[PARAGRAPH:1]Disputes over rights of exploration between Castile and Aragon and Portugal would eventually lead to the Treaty of Tordesillas (1494) which split the world in half. Portugal would be responsible for exploring the Eastern hemisphere while Aragon and Castile would have the Western hemisphere.[PARAGRAPH:1]Towards the end of his reign, Joao's only legitimate heir, Alfonso, died under mysterious circumstances. This prevented Portugal from inheriting ownership of Castile and Aragon through Alfonso's marriage to Isabella of Aragon - Isabella I of Castile and Ferdinand II of Aragon's eldest daughter. Joao II died without male heir in 1495, possibly poisoned by the vengeful Portuguese nobility and was succeeded by his first cousin, Manuel I.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]若昂二世[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]葡萄牙国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份:[\BOLD]约1455-1495[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]葡萄牙国王若昂二世是率先推动探索与开发未知世界的伟大政治家。在若昂统治时期，葡萄牙达成了一系列重要的地理发现，促进了航海技术的发展，一些历史学家甚至认为葡萄牙是第一个发现美洲的国家。[PARAGRAPH:1]“我是主人的主人，不是仆人的仆人。”这句话原本是若昂对一名反叛贵族的惩戒之词，它反映了这位国王的统治风格。若昂厌恶宫廷官员的阳奉阴违，不愿别人的政治观点影响自己的决策，许多贵族都对他心怀不满。若昂国王在统治初期主要致力于减少以至消除内部的腐败分子和反叛力量。在1483年截获布拉干扎公爵同卡斯提尔的伊莎贝拉一世女王之间秘密往来的信件之后，若昂下令处死公爵，其家人被驱逐出境，其领地和财产被没收充公。[PARAGRAPH:1]此后若昂二世的政策主要围绕探索与发展海上贸易线展开，特别是通往印度的新航路。葡萄牙海上探索及地理发现成果的详情有很多仍然是不为人知的政府机密（因为在这个领域里葡萄牙同其邻国卡斯提尔进行着激烈的竞争）。历史学家认为葡萄牙人在1470年和1480年即已抵达北美和巴西，即他们发现北美的时间要早于哥伦布的远航。[PARAGRAPH:1]在若昂统治时期，葡萄牙人还于1484年发现刚果河口，于1488年绕过好望角（非洲最南端），并于1493年在圣多美和普林西比群岛建立殖民点。[PARAGRAPH:1]卡斯提尔-阿拉贡与葡萄牙在海上探索领域的激烈争夺最终导致双方签署了分享世界的托德西拉斯条约（1494年）。葡萄牙取得东半球的探索权，卡斯提尔-阿拉贡则占有西半球。[PARAGRAPH:1]在若昂统治末期，他的唯一合法继承人阿方索神秘死亡。若不是由于这一事件，葡萄牙将继承卡斯提尔-阿拉贡的统治权——因为阿方索娶了阿拉贡的伊莎贝拉（卡斯提尔的伊沙贝拉一世与阿拉贡的斐迪南二世的长女）。若昂二世于1495年去世（可能是被暗中报复的葡萄牙贵族毒死），他身后没有留下直系子嗣，王位由他的堂兄曼努埃尔一世继承。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CUIRASSIER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Cuirassier was the last step in the evolution of European armored cavalry. Drawing their name from their heavy, metal breastplates - or "cuirasses" - the Cuirassiers were the heaviest of the heavy cavalry.[PARAGRAPH:1]The earliest Cuirassiers, born in the 15th century, were armored head-to-toe and armed with heavy saber and pistols. As European warfare began to rely more on firearms, much of this heavy armor was shed to increase mobility, eventually adapting into what is now recognized as the standard Cuirassier uniform - a breastplate and helm. Fielded almost exclusively in the battles of continental Europe, the Cuirassier saw its most widespread use under the command of Napoleon, who was fielding 14 regiments of the cavalrymen by 1812. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]胸甲骑兵是欧洲装甲骑兵发展的最后阶段。他们的名字来源于他们那厚重的金属护胸板条甲——或者叫“胸甲”——胸甲骑兵是最“重型”的重骑兵。[PARAGRAPH:1]最早的胸甲骑兵出现在15世纪。那时他们全身覆甲，并且装备了重型马刀和手枪。但是由于欧洲战争越来越依赖于火器，大量这样的装甲被削减以增加机动性，最终形成了现在公认的标准胸甲骑兵配置——一件护胸板甲和一副头盔。胸甲骑兵几乎是欧洲大陆的战场上独有的兵种，他们在拿破仑的军队中得到了最大规模的应用。拿破仑在1812年左右组建了14支骑兵团。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AIRSHIP_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]A large balloon of lighter-than-air gas, usually hydrogen, held within a rigid frame, the Airship became the first controllable method of manned flight. Seeing the military applications of the Airship's long flight distance and impressive speeds (the finest Airships could sustain 40mph), Germany, France and the United States each adopted the flying machines into regular use from the turn of the century until the 1930s. During World War I, the first Airship bombing runs struck London. But a number of high profile catastrophes, such as the crash of the US Navy's Macon or Germany's Hindenburg, along with the development of aircraft, returned the Airship to the hangar for good.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]飞艇是一个充满了比空气轻的气体（通常是氢气），并被固定在坚固框架中的巨大气球。它成为了第一种可以操控的载人飞行方式。飞艇的长飞行距离和令人印象深刻的飞行速度（最好的飞艇可以维持40英里的时速）在军事上都具有一定的实用性。因此，德国，法国和美国从20世纪初就各自将这种飞行机器列入正规使用，直到20世纪30年代。在第一次世界大战中，第一次飞艇轰炸袭击了伦敦。但是由于发生了不少令人震惊的空难，比如美国海军的梅登号坠毁和德国的兴登堡号坠毁，同时也伴随着飞机的发展，飞艇永远地回到了机棚中。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SHIP_OF_THE_LINE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Ships of the Line were the largest vessels deployed during the height of the European wooden navies, from the seventeenth until the mid-nineteenth century. In naval strategy, the most powerful ships of each respective navy would often form into lines and unleash a barrage upon their rivals. Ships of the Line, as they were known, usually carried 80 or more guns, but this extra-heavy armament cost the vessel dearly in maneuverability.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]从17世纪一直到19世纪中叶，主力战舰（Ship-of-the-line，或称“风帆战列舰”，现代战列舰的前身）都是代表欧洲木制军舰最高水平的最大型战舰，在海战策略中，交战双方各自海军中最强力的战舰通常排列成一条直线，并向它们的敌人倾泻出弹幕。正如大家所知道的，主力战舰通常携带80门或更多的火炮，但是这些极其沉重的武器装备使得这些战舰在机动性上付出了很高的代价。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_AT_INFANTRY_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Since its introduction at the tail-end of WWI, the tank has completely recast the modern battlefield. Being heavily armored, tanks are almost invulnerable to the small arms carried by standard infantry. To combat this new force, Anti-Tank Infantry units were developed by world militaries. These units employed high-velocity cannons capable of penetrating a tank's thick armor, turning once unstoppable war machines into oversized, mobile targets.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]自从一战末期坦克出现以来，它完全改变了现代战场。由于覆盖着厚重的装甲，坦克几乎完全不受一般步兵携带的轻武器的伤害。为了对抗这种新兴的力量，世界各国陆军发展了反坦克步兵部队。这些部队装了能够击穿坦克厚甲的高速加农炮，这使得坦克这种曾经无可阻挡的战争机器变成了特大号的移动靶子。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOBILE_ARTILLERY_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The campaigns of World War II brought to the forefront a key predicament in the development of mobile howitzers: how should new artillery reconcile the need for maneuverability with the demand for destructive power? Militaries the world round would have to wait until the 1960s for a machine that was both mobile and truly powerful.[PARAGRAPH:1]The M109 Paladin, capable of launching a 155mm-caliber artillery shell over nine miles and moving at speeds of 40mph, has become the world standard in self-propelled howitzers. But with the Paladin beginning to show its age, a new machine, the Crusader, capable of firing every six seconds and coordinating eight hits simultaneously, may soon find a spot at the top of the howitzer hierarchy. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]第二次世界大战的战场上，机动火炮的发展碰到了一个严重的困境：新型的炮兵部队如何协调机动性和破坏力这两者需求之间的关系？全世界的陆军直到20世纪60年代才等到了一种在不但拥有机动性，同时真正强力的机器。[PARAGRAPH:1]M109“帕拉丁”自行火炮可以发射155毫米口径火炮的炮弹，而且可以以40英里的时速行进。它很快就成为了自行火炮的世界标准。但是随着“帕拉丁”开始显露老态，一种新型的火炮，“十字军”，也许很快就会找到火炮层级的顶点所在。它能够每隔六秒就开火一次，而且能够协调八次打击同时命中。（塞爱维小提示：“十字军战士”自行火炮具有“多发同时弹着”的优点。即对目标实施快速射击时，迅速变换不同射角，发射一系列炮弹，从而使射弹在同一瞬间落达同一目标，实现了高密度射击，增大了火力杀伤强度。）</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOBILE_SAM_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Surface-to-Air Missile (SAM) systems have been in development since the end of World War II. And while the versatility of modern SAMs keeps numerous systems in use, the "Stinger" missile remains the most popular and effective low-altitude SAM available, thanks to its ability to be transported by both infantry and mobile units. The Avenger Air Defense System (a Humvee emboldened with eight "Stinger" missiles) and the M6 Linebacker (an armored fighting vehicle with a single "quad-pod" of Stingers), both employed by the United States, successfully fuse high mobility and surface-to-air suppression.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]地对空导弹（英文缩写为SAM“萨姆”）系统从第二次世界大战结束以来就一直处于发展中。虽然由于现代地对空导弹的多用途性导致存在为数众多的地对空导弹系统，但是“毒刺”一直都是最广泛使用，和最有效的低空防空导弹。这主要归功于它能够同时被步兵和机动单位携带。“复仇者”防空系统（一种配备了八枚“毒刺”导弹的“悍马”军车）和M6“线卫”（一种携带了四联“毒刺”导弹发射具的装甲武装车辆）均隶属于美国军队。它们成功地融合了高机动性和地对空压制能力。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CUSTOM_HOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]A Customs House is an organization responsible for collecting taxes on imports or exports, as well as for seizing contraband. Customs Houses were common during the Age of Sail, when the level of trade skyrocketed and the necessity for a centralized system of tax collection arose. In Spain, with the huge influx of wealth from the New World, Sevilla was designated the "Customs City" where all transports carrying Incan or Aztec gold were required to land so that the Crown could take its share. Tariffs became a hotly-debated topic in the New World, especially in the English colonies, where tariffs would fan the flames of several of that region's most violent conflicts.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]海关是指专门为了从进出口贸易中收税而成立的机关，其还有一个重要的功能是缉私。海关在大航海时代变成了政府的常设机构，是当时如火如荼的贸易往来促进了这样一个专业收税机构的出现。在西班牙，伴随着从新大陆流入的巨额财富，政府为了那些从印加和阿兹特克掠夺来的黄金中分一杯羹，塞维拉被指定为“海关城”专门处理此类事务。关税在新大陆成了各热门话题，特别是在英国的殖民地，在好几个地区甚至引起了猛烈的暴力冲突。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INDUSTRIAL_PARK_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]During the Industrial Revolution, newly-industrialized cities became grossly polluted, thick smoke filling the air, industrial waste contaminating local bodies of water. This arrangement remained virtually unchanged through the first half of the twentieth century, and cities became increasingly unhealthy places to live.[PARAGRAPH:1]One solution to this problem was to create specially zoned areas of industry - Industrial Parks. These parks took the harmful industries out of the population centers and centralized production facilities to increase efficiency.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]在工业革命期间，新兴的工业城市遭受了严重的污染，浓烟弥漫，工业废物威胁这当地人的身体和水源。这种状况直到20世纪上半叶都没有改变，城市环境对严重威胁着人们的健康。[PARAGRAPH:1]为了改变这种状况，人们特意划了专门用来盖工厂的区域——工业园区。工业园使污染远离人群并且由于工厂群聚使得企业效率更高。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PUBLIC_TRANSPORTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]At the turn of the twentieth century, most modern cities were cesspools of filth. In the United States, the affluent often moved to the suburbs, using automobiles to return to their jobs in the cities. In Europe, on the other hand, where most roads had been designed for horses, not cars, impressive systems of Public Transportation became the most effective way for large numbers of people to get about. As an added bonus, these mass transit systems greatly decreased the amount of pollution created. Subways, trolleys, monorails and buses have become staples in major metropolises like London, Barcelona and even in major US cities like New York City.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]十九世纪末二十世纪初，那些所谓最现代化的城市被污染所包围。在美国，有钱人通常搬到市郊去住，然后开着车到城里上下班。在欧洲，另一方面来说，大多数的路是设计来供给马或者马车行走的，而不是汽车，为了解决大多数人的出行问题大力发展公共交通成了最佳的方法。而且还有个额外的好处是，公交系统几乎没什么污染。在那些国家的首都或者大城市中，例如伦敦，巴塞罗那甚至在美国的大城市如纽约，地铁，电车，轻轨和巴士成了主要的公共交通方式。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GUIDED_MISSILE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Artillery was the only option for long-range, earthborn destruction until the creation of the Guided Missile. Created by German scientists during WWII, the first Guided Missile, the V, was essentially a long-range flying bomb. The V Missile, and the technology behind it, was rapidly upgraded during the Cold War, and later missiles became more precise with more formidable ranges. Capable of carrying a nuclear or conventional explosive payload, modern Guided Missiles fill a wide range of defense needs.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]在巡航导弹发明之前，火炮是人类唯一的远程破坏手段。世界上第一种巡航导弹代号“V”，是由德国科学家在二战中发明的。从本质上来说，它只是一种远程飞行炸弹。在冷战期间，“V”型导弹及其相关科技都得到了迅速的改进。而且在随后的时间里，导弹变得越来越精确，同时其射程也越来越恐怖。现代巡航导弹可以携带核弹头或者常规炸药弹头，它们满足了现代防御的广泛需求。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ATTACK_SUBMARINE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]An Attack Submarine is any submersible with the capacity to destroy enemy ships. In the past, nearly all subs would have been considered Attack Submarines, but with advances in technology, many shed their torpedoes for the capability to carry ballistic missiles. While able to attack land targets, such submarines are particularly vulnerable to attacks from their torpedo-armed cousins.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]攻击型潜艇是指任何拥有摧毁敌军舰船能力的潜水器。在过去，几乎所有潜艇都被归入攻击型潜艇。但是随着科技的进步，许多潜艇放弃了传统的鱼雷，而改装弹道导弹。虽然这样的潜艇能够攻击陆地上的目标，但是它们也变得很容易被它们那些使用鱼雷武装的堂兄弟们所攻击。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_PARK_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]While areas of great natural beauty had often been protected or revered in the past, the modern conception of a National Park did not appear until 1872. Yellowstone National Park, located in the western United States, departed from previous nature preserves - which tended to be set aside for nobility - by opening up the land for the enjoyment of the public. After the creation of Yellowstone, National Parks began popping up throughout the world. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]在过去那些拥有美妙风景的地方经常被人们自发的保护起来，现代意义上的国家公园直到1872年才出现。黄石国家公园，坐落于美国的西部，不同于以往的那些自然保护区——通常仅开放给上流人士游玩——是供给广大公众参观游乐的。自从黄石国家公园成立以后，世界各地的国家公园如雨后春笋般的出现了。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INTELLIGENCE_AGENCY_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]"Know thy enemy" has been an essential part of warfare since the dawn of time, with victory almost always falling into the hands of the informed. And while intrigue and backstabbing (usually quite literally) have been a part of the war since time immemorial, in the modern era, intelligence has become a multi-billion dollar endeavor. New technologies, such as spy satellites and remote microphones, have facilitated the gathering of information, giving eyes and ears all over the world to those who need to be in the know. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]自从有战争以来“认识敌人”就被当成重点，胜利始于对敌人的情况了如指掌。即使在史前时代，不择手段的取得胜利也已经是战争的一部分了；在现代，情报机构已经成了一项数十亿美元的“生意”。新技术，例如间谍卫星和微型麦克风，使收集信息变得更加容易，让那些需要知道这些信息的人仿佛拥有了世界范围的千里眼和顺风耳一样。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NATIONAL_SECURITY_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]As long as there has been espionage, there has been a need for counter-espionage. This is the realm of the Security Bureau. Bureaus like the American FBI or the British MI5 make sure that sensitive intelligence is protected from outside sources. While espionage is an ancient practice, most Security Bureaus are less than one hundred years old. MI5 has only been in existence since 1909, organized originally to fight against German spies before World War I. The FBI began its expansion in the 1930s thanks to J. Edgar Hoover, the Bureau's first director.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]自从间谍出现以来，对反间谍的需求就一直存在。反间谍属于安全部门的职责范围。诸如FBI、MI5等安全部门确保了敏感情报不被外部势力获取。与间谍这个古老的行当相比，大多数安全机构都非常年轻，通常成立时间都不足一百年，例如MI5是在1909年成立的。其在一次大战前创立时的目的是为了对付德国的间谍。FBI在20世纪30年代开始的扩张应归功于它的第一位局长小埃德加·胡佛。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_STEALTH_DESTROYER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The elusive element of surprise has brought about deciding victories on land, at sea and in the air for centuries. But in the face of more precise forms of radar developed in the latter half of the twentieth century, new technology was needed to return the tactical advantage stealth once provided.[PARAGRAPH:1]Beginning in the 1980s, breakthroughs in naval stealth research, such as radar-silent construction materials and simplified superstructures, initiated the creation of the world's first stealth navies. Since that time, France, Sweden and the United States have all adopted their own stealth ships, capable of performing missions while remaining invisible to enemy radar.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]几个世纪以来，不论是在陆地，海洋还是空中，隐蔽的偷袭带来了许多决定性的胜利。但是在20世纪下半叶，面对着发展得越来越精确的雷达，要想恢复隐形技术曾经带来的战术优势，需要许多的新技术。[PARAGRAPH:1]在20世纪80年代初期，在海军隐形技术的研究领域产生了突破，比如雷达静默建材和一体化上部结构，这导致了世界上第一种隐形海军的发明。从那时起，法国，瑞典和美国均启用了他们各自的隐形舰艇。它们能够保持在敌方雷达无法发现的状态下执行任务。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FOREST_PRESERVE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>Forest Preserve</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>森林保护区</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MAUSOLEUM_OF_MAUSSOLLOS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Maussollos died in 349 BC. King of Caria during his lifetime, Maussollos wished to leave a reminder of himself for future generations in the form of a great tomb. In addition to hiring hundreds of laborers, Maussollos commissioned five of the finest artisans in the Hellenic world to design the hundreds of statues that were to line the peripheries of his white marble resting place.[PARAGRAPH:1]Over 130 feet tall upon completion, the Mausoleum of Maussollos stood by the harbor of Halicarnassus until 1522, when the Knights Hospitaller tore it down in order to use the stones to build defenses against the approaching Turks.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]加里亚的国王摩索拉斯于公元前349年去世。在生时摩索拉斯希望给未来的子孙留下一座纪念他自己的建筑——一座雄伟的陵墓。除了雇用数百个劳工，摩索拉斯还把设计数百个陈列在他白色的大理石陵墓四边的雕像的任务交付给了五个古希腊最优秀的工匠。（塞爱维小提示：有资料认为只有四位，并各自负责陵墓的四边。）[PARAGRAPH:1]完工后约130英尺高（约合40米）的摩索拉斯陵墓屹立在哈利卡纳苏斯（古希腊城市，位于加里亚西南岸）的海港，直到公元1522年善堂骑士团为了用它的石料来建造抵御进犯的土耳其人而将它拆毁。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CRISTO_REDENTOR_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Cristo Redentor, "Christ the Redeemer" in English, is a 125-foot tall statue of Jesus Christ situated on Corcovado Mountain, watching over the Brazilian city of Rio de Janeiro. First proposed in 1921 during celebrations of the centennial of Brazilian independence, Cristo Redentor slowly began to take shape through the eyes of potential designers. By 1931, the statue had been completed, making it the largest art deco monument in the world. Since that time, the statue, seated 2330 above sea level, has become an awesome symbol of Rio de Janeiro and of Brazil.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]耶稣基督巨像高125英尺（约合38米），坐落在科尔科瓦杜山上，俯瞰着巴西城市里约热内卢。初在1921年巴西庆祝独立100周年时，耶稣巨像开始被计划建造；接着它在众多设计者的努力中逐渐成型并被选定。到1931年石像完工时，它成为了世界上最大的艺术性、装饰性、纪念性地标。也是从那时起，高出海平面2330米的耶稣巨像成为了巴西里约热内卢的美丽象征。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOAI_STATUES_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Moai Statues are the most recognizable feature of Easter Island. Nine-hundred of these massive stone heads populate the island, most weighing up to 14 tons, with some reaching 82 tons and stretching forty feet into the sky.[PARAGRAPH:1]Theory holds that the Moai Statues were erected by the denizens of Easter Island around 1000 AD, the workers carving them at the Rano Raraku Quarry and transporting them to every corner of the island. The statues were dedicated to the various ancestors of the Easter Island natives. They also stood as symbols of status, showing that the commissioner had the power and wealth to hire the workers necessary to have one made and transported. While the Statues could be moved at a quick pace with less than twenty people, it took nearly three hundred more workers to feed and create tools for those transporting the enormous stone structures.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]摩艾石像群是复活节岛上最容易识别的建造物了。九百多个像这样的大型石像聚集在岛上，大多都有14吨重，更有甚者达82吨、40英尺（约合12米）高。[PARAGRAPH:1]理论认为摩艾石像群是在公元1000年左右由复活节岛的居民所完成的。工匠们在拉诺拉拉库的采石场雕刻好它们并运送到岛上的每一个角落。而这些石像都是岛上的居民供奉给各自的祖先的。它们更是地位的象征，显示着委托者有权势与财富去雇佣足够多的工匠完成整个石像的雕刻及运输过程。尽管不用二十个人就已经能够快速地移动这些石像，但是对于那些大型石像的运输而言，则需要三百个以上的工匠制造运输器械才能完成。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STATUE_OF_ZEUS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Many monuments were created to honor Zeus, King of the Greek Gods, yet none could be as impressive as the Statue of Zeus at Olympia. Over forty feet tall, the Statue filled the temple in which it was constructed from floor to ceiling. Created by the master artisan Phidias between 438 and 446BC, the whole statue rested on a wooden frame built upon a cedarwood throne of appropriate size for a forty-foot deity. The frame was then draped in ivory and gold (ivory for skin, gold for clothing) and covered from head to toe in jewels. Before Zeus' feet, a shallow lake of olive oil reflected light into the temple, illuminating the otherwise closed building. Every four years, when the Olympic Games would be held in the town, Olympic competitors would approach the statue and make sacrifices to the King of the Gods with the hope of assuring their victory.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]尽管古希腊人建造了不计其数的纪念物以表达他们对希腊众神之王宙斯的敬意，然而没有一个能够与奥林匹亚的宙斯神像的震撼力相提并论。神像高约40英尺（约合12米），供奉在神庙里几乎与天花板齐平。它在公元前446至438年由工匠大师菲狄亚斯建造。整个神像以一个木制的框架为基础；这个框架被放置在一个足够大的雪松木王座上——与这个40英尺的神像相得益彰。接着，框架被裹上一层层的象牙（作为皮肤）和黄金（作为衣服），再从头到脚饰以宝石。在宙斯神像的脚前，一个灌有橄榄油的小池将光线折射进寺庙之中，照亮了这个在通常情况下完全封闭的建筑。当四年一度的奥林匹克运动会在这里举行时，参赛者们都会来到宙斯神像前，用他们必胜的决心取悦众神之王——宙斯。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SHWEDAGON_PAYA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Shwedagon Paya is one of the most sacred complexes in all of Buddhism. The story of the Shwedagon Paya is said to have begun with the Buddha himself, Siddhartha Gautama. Gautama gifted eight of his hairs to two young Burmese merchants, who carried them back to their homeland and presented them to the Burmese King, Okkalapa. When King Okkalapa opened the chest containing the hairs, trees blossomed, gems fell from the sky and beams of light shot from the hairs. These hairs were immediately enshrined and the resulting "stupa" - a Buddhist monument built for relics - would become the beginning of the Shwedagon Paya.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Shwedagon Paya of legend was further expanded by Burmese royalty over centuries; archeologists date the current shape of the complex to the eleventh century. Covering over 14 acres within the Burmese capital of Yangon, the centerpiece of the Shwedagon Paya is the massive central stupa. Reaching over 300 feet into the air and covered with gold and gems, the central stupa has been an important pilgrimage destination for Buddhists for hundreds of years.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]瑞光大金塔是佛教最神圣的建筑群之一。传说瑞光大金塔的故事可以追溯到佛陀悉达多·乔答摩本人。乔答摩将自己的八条头发赠送给两个缅甸商人。这两个年轻的商人把头发带回了家乡并献给了缅甸的国王欧卡拉帕。当国王欧卡拉帕打开保存着佛陀头发的匣子时，树上开起了花，宝石从天而降，头发则放出万道光芒。这些头发立即被秘藏起来，并促成了一座舍利塔（用来存放遗骨的佛教建筑）的建造——这只是瑞光大金塔建造历程的伊始。[PARAGRAPH:1]在接下来的数个世纪里，传奇的瑞光大金塔被缅甸王族不断扩建；考古学家认为如今的大金塔群在11世纪最终成型。在缅甸首都仰光，占地面积达14英亩的瑞光大金塔最核心的部分就是那座宏伟的中心舍利塔。塔身高达300英尺（约有90多米），为黄金和宝石所包裹。这座中心舍利塔在数百年来一直都是佛教信徒心中重要的朝圣地。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MISSILE_CRUISER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Once considered an obsolete class of ship, the Cruiser made an impressive comeback in the final decades of the twentieth century. Experiments in ship-mounted missile systems had begun as early as World War II and by the end of the war, the United States Navy had outfitted a slew of Cruisers with surface-to-air missile capabilities. In the 1980s, these early experiments in ship-mounted missile armaments culminated in AEGIS-equipped Ticonderoga-class Missile Cruisers. More than simply reviving the Cruiser class, the "Tico," with its 127 missile arsenal and its phase-array radar, turned the Cruiser into one of the most ferocious ships at sea.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]巡洋舰一度被认为是已经过时的舰种，但是在20世纪最后十年，它完成了一次令人印象深刻的回归。舰载导弹系统的实验早在第二次世界大战时就开始了，而到战争结束的时候，美国海军已经改装了大量的巡洋舰，使其拥有地对空导弹发射能力。20世纪80年代，这些早期的舰载导弹武器实验在装备了“神盾”系统的“提康德罗加”（Ticonderoga，简称“提寇”Tico）级导弹巡洋舰上达到了顶点。超出人们对巡洋舰这种舰种的简单回想，提寇级巡洋舰配备127个导弹仓和相控阵雷达，这使得巡洋舰又回到了海上最凶猛的战舰之列。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TACTICAL_NUKE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The term "Tactical Nuclear Weapon" describes all non-strategic methods of nuclear-weapon delivery, including short-range nuclear missiles, bombs or artillery shells. These weapons can carry a variety of payloads, ranging anywhere from .1 kiloton to 1 megaton. While no tactical nuke has ever been detonated - unlike its strategic cousin - it is believed that a number of nuclear-capable nations have them in their arsenals.[PARAGRAPH:1]Used for specific engagements rather than long-term deterrence, tactical nukes tend to be only a few times greater in destructive power than their conventional-explosive counterparts, allowing a more efficient, but less widespread, effect. This permits commanders to deploy tactical nukes on the field of battle in conjunction with a conventional assault without fear of overtly harming their own troops.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]术语“战术核弹”表示了所有非战略性的核武器投放方式，包括短程核导弹、核炸弹或者核炮弹。这些武器可以携带各种不同的弹头，当量从0.1千吨到1兆吨不等。虽然从来没有战术核弹被引爆过——在这点上和它的堂兄弟，战略核弹不同——但是人们相信一些有核国家在它们的武器库中保存着战术核弹。[PARAGRAPH:1]战术核弹用于特定的战局的作用更多于作为长期的威慑力量的作用。它在破坏力方面变得仅仅比使用常规炸药的同类武器高出几倍，其结果是变得更加有效，但是影响范围更小。这使得指挥官可以在常规攻击中对战场投放战术核弹，而不用担心伤害己方军队。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ADVANCED_FLIGHT_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Little did the Wright Brothers know that less than four decades after their first plane touched down in the North Carolinian sand, aeronautical engineers would have already created a completely new way to power flight - the jet engine. This new engine, based on a turbine churning ultra-compressed air, lifted aviation to previously unreachable heights.[PARAGRAPH:1]Applied to fixed-wing aircraft, the jet engine found its first application in World War II, powering the German Messerschmitt. In these machines, the jet engine increased speed by lowering the overall weight of the craft while providing a level of power unattainable in propeller-based engines. Modern jets, like the SR-71 Blackbird, are capable of speeds of over 2000 mph.[PARAGRAPH:1]The jet engine would find further application in the creation of the helicopter. While Leonardo da Vinci had sketched prototypes of a rotary-wing aircraft in the fifteenth century, no powering mechanism until the advent of the jet engine could provide the proper balance of horsepower and low weight necessary to keep such a machine airborne. With the engine's incorporation into rotary-wing aircraft, it became possible for helicopters to take part in operations from combat to mid-sea rescue, rapidly making them some of the most versatile flying machines ever built.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]莱特兄弟永远无法预料到，仅仅在他们发明的第一架飞机“飞行者1号”在北卡罗来纳州的基蒂霍克沙丘成功试飞以后不够四十年，航空技术工程师们就已经制造出了一种新式的强大航空飞行动力源——喷气式引擎。以不断搅动极度压缩的气体的涡轮机为基础的喷气式引擎，将航空学提高到了一个前所未有的高度。[PARAGRAPH:1]喷气式引擎在第二次世界大战首次应用在固定翼飞行器上，使德国“梅塞施米特”战斗机的作战能力得到增强。它在提高飞行速度的同时降低了飞行器的机身重量，由此提供了螺旋桨引擎无法实现的强大动力。而像SR-71“黑鸟”侦察机这样的现代喷气式飞机的速度已高达2000英里/小时。[PARAGRAPH:1]喷气式引擎在直升飞机发明后得到更加长足的应用。早在十五世纪，列奥纳多·达芬奇就已经描绘出了一种旋翼飞行器的草图；然而直到喷气式引擎的出现，足以满足提供直升飞机适当的平衡性和低重量要求的机械动力源才得到实现——使这样一种飞行器能够停留在空中。正是如此的引擎和如此的飞行器的完美结合，使直升飞机参与由战地作战到海上救援的各种复杂任务成为可能，也使它们迅速地踏进了有史以来用途最多的飞行器的行列。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEALTH_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Throughout the majority of history, warriors have used primitive methods to avoid detection by their foes. But as surveillance technology grew more sophisticated with the invention of radar, new countermeasures became necessary to provide the sort of protection that the cloak of darkness once granted. Combining advances in the fields of composites, engineering and electronics, Stealth technology has made it possible for enormous machines to leave nary a blip on enemy radar. The B2, or "Stealth," Bomber uses a unique shape and radar-resistant materials to avoid detection. Similar techniques have been applied to ships like the French La Fayette frigate, making them near invisible to radar and easily overlooked whilst they prowl the seas.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]在过去绝大多数时间里，战士们都一直在使用着原始的方法来防止被他们的敌军发现。但是随着雷达的发明，侦测技术变得越来越先进。而能够重新保障作战士兵像过去一般安全的反侦测技术的研究也随之变得迫切万分。蕴含了复合材料、工程学、电子学等各领域优点的匿踪技术使大型作战武器可以在敌军的雷达上连一点信号都不留下。B2隐形轰炸机通过独特的造型以及反雷达材料来有效防止被探测到。类似的匿踪技术被运用到像法国的拉法叶级护卫舰等军舰上，使他们在海上随心所欲，毫无顾忌。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SUPERCONDUCTORS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Superconductivity is a property of certain metals and ceramics that allows them to conduct electricity with absolutely no resistance. This superconductive property only emerges at extremely cold temperatures, meaning that their creation demands an in-depth knowledge of low-temp techniques.[PARAGRAPH:1]Since its discovery, the superconductor has found its way into high-power magnets, MRIs (magnetic resonance imagers) and power storage devices that would never have been possible without its unique properties. An interesting side effect of the superconductor is the production of a powerful magnetic field that can produce a levitating effect, called the Meissner Effect, which some hope to translate into the hovering vehicles that were once nothing more than the dreams of science-fiction fans.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]超导是某些金属和陶瓷的一种特性，使它们能够在完全没有电阻的情况下传导电流。因为这种超导特性仅仅在极其低温的环境中出现，这意味着它必须要以人们对低温技术的深刻认识为前提。[PARAGRAPH:1]从人们发现超导现象开始，超导体就被应用在高能磁场中——核磁共振成像系统和能量储存设备如果离开了这种独特的性质是绝对无法实现的。更让人感兴趣的是超导体的间接功劳。得益于超导体的强磁场能够产生一种悬浮效应——迈斯纳效应。这种效应有望能使过去仅出现在科幻小说中的悬浮交通工具成为现实。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LASER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The laser, short for "[BOLD]L[\BOLD]ight [BOLD]A[\BOLD]mplification by [BOLD]S[\BOLD]timulated [BOLD]E[\BOLD]mission of [BOLD]R[\BOLD]adiation," is a focused beam of photons, light energy released by excited atoms. Lasers rely on a phenomenon that occurs when a collection of atoms of certain elements are excited to the same state: they all release the same color of photon. When properly focused through reflective mediums, the result is a high-density beam of photons with innumerable uses, from military targeting to earthquake prevention.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]激光——指“藉由激励放射进行光放大作用所产生的光线”（英文缩写为LASER“镭射”），其实质是汇聚的光子束。这些光子是由处于激发态的原子所释放的高能粒子。当一群同种元素的原子被激发后再跃迁到同一能级时，它们都会放出同种频率的光子，即同种颜色的光——激光的产生就是依据这个原理。这些光子通过反射媒介进行适当的汇聚，就会形成高密度的光子束——激光。它有着从军事瞄准到地震预测的广阔应用前景。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AESTHETICS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Aesthetics is the branch of philosophy that deals with questions of art and beauty. Every culture in the world has its own Aesthetics, the study of art being nearly as old as art itself. Modern Aesthetics delves into all forms of art - theater, poetry, literature, film, etc. - but in its earliest form, aesthetics dealt largely with the visual arts.[PARAGRAPH:1]While clashing senses of Aesthetics have caused many squabbles in their times, one city has been the center of some of the most violent artistic struggles throughout history - Istanbul. During the ninth century, Christian killed Christian in the city then known as Constantinople as the followers of Christ attempted to decide whether religious icons should be considered blasphemous. With the conquest of the city by the Ottomans, previous artistic works deemed offensive were removed or vandalized. Inside the Hagia Sophia, mosaics of Christian religious figures were covered with plaster, that only now, several hundred years later, are finally being revealed.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]美学是哲学的一个分支，解决艺术和美观等方面的问题。世界上的每一种文化都有它们自身的审美学，而审美则往往是伴随着艺术本身而生。现代美学的研究涉及到艺术的各个方面：戏剧、诗歌、文学、电影等等。然而在最初，美学大部分都只涉及形象艺术。[PARAGRAPH:1]在不同的时代，审美学领域中的不同理解的摩擦碰撞往往导致许多的分歧。而有一个城市则是历史上为数几个处在最激烈的艺术纷争旋涡当中的一员——伊斯坦布尔。在九世纪，基督教徒在这个当时称作君士坦丁堡的城市里相互残杀——因为这些基督的追随者们试图由此来决定哪一方亵渎神圣。随着奥斯曼土耳其人攻占了这座城市，他们认为具有亵渎意味的前期艺术作品都被运走甚或是毁坏。在圣索菲亚大教堂内部，和基督教的宗教内容相关的镶嵌图案均被石灰泥所遮盖。更是到了几百年后的今天，这些图案才最终得以显露出来。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MILITARY_SCIENCE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]While truly masterful works on war by men like Sun Tzu and Machiavelli have remained valuable since their creation, the acknowledgement of Military Science as a field of study separate from war itself only began in the seventeenth century. During the next two hundred years, numerous treatises on contemporary warfare surfaced. Two of the most influential military scientists of their times, Carl von Clausewitz and Antoine Henri-Jomini, birthed a rivalry that continues to this day, focused in large part on their major works, Clausewitz's "On War" and Jomini's "The Art of War."[PARAGRAPH:1]In the modern era, Military Science has found a field of fresh minds with the establishment of military academies across the globe. West Point in the United States, Sandhurst in Great Britain and Saint-Cyr in France remain among the most renowned institution of learning in the world. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]尽管孙子和马基雅维里的伟大军事著作由它们诞生开始就一直为后人所追捧；然而直到十七世纪，人们对军事科学的认识才从战争中脱离出来并使之成为一门学问。在接下来的两百年里，许许多多针对同时期战争的著作涌现了出来。其中两个在他们的时代中最具影响力的军事科学家——卡尔·冯·克劳塞维茨和安东尼·亨利·约米尼，开启了一个延续到今天的聚焦在他们主要的著作中的争论——克劳塞维茨的《战争论》和约米尼的《战争艺术》。[PARAGRAPH:1]在现代，全球各地军事学院的创立给军事科学带来了一股新思潮。美国西点陆军军官学校、英国桑赫斯特陆军军官学校和法国圣西尔陆军军官学校在众多的著名军事学院中始终名声显赫。 </Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PRIVATEER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Privateers were government-sanctioned pirate ships prominent from the seventeenth century until the nineteenth century. Pillaging for their lords in the shipping lanes of Europe or in the seas of the New World, Privateers bore no marking of their affiliation, making it impossible to trace their employer short of the "Letter of Marque" commissioning them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Successful Privateers, such as Sir Francis Drake in the employ of Queen Elisabeth I or Barbarossa under Sultan Suleiman I, wreaked havoc among the merchant vessels of rival nations, securing for themselves and their sovereigns significant, if second-hand, wealth. In the cases of both Barbarossa and Drake, the disruptive effect these naval bandits had upon the enemies of their lords helped ensure the naval supremacy of both the Ottoman Empire and England in their respective ages.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]私掠舰就是有政府背景的海盗船，在17至19世纪尤为常见。私掠舰在欧洲和新大陆的海面为各自的国家进行掠夺。私掠舰上没有任何代表其雇主的标记，除非找到授权其活动的“私掠特许证”，没有任何线索可以追查他们的雇主。[PARAGRAPH:1]历史上著名的私掠者包括伊丽莎白一世女王属下的弗朗西斯·德雷克和苏莱曼一世苏丹属下的巴尔巴罗萨，他们都为了雇主的利益对敌国商船进行大肆劫掠，并捎带着为自己获取一些财富。不管是巴尔巴罗萨还是德雷克，这些海上强盗对他们雇主的敌人所造成的破坏性效果，都有助于奥斯曼帝国和英格兰在它们各自的时代确立海上霸权。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_PARATROOPER_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Infantry trained in the subtle art of leaping out of aircraft, Paratroopers have been surprising and encircling their opponents since World War II. While the concept of airborne troops had been suggested as far back as Benjamin Franklin (although his troopers were attached to balloons rather than parachutes), the Second World War became the first proving ground for the skyborne infantry. While the ability of Paratroopers to enter otherwise inaccessible territory gave the troops an invaluable tactical advantage, the use of Paratroopers in conjunction with regular troops provided the added bonus of confusion - dug-in troops were often unable to tell if the Paratroopers were the main opposing force.[PARAGRAPH:1]While massive deployments of Paratroopers are no longer considered tactically sound, new forms of drops, such as the HALO (High Altitude-Low Opening), have developed, allowing small groups of soldiers - usually special forces - to be placed precisely behind enemy lines with almost no radar signature.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[TAB]作为精于机降技巧的步兵部队，伞兵从第二次世界大战开始，就用于奇袭和包围他们的敌人。空降部队的概念早在本杰明·富兰克林（尽管他的部队是绑在气球上，而不是降落伞上的），而第二次世界大战则成为了空降步兵的第一个试验场。虽然伞兵能够进入其他部队难以接近的地区的能力，使得他们拥有无法估量的战术优势，但是伞兵与普通部队之间的协同运用也带来了额外的混乱因素——地面部队很难判断伞兵是否是敌人的部队。[PARAGRAPH:1]虽然大规模的伞兵部署已经完全不被列入战术考虑，但是新的降落方式，比如HALO（“高空降落-低空开伞”的英文缩写）被发展了出来。这使得可以将少数士兵——通常是特种部队——准确地投放在敌人战线的后方却几乎不会造成任何雷达标记。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_BUOY_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>Sea Route</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>海路</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LASER_QUOTE</Tag>
<English>"Nothing travels faster than the speed of light with the possible exception of bad news, which obeys its own special laws." [PARAGRAPH:1]- Douglas Adams</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>没有什么跑得比光速更快，坏消息除外——它们服从特殊定律。[PARAGRAPH:1]——道格拉斯·亚当斯（美国科幻小说家）</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SUPERCONDUCTOR_QUOTE</Tag>
<English>"What is happiness? The feeling that power is growing, that resistance is overcome." [PARAGRAPH:1]- Friedrich Nietzsche</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>什么是快乐？当你感觉力量在增强，阻碍被冲破。[PARAGRAPH:1]——弗雷德里希·尼采</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ADVANCED_FLIGHT_QUOTE</Tag>
<English>"Oh! I have slipped the surly bonds of Earth - [NEWLINE]Put out my hand and touched the Face of God." [PARAGRAPH:1]- John Gillespie Magee, Junior</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>哦！我已摆脱大地的束缚……[NEWLINE]伸手触摸上帝的面容。[PARAGRAPH:1]——小约翰·吉列斯皮·马吉（加拿大空军飞行员）</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEALTH_QUOTE</Tag>
<English>"Behind a veil, unseen yet present, I was the forceful soul that moved this mighty body."[PARAGRAPH:1] - Jean Racine</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>隐身幕后，尚未被察觉，我是这个强大机构的操纵者。[PARAGRAPH:1]——让·拉辛（法国剧作家）</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MILITARY_SCIENCE_QUOTE</Tag>
<English>"I must study politics and war that my sons may have liberty to study mathematics and philosophy." [PARAGRAPH:1]- John Adams</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>我们这代人必须学习政治和军事，我们的后代才有机会学习数学和哲学。[PARAGRAPH:1]——约翰·亚当斯（美国第二任总统）</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AESTHETICS_QUOTE</Tag>
<English>"Art for art's sake is an empty phrase. Art for the sake of truth, art for the sake of the good and the beautiful, that is the faith I am searching for." [PARAGRAPH:1]- George Sand</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>艺术至上只是一句空话。为了真善美的艺术才是我所追寻的信念。[PARAGRAPH:1]——乔治·桑</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APOSTOLIC_PALACE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Apostolic Palace, located in Vatican City, Italy, is the home of the Pope and the heart of the Catholic Church. Having only been occupied by the Pope since the breakup of the Papal State in 1871, the current Apostolic Palace is a relatively new addition to the Church's assets. Sitting adjacent to the iconic St. Peter's Square, the Palace acts as the administrative center for all business of the Catholic Church. Further, it is from here that the Pope issues decrees which affect Catholics throughout the world. And with nearly one in six people on Earth prescribing to Catholicism, this means the Apostolic Palace is the headquarters for one of the most influential organizations on the planet.[PARAGRAPH:1]While the palace's importance as a world administrative center cannot be doubted, the Apostolic Palace also houses one of the most famous art collections on Earth. Contained within the walls of the Apostolic Palace is the Vatican Museum, which displays the works of master artisans Caravaggio, Raphael and Da Vinci. Michelangelo's famous Sistine Chapel is also a part of the Apostolic Palace.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>坐落在意大利梵蒂冈城的教皇宫，是教皇的住所乃至基督教会的中心所在。随着1871年罗马教皇国被吞并，仅仅它为教皇所拥有；而如今的教皇宫名义上是对教会财产的一个新的追加。毗邻标志性的圣彼得广场的教皇宫是管理所有基督教会事业的行政中心。更重要的是，教皇正是在此处发布影响着全世界基督教徒的法令。正因为几乎每六个人中就有一个信奉基督教，这意味着教皇宫成为了全球最有影响力的组织的总部。[PARAGRAPH:1]教皇宫作为一个世界行政中心的重要性是不容质疑的；除此之外，它还是全球最著名的艺术收藏地之一。囊括了教皇宫的墙壁在内的梵蒂冈博物馆展示了卡拉瓦乔、拉斐尔和达芬奇等艺术大师的作品。米开朗基罗创作的著名的西斯廷教堂也是教皇宫的一部分。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_1_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]While most food processing corporations are less than 150 years old, food processing is an ancient tradition. The miller was the original food processing entrepreneur, turning inedible wheat into versatile flour, all while pulling in a tidy profit. Understandably, many modern food processing companies rose from the milling industry, often picking up a few new subsidiaries along the way. Today's food processors deal in a diverse range of consumer products, lining the walls of the local supermarket with everything from mayonnaise to deodorant.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>虽然大多数食品加工公司的历史都不超过150年，食品加工本身还是一项非常古老的行业。磨坊主可以说是最早从事食品加工业的人，他们通过将小麦等谷物研磨成面粉获取稳定丰厚的利润。实际上许多现代食品加工公司也是由这样的小磨坊发展而来的，随着业务的扩大这些公司还会不断拓展新兴的“副业”。今天的食品加工公司经营着从蛋黄酱到除臭剂等种类繁多的商品，将各地超级市场的货架挤得满满当当。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_3_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]As an energy source, few things can compare to fossil fuels. Yet, like most resources, the limited nature of fossil fuels has made an alternative energy source a necessary compliment to the world's power supply. Ethanol, which can be created from corn, beets and sweet potatoes, has become one of the leading candidates to wean consumers from their daily gasoline fix. Used as a fuel additive or a fuel itself, ethanol's renewable nature, as well as the increased availability of ethanol-powered vehicles, has made it the most widely used gasoline alternative in the world. But with an ever-increasing world population the use of fields to produce fuel instead of food has made the full-blown adoption of biofuels a difficult choice for those in positions of power. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>煤、石油、天然气等矿物燃料是无可比拟的优质能源。但矿物燃料和大多数资源一样在自然界的储量有限，因此人们需要努力寻找替代品以保证世界能源供给。可用玉米、甜菜和甘薯作为原料大量生产的乙醇（酒精）就成为填补当前汽油消费缺口的首选替代燃料。乙醇可作为添加剂制成混合燃料，也可作为单一燃料。由于生产原料是可再生的植物资源，各国均鼓励研制乙醇动力汽车，使得乙醇成为全世界最广泛采用的汽油替代品。但是随着世界人口的不断增加，燃料生产和粮食生产对有限耕地的争夺成为日益尖锐的矛盾，在此情况下各国领导人难以作出全面采用生物燃料的决策。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_4_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]The Great Pyramids, the Hagia Sophia and the Hoover Dam all started their famed existences in the same way - with a pile of stones and an ambitious engineer. In the past, grand projects were taken on by princes or heads of state, but today these works are built by corporations. Often employing both an architect and a construction team, modern construction companies both dream up and execute the shaping of a piece of land into a new edifice. Beyond simply erecting the building, it often falls upon the construction company to reign in the wild designs of upstart architects like Frank Lloyd Wright and Antoni Gaudi to ensure the completion of their works. Perhaps if a construction executive had been present during the designing of Gaudi's Sagrada Familia, it would already be complete and accepting donations for renovations.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>大金字塔、圣索菲亚和胡佛大坝等世界级奇观的诞生条件其实是相似的——足够的石料加一位雄心勃勃的工程师。在过去的时代，这样庞大的工程需要由帝王运用国家的力量，但在今天往往是由那些私营公司主持建造的。现代建筑公司雇佣优秀的建筑师和工程队，完成设计到施工的整个过程，将一块块空地变成一座座新的城市地标。建筑公司所做的不仅仅是简单的造房子，还为那些初出茅庐的年轻设计师——日后他们也许会成为象弗兰克·洛伊德·赖特和安东尼·高迪那样的大师——提供资助，将那些看似疯狂的创新设计变为现实。如果当初高迪设计圣家族大教堂时能遇到一位现代建筑公司的执行官，这座建筑可能早就完工并在接受修缮捐助了。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_5_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]For much of human history, victory has gone to those with access to the finest metals. From the Bronze Age onwards, metal tools, weapons and alloys have been an inherent part of the rise of civilization, spurring conquests and construction by the world's greatest empires. And while metal mining has had an impressive history, it was not until the nineteenth century that industrial mining truly began to take root.[PARAGRAPH:1]Two reasons explain this sudden intensification in mining operations. The first was the almost daily revolutions in the production of tools and consumer items, requiring a continual source of metal to produce them. The second was that the fuel that powered the Industrial Revolution was coal, nestled deep within the earth. In modern times, enormous excavators like the Bagger 288 have it possible to mine a pit three-hundred feet long and one-hundred feet deep in a day, a feat that, in the past, would have required the mobilization of nations.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>在人类历史的大部分时期，拥有最好的金属资源就意味着战争的胜利。自青铜时代起，金属工具、武器与合金技术就是一个文明崛起必不可少的条件，推动了历史上许多伟大帝国的创建和扩张进程。虽然金属矿藏的开采具有非常悠久的历史，但是人类直到19世纪才开始进入采矿产业化时代。[PARAGRAPH:1]这一时期矿业公司的迅猛发展有两方面原因。其一是由于生产工具和消费品日新月异的发明和改进要求充足的金属原料保证其生产。其二是由于推动工业革命的煤本身就是深埋于地底的矿藏。在今天象“掘进者288”这样的巨型挖掘机可以在一天之内挖出长三百英尺、深一百英尺的矿井，而在过去这样的工程往往需要倾全国之力。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_6_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Despite being the most abundant metal on Earth, aluminum in its purest form was exceedingly rare until the nineteenth century, with a price-per-pound comparable to that of pure silver. The development of the Hall-Heroult process in 1886, by which pure aluminum is drawn out of common bauxite ore, made aluminum cheap and readily available. Harnessing his invention, Charles Martin Hall created the Pittsburgh Reduction Company, which would grow into the largest provider of aluminum in the world, with its product included in everything from soda cans to spaceships.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>虽然铝是地球上蕴藏量最丰富的金属，但在19世纪之前，纯铝是极其少见的贵重材料，价格比白银还高。1886年出现的霍尔-埃鲁特制铝法能够用常见的铝土矿提炼纯铝，才使铝的价格剧降、产量大增。查尔斯·马丁·霍尔凭借这项发明创办的匹兹堡提炼公司后来成为世界上最大的铝材供应商，其产品从易拉罐到太空飞船等应有尽有。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_7_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Humanity's fascination with shiny objects has persisted since time immemorial. Gold, silver and jewels have decorated the heads of monarchs and the interiors of palaces for millennia, but it was the nineteenth century that began the true blossoming of the trade in treasures. Gold rushes throughout the world - in the United States, Canada and Australia - not only created new fonts of wealth, but left a lasting impression on the shape of world population, relocating avaricious prospectors to some of the most remote places on earth.[PARAGRAPH:1]The gem trade, with diamonds as its crown, grew up around similar circumstances. Throngs of miners flocked to South Africa in the mid-nineteenth century with the discovery of the "Star of Africa," an enormous 83.5 carat diamond. As of the turn of the twentieth century, the age of the traveling prospector bowed before the growth of enormous precious metal and jewel firms. South Africa remains one of the most important sources for gold and diamonds in the world, as well as the birth place to some of the most influential corporations in the business.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>自远古时代起，人类一直对那些闪闪发亮的东西着迷不已。几千年以来，黄金、白银和宝石装饰着无数位帝王的冠冕和无数座宫殿的墙壁，但珠宝行业真正的大发展是从19世纪开始的。在世界上许多地方——例如美国、加拿大和澳大利亚——出现的淘金热不但带来了新的财富之源，还永久地改变了世界人口的分布状况，贪欲吸引着无数人前往原本杳无人迹的遥远土地。[PARAGRAPH:1]以钻石为代表的宝石业也是在类似的历史背景下发展起来的。随着19世纪中叶重达83.5克拉的大钻石“非洲之星”的发现，大批探宝者蜂拥进入南非。到20世纪初，单枪匹马的探宝者时代宣告结束，专门经营贵金属及珠宝的公司控制了整个行业。今天的南非仍然是世界上最重要的黄金和钻石生产国之一，那里诞生了许多在这一行业最具影响力的大公司。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_BOUDICA_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Boudica[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Queen of the Celts[NEWLINE]Lived:[\BOLD] ? - 61AD[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Boudica was a queen of the Iceni, a Celtic people who lived on the eastern coast of Britain. The Roman Emperor Claudius had conquered much of Britain some twenty years ago; according to the treaty with the Iceni, Boudica's husband King Prasutagus would continue to rule his kingdom until his death, at which time it would come under Roman rule. Prasutagus died in approximately 60 AD, and the Romans were quick to seize control of the kingdom. According to the historical sources, the Romans treated their new subjects with unbridled cruelty, and greed. Boudica and her daughters were beaten and raped and sent like beggars from their kingdom.[PARAGRAPH:1]This was a huge mistake. The Romans badly underestimated the Celtic Queen: they would have been far better off killing her outright or treating her with the respect her title deserved.[PARAGRAPH:1]According to Cassius Dio, a Roman historian, Boudica was "very tall, in appearance most terrifying, in the glance of her eye most fierce, and her voice was harsh; a great mass of the tawniest hair fell to her hips; around her neck was a large golden necklace." She was also possessed of a great intelligence and was beloved by her people.[PARAGRAPH:1]After her humiliation Boudica convinced a number of nearby kingdoms to revolt against the rapacious Romans; they quickly raised a large army and made Boudica the commander. [PARAGRAPH:1]At the time, Paulus, the Roman in charge of the island's military forces, was away on business. In his absence Boudica's army wreaked havoc across the island, visiting on their Roman prisoners the same sort of depredations the Romans had recently tormented the Celts with. A number of Roman cities were burned, and the campaign ended with the capture and destruction of the important city of "Londinium" (London).[PARAGRAPH:1]By then the Roman forces had rallied, and though badly outnumbered, had decided to make their stand some miles distant from Boudica. The queen immediately launched an attack against the hated foe. Although she had the great advantage of numbers, her army was no match for the disciplined and highly-trained Roman troops, who blunted the initial Celtic rush with a wave of thrown javelins and then proceeded to kill every Celtic warrior they could catch. Boudica is said to have killed herself rather than risk Roman capture.[PARAGRAPH:1]Although she had led her people for only a year, Boudica's valiant but doomed rebellion would make her a legendary figure in history. Europe would not see another female warrior of her quality for some fourteen centuries, until a young woman named "Joan" would a see vision telling her to rise and fight for the Catholic King of France.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]布狄卡[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]凯尔特女王[NEWLINE]生卒年份:[\BOLD]?-61[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]布狄卡是居住在不列颠东海岸的凯尔特部族艾森夷的王后。大约20年前，罗马皇帝克劳迪厄斯已经征服了大部分不列颠；根据与艾森夷的条约，该国直到布狄卡的丈夫普瑞萨塔古斯国王去世为止由其继续统治，之后它将受到罗马统治。普瑞萨塔古斯在大约公元60年辞世，而罗马人迅速控制了王国。根据历史记载，罗马人用没有约束的残忍和贪婪对待了他们的新领地。布狄卡和她的女儿被殴打和强奸并像乞丐一样从她们的王国被赶走。[PARAGRAPH:1]这是一个巨大的错误。罗马人严重地低估了凯尔特人的王后：更好的方式是彻底杀死她或者给她以应得的尊重。[PARAGRAPH:1]根据罗马历史学家卡西乌斯·迪奥的描述，布狄卡“非常高大，相貌极其狰狞，目光极其凶恶，且嗓音刺耳；一头浓密的深褐色长发垂过腰际；在她的颈部周围是一条硕大的金项链。”（塞爱维小提示：同一个卡西乌斯·迪奥是这样描述克莱奥帕特拉的：“她是一名格外貌美的女子。在年轻时，她是最引人注目的；她的声音富有魅力，深谙如何使别人同意自己的观点。”）她也拥有超凡的智力并被她的人民所爱戴。[PARAGRAPH:1]在受辱之后布狄卡说服许多附近王国反抗贪婪的罗马人；他们迅速组建起一支大军并且推举布狄卡为指挥官。[PARAGRAPH:1]当时掌管岛上罗马军队的保罗斯因故离岛，在此期间布狄卡的军队横扫海岛造成一场浩劫，用与罗马人最近折磨凯尔特人的相同的暴掠加诸他们的罗马战俘，焚毁了一些罗马人的城市，并且最终攻克和摧毁了重要的伦迪尼乌姆城（今伦敦）。[PARAGRAPH:1]那时罗马军队业已集结，虽然对方在数量上占有优势，他们还是决定驻扎在离布狄卡数英里之地。王后立刻对其憎恶的仇敌发起攻击。虽然她拥有巨大的兵力优势，但她的军队不是经受过战争磨练和高度训练的罗马部队的对手，敌人用一轮密集的投枪瓦解了凯尔特人的攻势，然后便放手屠杀他们能抓住的每一名凯尔特战士。据传说布狄卡为避免被罗马人俘获而自尽。[PARAGRAPH:1]虽然她领导她的人民仅仅一年，但是布狄卡的英勇却注定失败的起义使其成为历史上的传奇人物。欧洲大约14个世纪再无可与之相提并论的女战士，直到一位名叫“贞德”的少女看到神灵召唤她挺身而出为法国的天主教国王而战。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BTS_WONDERS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Beyond the Sword Wonders[\H1][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_6]Aluminum Co.[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_APOSTOLIC_PALACE]Apostolic Palace[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_1]Cereal Mills[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_7]Civilized Jewelers[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_4]Creative Construction[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CRISTO_REDENTOR]Cristo Redentor[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_MAUSOLEUM_OF_MAUSSOLLOS]Mausoleum of Maussollos[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_5]Mining Inc.[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_MOAI_STATUES]Moai Statues[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_NATIONAL_PARK]National Park[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_SHWEDAGON_PAYA]Shwedagon Paya[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_2]Sid's Sushi[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_3]Standard Ethanol[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_STATUE_OF_ZEUS]The Status of Zeus[\LINK]</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]刀剑之上新增奇观[\H1][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_6]综合制铝公司[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_APOSTOLIC_PALACE]教皇宫[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_1]谷物研磨公司[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_7]文明珠宝公司[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_4]创新建筑公司[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CRISTO_REDENTOR]耶稣巨像[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_MAUSOLEUM_OF_MAUSSOLLOS]摩索拉斯陵墓[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_5]联合矿业公司[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_MOAI_STATUES]摩艾石像群[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_NATIONAL_PARK]国家公园[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_SHWEDAGON_PAYA]瑞光大金塔[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_2]席德寿司公司[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CORPORATION_3]标准乙醇公司[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_STATUE_OF_ZEUS]宙斯神像[\LINK]</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BTS_BUILDINGS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Beyond the Sword Buildings[\H1][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_MAYA_BALL_COURT]Mayan Ball Court[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_KHMER_BARAY]Khmer Baray[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CUSTOM_HOUSE]Customs House[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_NETHERLANDS_DIKE]Dutch Dike[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_PORTUGAL_FEITORIA]Portuguese Feitoria[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_BABYLON_GARDEN]Babylonian Garden[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_BYZANTINE_HIPPODROME]Byzantine Hippodrome[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_INDUSTRIAL_PARK]Industrial Park[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_INTELLIGENCE_AGENCY]Intelligence Agency[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_LEVEE]Levee[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_PUBLIC_TRANSPORTATION]Public Transportation[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_HOLY_ROMAN_RATHAUS]Holy Roman Rathaus[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_NATIONAL_SECURITY]Security Bureau[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_ETHIOPIAN_STELE]Ethiopian Stele[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_NATIVE_AMERICA_TOTEM]Native American Totem Pole[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_SUMERIAN_ZIGGURAT]Sumerian Ziggurat[\LINK]</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]刀剑之上新增建筑[\H1][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_MAYA_BALL_COURT]玛雅人祭球场[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_KHMER_BARAY]高棉人工湖[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_CUSTOM_HOUSE]海关[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_NETHERLANDS_DIKE]荷兰海堤[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_PORTUGAL_FEITORIA]葡萄牙商站[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_BABYLON_GARDEN]巴比伦花园[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_BYZANTINE_HIPPODROME]拜占庭赛马场[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_INDUSTRIAL_PARK]工业园区[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_INTELLIGENCE_AGENCY]情报局[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_LEVEE]防洪堤[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_PUBLIC_TRANSPORTATION]公交系统[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_HOLY_ROMAN_RATHAUS]神圣罗马议会厅[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_NATIONAL_SECURITY]安全局[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_ETHIOPIAN_STELE]埃塞俄比亚纪念石柱[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_NATIVE_AMERICA_TOTEM]北美土著图腾柱[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=BUILDING_SUMERIAN_ZIGGURAT]苏美尔神塔[\LINK]</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_BTS_UNITS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Beyond the Sword Units[\H1][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_AIRSHIP]Airship[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_AT_INFANTRY]Anti-Tank Infantry[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_6]Aluminum Co. Executive[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_ATTACK_SUBMARINE]Attack Submarine[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_KHMER_BALLISTA_ELEPHANT]Khmer Ballista Elephant[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_BABYLON_BOWMAN]Babylonian Bowman[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_PORTUGAL_CARRACK]Portuguese Carrack[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_BYZANTINE_CATAPHRACT]Byzantine Cataphract[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_1]Cereal Mills Executive[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_7]Civilized Jewelers Executive[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_4]Creative Construction Executive[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_CUIRASSIER]Cuirassier[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_NATIVE_AMERICA_DOG_SOLDIER]Native American Dog Soldier[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_NETHERLANDS_OOSTINDIEVAARDER]Dutch East Indiaman[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_GREAT_SPY]Great Spy[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_GUIDED_MISSILE]Guided Missile[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_MAYA_HOLKAN]Mayan Holkan[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_HOLY_ROMAN_LANDSKNECHT]Holy Roman Landsknecht[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_5]Mining Inc. Executive[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_MISSILE_CRUISER]Missile Cruiser[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_MOBILE_ARTILLERY]Mobile Artillery[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_MOBILE_SAM]Mobile SAM[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_ETHIOPIAN_OROMO_WARRIOR]Ethiopian Oromo Warrior[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_PARATROOPER]Paratrooper[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_PRIVATEER]Privateer[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_SHIP_OF_THE_LINE]Ship of the Line[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_2]Sid's Sushi Executive[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_3]Standard Ethanol Executive[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_STEALTH_DESTROYER]Stealth Destroyer[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TACTICAL_NUKE]Tactical Nuke[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_SUMERIAN_VULTURE]Sumerian Vulture[\LINK][NEWLINE]</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]刀剑之上新增单位[\H1][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_AIRSHIP]飞艇[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_AT_INFANTRY]反坦克步兵[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_6]综合制铝公司经理[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_ATTACK_SUBMARINE]攻击型潜艇[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_KHMER_BALLISTA_ELEPHANT]高棉重弩战象[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_BABYLON_BOWMAN]巴比伦弓手[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_PORTUGAL_CARRACK]葡萄牙卡拉克帆船[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_BYZANTINE_CATAPHRACT]拜占庭重甲骑兵[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_1]谷物研磨公司经理[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_7]文明珠宝公司经理[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_4]创新建筑公司经理[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_CUIRASSIER]胸甲骑兵[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_NATIVE_AMERICA_DOG_SOLDIER]北美土著猎犬战士[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_NETHERLANDS_OOSTINDIEVAARDER]荷兰东印度商船[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_GREAT_SPY]大间谍[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_GUIDED_MISSILE]巡航导弹[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_MAYA_HOLKAN]玛雅霍坎武士[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_HOLY_ROMAN_LANDSKNECHT]神圣罗马自由佣兵[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_5]联合矿业公司经理[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_MISSILE_CRUISER]导弹巡洋舰[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_MOBILE_ARTILLERY]自行火炮[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_MOBILE_SAM]防空导弹车[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_ETHIOPIAN_OROMO_WARRIOR]埃塞俄比亚奥罗莫战士[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_PARATROOPER]伞兵[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_PRIVATEER]私掠舰[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_SHIP_OF_THE_LINE]主力战舰[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_2]席德寿司公司经理[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_EXECUTIVE_3]标准乙醇公司经理[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_STEALTH_DESTROYER]隐形驱逐舰[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_TACTICAL_NUKE]战术核弹[\LINK][NEWLINE][NEWLINE][LINK=UNIT_SUMERIAN_VULTURE]苏美尔兀鹫战士[\LINK][NEWLINE]</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_BORDERS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Borders[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The land that your civilization controls - that is, the land within its "borders" - is determined by the number and cultural strength of your cities. When you first construct a city, its borders usually extend to the squares directly adjacent to it; as the city's [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]cultural value[\LINK] grows, its borders extend to squares farther away, eventually merging with the borders of your other nearby cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Seeing Borders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Squares within each civilization's borders are lightly tinted different colors. [LINK=CONCEPT_BARBARIANS]Barbarian-controlled[\LINK] squares are tinted black. If unsure of a square's status, put your mouse on that square and look at the "pop-up help."[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Borders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Borders have a number of important effects. Your cities can draw sustenance only from spaces within your borders, and your workers can only [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]"improve"[\LINK] such squares as well (except for roads and railroads, which they can build anywhere). Your units heal faster within your own borders, more slowly in neutral (unclaimed) territory, and even slower when in foreign borders. Further, other civilizations' units (with a few exceptions) cannot enter your territory without declaring war, nor can you enter theirs. Barbarians can enter your territory, but animals cannot.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Clash of Borders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When you have a city near another civilization's city, the two will compete for [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]cultural control[\LINK] over the squares between them. Generally, if the square is equidistant from both cities, the city with the highest culture will have control over it. It is important to keep in mind that the earlier a city begins producing culture, the more difficult it will be for a rival city to dislodge the tiles it controls. Cities are not guaranteed to control a certain number of tiles; if one city's culture greatly exceeds the other's, its control may extend to squares closer to the other city and possibly to the squares directly adjacent to it. Since a city can draw sustenance only from squares within its cultural borders, this may greatly limit the city's growth and possibly lead to [LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]starvation[\LINK] or even to the city switching sides and changing its allegiance to the encroaching civilization. See [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]culture[\LINK] for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Capturing Enemy Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When you capture an enemy city, that city must begin producing culture to expand its borders from square one, and this can only take place after [LINK=CONCEPT_RESISTANCE]"resistance"[\LINK] has ended in that city. It is not unusual for newly captured cities to have control of very few tiles until the conqueror begins producing culture in them.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Open Borders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]By entering into an Open Borders Agreement through the [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomacy[\LINK] screen, your units can move freely through your partner's territory, and vice versa. If you declare war against a civilization you have an open borders agreement with, all of your units are removed from his territory, and all of his units are removed from yours.[PARAGRAPH:2]Furthermore, your cities' trade routes extend to include those civs with whom you have Open Borders. Since foreign trade routes are much more lucrative than domestic ones, signing Open Borders can significantly increase the commerce of your cities. Various [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Buildings[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] can increase this income even more.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]国界[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]你的文明所控制的领地——“国界”范围内的区域——它取决于你的城市的数量和文化强度。当你新建一座城市，它的边界通常立即扩展到四周相邻的格子；随着城市[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化等级[\LINK]的增长，其边界将向外扩展，最后和邻近的城市相融合。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]国界视野[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]每个文明的国界范围将显示较亮的特定颜色。[LINK=CONCEPT_BARBARIANS]蛮族控制的[\LINK]区域则颜色较暗。如果一块土地的归属尚不确定，将鼠标放在该区域将“弹出帮助信息”。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]国界作用[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]国界有一些重要的作用。你的城市只能从你国界范围内的区域获得资源，你的工人也只能[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]“改造”[\LINK]本国区域（除了道路和铁路，可以在任何地方修建）.在国界单位恢复得更快，在中立（未被占据）区域较慢，在别国边界内则更慢。此外，其他文明的单位（有少数例外）非经宣战不能进入你的领土，你也不能进入他们的领土。蛮族可以进入你的领土，但是动物不能。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]国界争议[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当你有一个城市和其它文明的城市相邻时，两座城市之间会进行[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化控制权[\LINK]的争夺。通常，如果某个区域和两座城市的距离相等，文化等级较高的城市会控制它。记住在早期，城市的文化积累是十分重要的，将文化值高的对手从某个区域中驱逐出去会更加困难。城市不能保证确定数量的区域；如果一个城市的文化大大超过其它的城市，它的范围可能会扩大到其它城市的近旁。由于城市只能在它控制范围之内取得产出，所以这可能极大地限制城市的成长，导致[LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]饥荒[\LINK]甚至可能叛离，投靠邻近的文明。请查看[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化[\LINK]词条了解详情。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]夺取敌方城市[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当你夺取了一座敌方城市，那个城市必须从头开始进行文化积累以扩张边界，而且此过程只能在该城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_RESISTANCE]“抵抗”[\LINK]停止之后开始。通常在征服者开始积累文化前，一个刚被占领的城市只控制很小的区域。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]开放边界[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]通过[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交[\LINK]对话达成开放边界协定，你的单位将可在对方领土自由通行，对方亦然。如向签有开放边界协定的文明宣战，你在对方领土的单位将自动撤出，对方亦然。[PARAGRAPH:2]此外，你的城市商路将可通向签有开放边界协定的文明。由于国际商路的收益大于国内商路，因此签订开放边界协定可以大大增加城市的财富。某些[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]和[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]还能进一步增加国际商路的收益。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_MALI_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]Once one of the great centres of Islamic culture and wealth, Mali (which is among the continent's most ancient states outside of North Africa) owes much of its reputation to its situation as a major trading center and to the tax that is levied on its trans-Saharan route. The Mali Empire was located on the Mandinka plateau in West Africa, located in the southern part of the modern Republic of Mali. It was founded by Sundiata Keita, a Mandinka who led a revolt against the Soso Kingdom which had dominated the area. Sundiata's life is commemorated in the Epic of Sundiata, a poem of the Mandinka people. It is said that after his victory over the Soso, Sundiata Keita converted to Islam as a gesture of goodwill to the Islamic traders who brought his country wealth. After defeating the Soso, Sundiata pursued an expansionist policy, and soon the Empire covered not only modern Mali, but also extended west to the ocean across what is now Senegal. During war, the Mali often fought as "skirmishers" - soldiers who fanned out in loose formation to protect the main force's flanks or front. The Mali skirmishers were lightly-armed archers in that force, famed for their courage and their marksmanship. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Mali Empire reached its zenith under the rule of Mansa Musa (1312-1337) in the early 14th century. Previously, it had been part of the empire of Ghana, which flourished between the seventh and 11th centuries based on the trade of gold from the interior for salt from the coastal regions. Mansa Musa made a famous pilgrimage to Mecca in 1324 laden with gold and slaves to proclaim Mali's prosperity and power. It is said that he lavished so much wealth along his route that the price of gold was depressed for years afterwards. During Mansa Musa's rule Muslim scholarship reached new heights in Mali, and such cities as Timbuktu and Djenné (Jenne) became important centers of trade, learning, and culture.[PARAGRAPH:2]After the decline of the Mali Empire, the territory became part of the Songhai Empire, which occupied an area covering parts of modern-day Guinea, Burkina Faso, Senegal, Mali, Mauritania, Niger, and Nigeria. Songhai was brought to an end and its territory usurped by the Moroccan invasion of 1591. With the decline of the trans-Saharan trading routes in favor of naval commerce, the area enjoyed little strategic importance and was divided into small kingdoms for the next two centuries until the arrival of French colonists. Mali was absorbed into French West Africa in 1895. In 1960, together with what is now Senegal, it achieved independence as the Federation of Mali, although Senegal seceded after a few weeks. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>作为古代最重要的伊斯兰文化与财富中心之一，马里是北部非洲以南的广阔内陆中历史最悠久的国家，她因拥有作为主要贸易中心的优越地理位置，垄断了对穿越萨哈拉沙漠商路的征税权。马里帝国的中心位于西部非洲的曼丁卡高原（今马里共和国南部）。帝国的创立者是孙迪亚塔·科伊塔，他领导曼丁卡人反抗苏索王国对当地的统治。孙迪亚塔的生平事迹被曼丁卡人编成了一部长篇史诗“孙迪亚塔传”。传说孙迪亚塔在战胜苏索之后，为向给他的国家带来财富的穆斯林商人表达善意而皈依了伊斯兰教。击败了苏索的孙迪亚塔继续执行扩张政策，不久其帝国的控制范围不仅包括今马里全境，还一直向西延伸到大西洋沿岸（今塞内加尔）。在这一系列战争中，马里人通常担任“突击手”——采用疏散阵形，负责保护主力部队的侧翼或前沿的战士。马里突击手是使用投射武器的轻装步兵，以其过人的勇气和精准的投射而闻名于世。[PARAGRAPH:2]马里帝国在14世纪初曼沙·穆萨统治时期（1312-1337）达到力量的巅峰。马里继承了兴盛于7至11世纪的加纳帝国的大部分领土及其内陆的黄金和沿海的食盐产业。曼沙·穆萨甚至还在1324年率领满载黄金和奴隶的队伍前往麦加进行了一次著名的朝圣之旅，以显示马里的富庶和力量。据说他在沿途的大肆挥霍甚至导致此后持续多年的黄金贬值。在曼沙·穆萨统治期间，穆斯林文化在马里达到达了一个新的高度，廷巴克图、德杰恩和杰内等城市也成为重要的贸易、学术和文化中心。[PARAGRAPH:2]马里帝国衰亡后，其领地成为桑海帝国的一部分。桑海帝国的范围包括今几内亚、布基纳法索、塞内加尔、马里、毛里塔尼亚、尼日尔和尼日利亚的部分地区。1591年摩洛哥人的入侵宣告了桑海帝国的终结。随着海上商路的兴起，穿越萨哈拉沙漠的商路逐渐衰败，此后的两个世纪里这一地区的战略重要性不断下降，并分裂成为许多小王国。法国殖民者来到此地后，马里于1895年并入了法属西非。1960年，包括今塞内加尔的马里联邦获得独立，但仅仅几周之后塞内加尔即宣告分离。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_WONDERS_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Wonders[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Wonders are the spectacular buildings, inventions, and concepts that have stood the test of time and changed the world forever. The Pyramids, Notre Dame Cathedral, the Statue of Liberty and Hollywood are all examples of wonders. Wonders require much time and energy from your cities, but once completed, they provide your civilization with many benefits.[PARAGRAPH:2]There are two basic types of wonders: great wonders and national wonders.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Great Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] Great wonders are unique; only one of each can be constructed during a game. For example, the Great Lighthouse is a great wonder; whoever completes it first is the only one who may possess its benefits. Great Wonders tend to be quite powerful indeed, but also extremely time-consuming to build.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]National Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] National wonders may be built once by each civilization in the game. That is, each civilization can have the Wall Street national wonder (though no civilization can have two of them). Each city may only build two national wonders, so be sure to plan ahead where you wish to put them. [PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Constructing Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] Wonders are constructed in cities, like any other [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Building[\LINK]. If you can build a wonder, it will appear in your city build menu; just click on the wonder to get started. Note that only one city in your civilization can be building a single wonder at a time.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Losing the Construction Race:[\BOLD] If another civilization completes a great wonder while you are in the process of building it, your construction ceases, and a certain amount of your production efforts are converted into gold. This does not occur with national wonders, since each civilization can build its own copy of those.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Wonders and Resources:[\BOLD] Certain resources will allow cities to produce wonders of both types at double the usual speed. For example, a civilization that has Stone connected to its [LINK=CONCEPT_CITY_NETWORK]City Network[\LINK] can build the Pyramids at a much faster rate.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Civilization Traits:[\BOLD] [LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]Leaders[\LINK] who possess the Industrious trait build all wonders at twice the usual rate.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Wonders have a broad range of effects. Some increase productivity; others increase income from trade. Some improve research, others make your workers build improvements faster. All wonders improve their home city's [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Cultural Output[\LINK] as well as the speed at which the city generates [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great People[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Capturing Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If you capture a city with a great wonder, you gain possession of that wonder. If you capture a city with a national wonder, the national wonder is destroyed. If a city is destroyed, all wonders in that city are destroyed along with it. Great wonders can never be rebuilt once they are destroyed.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Wonder Obsolescence[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Some wonders can become obsolete over time. This obsolescence is caused by any civilization in the game learning a specific technology. When that occurs, the wonder's special effects vanish, but it still continues to produce culture. For example, the Great Lighthouse wonder provides a trade benefit to all coastal cities, as well as +8 culture to the city where it is constructed. The Lighthouse is rendered obsolete once the owner gains the [LINK=TECH_CORPORATION]Corporation[\LINK] technology, at which point he loses the Lighthouse trade bonus but retains its +8 cultural output.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]奇观[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]奇观指那些历经时间考验，深刻影响世界历史的伟大建筑，发明创造或思想观念等。例如大金字塔，圣母院，自由女神像和好莱坞等等。建设奇观需要城市付出大量时间和精力，但如果能够完成，将为你的文明带来许多利益。[PARAGRAPH:2]奇观分为两类：世界奇观（大奇观）和国家奇观（小奇观）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]世界奇观[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]大奇观是独一无二的；整个游戏中只能建造一个。例如，大灯塔即属于大奇观；最先完成大奇观的文明将独享其利益。大奇观的作用非常大，但其建造也需要付出非常多的时间。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]国家奇观[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]国家奇观每个文明均可在游戏中建造一个。例如，每个文明都可以拥有自己的华尔街（但不能拥有两个）。每个城市只能建造两座国家奇观，因此需要事先做好规划。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]建造奇观[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]奇观在城市中建造，和其他[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]一样。如果你可能建造某座奇观，它将出现在城市的建造菜单中；只需点击该奇观即开始建造。注意你的文明在同一时间只能有一座城市建造某一特定奇观。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]在建造竞争中失败:[\BOLD]如果其他文明先于你完成一座大奇观，你的建造进程将中断，已经积累的产能将转换为一定数量的金钱。但国家级奇观则不存在此种文明间竞争的问题。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]奇观和资源:[\BOLD]某些资源可使奇观建造速度加倍。例如，一个文明的[LINK=CONCEPT_CITY_NETWORK]城市网络[\LINK]中如果有花岗石，则可以更快速地建造大金字塔。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]文明特质:[\BOLD][LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]文明领袖[\LINK]如果拥有勤奋刻苦的特质，则奇观建造速度加倍。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]奇观的作用[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]奇观拥有各种不同的作用。有些增加生产力；有些增加贸易收入。有些提升科研能力，还有的能使你的工人更有效率。所有奇观均能增加所在城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化产出[\LINK]以及城市产生[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]的几率。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]夺取奇观[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你夺取了拥有大奇观的城市，也就拥有了该座大奇观。如果你夺取了拥有国家奇观的城市，该国家奇观会被摧毁。如果城市被摧毁，其中所有的奇观也会随之毁灭。大奇观被摧毁后无法再次重建。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]奇观的过时[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]有些奇观会随时间的流逝而失去作用。任何发明特定科技将使某些奇观过时。在这种情况下，奇观的特殊作用将消失，但是仍能继续积累文化值。例如，大灯塔能为所有海滨城市带来商业收入，并使所在城市文化产出+8。大灯塔的将在任何文明获得[LINK=TECH_CORPORATION]公司制[\LINK]科技之后过时，该奇观将不再带来商业收入，但城市每回合文化产出则继续+8。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_TAOISM_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[TAB]When discussing "Taoism," one must be careful to distinguish between the philosophy of Tao and the religion of Tao. The philosophy of Tao came first. According to tradition, the philosopher Lao-Tsu lived in the 4th Century BC. He wrote the "Tao Te Ching," which can be roughly translated as "The Book of the Way and its Virtue." [PARAGRAPH:2]The Tao Te Ching is written in verse. It is extremely subtle and difficult to understand. Many scholars have spent years trying to interpret it. The book can be (very primitively and probably inaccurately) summarized as follows: the "Tao" is what exists before everything else. It is formless, and from it all things are formed. Man must aspire to simplicity; only by discarding the useless trappings of culture and civilization can man return to his original state of emptiness - Tao - when all is possible. According to Lao-Tsu, "the sage has no heart of his own" - no intentions, no preconceptions, and no agenda. [PARAGRAPH:2]The religion of Taoism is based upon worship of Lao-Tsu as a deity. According to Taoist religious tradition, in 142 AD Lao-Tsu appeared to Zhang Daoling, a hermit, and told him that the world was coming to an end, and those who followed Lao-Tsu would go on to another, better life. Further, Lao-Tsu's followers would have access to the celestial powers that control the fate of mankind. Zhang preached Lao-Tsu's words and gained many converts.[PARAGRAPH:2]Over time, Taoism split into a number of schools. Some believed that they could change the world through talismans, alchemy, and magical spells. Some sought to achieve immortality through a Buddhist-like enlightenment. A variety of gods from Chinese folklore and Buddhist tradition were incorporated into the religion.[PARAGRAPH:2]Taoism spread widely throughout China, and it was the official state religion for a thousand years, until the end of the Qing Dynasty in 1911. The Communists virtually eradicated the religion in China during the Cultural Revolution (1960-76), when many of the temples were destroyed and the monks and priests sent to "reeducation" camps. In the 1980s China restored some religious tolerance, and Taoist temples are slowly being rebuilt and repaired. [PARAGRAPH:2]It is believed that many Chinese still practice Taoism in some form, despite the government's restrictions. Taoism is also practiced by some 31 million people outside of China, the largest group being in Taiwan. Its influence can be felt world-wide in the practices of acupuncture, herbalism, feng shui, and martial arts. </English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>在讨论“道”这一名词的时候，必须小心区分作为哲学流派的道家和作为宗教信仰的道教。首先出现的是道家哲学。据记载，哲学家老子生活的年代是公元前四世纪。他的著作就是“道德经”——这一书名的含义大致可以理解为“关于道及其美德的阐述”。[PARAGRAPH:2]道德经是以韵文的形式写成的。用词极其玄妙，非常难懂。无数学者花费了无数的时间尝试解释其中所包含的意义。这部著作的含义可以（极其粗浅和简略地）解释如下：“道”先于天地而生。道无形无象，但创生了宇宙万物。人应当追求无为；只有弃绝所谓的仁义礼智，人类才能回归原本自然，无知无欲的状态，像“道”对待万物那样的无为而治。根据老子的观点，“圣人处无为之事，行不言之教”——不强加意图，不强作判断，不强行干涉。[PARAGRAPH:2]作为一种宗教信仰的道教则将老子奉为神明。根据道教传说，在公元142年，老子降临在一位隐士张道陵的面前，告诉他世界即将面临末日，只有信奉老子的人才能脱离尘世，得道成仙，拥有呼风唤雨，掌控命运的能力。张道陵于是开始宣扬老子的教导，并获得了大批追随者。[PARAGRAPH:2]随着时间的推移，教道中分出了诸多流派。有的流派相信能通过神符，丹药或是咒语控制万物。有的流派则试图通过类似佛教信徒的修行方式求得永生。大量来自中国神话和佛教传说的神灵也逐渐被引入道教的信仰体系。[PARAGRAPH:2]道教在中国各地均相当普及，并被作为官方信仰达上千年之久，直到1911年清朝的灭亡。在文化大革命期间（1966-1976），中国共产党政权实际上完全禁绝了任何宗教信仰，许多道教观宇被拆毁，大批道士被送往“劳改营”。到20世纪80年代，中国政府基本恢复了信仰宽容政策，各地的道观才得以重建和修缮。[PARAGRAPH:2]据认为，虽然政府采取了各种限制措施，但目前在中国仍有许多人信奉着各种流派的道教。道教信徒在中国大陆之外约有3100万人，主要分布于台湾地区。来自于道教的针灸、风水和武术文化已经传遍了整个世界。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_PORTUGAL_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]The[\BOLD] naval empire, Portugal shines when placed near the sea. The Feitoria building, the Portuguese replacement for the Customs House, must border water to be built but the sheer amount of commerce it creates will make any restriction worth the while of its builder. And with the combined strength of Joao's "Expansive" and "Imperialistic" traits, allowing a healthy empire to be developed at breakneck speeds, and the Portuguese Carrack, a Caravel replacement that allows the Portuguese to begin exploring the seas far before any other, no other civilization in the game can compare to the sheer colony constructing power of the Portuguese.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The area which encompasses modern Portugal was originally settled by Celtic tribes around 1000 BC and was then subsequently conquered by the Visigoths and finally the Moors. The Christian Kings of Asturia eventually drove the Moors out of the area; the new nation of Portugal was formed after its separation from Spanish rule.[PARAGRAPH:1]Portugal was one of the first great internationally-based sea empires in the European world. Between 1415 and 1665, Portugal created a series of resting and refueling ports along the eastern and western coasts of Africa in a bid to eventually reach the profitable shores of India. In 1498 they achieved their goals when Vasco da Gama reached Kozhikode (known then as Calicut). Several important battles took place between the Arabs (who had previously monopolized spice trade in the Indian Ocean) and the Portuguese during this era, the most important of them being the victory over the Egyptian-Gujarati fleet off of Diu in 1509. This victory assured the Portuguese maritime superiority in the Indian Ocean and enabled them to capitalize on the rich spice trade routes between India and Europe. However, in 1578 King Sebastian of Portugal was killed at the battle of "Field of the Three Kings" in Morocco (which Portugal had long hoped to conquer), along with the majority of his force, destroying a central part of Portugal's land armies.[PARAGRAPH:1] In 1580 the throne of Portugal was given over to the Habsburg kings of Spain, partially a result of the Portuguese weakness after the demise of its own king. At the same time, Portuguese power in both the east and west was declining due to a lack of skilled sailors available in Portugal. The English and the Dutch had also been amassing large navies, and began expanding their spheres of influence along routes traditionally held solely by the Portuguese. Although the Portuguese wrested national control back from the Spanish in a 1640 revolt, they lost their control in Malacca, Ceylon, Cochin, Hormuz, among many others to the Dutch or other seafaring nations. With their eastern territories diminishing, Brazil, discovered by Pedro Alvares Cabral in 1500, became increasingly important.[PARAGRAPH:1]Gold was discovered in Brazil in 1690, which had previously been exploited mostly for its dyewood, sugar, diamonds, tobacco and slaves. The ensuing gold rush boosted the population of Brazil from 200,000 in 1650 to 1.5 million in 1770. Brazil today remains the largest Portuguese-speaking country in the world.[PARAGRAPH:1]In 1808, French troops under Napoleon Bonaparte invaded Portugal, forcing the prince regent, Dom João, to flee to Brazil and set up a new government. In 1821, the royal family moved back to Portugal after reclaiming the country. Dom João stayed behind, and then his son, Dom Pedro I, ruled Brazil until the country broke away from its mother country, declaring independence in 1822. [PARAGRAPH:1]After losing Brazil, Portugal focused on building its African acquisitions in order to compete with their British and French counterparts. However, after World War II, the majority of European nations began abandoning their outlying colonies. India forcibly retook the Portuguese colonies still in their territory. In 1974, a democratic government was established in Portugal. This new government negotiated the release of its African holdings, which were promptly devastated by civil war and vicious in-fighting generated by the Cold War.[PARAGRAPH:1]Today Portugal is ruled from its capital in Lisbon as a democratic republic under the constitution of 1976. It remains an important participant in the European Union as well as one of the major environmental reformers of Europe.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[BOLD]策略提示:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]作为一个海洋文明，葡萄牙人要是定居在海边将会如鱼得水。葡萄牙替代海关的特色建筑——商站必须建造于海滨城市，但其所能提供的巨额商业收入使这一限制所带来的不便几乎可以忽略不计。文明领袖若奥“开拓”加“霸权”的特质组合使他的帝国能以可怕的速度发展，同时保持平稳有序。而葡萄牙替代轻帆船的特色单位——卡拉克帆船使其能率先开展远洋探险，在游戏中没有其他文明能在建立海外殖民地的能力方面同葡萄牙相比。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]最早在现今葡萄牙所处地区定居的是凯尔特部族（约公元前1000年），后被西哥特人征服，接着又被摩尔人占据。阿斯图里亚斯的基督教国王最终逐走了摩尔人，在脱离西班牙人的统治之后，新的葡萄牙王国宣告成立。[PARAGRAPH:1]葡萄牙是欧洲历史上最早的世界级海上帝国之一。1415至1665年间，葡萄牙人在非洲东西海岸建立了一系列驻泊与补给港口，以期到达富庶的印度海滨。这一目标随着1498年瓦斯科·达·迦马船队抵达科泽科德（后改名为卡利卡特）而终获实现。在此期间，葡萄牙人同原本垄断印度洋香料贸易的阿拉伯人之间发生了数场重要战事，其中最关键的是击败埃及-古吉拉特舰队的第乌海战（1509年）。这场胜利确保了葡萄牙人对印度洋的控制权，使他们通过印度与欧洲的香料贸易积累起雄厚的资本。但到1578年，葡萄牙国王塞巴斯蒂昂在“三王之战”中阵亡于摩洛哥（葡萄牙一直试图征服该地区），所率部队几乎被全歼，这使葡萄牙陆军的主力遭到重创。[PARAGRAPH:1]1580年，葡萄牙统治权落入西班牙哈布斯堡王室之手，导致此结果的原因之一就是先王去世后葡萄牙的衰落。于此同时，葡萄牙在海外的影响力也由于本国熟练海员的缺乏而日益降低。英国人与荷兰人都集结起强大的舰队，不断蚕食原本由葡萄牙人独占的贸易航线。虽然葡萄牙人在1640年发动起义脱离西班牙的统治重获独立，但马六甲、锡兰、柯钦、霍尔木兹等海外领地均已被荷兰或其他海上强国夺走。在东方的领地日渐压缩的情况下，由佩德罗·阿尔瓦雷斯·卡布拉尔于1500年发现的巴西成为葡萄牙最重要的海外殖民地。[PARAGRAPH:1]1690年，巴西的金矿被发现，此前这里产出的贸易品主要是染料、食糖、钻石、烟草和奴隶。随之而来的淘金热使巴西的人口暴涨，从1650年时的20万迅速增加到1770年时的150万。巴西至今仍是世界上最大的葡萄牙语国家。[PARAGRAPH:1]1808年，拿破仑·波拿巴下令法军入侵葡萄牙，迫使摄政王唐·若昂逃往巴西建立流亡政府。1821年，王室在恢复统治权后迁回了葡萄牙。但唐·若昂并未回国，后来他的儿子佩德罗一世继续统治巴西，直到1822年这个国家脱离母国宣布独立。[PARAGRAPH:1]失去巴西之后，葡萄牙转而致力于经营其在非洲的领地，继续同英国、法国展开竞争。但到二战结束后，多数欧洲国家开始放弃其海外殖民地。葡萄牙在印度的仅存的据点也被对方强行收回。1974年，葡萄牙建立了民主制政府，新政府通过谈判放弃了在非洲的所有领地，实际上这些殖民地早已被冷战所引发的内战和冲突折磨得千疮百孔了。[PARAGRAPH:1]今天的葡萄牙是以里斯本为政治中心、以制定于1976年的宪法为立国之本的民主共和制国家。葡萄牙还是欧盟的重要成员国及欧洲环保主义改革的先行者之一。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_APOSTOLIC_PALACE_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Apostolic Palace and United Nations[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=BUILDING_APOSTOLIC_PALACE]Apostolic Palace[\LINK] is a new Medieval Wonder with abilities similar to the [LINK=BUILDING_UNITED_NATIONS]United Nations[\LINK]. To found the Apostolic Palace, the Player must have researched the [LINK=TECH_THEOLOGY]Theology[\LINK] Technology and must have a State Religion. When the Apostolic Palace is completed, it will be locked into the religion of the player who has built it. A vote to decide who will be the Resident of the Apostolic Palace will then take place, with the owner of the Palace as one candidate and the player with the largest combined population of cities containing the Palace's religion as the other. The Resident of the Apostolic Palace decides which resolutions will be voted on.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Apostolic Palace Membership and Benefits[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]There are two different types of members of the Apostolic Palace - "Full Members" and "Voting Members." Voting members own one or more cities containing the Palace's religion but do not accept it as their state religion. Full members own cities containing the Palace's religion and accept the Palace's religion as their state religion. Players owning no cities with the Palace's religion are referred to as "Non-members." All members receive a production bonus for every Temple, Cathedral, Monastery, and Shrine they own of the Palace's religion.[PARAGRAPH:1]Full members receive a number of benefits. Only full members or the current owner of the Apostolic Palace may be elected as Resident of the Apostolic Palace and can win a Diplomatic Victory through the Palace. Full members also get twice as many votes as they would if they were just voting members.[PARAGRAPH:1]Full members can be demoted to voting members by defying a Resolution (see below). They may restore their full member status by voting for a Resolution that passes.[PARAGRAPH:1]Players may view their Membership status on the Victory Screen [F8].[PARAGRAPH:1]A variation of these membership rules have also been adopted for the United Nations Wonder. See below for more information.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Resolutions[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The Resident of the Apostolic Palace selects the Resolutions for the Palace Members to vote on. The Resolutions are:[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]Declare War:[\BOLD] Vote to have all members declare war on a voting member, or to declare war on a non-member already at war with any full member. Full members cannot be declared war on in this manner[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]Trade Embargo:[\BOLD] Vote to cancel all trade between a Palace voting or non-member and all other Palace members[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]Force Peace:[\BOLD] End a war between a full member and any other member[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]Sign a Defensive Pact:[\BOLD] Sign a Defensive Pact between all members[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]Open Borders: [\BOLD]Sign an Open Borders Agreement with all members[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]Assign City:[\BOLD] Switch ownership of a city to the player with the highest culture in that city. Cities can only be transferred in this way from voting members to full members[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Defying Resolutions[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Players have the option of "Defying" Resolutions of the Apostolic Palace, in effect vetoing the Resolution, which does not take effect for anyone. Players defying an Apostolic Palace Resolution will lose all Religious Building production bonuses and will receive an unhappiness penalty in their cities with the Apostolic Palace religion. Religious Building bonuses return when a player votes for a new Resolution that passes. Players may defy any Resolution except a Religious Victory Resolution.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Religious Victory[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A full member or owner of the Apostolic Palace can also win a Diplomatic Victory. To win a victory through the Apostolic Palace, every Civilization in the game must be able to vote for Apostolic Resolutions, meaning they all must have a city with the Palace's religion. Then the candidate simply needs the requisite number of member votes and victory will be theirs![PARAGRAPH:2][H1]United Nations Updates[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Membership[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Like the Apostolic Palace, the United Nations now also has different levels of membership. When it is founded, all players become full members of the United Nations. Player can only be demoted to Voting Members by defying a Resolution. There are no Non-Members. Only Full Members or the current owner can be Secretary General or win a Diplomatic Victory. Players may restore their full member status by voting for a resolution that passes.[PARAGRAPH:1]Players may view their Membership status on the Victory Screen [F8].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Defying Resolutions[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Players may defy Resolutions of the United Nations in the same manner as the Apostolic Palace, with similar consequences: the defying player will receive a major unhappiness penalty in his cities. Players may defy any resolution except a Diplomatic Victory Resolution.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]New Resolutions[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The United Nations may now pass "Force Peace", "Assign City", "Trade Embargo" and "Declare War" resolutions similar to those available from the Apostolic Palace.</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]教皇宫/联合国[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=BUILDING_APOSTOLIC_PALACE]教皇宫[\LINK]是新增的中古时代大奇观，其作用类似于[LINK=BUILDING_UNITED_NATIONS]联合国[\LINK]。要建造教皇宫，玩家需要研究[LINK=TECH_THEOLOGY]神学[\LINK]，并设立官方信仰。建成教皇宫的国家的官方信仰将成为“国际主流信仰”，并将触发“教皇监护者”选举投票，第一候选人是拥有教皇宫的领袖，第二候选人则是拥有最多“国际主流信仰”人口的领袖。“教皇监护者”将可以选择教皇宫议案提交表决。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]教皇宫成员国资格及成员国权益[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]教皇宫成员国可分为两种类型——“全权成员国”和“投票成员国”。投票成员国是指存在“国际主流信仰”但未将其设为官方信仰的国家。全权成员国是指存在“国际主流信仰”并将其设为官方信仰的国家。不存在“国际主流信仰”的国家则是“非成员国”。各成员国所有“国际主流信仰”的宗教建筑（寺庙、大教堂、修道院、圣坛）可以额外提供1单位产能奖励。[PARAGRAPH:1]全权成员国拥有许多权益：可以竞选教皇监护者；可以进一步通过教皇宫投票赢得外交胜利；作为全权成员国所拥有的选票比作为投票成员国多一倍。[PARAGRAPH:1]全权成员国如拒绝履行教皇宫决议（详情见后文），将降级为投票成员国，待日后其投下赞成票的某一议案获得通过时才能恢复全权成员国资格。[PARAGRAPH:1]玩家可以在胜利条件界面（[F8]）中查看自己的教皇宫成员国资格。[PARAGRAPH:1]联合国成员国资格规则与教皇宫成员国资格规则类似（详情见后文）。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]教皇宫议案[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]教皇监护者负责选择教皇宫议案提交表决。以下是可供选择的议案：[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]宣战:[\BOLD]所有成员国对某个投票成员国宣战，或是对某个与任一全权成员国处于战争状态的非成员国宣战。此项议案不能针对全权成员国。[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]贸易禁运:[\BOLD]所有成员国中止与某个投票成员国或非成员国的贸易。[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]停战:[\BOLD]中止某个全权成员国与其他成员国之间的战争。[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]签署共同防御协定:[\BOLD]所有成员国签署共同防御协定。[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]开放边界:[\BOLD]所有成员国签署开放边界协定。[PARAGRAPH:1][BOLD]移交城市:[\BOLD]将城市所有权移交给该城主流文化族群所对应的文明。此项议案只适用于投票成员国向全权成员国移交城市。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]拒绝履行决议[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]玩家可以选择“拒绝履行”教皇宫决议。拒绝履行教皇宫决议的玩家将失去宗教建筑带来的产能奖励，其拥有“国际主流信仰”的城市还将增加1单位不满。待日后其投下赞成票的某一议案获得通过时才能恢复。玩家可以拒绝履行任何决议，但这一选项不适用于宗教胜利投票。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]宗教胜利[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]教皇宫的全权成员国有机会赢得外交胜利。要通过教皇宫投票赢得胜利，要求游戏中全部现存文明均有投票权（即均存在“国际主流信仰”）。候选人只要获得足够票数即可赢得最后胜利！[PARAGRAPH:2][H1]联合国的改进[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]成员国资格[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]与教皇宫一样，联合国成员资格也分成不同等级。当联合国建立时，所有现存文明自动成为全权成员国。拒绝履行联合国决议的国家将降级为投票成员国，但不能完全退出联合国。只有全权成员国的领袖才有机会当选联合国秘书长或赢得外交胜利。非成员国在日后其投下赞成票的某一议案获得通过时才能恢复全权成员国资格。[PARAGRAPH:1]玩家可以在胜利条件界面（[F8]）中查看自己的联合国成员国资格。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]拒绝履行决议[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]玩家也可以选择拒绝履行联合国决议，后果也类似拒绝履行教皇宫决议：所有城市增加1单位不满。玩家可以拒绝履行任何决议，但这一选项不适用于外交胜利投票。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]新增联合国议案[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]联合国也可以通过与教皇宫议案类似的“停战”、“移交城市”、“贸易禁运”和“宣战”等新增议案。</Chinese>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_WINSTON_CHURCHILL_PEDIA</Tag>
<English>[H1]Winston Churchill [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Prime Minister of Great Britain [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1874 - 1965[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Winston Churchill, whose full name was, "Sir Winston Leonard Spencer-Churchill," was undoubtedly one of the most important people of the twentieth century. At various times a soldier, journalist, author, and politician, during his long life Churchill was known for both his intellectual brilliance and his outspoken support for what were often unpopular opinions. At various times he was either the most beloved or the most hated man in Britain. In the years since his death Churchill's reputation has grown to semi-legendary proportions. [PARAGRAPH:2]A descendant of the famous English general the Duke of Marlborough, Churchill was born in 1874 at Blenheim Palace in Oxfordshire. After a mediocre performance at the public school Harrow, Churchill joined the army, where he freely used his family connections to get assigned to several colonial wars, narrowly escaping death on a number of occasions - and by all accounts having a ripping good time while doing so. During this period Churchill became a very popular wartime journalist, writing numerous columns and several best-selling books about his experiences. Churchill's maneuvering and flagrant self-promotion alienated his fellow officers and essentially ended any chance of high promotion in the Army; however he was able to parlay his popularity to gain a seat in Parliament. [PARAGRAPH:2]In 1900 Churchill was elected to a Conservative seat in Parliament. However in 1904 his strong opposition to the Conservative policy of tariff protectionism led him to change parties and join the Liberals, who held power at the time. In the Liberal government Churchill held a number of different minor posts. In 1911 he was appointed First Lord of the Admiralty, overseeing the Royal Navy's ambitious modernization program. [PARAGRAPH:2]During the First World War, Churchill approved the disastrous Gallipoli invasion of Turkey. Churchill was soundly criticized for the failure, and in 1916 he resigned the Admiralty and left the government, rejoined the army and went off to the Western Front to fight in the trenches. [PARAGRAPH:2]Despite his many eccentricities and flaws, however, Churchill was widely recognized as one of the ablest men in Great Britain, and in 1917 he was back in government again, holding a number of important Cabinet posts. After the Liberal Government fell in 1923 Churchill swapped parties once again and joined the Conservatives, famously saying, "Anyone can rat [change parties], but it takes a certain ingenuity to re-rat." He was appointed Chancellor of the Exchequer in 1924 and presided over Britain's disastrous return to the Gold Standard, for which he was again soundly criticized. After the Conservative Government fell in the 1929 General Election, Churchill lost his government post and became estranged from the political power brokers in both parties. [PARAGRAPH:2]The rise of Nazi Germany also led to a resurgence of Churchill's political career. Although he had earlier praised Fascist Italy as a bulwark against communism, in the late 1930s Churchill became one of the few voices speaking out against the growing power of Hitler. When the British government adopted the policy of appeasement, Churchill was almost alone in voicing opposition, a position which gained him a number of admirers, but which also earned him a lot of public and political criticism. [PARAGRAPH:2]When the Second World War broke out, the public lost a great deal confidence in the government of Neville Chamberlain (who had spearheaded the policy of appeasing Hitler). To shore up support for his government Chamberlain asked Churchill to resume his post as First Lord of the Admiralty. Showing genuine greatness of character Churchill accepted the position, working tirelessly to improve the Royal Navy and absolutely refusing to criticize his Prime Minister during wartime. However by early 1941 it was clear that Chamberlain no longer enjoyed the confidence of the people or of Parliament, and Churchill was appointed Prime Minister of Great Britain. [PARAGRAPH:2]In the west the war began catastrophically for the Allies. The Germans launched their attack against the British and French forces in 1940. Supported by air power and infantry, the German tanks had outflanked the Allied positions, forcing the French and British into precipitous retreat, advancing so rapidly that the defenders didn't have enough time to reform a new line. The Germans came within inches of destroying the British army, forcing it to abandon all of its equipment and stage a chaotic evacuation at Dunkirk, leaving thousands of British soldiers behind to be captured. France was forced to surrender, and German soldiers occupied Paris. [PARAGRAPH:2]As past events had foreshadowed, Churchill was at his very best during adversity. Britain stood alone against Hitler. Her army was badly crippled; only the Royal Navy and Air Force stood between the British and the Germans. Churchill worked tirelessly to shore up Britain's defenses and to find allies against Hitler, and his brilliant rhetoric rallied the battered spirits of the British people and earned him the admiration of people across the world. Throughout the dark days of the Battle of Britain and the Blitz that followed, Churchill seemed to hold the empire together by sheer indomitable force of will. [PARAGRAPH:2]Diplomatically, Churchill was an opportunist. Despite his hatred of Communism and his extreme personal dislike of Stalin (who had earlier allied with Germany to gobble up Poland), when the Germans attacked the Soviet Union Churchill sought an alliance with the USSR, famously saying, "If Hitler invaded hell I would make at least a favorable reference to the devil in the House of Commons." His most important diplomatic task, however, was to cultivate the good will - and eventually the military intervention - of the United States. [PARAGRAPH:2]It can be argued that Churchill's friendship with American President Franklin Delano Roosevelt saved Great Britain from destruction. Facing strong internal opposition to becoming involved in the war, at first the President had to move slowly, maintaining at least a nominal appearance of neutrality while gradually shifting American public opinion from Isolation to Intervention. However when Japan attacked Pearl Harbor at the end of 1941, Germany stupidly declared war against the United States, allowing Roosevelt to openly bring the growing might of the US military and industrial complex to Great Britain's (and the USSR's) aid. [PARAGRAPH:2]Within a very short period the US Army Air Force was attacking German targets in Europe, and soon thereafter large numbers of American troops were staged in Great Britain, ending forever any chance of a successful German invasion. As the war progressed the growing English and American forces launched a major invasion of Europe while their air forces pounded German factories and cities around the clock, crippling the Nazis enough to allow the Soviet Union to annihilate the German army in the Eastern Front. [PARAGRAPH:2]After the war ended in victory Churchill lost power almost immediately - perhaps because the people thought he was too old, or because they didn't believe he was the correct leader to rebuild the shattered empire. Though he remained in Parliament for a number of years (and briefly regained the post of Prime Minister during the Korean conflict), by and large Churchill's direct participation in world events was at an end. [PARAGRAPH:2]After being voted out of office Churchill wrote a history of the Second World War, for which he received the Nobel Prize in Literature in 1953. In 1965 Churchill suffered a stroke and passed away at the age of 90. Churchill's death was mourned across the globe, and his funeral was attended by an enormous number of foreign dignitaries. His reputation has only grown in the years since his death, and today Churchill is possibly the most popular and revered figure in all of English history. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1/>
<L2/>
<L3/>
<L4/>
<Chinese>[H1]温斯顿·丘吉尔[\H1]英国首相[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1874-1965[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景：[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]温斯顿·丘吉尔的全名是：温斯顿·伦纳德·斯宾塞-丘吉尔爵士，他可以无庸置疑地位列20世纪里最重要的人物之一。他在不同时期从事过不同的职业，包括士兵、记者、作家和政治家，在他的一生当中，丘吉尔最为人所了解的是他对常常不受欢迎的见解表现出的聪明才智和坦率的支持。很多时候他在英国不是最受人爱戴的人，就是最令人讨厌的人。在他去世之后，丘吉尔的名声越发具有传奇色彩。[PARAGRAPH:2]作为英国著名将军马尔巴罗公爵的子孙，丘吉尔1874年出生于牛津郡布莱尼姆帕里斯。在哈罗公立学校获得普普通通的成绩毕业后，丘吉尔参军了，在那里他自主地利用他家庭的关系被指派到几个殖民战事当中，有多次差点丧命，而且据说都是在非常惊险的情况下逃离死亡的。在这个时期的丘吉尔成为一个很受欢迎的战地记者，并写了许多专栏和几本关于他的经历的畅销书。丘吉尔的肆意妄为和公然的自我晋升疏远了同行军官而且在本质上终止了在军中高升的任何机会。然而他却能够连本带利地提高他的声望来获得议会的一个席位。[PARAGRAPH:2]1900年丘吉尔取得在议会中保守党的一席。然而在1904年对于关税保护的保守党政策的强烈反对使他改变了党派并加入了自由党，该党派在当时很有权力。在自由党政府里丘吉尔担任许多不同的小职位。在1911年他被委派为英国海军大臣，监督英国皇家海军野心勃勃的现代化规划。[PARAGRAPH:2]在第一次世界大战期间，丘吉尔批准了导致损失惨重的土耳其加里波里登陆计划。丘吉尔因为这场失败受到强烈批评，并在1916年辞去海军部职务并离开政府，重新加入陆军并前去西线战壕里战斗。[PARAGRAPH:2]尽管他有许多怪僻和缺点，然而，丘吉尔被公认为英国最有才干的人之一，而在1917年他再次回到政府，在内阁中担任重要职位。1923年自由党政府下台后，丘吉尔再次改变党派并再加入到保守党，说了句著名的话“任何人都能变节（改变党派），但再变节需要一定的灵活性。”1924年他被委任为英国财政大臣，负责灾难性恢复金本位制计划，这导致了灾难性的结果，因此他再次受到强烈批评。保守党政府在1929年的大选下台后，丘吉尔失去他的政府职位并同两党的政治掮客疏远了。[PARAGRAPH:2]纳粹德国的崛起也使得丘吉尔的政治生涯得到苏醒。虽然他早期赞扬过作为对抗共产主义的防波堤的法西斯主义意大利，但在19世纪30年代末却成为其中少数大声反对力量在增长中的希特勒的人。当英国政府采取绥靖政策，丘吉尔几乎孤独的处在反对声音中，在这个形势下很多人敬慕他，但也受到很多公众和政治上的批判。[PARAGRAPH:2]当二战爆发，公众对尼维尔·张伯伦（对希特勒实施绥靖政策）的政府失去信心时。为维持对他的政府的支持，张伯伦邀请丘吉尔再度出任英国海军大臣。表现出性格真实伟大的丘吉尔接受了职位，不知疲倦地工作来改进皇家海军并在战争期间完全拒绝评论他的首相。然而到了1941年初张伯伦显然不再受人们和议会的信任，而丘吉尔就被委任为英国的首相。[PARAGRAPH:2]在西线，盟军的开局变成了一场灾难。德军在1940年对英法军队发动大规模进攻。在空军和步兵的支援下，德国坦克两翼包抄盟军的阵地，迫使英法两军紧急撤退，推进是如此的迅速，以致防守一方没有足够的时间去形成新的战线。德军几乎完全摧毁了英军的斗志，迫使他们在敦克尔克放弃所有的装备并实施了一场混乱的撤退，留下数千名士兵成为战俘。法国被迫投降，德军占领了巴黎。[PARAGRAPH:2]正如过往的事件所预示，丘吉尔在逆境下才会处于最佳状态。英国独力对抗着希特勒。英国陆军元气大伤，只有皇家海军和空军屹立在英国和德国入侵者之间。丘吉尔竭尽全力支撑英国的防御体系，并寻求同盟对抗希特勒，而且他出色的言辞重振了英国人崩溃的精神，并为他赢得了全世界人民的钦佩。在紧随的整个英国战役和闪电战的艰苦岁月里，丘吉尔似乎全靠意志中不屈不挠的力量把帝国紧紧团结在一起。[PARAGRAPH:2]外交方面，丘吉尔是个机会主义者。尽管他憎恨共产主义并十分不喜欢斯大林（他在早期和德国结盟吞并波兰），但是当德国人进攻苏联时邱吉尔就和苏联结盟，并说了一句名言：“即使希特勒入侵地狱，我也会在下院发表支持撒旦的声明。”不过他最重要的外交成就却是使美国最终下定参与军事干涉的决心。[PARAGRAPH:2]有人坚持认为是丘吉尔与美国总统罗斯福的友谊挽救了英国。由于国内强烈反对卷入战争，起初美国总统只能慢慢地鼓动，至少在名义上表现中立，然而却逐渐地使美国民意由孤立变为干预。然而当日本在1941年末偷袭珍珠港，德国愚蠢地向美国宣战，终于使得罗斯福能够公开地给予英国（和苏联）以充足的援助。[PARAGRAPH:2]在很短的时间内美国空军开始攻击德国在欧洲的目标，不久后大量美军登陆英国，永远结束了德国入侵英国的任何成功机会。随着战事的发展，壮大中的英美军队发动对欧洲的大反攻，同时他们的空军日以继夜地重击德国的工厂和城市，充分削弱纳粹以使苏联有能力消灭东线的德军。[PARAGRAPH:2]二战胜利结束后，丘吉尔几乎迅速地失去权力——也许是因为人们认为他年纪太大了，或者因为他们不相信他是重建破碎的帝国的好领导。虽然他留在议会里很多年（并在朝鲜战争期间暂时地恢复首相的职位），但基本上丘吉尔对世界政治的直接参与就到此为止了。[PARAGRAPH:2]卸任之后的丘吉尔撰写了一部二战史，他因此在1953年获得诺贝尔文学奖。1965年丘吉尔因中风而逝世，享年90岁。丘吉尔的去世令全球哀悼，大批外国政要参加了他的葬礼。他去世之后声誉日隆，时至今日丘吉尔可能仍是英国历史上最受欢迎和最受尊敬的人物。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>