<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- freesand -->
<!-- Game Text - New -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<!--Please place any new text entries into this file-->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AMERICAN_BROADCAST_TOWER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Although scientists from many different countries contributed to the development of radio, the American civilization was perhaps the first to fully exploit the potentials of the new media. The first ever radio news program was broadcast in 1920 from Detroit, Michigan, and within two decades hundreds of radio stations were broadcasting programs around the clock. [PARAGRAPH:2]The period of 1930 - 1960 in the United States is called the "Golden Age of Radio." During that era American radio produced hundreds of top-quality programs in a huge variety of formats and topics, including quiz shows, news programs, variety programs, mysteries, musicals, romances, soap operas, thrillers, dramas, and comedies. Perhaps the most graphic demonstration of the media's power occurred with the broadcast of "The War of the Worlds," a science-fiction short play about an invasion from Mars. Thousands and thousands of listeners across the country did not realize that the story was fictional and believed that an invasion was actually occurring; there was chaos in the streets during the ensuing panic. In the US, radio's golden age ended with the arrival of television. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>虽然来自不同国家的许多科学家都对无线电广播技术的发展作出过贡献，但可以说是美国人最早将这种富有潜力的新兴媒体引入完全实用的阶段。1920年，第一个无线广播新闻节目出现在密歇根州底特律市，在此之后不到20年，美国已拥有数百家全天播出各种节目的广播电台。[PARAGRAPH:2]1930-1960年间被称为美国“无线广播的黄金时代”，其间美国广播业制作的高品质广播节目数量成百上千，风格主题各不相同，包括益智游戏、国内外新闻、神怪剧、音乐剧、浪漫剧、肥皂剧、惊悚剧、话剧、喜剧等等等等。广播媒体巨大影响力的一个最著名例子就是1938年的“世界之战”事件，当时电台播出了一个有关火星人入侵地球的科幻短剧“世界之战”。成千上万的美国听众对这个虚构故事信以为真，以为火星人确实正在入侵地球；许多市民惊慌失措，大街小巷陷入一片混乱。后来随着电视的普及，美国广播的黄金时代结束了。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ARABIAN_MARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Arabian bazaars are lively and crowded places with hundreds of stalls, and the air is filled with the cries of merchants trying to entice wary customers to purchase their goods. Virtually anything imaginable can be found in markets, from food to clothing, DVDs, rugs, perfume, furniture, and so forth. Such places can be perilous for the uninitiated, for the merchants will seek to wring out the largest sum possible for their wares, and a customer who is not versed in the fine art of haggling is very likely to get taken for every penny he or she has. [PARAGRAPH:2]Bazaars have existed virtually unchanged in Arabian cities for centuries. The Grand Bazaar in Istanbul, Turkey, covers some 60 streets and contains around 400 shops. The Grand Bazaar in Tehran, Iran, has been around in one form or another for over a thousand years: with over 10 km of corridors, it is the largest covered neighborhood in the world.  [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>阿拉伯市场“巴扎”（bazzar）是拥挤的露天交易场所，市场内有成百上千的摊位，商贩大声叫卖，一片喧闹和嘈杂。市场上几乎可以找到任何能想到的东西：食物、衣服、影碟、毛毯、香水、家具等等等等。这种市场会让不擅购物之道的人感到很不适应，因为商贩往往会狮子大开口漫天要价，顾客如果不懂得还价，一定会被宰得鲜血淋漓。[PARAGRAPH:2]阿拉伯城市中的传统市场几个世纪以来几乎没有多少改变。位于土耳其伊斯坦布尔的“大市场”中有60多条街道，400多个店铺。而伊朗德黑兰的大市场几乎在同一个位置上存在了上千年，所有通道的总长度超过10公里，是世界上占地面积最大的露天集市。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AZTEC_COURTHOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In Aztec culture, religion was inextricably woven into the fabric of daily life. The king was the leader of the nation; he also held high office in the religion. Aztec religious policies had the full force of law behind them. When a condemned criminal was executed, he was killed on the same sacrificial altars that the Aztecs used to sacrifice captured prisoners (and others) during religious rituals. [PARAGRAPH:2]Despite their bloodthirsty - even savage - reputation, the Aztecs had quite a sophisticated judicial system to protect both person and property. Each major city or town had a supreme judge. Once appointed, the supreme judge was totally independent of the monarchy; he wielded ultimate judicial control over his jurisdiction. Beneath the supreme judge was a three-member court, and beneath them were a group of lesser magistrates who were elected to their office by the people of the city. There is little evidence of corruption in the Aztec courts: judicial misconduct was punishable by death. [PARAGRAPH:2]Though the Aztecs could be considered barbaric by most modern standards, their justice system was fairly effective at deterring crime and keeping the peace. For example, there could not have been much theft in the cities: the Aztec residences were not equipped with locks or even bolts. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在阿兹特克文化中，宗教信仰与日常生活是密不可分的。国王既是一国的统治者，又是至高的宗教领袖。阿兹特克的宗教制度有强大的法律作为配合。死刑犯人在定罪之后，将会作为人牲在宗教祭坛上处决。[PARAGRAPH:2]虽然阿兹特克人给世人留下的印象是嗜血而野蛮，但事实上阿兹特克的司法审判系统是相当完善复杂的，人身自由权和私有财产权得到充分的保护。每座主要城镇都有一位大审判官。审判官获得任命后就拥有完全的司法自主权，不受国王的干涉；对管辖范围之内的案件可以作出最终裁决。在大审判官之下有三名审判官组成的法庭，在审判官之下还有更低一级的司法官，司法官是由所在城市的市民推举的。阿兹特克法庭很少有腐败现象：知法犯法者将被处以死刑。[PARAGRAPH:2]虽然以现代的标准来看，阿兹特克人的社会制度可算野蛮，但其司法系统在遏制犯罪，维持社会安定方面确实富有效率。例如城市中很少有窃贼：阿兹特克民居都不装锁，甚至连门闩都没有。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CARTHAGE_LIGHTHOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Carthage began its existence as a trading colony of the maritime Phoenicians, and its fortunes rose or fell according to the success of its fishing fleet, trading fleet and navy. Ships of the time were primitive affairs, lacking (of course) any modern navigation aids like radar, sonar, or even accurate charts. The captains piloted their vessels by sight and by "dead reckoning." [PARAGRAPH:2]Sailors of the day were quite rightly reluctantly to travel in the dark, as they ran the risk of running into shoals or being swept inshore and torn apart in the surf. To light the way for their fleets, the Carthaginians placed bonfires atop the headlands at the mouths of harbors. Over time they constructed platforms to increase the fires' visibility, and these eventually evolved into lighthouses. At the height of its maritime strength, the Carthaginians had dozens of lighthouses and beacons lighting the way to colonies across the Western Mediterranean. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>迦太基最初是作为腓尼基移民的贸易据点逐步发展起来的，她的财富来自于渔船队、商船队和海军舰队的力量。当时的船只还相当原始，没有雷达、声纳等等现代导航设备，甚至没有精确的海图。船长是凭借经验和肉眼操纵船只的。[PARAGRAPH:2]当时的水手自然不愿意在黑暗中行船，那样很可能触礁或是搁浅。为了给船队带来光明，迦太基人在港口尖岬设立篝火。随着时间的推移，人们建造高台以使篝火能在更远的地方看到，最终发展成为灯塔。在迦太基的全盛时期，他们在西地中海沿岸据点建立了数十座大小灯塔。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CELTIC_OBSERVATORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An observatory is a structure which helps men to study the night skies. While modern observatories are equipped with mighty telescopes allowing astronomers to probe the origins of the universe, the earliest were little more than rooms or platforms open to the sky, from which the primitive astronomers - often priests or astrologers - tracked the movement of the stars with their naked eyes. [PARAGRAPH:2]The early Celts were enthusiastic astronomers. After countless years of patient observation they were able to chart and predict the movements of many celestial bodies. The movement of the stars had religious and magical significance, but were also of immense practical use, as well: by charting the progress of the night sky one could construct a very accurate calendar, which was extremely useful for determining the correct time to plant and harvest crops. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>天文台是供人们研究星辰的建筑物。现代天文台装有强大的望远镜，天文学家可用以研究宇宙的起源。但最早的天文台不过是一座露天高台，古代的天文学家——往往是祭司或星象学家——只能凭借肉眼追踪星星的运行。[PARAGRAPH:2]凯尔特人非常注重天象。经过几百年的耐心观测，他们记录了许多天体的运行轨迹，甚至能预测其运行轨迹。星星的运行对宗教信仰有重要意义，但也有许多实际的用处：观测天象可以帮助人们制订精确的历法，指导人们确定农时种植庄稼。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHINESE_COURTHOUSE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>It could be said that early China created and then mastered the art of bureaucracy. A huge country spread over a large portion of the world requires a huge number of functionaries to run it, and this was especially true in the days before electronic communication: some Chinese cities were hundreds - even thousands - of miles from the capital. [PARAGRAPH:2]Chinese cities were often run by governors, appointed officials with authority over the local government, judiciary and military. The exact amount of autonomy these officials possessed  varied greatly by time and location - during the Warring States period, for example, a number of kingdoms made great efforts to curtail the power of local governments and return power to the central government, as some local officials had become far too autonomous - and corrupt. [PARAGRAPH:2]Governors' palaces housed a large portion of a city's government. They were often large, ornate buildings, lavishly constructed to best display the governments' power and wealth to overawe the local populace. The governor might reside in the palace itself, or have a lavish residence nearby. In addition to the governor's offices, the palace would contain the governor's treasury, offices for bureaucrats and tax collectors, courtrooms, guards' quarters and perhaps jail cells. Depending upon local conditions the palace might be heavily-fortified. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>古代中国最早发展并完善了官僚制度。作为一个拥有极其辽阔领土的国家，中国需要保持庞大的政府机构，在电子通讯技术发明之前更是如此：有些城市距离首都可达千里之遥。[PARAGRAPH:2]每座中国城市由一位地方长官总体负责，在他属下有一系列官员分别管理行政、司法和军事。地方政府的自主权随时代和地区的不同而有很大差别——在战国时代，各国政府努力削弱地方的力量，将权力集中到中央，因为某些地方官员权力过大，甚至导致腐化。[PARAGRAPH:2]地方长官的驻所（“官衙”）往往占据很大的面积，建筑众多、装饰豪华，以向民众显示政府的力量和财富。地方长官可能住在官衙，也可能另选别墅居住。除了作为办公场所，官衙还是长官的私人财产存放处、下属官吏的居所、法庭，还可能设有监牢，并由差役保卫，戒备森严。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EGYPTIAN_OBELISK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An obelisk is an upright four-sided pillar that tapers to a point, usually placed to commemorate some important god, person or event. The earliest known obelisks are found in Egypt, which is believed to have invented the form. Obelisks were a prominent feature of Egyptian architecture, and two were generally placed at the entrance to Egyptian temples. [PARAGRAPH:2]Cleopatra's Needles - the most famous Egyptian obelisks (which were later looted and relocated to various countries around the world) - were constructed of granite and stood over 20 meters in height. While much larger obelisks have since been built - at 167 meters the Washington Monument in the United States is the tallest obelisk in the world - the Egyptian obelisks were extremely impressive feats of architecture and engineering for their time. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>方尖碑是一个四棱柱体，上端为尖顶，通常用以纪念某个重要的神灵、人物或事件，方尖碑最早出现于埃及。方尖碑是反映古埃及风格的重要建筑样式的，埃及神庙入口两侧往往会建有方尖碑。[PARAGRAPH:2]克利奥帕特拉方尖碑是最著名的一座埃及方尖碑（后来被欧洲殖民者掠走，曾经放置于世界许多国家），此碑以花岗岩制成，高20余米。虽然后来人们又建造了更高的方尖碑——世界上最高的一座方尖碑是高167米的美国华盛顿纪念碑——但古埃及的方尖碑仍是当时工程技术水平下所能达到的伟大成就。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ENGLISH_BANK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>At the risk of dramatic oversimplification - a stock exchange is an organization which allows "brokers" to buy and sell "stocks" and "bonds." A stock represents part ownership in a company, and a bond is a loan to a company, which the company guarantees to repay with interest. If the company does well, the investors make money; if the company does poorly (or fails entirely) the investors lose money. [PARAGRAPH:2]The primary benefit of a stock exchange to society is that it allows companies to concentrate a large amount of wealth to accomplish something that no individual (or perhaps government) would be able to afford. In the nineteenth century, for example, construction of the United States' railroad network was in large part financed by individuals who purchased shares of railroad companies. Earlier in history, the great British and Dutch trading companies were similarly financed. [PARAGRAPH:2]For a long period of history, the English city of London was the financial center of the world. The London Stock Exchange is one of the largest exchanges in the world, as well as one of the oldest. Though officially founded in 1801, it can trace its origins to the late seventeenth century, when - the brokers having been expelled from the Royal Exchange for rowdiness - buying and selling stocks took place in London coffee houses. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>如果要简单地（也许是过度简单了）解释“证券交易所”这一名词，则可以说：证券交易所是一个允许“经纪人”（broker）进行“股票”（stock）和“债券”（bond）买卖的机构。股票代表一家公司的部分资产的所有权，而债券代表一家公司部分债务及其利息的所有权。如果公司业绩好，投资者就会赚钱；如果公司业绩差（或完全破产），投资者就会亏损。[PARAGRAPH:2]证券交易所带给社会的最大好处是它使得公司能够集中大量财富，完成个人（或者政府）无法独立负担任务。譬如，在19世纪，美国铁路网络的建设很大一部分是由购买铁路公司股份的个人提供资金的。在更早的历史上，英国和荷兰的贸易公司也是类似地筹集资金的。[PARAGRAPH:2]在很长一段历史时期里，英国伦敦是世界金融中心。伦敦的证券交易所是世界上最大的交易所，也是最古老的交易所之一。伦敦证券交易所正式成立于1801年，但它的起源则可追溯到17世纪晚期，当时有一批经纪人因纠份而被驱逐出“皇家交易所”，他们转而在伦敦的一家咖啡厅进行股票买卖。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FRENCH_CASTLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In English, the French term "chateau" is often imperfectly translated as "castle." In common English usage "castle" denotes a complex of heavily-fortified stone buildings constructed during the Middle Ages. The stereotypical castle consists of a central building (or "keep") which stands in an open area surrounded by high walls, which in turn are surrounded by a ditch, or moat. A French chateau may have these features as well, but a better translation might be "manor house." [PARAGRAPH:2]At one time the word "chateau" was reserved to describe the feudal home of a member of the French royal house or other high nobility. The original design was based upon the Roman villas; as the empire fell and times became more dangerous, the villas' walls were heightened and eventually the entire structure was fortified. The French chateaux were often centers of art and culture in a region, as the nobility were the only ones who could afford artists and musicians and the like. [PARAGRAPH:2]Eventually life would become more peaceful in France and the chateaux lost their walls, moats and other fortifications. The dwellings of the nobility gradually transformed into large, sprawling homes filled with light and color. Although beautiful indeed, these buildings were quite undefendable, as the nobility discovered during the French Revolution. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>“法国城堡”（chateau）与一般意义上的“城堡”——坚固的中世纪防御设施——有所差异。普通城堡的样式通常包括一座中心建筑（“要塞”），要塞周围环绕高墙，高墙周围环绕濠沟。法国城堡也可能有这些东西，但更多的是作为一座“领主宅邸”。[PARAGRAPH:2]“法国城堡”一词最初是指法国王室和豪门贵族在其领地上所建造的居所，这些居所的风格起初类似于古罗马的别墅；随着国势衰落内乱不断，原先别墅的外墙建得越来越高，整个建筑的风格也变得类似于防御要塞。法国城堡体现着不同地区的艺术和文化，贵族有充足的财力聘请艺术家和音乐家，将自己的宅邸打扮得美仑美奂。[PARAGRAPH:2]到了和平安定的年代，法国城堡的外墙、濠沟就慢慢消失。贵族们的居所更象是一座占地广阔的乡间别墅，色彩缤纷华丽。这样的“城堡”虽然美丽，但其防御能力实在差强人意，贵族们直到法国大革命爆发之后才痛苦地认识到这一点。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GERMAN_FACTORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A factory is a building or complex of buildings where workers manufacture goods. In many cases the goods are manufactured using an "assembly line" style of production in which individual parts are added to the product by a number of workers, each of whom performs his or her actions in sequence as the product moves down the production line. The factory also may include a warehouse to store parts as well as the finished products. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Venice Armory is the first known factory in history. Founded in Venice, Italy, in the twelfth century, it produced ships using an assembly-line style of production. During the Industrial Revolution in the eighteenth century, factories sprang up across Europe and North America, with the earliest concentration in the British Isles. The United States greatly streamlined the process during the early twentieth century. [PARAGRAPH:2]Although a relative latecomer to manufacturing, by the early twentieth century the German factories were among the most efficient. During the First and Second World Wars German plants built thousands of tanks, planes, and other war materiel under horrendous conditions and in the face of concentrated Allied bombing attacks. Moving into the twenty-first century the German factories remain among the best in the world. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>工厂由单个或多个厂房建筑组成，供工人在其中制造各种产品。工厂往往采用“生产流水线”进行装配，在“生产流水线”上，整个装配工作被分割成若干道工序，每个工人只在流水线上完成自己的一部分工序。装配工厂有时也包括储存货物的仓库。[PARAGRAPH:2]建立于12世纪的意大利威尼斯兵工厂是已知最早的一家工厂。该厂使用流水线式的生产方式建造战船。在18世纪工业革命期间，大批工厂在欧洲和北美地区涌现出来（最初是集中于英伦三岛）。20世纪初的美国工厂又进一步地推进了工业生产方式的完善。[PARAGRAPH:2]尽管德国在工业革命时代中是一个后起者，但到了20世纪早期，德国工厂已处于世界上最有效率的工厂之列。在一战和二战期间，德国工厂生产了成千上万的坦克、飞机和其他战略物资，而且这些成就都是在非常艰难的条件——例如盟军的集中轰炸之下完成的。进入21世纪，德国的制造业仍然是世界一流的。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_WALL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Great Wall of China is one of the largest and most famous man-made constructions in the entire world. Chinese rulers built the Great Wall to ward off attack from nomadic tribesmen living in modern Manchuria and Mongolia. Interestingly, the Great Wall was not designed to keep the nomads out - the Chinese knew it was all but impossible to defend such a long border - it was designed to make it difficult for the raiders to carry off loot, thus making raids far less profitable and thus less worth the risks involved. [PARAGRAPH:2]There have actually been five different "Great Walls" built by different Chinese dynasties. The first four were constructed of earth and have since all but disappeared. The current wall was built almost entirely by the Ming Dynasty between 1368 and 1640 AD. This wall was constructed on a grander scale, using more permanent materials (like stone). The Ming wall stretches for 3,948 miles from Shanhai Pass on the Bohai Gulf in the east to Lop Nur in the southeast portion of Xinjiang's Uygur Autonomous Region in the west. This was the region where the Silk Road first entered China, and a series of watchtowers which could communicate via smoke signals were intended to pass messages rapidly along the vast length. [PARAGRAPH:2]In pure military terms, the Great Wall turned out to be something of a failure. The Manchus were able to bribe a Chinese general to let them pass through the wall, so it turned out to be of little value in stopping a major barbarian attack. After the Manchus conquered China, the borders of the country extended far to the north, rendering the wall irrelevant. The sheer cost of the wall was also staggering, and the cost in human lives is said to have exceeded over one million souls (the Great Wall is sometimes nicknamed "the long graveyard"). [PARAGRAPH:2]Today much of the Great Wall is in a state of disrepair - though the tourist regions are well-preserved, much of the rest of the structure is crumbling, and perhaps only 20%% of the wall is in good condition. Despite its decay, the Great Wall remains one of China's most popular tourist attractions and a true wonder of the world. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>中国的万里长城是世界上最宏伟、最负盛名的人造工程之一。古代的中国统治者们建造长城，是为了抵御生活在现今东北和蒙古地区游牧部族的入侵。有意思的是，长城的设计并不是为了拒敌于国门之外——中国人明白要全面防御如此漫长的边境线是一项不可能的任务——而是为了使入侵者难以轻易地带着他们的掠获物离开，令劫掠活动能得到的利益不足以弥补需承受的风险。[PARAGRAPH:2]实际上存在着五条不同的“长城”，兴建于五个不同的历史朝代。起初的四座皆以夯土筑成，因此现在已几乎完全湮沒。现存的城墙大都建于公元1368-1640年明朝时期。这条长城建筑规模空前宏大，并采用更为坚固耐久的砖石材料。明长城绵延达3948英里（6352公里），东起渤海之滨的山海关，西至现今新疆维吾尔自治区东南部的罗布泊。（塞爱维小提示：通常认为明长城东起辽东虎山，西至甘肃嘉峪关，全长6350公里。）古丝绸之路从这里开始进入中国本部，长城沿线建有一系列烽火台，能够通过烽火及狼烟高速度长距离的传送信息。[PARAGRAPH:2]从纯军事角度来看，长城可以算是一个失败的工程。满族军队在中国内奸的引导下轻易地越过了她，所以长城在蛮族大举入侵的时代并没有发挥多少作用。满清入主中原之后，中国的疆域大大向北扩展，长城也不再合乎时宜。修建长城所付出的代价也是令人瞠目结舌的，期间牺牲的劳工据说超过了一百万（因此长城有时也被戏称为“最长的墓地”）。[PARAGRAPH:2]在今天，长城大部分都处于年久失修的状态——尽管在一些旅游区保护妥善，但在其他许多地方的长城则正在不断碎裂崩塌，可能仅有20%%的城墙的保护状况尚属理想。虽然状况堪扰，长城仍然是中国最吸引人的游览胜地之一，也是一座真正的世界奇观。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREEK_THEATRE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Modern western drama was created in Greece around 530 BC, evolving from the "dithyramb," a fertility ritual of songs, poems and dances offered to the Greek god Dionysus. A theatre could be be constructed inside a building, or out in the open air. The audience sat in a semicircle of seats around a central paved "dancing square" (orchestra). The first row of seats was reserved for important officials or priests. There was usually an altar dedicated to Dionysus somewhere in the theatre. The "logeion" was a small raised platform where the performers acted (the original dramas had at most three or four actors; the size of the stage would increase as later plays required bigger casts). [PARAGRAPH:2]Theatre was a vital part of Greek cultural life. In addition to providing the population with entertainment, plays were also important contributors to the political discussions of the day. The great playwright Aristophanes wrote a number of satires that criticized the great citizens of the day and their conduct during the Peloponnesian War. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>西方现代戏剧的诞生可以追溯到约公元前530年时的古希腊，由“酒神赞歌”（dithyramb）逐渐演化而来——这是为庆祝丰收、向酒神狄俄尼索斯献祭而举行的一种表演仪式，包括歌唱、诗朗颂和舞蹈等等。古希腊的“露天剧场”（odeon）是一种大型开放式建筑，专门用于举行这类演出。听众坐在四周的看台之上，中间是演出的舞台。看台的第一排座位是为重要的官员和祭司准备的。在歌剧院里面有专门用于祭拜酒神的祭坛。“舞台”是一块高起的小平台，用于演员演出（最初的戏剧最多只有三四个演员；随着后来的发展，需要的演职人员也越来越多。）[PARAGRAPH:2]剧场在希腊文化生活中占据着重要的地位。除了向民众提供娱乐，戏剧还具有议论时政的作用。著名的剧作家阿里斯托芬创作的戏剧中就有许多内容是讽刺当时政客所作所为的。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INCAN_AQUEDUCT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Although many Incan cities were built in high, inaccessible locations, all appear to have had within them elaborate baths and fountains. Water was carried to the baths through intricate systems of stone channels and conduits, construction of which required both sophisticated engineering and architectural design as well as an extraordinarily high quality of stone masonry. [PARAGRAPH:2] While little is known about Incan daily life (the Incas themselves lacked a written language), it appears that these baths and fountains served practical, artistic and religious purposes. In practical terms a consistent water supply is necessary for any city, especially for one that might be put under siege by its enemies. However, this can be accomplished with wells and cisterns - the Incans seem to have gone to the huge effort to construct the elaborate fountains simply because they beautified the city. Since a city's highest fountains and baths (which would contain the purest water) were usually located near a temple, it is a good bet that ritual purification played a role in the Incan religious ceremonies. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>虽然许多印加城市建在崎岖的山地，但也拥有许多浴场和喷泉设施。水流通过石制地下管网或高架渠道引入浴场，这样的系统无疑需要良好的工程、建筑设计以及石工技术水平。[PARAGRAPH:2]我们对印加社会的日常生活所知甚少（印加人没有完善的书面文字），不过看起来印加人的浴场和喷泉有实用、艺术和宗教等多方面的作用。首先城市需要维持的供水，特别是在被敌人包围的情况下。但依靠水井和蓄水池也可以解决供水问题——印加人建造喷泉更多的是因为其看上去更美丽。由于城市地势最高的喷泉和浴场（那里能提供最清澈的水）通常都建在神庙旁边，因此清洁身体很可能是印加宗教仪式非常重要的组成部分。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INDIAN_GRANARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>India is a country of flood and drought. Eighty percent of the country's rainfall is concentrated in the monsoon months - July to October - the rest of the year is quite dry. Throughout its history most of India's food crops were grown during the monsoon and the months immediately thereafter, as the rest of the year the soil was too dry for effective crop yield. When harvested, these crops were stored in granaries to be consumed over the course of the year. [PARAGRAPH:2]Given that they could spell the difference between feast and famine, the building, maintenance and improvement of granaries played a critical part in the success or failure of an Indian village. Villages with enough to eat could expend energy on music and the arts; starving villages could not. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>印度是水旱灾害多发的国家。百分之八十的降水集中在寸雨季——七月至十月——其他时间则相当干旱。在历史上，印度的大部分农作物都是在雨季种植并在旱季开始时收割的，一年里其余的时间不适宜种植庄稼。收获的粮食将存在放粮仓中供全年食用。[PARAGRAPH:2]由于粮仓意味着丰足与饥荒的差异，因此其建造、维护与改造在印度乡村地区是一件大事。只有粮仓装满了，人们才有精力去从事音乐和艺术创作；饿着肚子是不可能发展文化的。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JAPAN_LIBRARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Japanese word "Bushido" means "way of the warrior."  Bushido is a set of codes and philosophies that were adopted by the "samurai," the Japanese warrior class, during the eleventh and twelfth centuries. Roughly analogous to the European feudal code of the Middle Ages, Bushido encourages a samurai to be totally without fear, to treat women and children gently, to live a good and moral life, and - most importantly - to be utterly loyal to his master in all things. [PARAGRAPH:2]A samurai was educated to be an superb warrior. He was expected to be in excellent physical condition, a matchless swordsman, willing to follow his master's orders without thought for his own safety, and to be willing to die if it was necessary. In addition to their military training, samurai were also educated in letters and the arts. A samurai was expected to be able to read and write and to be skilled in poetry, calligraphy, the dance, and so on. The greatest samurai were both men of the sword and of letters. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>日本的“武士道”就是作为一个武士所应信守的行为准则，包括一系列严格的规定和哲学理念。日本的武士阶层兴起于11至12世纪。武士道与欧洲中世纪的骑士精神有些类似，它要求武士在战时英勇无畏，在平时尊敬老幼妇孺，保持道德方面的正直无瑕，最重要的一点则是在各方面完全忠于他的主公。[PARAGRAPH:2]武士需要接受成为优秀战士的严格训练。他需要拥有强健的体格、高超的剑法，随时听候主公的命令而不顾惜自己的生命。除了军事训练，武士也需要学习其他方面的本领。一位武士应该能够读书识字，懂得书画和诗词，等等等等。理想中的武士应该既善用剑，又善用笔。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KOREA_UNIVERSITY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Throughout its history, Korea has always placed great emphasis on education. The first system of formal education was created during the "Three Kingdoms" period (57 BC - 668 AD). This system was loosely based upon the education system used in Korea's northern neighbor, China. The National Confucian Academy, first state-run institution of higher learning, was founded in 372 AD, and some three hundred years later another university - the National Confucian College - was founded in 660 AD. Early Korean universities emphasized the study of Chinese classics. Confucianism was an important topic of study, and it remained so even after the Koryo Dyansty adopted Buddhism as the state religion. [PARAGRAPH:2]In modern Korea (at least in the South) education continues to be held in high importance. There are over 300 institutes of higher education - including junior vocational colleges and colleges and universities and graduate schools - in South Korea, with enrollment in excess of two million students. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>高丽（朝鲜）自古以来即非常重视教育。高丽最早的正规教育体制早在“三国”时期（公元前57-公元668）就已出现。这个教育体制是仿照其北方的强邻——中国的儒家教育体制建立起来的。“三国”之一的高句丽于公元372年首度设立“太学”，同时在地方上设立传授儒学的私立书院（“私塾”）。约三百年之后的统一“三国”的新罗也设立“国学”作为最高教育机构。古代高丽的学校非常强调对中国典籍的研究。儒学思想是最主要的学习内容，甚至在高丽王朝将佛教定为官方信仰的背景之下这一状况仍然得以延续。[PARAGRAPH:2]在现代的朝鲜——至少是在南朝鲜（韩国），教育继续得到相当程度的重视。韩国拥有300余座高等学府——包括职业教育学院、高等专科学院、综合性大学以及研究生院等等，登记在册的高校学生数超过200万。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MALI_FORGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>At the height of its power, the Mali Empire had a trading empire that stretched across Africa and into Europe, the Middle East, and Asia; the great wealth of the Mali Empire in large came from the rich gold mines of Bumbuk and Bure. [PARAGRAPH:2]Once the gold was extracted from the mine and purified, it needed to be shaped into a size and form that was easy for the Malinese to transport and to trade. Gold could be formed into large blocks or bars, but these were extremely heavy and cumbersome, and quite awkward to transport on horse/camelback. They were also so expensive that only governments and the very rich would be able to afford them, and so that form was usually reserved for large quantities of gold that were to be transported by ship. For smaller and more convenient uses, gold was formed into coins. [PARAGRAPH:2]A place where money is created is called a "mint." At a mint, the gold is melted and poured into a standardized coin form - or, in earlier times, it might be manually pounded and cut into shape. The coin is usually decorated with the ruler's head or some other recognizable symbol. The value of the gold coin is dependent upon the purity of the metal in the coin, and its weight. Throughout history the unscrupulous have attempted to pass off light or impure coins to unsuspecting purchasers. If widespread, this practice can seriously damage trade and cripple a nation's entire economy. To maintain a reputation for honest dealing, the Malinese needed to use fairly sophisticated measuring tools to ensure that their coins maintained a consistent value. This in turn spurred advancements in science and technology. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在其最兴盛的时期，马里帝国的贸易网络遍及非洲、欧洲、中东及亚洲各地；马里的巨大财富大部分是来自于其丰饶的金矿。[PARAGRAPH:2]黄金从矿石中提炼出来以后，需要加工成容易携带和交易的形状。黄金可以制成大块的金砖或金条，但这样的金子过于沉重，不适宜用马或骆驼驮运。而且也不便于一般商品的交易，因此通常只在存放或船运时采用这种形式。在更多的场合，金子则被铸造成钱币。[PARAGRAPH:2]铸造钱币的地方称为“铸币厂”。铸币厂将黄金融化倒入圆形模子——更早时侯则是靠手工敲打分割成形。铸币上通常印有统治者的头像或是其他易识别的标志。金币的价值是由其所用黄金的纯度及重量决定的。历史上有许多不法之徒用劣质金或假材料制造伪币，伪币的泛滥可能严重损害贸易活动，破坏国家的经济体系。为了保证铸币的信誉，马里人使用精细的工艺制造金币，这在同时也促进了科学技术的发展。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MILITARY_ACADEMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A "military academy" is an educational institution created to prepare young men and women for positions of leadership within the military. Such academies have existed throughout history.  At these institutions students are taught how to command troops, how to communicate effectively, how to read maps, how to give and receive orders. They learn of the history of warfare. They are taught to understand strategy and tactics, as well as engineering, logistics and intelligence, and they often study classic treatises such as Sun Tzu's "The Art of War." They learn how to operate the weapons of the day - whether muzzle-loading rifle or satellite-guided artillery. [PARAGRAPH:2]In most such institutions the young officers are taught a "code of honor" which emphasizes following orders and selfless dedication to their fellow soldiers and to their country. Students usually must follow an extremely rigorous course of physical training to ensure that their bodies are as finely-tuned as their minds. Military academies are undoubtedly effective, and most of the best generals of modern history have emerged from such institutions. [PARAGRAPH:2]President Thomas Jefferson created the United State's Military Academy at West Point in 1802. Its mission is: "To educate, train, and inspire the Corps of Cadets so that each graduate is a commissioned leader of character committed to the values of Duty, Honor, Country and prepared for a career of professional excellence and service to the Nation as an officer in the United States Army." [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>“军事学院”是专门培养男性或女性军官的教育机构。军事学院在古代就已出现，军事学院的学员将学习如何指挥部队、进行通讯、识读地图、传达命令等等。学员还要学习战争史、战略和战术、工程、后勤和情报知识。军事学院的教材包括许多经典兵书，例如《孙子兵法》。学员还要掌握各种武器的使用——或是来复枪、或是卫星定位火炮。[PARAGRAPH:2]大部分军事学院都要求学员尊守“荣誉章程”，强调服从命令、忠于国家、无私奉献、团结协作等等等等。学员也需要接受非常严格的体格训练，使身体和思想都保持强健。军事学院无疑是非常有效的教育机构，现代历史上许多最优秀的将领都曾是军事学院的学员。[PARAGRAPH:2]托马斯·杰斐逊总统于1802年在西点建立了美国军事学院。西点的目标是：“教育、训练和启迪所有学员，使每位毕业生都成为忠于责任、荣誉和国家的优秀指挥员，并为加入美国军队服务于国家的职业军人生涯做好充分准备。”[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MONGOL_STABLES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As nomadic tribesmen (and later as cavalry-based conquerors), the Mongolians' survival was dependent upon the quality of their horses and the skill of their riders. [PARAGRAPH:2]A warhorse must be extensively trained if it is to be successfully used in battle. In their natural state, most horses quite sensibly seek to run away from dangerous situations - say, when surrounded by screaming men armed with sharp objects. A cavalryman's horse, on the other hand, needs to be able to suppress this instinct and instead instantly carry out any order given it by its rider - no matter how suicidal. Such training takes time and skill - for both mount and rider. Mongolian stables provide such training. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>作为一个游牧民族（后来又成为马背上的征服者），蒙古人的生存主要依赖于马匹和骑手的素质。[PARAGRAPH:2]战马在投入战斗前必须经过长时间的训练。马的天性是一遇到危险情况就会逃跑，换句话说，每当被手持锋利武器、口中大声呼喝的人包围时，它们就会这么做。但是作为战马，就必须克服自己的本能，当接到骑手的指令后，无论处于什么境况都必须执行。对战马的训练需要时间和技巧，对马匹和骑手来说都是如此。遍布草原的蒙古毡帐旁的马厩就可以提供这样的训练。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_OTTOMAN_WALLS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>From humble tribal beginnings in western Anatolia, the Ottoman Empire would eventually conquer an area that covered Asia Minor, the Balkans, the Middle East, and Northern Africa. During its seven-hundred year existence, the Empire would come to learn a thing or two about siege warfare and fortifications. [PARAGRAPH:2]During the Middle Ages, like all other Powers the Ottomans needed to protect their cities against attack. The Ottomans surrounded their important cities with heavy and high walls, which stood up well against the siege equipment of the day - catapults and trebuchets and the like. The walls were at least partially effective against the earliest cannon; however, as the strength and accuracy of artillery increased, even the Ottoman's strongest walls provided little protection from the powerful new weapons. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>奥斯曼人从安纳托利亚西部崛起，最终发展成为一个庞大的帝国，领土范围包括小亚细亚、巴尔干、中东及北非大部分地区。在七百年间，奥斯曼人发展出了完善的攻城和守城技术。[PARAGRAPH:2]中世纪的奥斯曼与其他强权一样需要防卫自己的城市免遭攻击。奥斯曼城市都环绕着又厚又高的城墙，能够抵御当时的攻城武器——例如投石车和抛石机。城墙对早期的加农炮也有一定防御能力；但是随着火器的不断改进，最坚固的奥斯曼城墙也无法抵御新式大炮的轰击。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PERSIAN_GROCER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An apothecary is the name of a person who researches and creates herbal medicines (it's also the name of his business establishment). In ancient Persia, the practice of medicine was split between two professions. The "ashpiu" was a sort of sorcerer or witch-doctor, who determined the spiritual cause of the ailment and prescribed the religious and magical rituals necessary for a cure. The ashpiu could also refer the patient to an apothecary or "asu," a combination of pharmacist and physician, who would provide the necessary medicines and treatments to cure the ailment. [PARAGRAPH:2]Persia stood atop one of the great trading crossroads of the world, and their apothecaries had access to medicines and procedures from Africa, Europe, and Asia. And though like anywhere else there was much superstition and misinformation about disease and how best to treat it, Persian medicine was among the most advanced in the ancient world. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>西方语言中“apothecary”一词既指研究和配制草药的“药剂师”，也指药剂师的工作场所“药剂店”。在古代波斯，与医药有关的职业有两种：“巫医”（ashpiu）负责寻找导致疾病的精神原因，也使用巫术进行治疗。巫医在完成诊断之后还可能指点病人进一步求助于药剂师或是“阿苏”（asu）。所谓“阿苏”可以认为是配药师兼内科医师，他们负责提供具体的药物和治疗手段来治愈疾病。[PARAGRAPH:2]波斯人身处古代西方世界的十字路口，他们的药剂师能接触到来自非洲、欧洲和亚洲的各种医药和治疗手段。尽管像其他任何地方一样，波斯人对于导致疾病的机理的治疗疾病的手段包含有许多迷信和错误的成分，但他们的医学古代世界中仍然可以算是最为先进的。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ROMAN_AQUEDUCT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An aqueduct is a channel or pipe that carries water. In ancient times the water was carried from the source (a spring or well) to the destination (a city) by the power of gravity alone. Thus it was necessary that the source be higher than the destination, and that the aqueduct's channel be straight and true, without major dips or kinks to obstruct the flow of water. Also, all seams had to be watertight to prevent leakage. [PARAGRAPH:2]Aqueducts were first employed in the Middle East by ancient Egyptians and Babylonians to supply their massive irrigations systems. However, the form was mastered in ancient Rome. The Roman engineers were the best that the world had yet seen; to quench the thirst of the growing city of Rome they constructed over 260 miles of waterworks, including many remarkable arched bridges to span valleys and rivers. By the first century AD, the complex of aqueducts provided the people of Rome over eighty million gallons of water per day! Many sections of the remarkable structures still stand today, some two millennia after their construction. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>引水渠一种输水设施。在古代，将水从水源（泉水或井水）引到目的地（城市）只能依靠地球的引力。因此水源地的水位必须高于目的地，引水渠也需要保持水平，不能有影响水流的明显起伏。引水渠还需要良好的封闭以避免漏水。[PARAGRAPH:2]引水渠最早出现于中东地区，古埃及人和巴比伦人建造引水渠提供灌溉。但古罗马人充分完善了引水渠的建造技术。罗马拥有当时世界上最出色的工程师，为了满足罗马日益增长的人口的需要，他们建造了长达260英里的输水设施，其中包括跨越山谷与河流的拱桥。到公元1世纪，引水渠每天能为罗马人提供超过八百万加仑的用水！许多罗马引水渠在两千多年后的今天仍然屹立不倒。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RUSSIAN_LABORATORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Russian scientific research has a long and storied history. The great seventeenth century Russian artist and scientist Mikhail Lomonosov (1711-1765) is credited with many important advances in chemistry. He also suggested the wave theory of light long before it was generally accepted, and he helped create the University of Moscow, one of the great scientific institutions of the world. Tsar Peter the Great founded the prestigious Russian Academy of Science by decree in 1724. [PARAGRAPH:2]When the Communists took over Russia in the early twentieth century they placed great emphasis upon modernizing and industrializing the Soviet Union, and they heavily funded scientific research. Though initially well behind their European and American counterparts, Russian scientists quickly caught up, and in some areas - especially in the theoretical sciences - surpassed their colleagues in the West. For a number of decades the Soviets posed a serious challenge to the Americans in space science and exploration. [PARAGRAPH:2]The collapse of the Soviet Union in the latter half of the twentieth century did great damage to scientific research; however, as Russia regains economic strength, it can be expected her scientists, universities and laboratories will once again be among the leaders in the world.  [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>俄罗斯的科学研究有着悠久的历史。俄国伟大的艺术家兼科学家米哈伊尔·罗蒙诺索夫（1711-1765）就曾经参与了莫斯科大学的建设，后者也成为了世界闻名的科研机构。彼得大帝则于1724年设立了享有盛名的俄罗斯科学院。[PARAGRAPH:2]当布尔什维克在二十世纪初统治俄罗斯之后，他们将精力投入到全苏联的工业化和现代化进程上，大力开展科学研究。尽管当时苏联与欧美列强的科技水平相差甚远，但他们很快就迎头赶上，甚至在以理论科学等领域还超过了西方国家。[PARAGRAPH:2]这个红色帝国在二十世纪后半段的崩溃对科学研究造成了极大破坏；不过，随着俄罗斯经济的复苏，国内的科学家、大学以及研究机构再一次以领袖姿态出现在世界舞台上。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UNIVERSITY_OF_SANKORE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The University of Sankore was located in the city of Timbuktu during the height of the Empire of Mali. Founded in the late tenth century AD, the main building was located in Sankore Mosque, a spectacular pyramid-shaped work of architecture. During the sixteenth century AD, the University of Sankore stood at the heart of a great Islamic center of learning. Scholars traveled across the Islamic world from as far away as India and Persia to visit the famed school. [PARAGRAPH:2]The organization of the University of Sankore was very different from that of medieval European universities. It had no central administration, student registers, or prescribed courses of study: instead, it was composed of many entirely independent colleges, each run by a single "imam" (scholar). Students associated themselves with an imam (rather than with a subject or department) and instruction was often carried out on an individual basis. Anyone could establish a college if he so wished; not surprisingly, the quality of the different schools was said to be very uneven. [PARAGRAPH:2]Courses took place in the open courtyards of mosques or in private homes. The primary focus of the university was study of the Qur'an, although some imams gave lessons in history, astronomy, and logic. Scholars were encouraged to write their own books because it was profitable to do so - in the Islamic world at that time, books commanded a much higher price than gold or slaves. Among the most famous scholars at the University of Sankore was Ahmed Baba, a highly-distinguished historian quoted often in Islamic scholarship. [PARAGRAPH:2]Unfortunately, the best scholars left the school during the Moroccan invasion of Mali in the 1590s and did not return later. Sankore was never able to recover its former glory. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>桑科雷大学在马里帝国全盛时期创立，位于庭巴克图古城。其主体建筑即桑科雷清真寺，建于公元10世纪晚期，外形类似金字塔。在16世纪，桑科雷大学是伊斯兰学术的中心。伊斯兰世界各地学者——有的来自遥远的印度和波斯——都集中到这里参观学习。[PARAGRAPH:2]桑科雷大学的教学组织形式与中世纪的欧洲大学有很大差异。它没有集中管理体制，学生也无须注册，也没有预设的课程：整个大学是由许多独立的学院组成的，每个学院由一位“依玛目”（学者）主持。学生从属于某一位学者（而不是某一个专业或系），教学活动往往是个别进行的。任何学者都可以建立自己的学院，当然，不同的学院之间教学水平相差很大。[PARAGRAPH:2]教学是在清真寺的庭院或是私人住宅中进行的。桑科雷大学最主要的学习科目就是《古兰经》，也有许多学者教授历史、天文和逻辑学。学者撰写著作受到鼓励，而且收益不菲——在当时的伊斯兰世界，书籍的价格同黄金或奴隶一般高。桑科雷大学最著名的学者之一是优秀的历史学家艾哈迈德·巴巴，在伊斯兰世界拥有很高的声誉。[PARAGRAPH:2]不幸的是，在16世纪90年代摩洛哥人入侵马里期间，大批优秀的学者被迫离开，此后的桑科雷大学再也未能重现昔日的辉煌。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SPANISH_JAIL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In the eighth century, the European Spaniards began the arduous task of retaking the Iberian Peninsula from its Arabian conquerors (whom the Europeans referred to as "Moors"). The Moors fought tenaciously to hold onto what had become their homes, and the "Reconquista" would take some eight hundred years, until in 1492 Queen Isabella and King Ferdinand finally captured the last Moorish stronghold in Europe, the southern city of Granada. [PARAGRAPH:2]This left Elizabeth and Ferdinand with the problems associated with ruling a conquered country, a large number of whose inhabitants would probably aid the Moors if they launched an invasion. To combat these problems, the royal couple took several actions: they made a peace treaty with the Moors that guaranteed that they would suffer no mistreatment at the hands of Christians, they expelled most of the Jews from Spain (a pointless and brutal early example of "ethnic cleansing"), and they instituted the "Inquisition." [PARAGRAPH:2]The Inquisition was a militant Catholic organization created, (over the Pope's strong objections it should be noted) to root out "heretics" - people pretending to be Catholics, but who in reality worshipped other religions. It carried out its charter with ruthless efficiency and terrible zeal. While both Jews and Muslims suffered at the hands of the Inquisition, Christians were its primary targets, and the bulk of its victims were those who professed to be Catholics. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Inquisition was far less brutal than it has been portrayed in popular history. A very small portion of its prisoners were tortured, for example, and most of the sinister devices - the rack and iron maiden, for instance - attributed to the Inquisition were in fact created and employed by other Europeans elsewhere. But it was still brutal enough: it's been estimated that perhaps as many as 30,000 people were killed outright by the Inquisition, and maybe 120,000 more died of starvation or disease (or despair) in their horrible, overcrowded prisons. [PARAGRAPH:2]To the extent that there was never a serious Moorish revolt in Spain, the program could be said to have been effective. But whether the same results have been achieved through less brutal and horrible means remains an open question. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在8世纪，西班牙人开始逐步将阿拉伯征服者（欧洲人称为“摩尔人”）赶出伊比利亚半岛。摩尔人也奋力保卫自已的领地，这场“光复之役”（Reconquista）持续了八百年，直到1492年伊莎贝拉和斐迪南统治时期，西班牙人才最终占领了摩尔人在欧洲的最后据点格兰纳达。[PARAGRAPH:2]伊莎贝拉和斐迪南面临着如何在新征服地区实施统治的问题，这些地区的许多居民都还指望摩尔人会卷土重来。为此他们采取了一系列措施：同摩尔人签订和约，保证基督徒不干涉摩尔人的信仰自由，并将西班牙的犹太人驱逐流放（残酷“种族清洗”的早期事例），他们还建立了“宗教裁判所”。[PARAGRAPH:2]宗教裁判所是天主教清除“异端”的专政机构，西班牙宗教裁判所的建立受到了民众的广泛反对——许多人被迫皈依天主教，但私下仍在信奉其他宗教。宗教裁判所的工作残酷而高效。犹太人和穆斯林都遭受了疯狂的迫害，但基督徒也不能置身事外，许多天主教徒同样是它的受害者。[PARAGRAPH:2]不过真实的西班牙宗教裁判所并没有人们传说的那样血腥恐怖。受到肉刑折磨的人只是犯人中的一小部分。那些名目繁多可怕刑具很多其实都是欧洲其他地方的宗教裁判所使用的。但西班牙宗教裁判所仍是一个残酷的机构：据估计有30,000人被直接处死，另有120,000人死于饥饿、疾病或是长期监禁导致的绝望。[PARAGRAPH:2]这一系列措施的实行还是相当成功的，并没有带来摩尔人大规模的反抗。当然人们仍然会继续争论，因为用更宽容的方式也许同样能达到效果。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STABLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A stable is any building in which horses are kept; a military stable would also include training grounds, barracks for the troopers, blacksmiths, armories, and the like. A horse must be extensively trained if it is to be successfully used in battle. In their natural state, most horses quite sensibly seek to run away from dangerous situations - say, when surrounded by screaming men armed with sharp objects. A cavalrymen's horse, on the other hand, needs to be able to suppress this instinct and instead instantly carry out any order given it by its rider - no matter how suicidal. Such training takes time and skill - for both mount and rider. Stables provide such training: any civilization which plans to employ large numbers of horsemen would be well-advised to make the investment and build as many stables as possible. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>马厩是饲养马匹的场所；军用的马厩还包括训马场、骑兵军营、铁匠铺、盔甲作坊等等。马需要经过长期的训练才能适应战场环境，因为马的天性是一遇到危险情况就会逃跑，换句话说，每当被手持锋利武器、口中大声呼喝的人包围时，它们就会这么做。但是作为战马，就必须克服自己的本能，当接到骑手的指令后，无论处于什么境况都必须执行。对战马的训练需要时间和技巧，对马匹和骑手来说都是如此。军用马厩就提供这样的训练：任何需要组建大规模骑兵的国家都需要建设足够数量的马厩。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLE_OF_ARTEMIS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Temple of Artemis was located in the city of Ephesus in modern Turkey, and it was considered to be one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. At its grandest the building contained more than 100 marble columns (each 50 feet or more in length) and covered an area larger than the Acropolis in Athens. The first temple built on the site was finished around 600 BC, but was burned down and destroyed some 50 years later. The temple was rebuilt starting circa 550 BC, and its new incarnation was even larger and more magnificent than before. Its construction was sponsored by the Lydian king Croesus and it was designed by the Greek architect Chersiphron. The temple was decorated with bronze sculptures made by the finest artists of the era, including Phidias, Polycleitus, Kresilas, and Phradmon. It served as both a marketplace and a religious institution, drawing tourists from far and wide across Greece and the Near East. [PARAGRAPH:2]Unfortunately, the Temple of Artemis was destroyed again in 356 BC by a man named Herostratus, who deliberately committed arson in an attempt to immortalize his name (in which he obviously succeeded). Legend has it that the temple burned to the ground on the same night as Alexander the Great was born, and that Artemis was too busy attending his birth to save her temple. After Alexander's death, the Temple of Artemis was rebuilt once more, achieving its largest and most impressive size yet. Aside from its roof, the new temple was made entirely out of marble, with steps leading up to a huge terrace that measured 260 by 430 feet in size. The temple was re-adorned with statues, paintings, and other fine artwork, and over time regained its position of glory. [PARAGRAPH:2]When St. Paul visited Ephesus in the first century AD, the Temple of Artemis was still standing and its priests had no intention of renouncing their goddess. Unfortunately, the building was burned down by the Goths during a raid in 262 AD. The Ephesians vowed to rebuild it, but interest in the Hellenic gods and goddesses was beginning to wane by that point. By 400 AD, most of the people of Ephesus had converted to Christianity, and the remnants of the temple were torn down by St. John Chrysostom. The marble from the temple was salvaged for use in other building projects, and almost nothing remains of the Temple of Artemis today. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>阿尔忒弥斯神庙坐落于爱琴海东岸以弗所城（今土耳其境内），是古代西方世界七大奇观之一。在其规模最宏大的时候，神庙主殿竖立着上百根大理石柱，每根高50英尺（15米）以上，占地面积比雅典卫城更大。在此位置上的第一座神庙建成于公元前600年左右，但约50年后遭到焚毁。后在前550年左右完成重建，重建后的神庙比原先那座更为宏伟壮丽。新神庙由吕底亚王克利萨斯出资建造（他的名字现在已是“大富豪”的同义词），由希腊建筑师伽尔瑟夫农主持设计。神庙中所装饰的青铜雕塑均出自当时最杰出的艺术家之手，包括菲迪亚斯、波里克里托斯、克雷西拉斯和福雷德蒙。除作为宗教活动场所外，神庙广场还兼作贸易集市，吸引着希腊和近东地区的大批访问者。[PARAGRAPH:2]不幸的是，阿尔忒弥斯神庙在公元前356年又被一个名叫希罗斯特图斯的疯子再次焚毁，他蓄意纵火以使自己能够名留史册（好吧，显然他确实做到了）。传说神殿化作焦土之夜亦即亚力山大降生之时，阿尔忒弥斯女神因忙于照料他的出世而未能顾及自己的神庙。在亚力山大去世之后，阿尔忒弥斯神庙再获重建，益发彰显其规模之宏大、结构之美妙。除顶部之外，第三座神庙完全由大理石构筑，附以层层台阶一路升叠，通向长260英尺、宽430英尺的广阔月台。神殿以雕像、绘画及其他精美艺术品修饰一新，往日的荣光又再度重现。[PARAGRAPH:2]公元1世纪圣保罗到访以弗所的时候，阿尔忒弥斯神庙依旧巍然矗立，神庙的祭司们多年以来从未想与他们的女神背渎相离。可惜天不遂人愿，这座建筑在公元262年的哥特人入侵中被焚毁殆尽。以弗所人曾誓言要再度恢复其原貌，但是从那一刻起，希腊诸神在尘世的影响力已开始日渐衰落。到公元400年的时候，大多数的以弗所居民都已皈依基督教，残存的建筑也在圣约翰·克里索斯托姆的号召下被彻底拆除（他将其视作异教世界力量的象征）。其中的大理石被移往其他的建筑，时至今日，阿尔忒弥斯神庙遗迹已是荡然无存矣。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VIKING_HARBOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Living in the cold, north, on mountainous inhospitable terrain, the Vikings looked to the sea to provide food and wealth. At their height the Vikings possessed a huge trading empire that spanned much of Europe, the British Isles, Greenland and Iceland, and North Africa. Most Viking cities were on the coast, and usually at natural harbors. [PARAGRAPH:2]A Viking harbor needed to be situated so that it provided ships some protection from the harsh winter storms of the North and Baltic seas. There would be shipyards to build and repair the all-important longboats, warehouses to hold imported and exported goods, and beaches where fishing, trading and war vessels could be pulled ashore when not in use. There would be housing for the workers and their families, and perhaps fortifications to protect the harbor from land or sea assault. [PARAGRAPH:2]Along the coasts of Northern Europe Archaeologists have found traces of dozens of Viking harbors, and it's likely that hundreds more remain to be discovered, each a vital part of a chain that nurtured the greatest maritime empire the world had yet seen. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>维京人生活的环境寒冷而多山，他们主要依靠海洋提供食物和财富。在最兴盛的时期，维京人的贸易网络遍布欧洲大陆、不列颠群岛、格陵兰、冰岛和北非各地。大多数维京城市位于海滨，拥有天然良港。[PARAGRAPH:2]维京港口的选址需要能阻挡北海和波罗的海的强烈风暴，并拥有可建造和修理船只的船坞，存放货物的仓库，以及适合捕鱼、贸易和停放战船的海滩。维京港口还建有工人及其家属的住所，可能还包括防御敌人从陆地或海上攻击的要塞。[PARAGRAPH:2]考古学家在北欧沿海各地发现了许多维京港口的遗迹，可能还有更多的未被发现，这些都是那个古老海洋帝国当年兴旺发达的明证。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ZULU_BARRACKS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Upon ascending to power, the great Zulu leader Shaka implemented a number of important civil and military reforms to his growing civilization. In addition to his important innovations to Zulu warfare - he is often credited with the invention of the famous Zulu "buffalo horns" formation, as well as the introduction of the "iklwa," a short stabbing spear that proved enormously successful in combat - Shaka also reorganized Zulu society to better support his military ambitions. [PARAGRAPH:2]At the age of six, young boys joined Shaka's military as apprentice warriors. (This is a surprising parallel to the way that Spartan boys were raised - though it's unlikely that Shaka every heard of the Spartans.) During their training the Zulu boys were imbued with military fervor, put through rigorous physical exercise, and of course instructed in the use of the Zulu's powerful weapons. In battle they carried supplies and extra weapons for the warriors, and it is believed that they occasionally went out on hit-and-run raids against less dangerous enemy tribes. When the boys reached the appropriate age, they became full-fledged warriors. [PARAGRAPH:2]As a result the Zulu warriors were among the bravest and best-trained soldiers in the world. It was their great misfortune to come up against the British, whose soldiers were also very well trained - and equipped with weapons hundreds of years more advanced than the Zulu's. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在获得统治权之后，伟大的祖鲁首领沙卡在整个祖鲁部族推行了一系列的社会和军事改革。除了最重要的对祖鲁人传统战术的创新——包括著名的祖鲁“牛角”阵形，以及在实战中被证明极其有效的刺杀型短矛“伊基瓦”等等——之外，沙卡还改造了祖鲁的社会组织形式，以更好地满足他的军事野心。[PARAGRAPH:2]祖鲁男孩年满六岁就要加入沙卡的军队做“学徒战士”。（这与古希腊斯巴达人的做法惊人地相似，虽然沙卡不大可能听说过斯巴达人。）这些少年战士在大型特训兵营（“ikhanda”）中接受训练。在训练过程中，祖鲁孩子被灌输以军事狂热，经受严格的体能训练，当然也要学习使用威力强大的祖鲁武器。在战斗中，他们为正规战士携带补给以及额外的武器，据信他们偶尔也会参与对敌方部落的袭扰活动。当孩子们达到适当的年龄，他们就会成为祖鲁军队的正式成员。因此祖鲁战士可以说是当时世界上最勇敢、最训练有素的战士之一。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CARTHAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Carthage was an ancient city-state in North Africa located somewhere near the site of modern Tunis. It was settled by Phoenician colonists from the city of Tyre sometime around 814 BC. According to tradition, the first ruler was a queen named Dido, who is mentioned in a number of surviving Greek and Roman legends. Carthage had an excellent harbor, and the city was well situated to form a maritime empire based on Mediterranean trade. As time passed and Carthage expanded, it gained control over the other Phoenician colonies on the northern coast of Africa. Carthaginian merchants dominated trade in the western Mediterranean, and navigators may have sailed as far as Britain and Nigeria. The rise of Carthage in power and influence would bring it into conflict with first the Greek city-states of Sicily, and later the Roman Republic. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Carthage's government was an oligarchy not unlike that in republican Rome. One or two "Sofetim" (which best translates as "judges") were elected annually from among the wealthy and influential families of Carthage to hold positions of executive and judicial power. These aristocratic families were also represented in a deliberative body that appears to have been similar to the Roman Senate. Although Carthage was primarily controlled by these oligarchs, there were also a few limited elections for minor positions of authority within the government. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Carthage's economic prosperity was based largely upon its lucrative trade with the silver and tin mines of Spain, and those trade routes were jealously guarded by Carthaginian merchants. Culturally, the Carthaginians practiced the polytheistic religion of the Phoenicians, based upon worship of the divine couple Tanit and Ba'al. The Carthaginians also appear to have participated in the unsavory practice of child sacrifice as part of their religion, although some historians have disputed this. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Carthage first came into military conflict with the Greeks over control of the island of Sicily, whose strategic location would allow the Carthaginians to control access to the western Mediterranean. Carthage fought three separate wars against the Greek colonies on Sicily, all of which largely ended in inconclusive stalemates. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Eventually Rome occupied the Greek colonies in the south of mainland Italy, allowing Carthage an opportunity to conquer most of Sicily. Tension between the two states soon boiled over into the First Punic War (264 - 241 BC) during which the Romans recovered from initial setbacks and built a navy for the first time, with which they defeated the Carthaginians at the Battle of the Aegates Islands. This victory won Sicily for Rome, and the two sides entered into an uneasy peace. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]After losing Sicily to the Romans, the Carthaginians expanded their holdings in Spain to compensate. They also began to prepare for a second conflict with Rome. The war faction was led by the members of the Barca family, and in particular the soon-to-be-famous Hannibal. When a border dispute in Spain provoked an incident between the two states, the Carthaginian senate declared war, initiating the Second Punic War (218 - 202 BC). [PARAGRAPH:2:1]During this conflict Hannibal was authorized to lead a campaign into Italy. He led his large force - which included war elephants - across the Alps, taking the Romans completely by surprise (and creating one of the most enduring war stories of all time). Hannibal met and soundly defeated the main Roman army at Lake Trasimene (217). Despite this disaster the Romans mustered up an even larger army the following year. The two forces met at Cannae, and employing a series of brilliant tactical maneuvers, Hannibal once again utterly destroyed the Romans. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Following this grisly slaughter, the Romans adopted a Fabian strategy of retreat, refusing to give battle against Hannibal. Hannibal continued to devastate the Italian countryside for the next decade, but he was unable to knock Rome out of the war. Meanwhile, the Roman general Scipio attacked Carthage's holdings in Spain, gaining complete control of the region by 206. Scipio then led an expedition to Africa itself, and Hannibal was recalled from Italy to defend the city of Carthage. The two sides met at the Battle of Zama in 202 BC and Hannibal was defeated, Scipio taking the name "Africanus" to celebrate his victory. Carthage was forced to sue for peace, and Rome imposed very harsh terms on the city. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Despite the destruction of the Second Punic War and the harsh peace terms, Carthage soon recovered her strength and began once more to exert control over trade in the Western Mediterranean. This caused great fear among the Romans, who had never forgotten the damage that Hannibal had done to Italy in the earlier war. In 149 BC Rome declared war on Carthage again on spurious pretexts, initiating the Third Punic War. The Carthaginians attempted to negotiate a settlement, but the Romans would be satisfied with nothing less than the city's total destruction. After a long siege, the city fell and its people were killed or sold into slavery. Carthage itself was pulled apart brick by brick and completely destroyed. The city would be rebuilt by the Romans, but the former Phoenician state would never rise again. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>迦太基是古代北非地区的一个城邦，位于今突尼斯附近。来自腓尼基的移民于公元前814年左右到达此处建立定居点。据传迦太基的首任统治者是一位女王，名叫狄多，许多流传至今的希腊和罗马传说故事都曾提到她的名字。迦太基拥有一座天然良港，地理位置也十分优越，非常有利于建设一个以地中海沿岸商业活动为基础的海上贸易帝国。随着时间的推移，迦太基的领地不断扩张，逐渐控制了北非沿海的其他腓尼基移民城市。迦太基商人拥有西地中海贸易的支配地位，迦太基航海家最远可能到达过不列颠岛和尼日利亚。迦太基国力和影响的日益增强最终使其同西西里岛上的希腊城邦，以及后起的罗马共和国发生了冲突。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]迦太基拥有一个由贵族寡头掌权的政府，与罗马共和国不无相似之处。每年在各大豪门望族之中选举产生一至两位执政官“斯普瑟姆”（该词的原意为“审判者”）行使行政及司法权力。来自各大豪门望族的代表还组成一个与罗马元老院类似的议事机构。虽然迦太基的权力主要控制在这些大贵族手里，但政府的较低层职位也在有限范围之内通过选举产生。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]迦太基的经济繁荣是建立在其利润丰厚的西班牙银矿、锡矿基础之上的，迦太基商人非常小心地保护这些商路。在文化方面，迦太基人继承了腓尼基人的多神信仰，主要的崇拜对象是坦尼特女神及其配偶巴奥尔。迦太基人似乎还有用婴儿献祭的可怕习俗，不过这在历史学家中还存在争议。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]迦太基为争取西西里岛的控制权而同希腊人发生了军事冲突，该岛的战略地位十分重要，占据西西里就能控制通向西地中海的商路。迦太基与西西里各个希腊移民城市先后进行了三场战争，但基本上都没能获得决定性的结果，各方处于胶着状态。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]后来，罗马人攻占了意大利南部地区的希腊移民城市，迦太基人乘机征服了大半个西西里岛。紧张的对峙最终导致第一次布匿战争的爆发（前264-前241），起初罗马人一度受挫，但很快恢复了力量，并首次建立起自己的舰队，在爱格提斯群岛海战中大败迦太基舰队。这场胜利为罗马赢得了西西里，随后双方勉强实现了和平。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]失去西西里之后，迦太基人努力扩张其在西班牙的领地作为弥补。同时也开始为同罗马进行第二次战争做好准备。迦太基的主战派以巴卡家族的成员为领袖，特别是后来闻名于世的汉尼拔。最终随着一场发生在西班牙的边境冲突，迦太基元老院决定向罗马宣战，拉开了第二次布匿战争（前218-前202）的序幕。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]在这场战争中，汉尼拔受命指挥对意大利半岛的远征。他率领一支大军——其中包括战象——跨越阿尔卑斯山，出其不意地出现在罗马人面前（汉尼拔也因此创造了一个永世不朽的战争传奇）。汉尼拔在特拉西梅诺湖战役（前217）中大胜罗马的主力部队。虽然经历了一场惨败，罗马人又在次年聚集起一支更大规模的军队。双方在坎尼展开决战，通过一系列天才的战术调遣，汉尼拔又一次全歼了罗马大军。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]遭受了这样一场恐怖的屠杀之后，罗马人转而采取以撤退及稳守为主的 “费边战术”，避免与汉尼拔正面交锋。在此后的十年间，汉尼拔不断劫掠意大利的乡村地区，但始终无法摧毁罗马的战斗意志。与此同时，罗马将领西庇阿攻击了迦太基人在西班牙的据点，并于前206年完全控制了这一地区。西庇阿随后率军远征非洲，为此汉尼拔被自意大利召回，以保卫迦太基城。双方于前202年在扎马展开会战，这一次汉尼拔被击败了，西庇阿因这场胜利而获得“阿非利加努斯”的称号。迦太基被迫求和，接受了罗马人严苛的和平条款。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]虽然遭受到第二次布匿战争失败和严苛的和平条款的沉重打击，迦太基仍然快速恢复了实力，重新控制了西地中海的贸易。这使罗马人感到非常恐慌，他们无法忘记汉尼拔在上一场战争中给他们制造的巨大损失。公元前149年，罗马以莫须有的借口再次向迦太基宣战，开始了第三次布匿战争。迦太基人提出进行和平谈判，但罗马不会满足于除完全毁灭迦太基之外的任何和平条件。经过一场漫长的围城战，迦太基终于陷落，所有迦太基人或被杀死，或被卖为奴隶。迦太基城也被完全夷为平地。罗马人后来又在此地建立了新的城市，但先前那个腓尼基移民的国家已经永远消失于历史之中。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_CELT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Celts were a group of Indo-Europeans who inhabited much of Central and Western Europe in the period between 1000 and 500 BC. While Celtic culture today is associated with Ireland, Scotland and Wales, the ancient Celts were spread out over a much larger distance. In addition to those locations, different groups of Celts were also present in Spain, France (Gaul), Hungary, and Bulgaria (Thrace). Although the Greeks and Romans considered the Celts to be barbarians, they possessed a sophisticated and unique culture. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The ancient Celts of Gaul and Britain (who we know the most about) were divided into many tribes loosely based on kinship ties. Social structure was determined by a mixture of class standing within the tribe and one's place within the Celtic religion. Kings were elected to lead the tribes, and society was divided into the three groups: warriors, an intellectual class of druids and bards, and everyone else. Society was based around warfare, but to the Celts it was more of a sport than a battle to the death: raids were the norm, and pitched battles were rare. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The Celts do not appear to have had any large cities, although there were many small towns and fortresses across the regions they controlled. Trade was rather primitive and mostly consisted of a barter economy, although in some coastal regions it was more developed. The Celts shared a common religion emphasizing sacred groves, the role of druids as priests and scholars, and the use of periodic sacrifices (which were occasionally human sacrifices). Celtic gods were named after natural phenomenon and they were quite numerous. Other Celtic practices included the removal of body hair (done to ensure cleanliness) and the taking of enemy heads as trophies in battle. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The most notable event in the early history of the Celts was the sacking of the city of Rome in 390 BC under the great King Brennus. Although the victory was a military triumph and provided a large immediate gain to the Celts, the Romans would prove to have a very long memory, and over the years they would make their enemies pay dearly for it by methodically conquering all Celtic territory their mighty legions could reach. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]By 192 BC, the Romans had subjugated the last of the Celtic tribes in Italy, and they then began a program of colonization of southern Gaul on the Mediterranean coast. Under the great general Julius Caesar, the Romans conquered the entirety of Gaul and defeated a large revolt headed by Vercingetorix between 58 - 51 BC, removing the Celtic threat to the Imperial City once and for all. Under the Emperor Claudius, the Romans went on to invade and occupy Celtic Britain as well. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The Celts remained under Roman rule for the next four centuries until the Germanic invasions of the fifth century AD destroyed the Roman Empire in the west. Although Celtic culture disappeared in many parts of Europe during those years of foreign occupation, it was preserved in Ireland and the western fringe of Britain. Over time the pagan Celtic culture would combine with Christianity to give rise to beautiful new forms of artwork and literature. Despite many attempts over the centuries to destroy it, the Celtic culture survives. In fact, today it enjoys a great deal of popularity and is even experiencing something of a revival. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>凯尔特人是一个属于印欧人种的族群，前1000年至前500年期间在中欧及西欧大部分地区均有分布。虽然凯尔特文化在今天只同爱尔兰、苏格兰和威尔士联系在一起，古代凯尔特人的影响范围则要大得多。除上述地区以外，凯尔特人诸部散居于今西班牙、法国（高卢）、匈牙利和保加利亚（色雷斯）等地。虽然希腊人和罗马人将凯尔特人视为蛮族，其实他们也拥有丰富而独特的民族文化。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]在古代居住于高卢与不列颠的凯尔特人最为我们所熟知，他们根据血缘关系分成许多个小部落。人们在凯尔特社会中的地位受部落内部分工和凯尔特人的宗教信仰影响，分成三个主要阶层：战士、学者（包括德鲁伊祭司和吟游诗人）以及普通人。这是一个尚武的社会，不过对于凯尔特人来说，战斗更象是一种日常运动：主要是为了劫掠财富，而不是硬碰硬的交锋。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]凯尔特人似乎从不建造大型的城市，不过在他们控制的地区也分布着许多小市镇和堡垒。他们的商业非常原始，以易货贸易为主，不过在某些沿海地区则较为发达。凯尔特人拥有共同的宗教信仰，其特征包括作为圣地的“神木林”，兼任学者的德鲁伊祭司，以及定期献祭的制度（有时还用活人献祭）。凯尔特诸神都与自然界相关联，数量非常之多。凯尔特人的其他习俗还包括刮除体毛（保证个人卫生）以及砍下敌人头颅作为战利品等等。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]凯尔特早期历史中最有名的一个事件发生于公元前390年，当时的（高卢）凯尔特人首领布雷努斯率军攻陷了罗马城。虽然这是一场辉煌的胜利，也为凯尔特人带来了巨大的财富，但罗马人是个非常记仇的民族，他们会在多年以后让敌人为自己的行为付出高昂的代价——最终凯尔特人的土地几乎全被罗马人夺走。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]到公元前192年，罗马人征服了在意大利半岛的最后一个凯尔特部落，随即向高卢南部地中海沿岸推进。在朱利乌斯·恺撒的领导下，罗马军队征服了高卢全境，并镇压了以维钦托利为首的凯尔特人大起义（前58-前51年），一劳永逸地解除了（高卢）凯尔特人对罗马的威胁。在克劳迪乌斯皇帝统治时期，罗马人又征服了不列颠的凯尔特人。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]此后四个世纪凯尔特人在罗马人的统治之下生活，直到5世纪时日耳曼人入侵导致西罗马帝国的灭亡。在民族大迁徙的浪潮中，凯尔特文化在欧洲大陆销声匿迹，仅存留于爱尔兰及不列颠西部地区。原始的凯尔特文化也逐渐与基督教文化相融合，形成一种美丽的新艺术与文学形式。虽然数个世纪以来饱受摧残，凯尔特文化始终顽强地生存着。实际上，凯尔特文化在当代越来越受欢迎，甚至可称之为凯尔特文化的复兴。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_KOREA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Archaeological evidence indicates that humans have been living on the Korean peninsula for the last 700,000 years. The earliest discovered settlements date back to at least 3000 BC. According to legend, Korean history began in 2333 BC when King Dangun founded the kingdom of Gojoseon. Dangun was said to have been born of the son of Heaven and a woman from a bear-totem tribe; ancient Korea was characterized by clan communities which combined to form small city-states. The Bronze Age began around 1000 BC in Korea, and many weapons from this period have been found, as well as archaeological evidence of walled settlements. This suggests that the Korean city-states did not always enjoy peaceful relations with one another, despite their nominal unity under the Kingdom of Gojoseon. The kingdom of Gojoseon came to an end in 109 BC when the Chinese launched a massive invasion near the Liao River. The Chinese established four provinces in northern Korea and Manchuria, but were unable to hold these for any length of time. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]After the fall of the Gojoseon kingdom, three new states emerged in Korea (these are collectively known as the "Three Kingdoms"). Baekje was founded in 18 BC on the southwest of the Korean Peninsula; it was based around the city of Seoul and played an important role in transporting Chinese culture (such as Buddhism, iron making, the Chinese alphabet, etc.) across the sea to Japan. Goguryeo was founded in 37 BC; it usually was the largest of the three kingdoms. In addition to its Korean citizens, it also included Chinese and Tugusic tribesman from Manchuria. Finally, the third kingdom of Silla (founded 57 BC) was culturally distinct from the other two because of the cultural influence of northern nomads from the steppes - Baekje and Goguryeo were mostly dominated by Chinese culture. The three kingdoms coexisted on the peninsula for over six centuries, until King Munmu of Silla ordered an attack on Baekje in 660 AD. With the help of forces from Tang China, the Sillans conquered first Baekje and then Goguryeo (in 668 AD). The Sillans then drove out the Chinese and ruled over a united Korean state. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Unified Silla remained peaceful and prosperous for the next two centuries, until it was overthrown in 935 AD by a new dynasty, the kingdom of Goryeo, which would last for over four hundred years. During this period laws were codified, a civil service system was introduced, and Buddhism spread throughout the Korean peninsula. In 1231 the Mongols invaded Korea, and the king of Goryeo was forced to surrender a short time later. Under the treaty of capitulation the Korean kings continued to rule as a figurehead, while the Mongols held all of the real power. As time passed the Mongol power began to decline, and in the 1340s King Kongmin was able to throw them out. Upon regaining power the Goryeo dynasty enacted important reforms to the government. It remained in power some fifty years, until overthrown by the turncoat Korean general Yi Seonggye in 1392. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Yi Seonggye had been sent to China to fight against the Ming Chinese, but once there he switched sides and returned to Korea backed by Chinese power. He then overthrew the Goryeo Dynasty and founded his own. This new Joseon Dynasty moved the capital to Seoul and adopted Confucianism as the state religion, causing great loss of power and wealth by Korea's Buddhists. The Joseon state successfully fought off a series of invasions from Japan between 1592 and 1598, but succumbed to an attack by the Qing Dynasty of China in 1636. For the next two centuries Korea remained nominally independent, but in actuality was a province of the Chinese Qing Empire. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]At the end of the nineteenth century Korea was invaded and occupied by Japan after its victories over China in the Sino-Japanese War (1894-95) and Russia in the Russo-Japanese War (1904-05). The Japanese ruthlessly exploited the Korean population and attempted to destroy the Korean culture in order to replace it with their own. After Japan's defeat in World War II (1945), Korea was divided at the thirty-eighth parallel into north and south regions, a division which the Korean War of 1950-53 made permanent. South Korea has since become a prosperous economic powerhouse, while North Korea remains stifled by an oppressive communist regime. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>（塞爱维小提示：以下内容基本属于高丽人意淫，不足为信，姑妄听之可也）[PARAGRAPH:2:1]考古证据表明早在70万年前，朝鲜（高丽）半岛上就有人类居住，目前发现的最早人类定居点则可上溯至公元前3000年。根据神话传说，高丽民族的历史是从公元前2333年开始的，在这一年，“檀君大王”建立了“古朝鲜王国”。据说檀君系天上下凡的父亲和一位以熊为图腾的部落女子所生。古朝鲜实际上包括了各个部族组成的许多小城邦。古朝鲜约于公元前1000年进入青铜时代，当时制造的兵器有大量出土，考古证据也表明这一时期的居民点已有城墙保护。以上情况说明各个城邦虽然在名义上同属于古朝鲜王国，但相互之间并不总是和平相处的。古朝鲜王国最终于公元前109年灭亡，当时中国汉朝军队越过辽河，对其发动大规模入侵。汉朝在今朝鲜半岛北部及中国东北地区建立了四个郡治，但其统治所维持的时间并不长久。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]古朝鲜王国灭亡后，朝鲜半岛上逐渐形成了三个新国家（合称“三国”）。其中百济建立于公元前18年，位于半岛西南部以今首尔市为中心的地区，在输入中华文化（例如佛教、铁器、汉字）并向日本传播方面发挥了重要的作用。高句丽建立于公元前37年，在三国中面积最大，高句丽的居民除了朝鲜人，还包括今中国东北地区的汉人和通古斯人。新罗建立于公元前57年，在文化上深受亚洲北部游牧民族的影响，同另两国存在明显的差异——百济和高句丽基本是以中华文化为主导的。三国鼎立的状态在朝鲜半岛保持了六个世纪之久，直到660年新罗的文武大王开始对百济的进攻。在中国唐朝军队的帮助下，新罗先后征服了百济和高句丽（668年）。新罗随后又逐走唐军，最终统一了整个朝鲜半岛。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]统一的新罗王国在此后两个世纪保持和平与繁荣，直到935年被一个新的王朝——高丽所取代，高丽王朝的统治持续了四百余年。高丽王朝制定了完备的法律，引入了文官制度，并定佛教为官方信仰，遍传整个朝鲜半岛。到1231年，蒙古入侵高丽，高丽国王被迫投降。高丽国王虽仍是名义上的统治者，但实际权力均掌握在蒙古人手中。随着时间的推移蒙古开始走向衰落，到14世纪40年代，高丽恭愍王终于摆脱了蒙古人的控制重新掌权，并大力推动政治改革，但其后高丽王朝仅维持了约五十年，即于1392年被大将李成桂发动的兵变所推翻。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]李成桂受高丽国王之命出兵对抗中国明朝军队，但却在阵前倒戈相向，在中国军队的支持下杀回国都，废黜旧主自立为王。李成桂建立的朝鲜李氏王朝迁都汉阳（今首尔），并改奉儒学为官方信仰，在高丽王朝受到厚待的佛教势力遭受沉重打击。李氏朝鲜成功击退了1592至1598年的日本入侵（“壬辰倭乱”），但却于1636年被清军征服。此后的两个世纪，朝鲜保持着名义上的独立，但实际上已是中国清朝属下的一个省份。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]到19世纪末，迅速崛起的日本连续赢得中日甲午战争（1894-95）和日俄战争（1904-05）的胜利，入侵并吞并了朝鲜。日本人残酷地压迫朝鲜人民，并试图消灭朝鲜文化，以日本文化取而代之。日本在第二次世界大战中战败后（1945年），朝鲜以北纬38度线为界被一分为二，1950-53年的朝鲜战争使分裂状态持续至今。南朝鲜（大韩民国）逐步发展为繁荣的经济强国，而北朝鲜（朝鲜民主主义人民共和国）则在共产政权统治下陷于停滞状态。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_VIKING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>More properly known as Scandinavians or Norsemen, the Vikings were a group of people from northern Europe who became famous for carrying out a series of raids across the continent between roughly 800 - 1050 AD. The period is sometimes known as the "Viking Age," and it was an era of chaos and disruption for large parts of Europe. The Vikings can be classified into three main groups: the Danes largely attacked England; the Norwegians visited Scotland, Ireland, and points further west; while the Swedes invaded the river systems of what is now Russia. Although the Vikings usually employed hit and run tactics, many of them settled in new communities in the areas they had subjugated, eventually mixing with the local population. And while the Vikings are thought today to be bloodthirsty brigands, they probably acted more often as commercial traders than as warriors.[PARAGRAPH:2:1]Historians debate the reason why the Vikings suddenly emerged from Scandinavia at the end of the eighth century AD and began preying upon other parts of Europe. Theories include: the Vikings were suffering overpopulation caused by better agricultural tools; that the unification of Norway led to an excess of idle warriors; the Vikings were reacting to attempts by the Franks to muscle them out of the trade with the east; or that the men went off to raid and pillage out of simple boredom. One particularly interesting theory is that the climate of Europe was warmer during the early Middle Ages, leading to an excess population in Scandinavia and the subsequent Viking colonization of places such as Iceland and Greenland. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Whatever the actual reason for their expansion, the Viking drive outward began with the sacking of the important island monastery of Lindisfarne, located off the coast of Britain, in 793 AD. England was regularly raided by the Danes in the following decade, and in 865 a major invasion landed in East Anglia. This force was led by several landless Viking kings; in the battles that followed most of the English kingdoms were defeated, but the state of Wessex under Alfred the Great managed to hold the invaders off. The Vikings settled in Northumbria, and their territory became known as the "Danela" (most of these Vikings were Danes). [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Another wave of Vikings landed in England in 947 under the command of Erik Bloodaxe, who managed to capture the city of York. Vikings would largely remain in control of England until the Norman invasion of 1066 - and the Normans were themselves the French descendents of Vikings. Scotland and Ireland also experienced a heavy Norwegian Viking presence at this time; a number of important cities were founded by them - including Dublin. Eventually the Vikings settled down and intermarried with the native Irish. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The main target for Viking aggression, however, was France. All throughout the ninth century the Vikings sailed up and down the Seine River with impunity, sacking French towns and monasteries at their leisure. Finally the French king Charles the Simple made an agreement with the Viking leader Hrolf Ganger in 911, in which Hrolf was granted control over territory in northern France. In exchange, Hrolf and his men agreed to convert to Christianity and become vassals of the French king. Hrolf's name was changed to Rollo and he became duke of the province of Normandy (named for the Norsemen who settled in it). The Normans retained their martial edge even after conversion to Christianity, and would go on to make a number of important conquests in England, the Mediterranean, and during the Crusades. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The exploits of the Viking sailors were the stuff of legend. Viking mariners found their way to Iceland, Greenland, and even Newfoundland in North America, setting up colonies in all of these locations. Viking longboats were both fast and seaworthy, and their shallow drafts allowed them sail far up the river systems of Europe. The Vikings could strike from the sea and be gone again before the military forces of a kingdom could be marshaled to meet them. In the east, the Swedes traveled down the rivers of modern Russia and founded the state of Kievan Rus', which grew rich off the river trade between the Baltic and the Byzantine Empire. These Vikings also found employment as mercenaries within the Byzantine domains, and their most elite warriors found employment in the Byzantine Varangian Guard. The Viking Age finally came to a close around 1050AD, as the Vikings were incorporated into Christian Europe and settled down to the less exciting but more stable pursuits of agriculture and fishing; their reputation as fierce invaders from the sea has endured to this day. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>“维京人”的更准确名称应为“斯堪的纳维亚人”或“北欧人”，他们的巨大声名主要来自于800至1050年间在欧洲各地的劫掠生涯。这一时期也因而被称为“维京时代”，当时的欧洲大部分地区都因维京入侵而陷于混乱和恐慌。维京人可以细分为三大族群：丹麦人，他们入侵的对象主要是英格兰；挪威人，他们航行的方向包括苏格兰、爱尔兰，以及更遥远的西方；瑞典人则沿河流深入今属俄罗斯的广袤原野。维京人通常都是四处流动袭扰，但其中也有一部分在他们所征服的土地上定居下来，最终同原住民融合在一起。虽然当代的人们总是把维京人视为一群嗜血的暴徒，但是他们最常从事的职业其实是商人而非战士。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]对于8世纪末的维京人为何突然离开斯堪的纳维亚掀起入侵欧洲大陆的风潮，历史学家仍在争论不休。相关的理论包括：维京人农业技术的发展造成人口过度膨胀；挪威的统一导致大批战士无所事事；法兰克人大力挤占东欧贸易份额激起维京人的报复；或仅仅是由于维京人厌倦了沉闷无趣的定居生活想找点刺激……另一个有趣的理论认为中世纪早期欧洲气候变暖导致斯堪的纳维亚人口大量增加，也使得冰岛和格陵兰更适于移民居住。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]无论真正的原因为何，维京人扩张的时代开始了，他们最早发动的一次袭击是在793年洗劫不列颠东部海滨著名的林迪斯法尼岛修道院。此后十余年英格兰频繁遭丹麦人入侵，包括865年对东盎格利亚的大规模进攻。这批维京入侵者包括多名失去领地的维京王族，当时的英格兰诸王国大都被摧垮，只有西撒克斯王国在阿尔弗雷德大帝的领导下击退了入侵者。这批维京人随后在诺森伯兰定居下来，其领地被称为“丹尼拉”（因为他们主要来自丹麦）。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]947年，另一批维京人在埃里克·布拉德艾克斯的率领下登陆英格兰并攻占了约克。此后维京人继续统治英格兰大部分地区，直到1066年的诺曼征服——而实际上诺曼人就是定居法国的维京人后裔（详情见后文）。在这一时期，苏格兰与爱尔兰也处于来自挪威的维京人控制之下，当地的许多城市都是他们建立的——包括都柏林。维京移民与爱尔兰原住民相互通婚，逐渐融合到一起。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]不过维京入侵的最主要对象还是法国。在整个9世纪，维京人沿塞纳河横行无阻，随心所欲地劫掠法国城镇与修道院。911年，当时的法王“庸人”查理与维京人首领赫罗夫·冈格尔签订和约，赫罗夫获得了法国西北地区的统治权，作为交换，赫罗夫及其手下皈依了基督教并承认法王的宗主权，他们被称为“诺曼人”（即“北方人”之意），改名罗洛的赫罗夫也就成为诺曼底公爵。诺曼人在皈依基督教之后仍然保持着尚武的传统，他们对英格兰及地中海沿岸的征服在历史上造成了深远的影响，也是十字军东征的重要参与者。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]维京人的海上探险历险仿佛是一部传奇。维京航海家的足迹远至冰岛、格陵兰，甚至北美洲的纽芬兰，在这些地方建立了许多定居点。维京人的海船航速极快且易与操纵，由于吃水较浅也能够深入欧洲内河。因此维京人能够快速自海上发动袭击，并在敌人的大军赶到前扬长而去。瑞典人在东欧溯江而上，建立了后来的基辅罗斯公国，基辅罗斯凭借内河航运优势在波罗的海诸国与拜占庭帝国之间开展繁忙的贸易活动。许多维京人还成为了拜占庭帝国的雇佣军，即“瓦兰吉卫士”。随着维京人逐渐融入欧洲基督教世界，他们转而从事农业和渔业，开始平静的定居生活。到1050年左右，维京时代最终结束，但他们的海上劫掠生涯留给世人的印象实在太深刻了，直到今天，“维京人”依然是“海盗”的同意词。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OTTOMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Ottoman Empire was a Turkish state situated upon the eastern Mediterranean that lasted for some 630 years, from 1299 - 1922 AD. At the height of its power, in the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries, the Ottoman domains stretched across vast regions in Anatolia, the Balkans, the Near East and northern Africa. For several centuries it was one of the foremost military powers in the world (until it began to stagnate technologically and fell far behind its competitors).[PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottoman state began as a vassal of the earlier Seljuk Turks, who had formed a large empire in the Near East in the eleventh century. When the Seljuk state of Rum in Anatolia collapsed, the Ottomans took advantage of the ensuing power vacuum and rose in power. According to tradition, Osman I became the bey, or chief, of the state of S&#246;?&#252;t in 1281. When Osman captured the Byzantine city of Bilecik in 1299, he declared his state's independence from the Seljuks. This is the traditional date given as the foundation of the Ottoman Empire - which was named after its first leader, Osman. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottomans expanded rapidly in Anatolia throughout the fourteenth century. A series of capable military leaders made many gains against the tottering Byzantine state. The important cities of Nicaea and Nicomedia fell in 1331 and 1337, and by the 1360s the Ottomans had crossed over into Europe and began capturing territory in Thrace. As a sign of this growing power, Murad I declared himself a sultan (or king) in 1383. Around the year 1400, Timur invaded Anatolia. This caused a great deal of disruption, but the Ottomans bounced back and continued to make territorial gains. Under the rule of Mehmed II, the Ottomans attacked and captured Constantinople, whose mighty walls finally fell to the cannon of the Ottomans. This destroyed the Byzantine Empire, and the Ottomans made Constantinople their capital. Mehmed II became known as "Mehmed the Conqueror." Suleiman I, also known as Suleiman the Magnificent, continued to expand and consolidate the Empire; the Ottomans were at the height of their power and influence during his reign[PARAGRAPH:2]After the capture of Constantinople the Ottoman state virtually adopted the Byzantine civil service to run the empire, and its administration was generally sound (until the nineteenth century, when it began to fossilize and became outdated). The Ottoman Empire was very much a pre-modern dynastic state, made up of many different nationalities - in fact, Greeks largely ran its bureaucracy and were vital to its continued success. Militarily, the Ottomans were very strong largely because of their early adoption of gunpowder and their powerful cavalry forces. The military also employed elite slave soldiers known as "janissaries" who won victory after victory for the expanding Ottoman state. The military remained powerful until the late eighteenth century, when they fell fatally behind Western Europe in military technology. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Ottomans were known for their religious tolerance. The Empire was an Islamic state, and Islamic law dominated its legal system, but non-Muslims were generally well treated and enjoyed the freedom to worship their own religion. The Ottoman Empire was long seen as a refuge for Jews across Europe. Economically, the Ottoman Empire was somewhat of a failure. Most of the region's commerce was carried on by Greek or Italian merchants, which slowed the development of Turkish industry. Once the European voyages of exploration found new routes to India and China which did not involve passing through the Near East, the Ottoman Empire began a slow commercial decline. [PARAGRAPH:2]By the start of the nineteenth century, the Ottoman Empire still held enormous amounts of land, but the empire was stagnant and corrupt, and was widely viewed as the "sick man of Europe." The western powers, their commercial and military strength exploding under the influence of the Industrial Revolution, began to snap up vulnerable Ottoman territories. Britain and France forced humiliating commercial treaties on the Ottomans, and the Ottoman state was forced to take out massive loans to cover its debts - the start of a vicious cycle which only incurred more debt for the empire. [PARAGRAPH:2]While some positive reforms were carried out in terms of modernizing the Ottoman state, custom and tradition prevented the reformers from moving fast enough. Furthermore, the rising tide of nationalism began to tear the empire apart, as Serbians, Bulgarians, Romanians, and Greeks all declared their independence and set up their own nations. By the outbreak of World War I, the Ottomans had lost virtually all of their holdings in Europe. Desperate to preserve what was left, the Ottomans threw in their lot with the Central Powers (Germany and Austria), only to be defeated by a British-led Arab revolt in the Near East. When the war ended the victors partitioned and dissolved the Ottoman Empire at the Paris peace conference. However, the Turkish Revolution prevented the planned division of Anatolia from taking place. With the creation of the nation of Turkey in 1922, and the deposition of the final sultan Mehmed VI, the Ottoman Empire came to a close. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>奥斯曼帝国最初是一个位于地中海东岸的土耳其人（突厥人）小邦，至今约有630年的历史（1299-1922）。在其处于力量巅峰时期的16至17世纪，奥斯曼帝国的领土包括安纳托利亚、巴尔干、近东及北非的大部分地区，并拥有世界上最强大的军事实力（但后来其发展陷入停滞，开始落后于欧洲列强）。[PARAGRAPH:2]奥斯曼最初只是塞尔柱土耳其的附庸，塞尔柱土耳其是11世纪时近东地区的一个大帝国。当塞尔柱人在安纳托利亚地区的统治崩溃之后，奥斯曼人抓住时机开始崛起。据记载，奥斯曼一世于1281年成为索古特邦的拜伊（首领）。1299年他率军攻占拜占庭帝国的城市比莱奇克之后，他宣布脱离塞尔柱独立建国。这被认为是奥斯曼帝国建立的标志——帝国的名称也是来自于她的创立者奥斯曼一世。[PARAGRAPH:2]整个14世纪，奥斯曼人在安纳托利亚迅速扩张。一系列能力出众的军事领袖使其从风雨飘摇的拜占庭帝国夺取了大片土地。地位显要的重镇尼西亚和尼科美迪亚分别于1331年和1337年落入奥斯曼人之手，到14世纪60年代，奥斯曼人已跨越海峡进入欧洲，开始控制色雷斯地区。随着实力的不断增强，穆拉德一世于1383年宣布自己为“苏丹”（国王）。到1400年左右，帖木儿率军入侵安纳托利亚，对奥斯曼人造成了巨大的打击，但奥斯曼人很快恢复了元气，重新开始扩张。在穆罕默德二世统治时期，奥斯曼人凭借大炮的威力攻占了君士坦丁堡，灭亡了拜占庭帝国，并将君士坦丁堡定为新首都。穆罕默德二世也因此获得了“征服者穆罕默德”的称号。苏莱曼一世（“苏莱曼大帝”）继续帝国的扩张与巩固事业，在他的统治下，奥斯曼帝国达到其力量与影响的顶峰。[PARAGRAPH:2]在占领君士坦丁堡后，奥斯曼人实际上开始依靠拜占庭所建立的一套文官制度管理整个帝国，政府机构基本运转良好（但到19世纪时这套制度已变得僵化过时）。奥斯曼帝国是一个传统型的封建王朝，境内居住着各位不同的族群——事实上，希腊人是帝国官僚系统的最主要组成部分。在军事方面，奥斯曼帝国具有很强的实力，这主要是因为其迅速引入了火器，并拥有强大的骑兵部队。奥斯曼军队还包括一支由奴隶战士组成的精锐部队“苏丹亲兵”，这支部队在帝国的扩张战争中发挥了巨大的作用。但到18世纪晚期，奥斯曼的军事实力走向衰落，在军事技术方面严重落后于欧洲列强。[PARAGRAPH:2]奥斯曼帝国实行宽松的宗教政策。虽然伊斯兰教是官方信仰，伊斯兰法主导着帝国的司法系统，但非穆斯林也受到良好的对待，可以自由地信奉各自的神灵。奥斯曼帝国长期被欧洲各地的犹太人视为他们的避难所。在经济方面，可以说奥斯曼帝国做得相当失败。各地的商业活动主要被希腊和意大利商人所把持，这导致土耳其民族工业的发展陷于停滞。随着开始大航海时代的到来，欧洲人建立了通向印度和中国的新商路，无须再经过近东地区，奥斯曼帝国在商业上日益衰退。[PARAGRAPH:2]到19世纪初，奥斯曼帝国虽然仍控制着大片领土，但帝国的根基已经腐败变质，被世人视为“欧洲病夫”。西方列强的经济军事实力由于工业革命的影响而呈现爆炸性的增长，他们不断蚕食日益衰落的奥斯曼帝国的领地。英国和法国迫使奥斯曼帝国签订屈辱的商业条约，奥斯曼人为弥补国债而不断大量贷款——由此形成恶性循环，帝国的债务变得越来越多。[PARAGRAPH:2]虽然奥斯曼人积极尝试进行现代化改革，强大的传统习惯势力却使得改革者步履维艰。与此同时，民族主义浪潮也开始兴起，将帝国冲得四分五裂，塞尔维亚人、保加利亚人、罗马尼亚人以及希腊人纷纷宣布独立建国。到第一次世界大战爆发时，奥斯曼人实际上已经失去了几乎所有的欧洲领地。为了保住剩余的领土，奥斯曼人将赌注押在中欧强权（德国和奥匈帝国）身上，结果却是一场惨败。英国人帮助阿拉伯人在近东发动大规模起义。到大战结束时，战胜国通过凡尔赛和约使奥斯曼帝国走向解体。然而，进一步分割安纳托利亚的企图被土耳其革命的爆发所阻止。随着土耳其共和国于1922年成立，末代苏丹穆罕默德六世被废黜，奥斯曼帝国的历史也走到了尽头。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_ZULU_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Zulu came from a group of peoples known as the Nguni, a linguistic subgroup of the Bantu family of languages. The Nguni had been migrating south for almost a thousand years before reaching the region of the White Umfolozi River around 1700 AD. It was here that the Zulu decided to settle and make their home, according to tradition in 1709. The Zulu are named after Zulu kaNtombhela, who was the founder and chief of the tribe. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Zulu were never more than one unremarkable small tribe among many - until the coming of the great warrior Shaka Zulu, who was born sometime around 1787. While growing up, Shaka was exiled by his father and found refuge with Digiswayo, the chief of another neighboring tribe. When his father died around 1816, Digiswayo helped Shaka succeed to the Zulu throne. [PARAGRAPH:2]Once in power Shaka instituted something of a military revolution among the Zulus, replacing the traditional "assegai" (a javelin-like throwing spear) with a shorter stabbing spear called the "lklwa." He also equipped his warriors with a larger shield which covered most of the soldier's body. This change in Zulu weaponry reflected Shaka's innovations in warefare: while previous battles had tended to be somewhat ritualistic - with much chanting and spear-throwing at a distance - and thus did not have decisive results, Shaka taught the Zulu to kill. [PARAGRAPH:2]Under Shaka's command, the Zulu warriors would close to melee range with their opponents, where their shorter stabbing spears were more effective than the opposition's throwing weapons. Shaka also taught his warriors to fight in a new tactical formation known as the "buffalo horns. Under this formation the center of the Zulu line would engage the enemy to hold them in position, while the right and left "horns" would move forward and envelop the enemy. Outflanked on right and left and equipped with inferior weapons, few enemies could stand up to the Zulu assault; the Zulu were soon terrorizing the neighboring tribes. [PARAGRAPH:2]Within a decade, Shaka had accumulated an army of 50,000 warriors, defeated all of the surrounding tribes, and was master over most of the interior of what is now South Africa. Shaka set up a new capital for the Zulu at Bulaweyo, but his arrogance and cruelty caused dissatisfaction among his people. In 1828 Shaka was assassinated by his half-brothers Dingane and Mhlangana. Dingane then immediately killed Mhlangana and began a purge of the pro-Shaka chieftains under his control. [PARAGRAPH:2]It was into this picture of chaos and violence that the European settlers first began appearing onto the scene in the 1830s. The first European settlement in the Zululand region was the English colony of Port Natal (modern Durban). An English missionary went to live with the Zulu in 1837, and was tolerated by King Dingane. However, at the same time a group of Boer settlers known as the "Voortrekkers" (or pioneers) were moving north across the Orange River into the now-empty lands which had been vacated by tribes fleeing the Zulu. Dingane had given the Voortrekkers permission to settle in the area, but in 1838 - either as the result of a misunderstanding or because Dingane had planned it from the start - the Zulus attacked the newcomers. [PARAGRAPH:2]This proved to be a huge mistake. At the Battle of Blood River, the Zulus vastly outnumbered their opposition, having 10,000 warriors fighting 400 Boers. Despite the odds, however, the Boers slaughtered their opponents, their firearms giving them an overwhelming advantage against their spear-wielding opponents. The Zulus were forced to allow the white men to settle in their territory, which became known as the Republic of Utrecht. [PARAGRAPH:2]Following the battle, there was a generation of uneasy peace between the Zulus and the growing British and Boer presence in the region. However, after the discovery of diamond mines in South Africa in 1878, the British cast covetous eyes on the Zulu land, and they began to look for an excuse to attack and displace the natives. Following a minor border dispute in 1878, the British declared war and invaded Zululand on three fronts. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Zulu warriors fought bravely (and much to the Europeans' shock managed to slaughter a British force at Isandlwana), but the British rifles and Maxim guns made the ferocity of individual Zulu warriors irrelevant, and the outcome of the war was never in doubt. The Zulu were defeated and Zululand was incorporated into British South Africa. King Cetshwayo was taken to London to meet Queen Victoria as an honored prisoner. However, the rest of the nation did not fare so well, and the Zulus spent the next century under British and Afrikaner domination, forced to live under the racist apartheid laws of South Africa. [PARAGRAPH:2]Following the fall of apartheid in the 1990s, however, today Zulus enjoy full citizenship rights in South Africa. Zulu is the most widely spoken language in the country, and with over 11 million people, the Zulus are the largest ethnic group in South Africa. [PARAGRAPH:2] </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>祖鲁人源自恩古尼人（南部非洲班图语系诸民族之一）。恩古尼人在近千年时间里不断向南迁徙，约在公元1700年（或1709年）到达白乌姆福洛济河流域并最终定居下来。“祖鲁”这一称谓得名于部族创立者及首领祖鲁·卡恩托姆伯拉。[PARAGRAPH:2]起初的祖鲁只是一个不起眼的小部族——直到伟大的勇士沙卡·祖鲁成为他们的领袖。沙卡出生于约1787年，是一个私生子，他在尚未成年时即被其父放逐，流落到邻近的姆特瓦部族，被首领丁吉斯瓦约收留。其父于约1816年去世，丁吉斯瓦约又帮助沙卡成为祖鲁首领。[PARAGRAPH:2]沙卡掌权之后，在整个祖鲁部族推行军事改革，淘汰了传统的投射型长矛“阿塞盖”，代之以刺杀型短矛“伊基瓦”。他还让手下的战士装备能保护整个躯体的盾牌。这些变革体现了沙卡的新战争理念：过去的部族战争还保存着某种仪式性质——交战双方吟唱歌谣，在远距离投掷标枪——实际杀伤作用十分有限，沙卡则要教会祖鲁人如何进行真正的杀戳。[PARAGRAPH:2]根据沙卡的要求，祖鲁战士必须迅速冲锋，与敌人进行肉搏战。在近战中，刺杀型短矛比投射型长矛更有杀伤力。沙卡还指导他的战士组成一种名为“牛角”的新式作战阵形。中央阵线负责阻止敌军前进，左右“牛角”则负责包抄敌军的侧翼，很少有敌人能够抵御这样强大的攻势。[PARAGRAPH:2]在十年时间内，沙卡聚集起一支五万人的大军，击败了所有邻近的部族，控制了今南非内陆的大部分地区。沙卡在布拉维约建立了祖鲁王国的新首都，但他的骄傲自大和残酷无情激起了许多臣民的不满。1828年，沙卡被他的异母兄弟丁冈和穆赫兰加纳阴谋刺杀，随后丁冈又杀死了穆赫兰加纳，并开始对支持沙卡的酋长们进行大清洗。[PARAGRAPH:2]在一片血腥与混乱之中，首批欧洲移民于19世纪30年代到达这里。在祖鲁地区（“祖鲁兰”）的首个欧洲移民城市是纳塔尔港（今德班）。一位英国传教士于1837年在丁冈国王的许可下深入祖鲁人的领地。而与此同时，一批布尔人（定居南非的荷兰移民后代）“先驱者”也向北渡过奥兰治河，进入因祖鲁人扩张战争而被逃离的原住民所抛弃的土地。丁冈同意他们在该处定居，但到了1838年——或是因为双方发生误会，或是因为丁冈早有预谋——祖鲁人又对这批新移民发动了进攻。[PARAGRAPH:2]事实证明祖鲁人犯下了一个巨大的错误。这场冲突史称“血河之战”，祖鲁人在数量上占据绝对优势：他们拥有10,000名战士，布尔人仅有400人。结果却成了一边倒的屠杀，祖鲁长矛完全不是布尔人火器的对手。最终祖鲁人被迫同意白人在自己的领地上定居，布尔人的“乌得勒支共和国”自此建立。[PARAGRAPH:2]血河之战后，祖鲁人、英国人和布尔人之间维持着并不稳定的和平状态。然而到了1878年，南非丰富的钻石矿藏被发现了，英国人贪婪的目光紧盯着这片土地，时刻寻找攻击并逐走原住民的借口。1878年，英国以一场微不足道的边境争端为由，从三个方向全面入侵祖鲁兰。[PARAGRAPH:2]祖鲁战士英勇地抵抗入侵者，他们在伊桑德瓦纳战役中歼灭了英军一个整团，令全欧洲感到震惊（塞爱维小提示：此役有1300余名英军阵亡，是长矛打败来复枪的真实战例），但英国人的来复枪和马克沁机枪使祖鲁人的勇气失去了意义，战争的结果是毫无悬念的。祖鲁人战败了，祖鲁兰并入了英属南非。祖鲁国王塞奇瓦约作为战俘被送往伦敦，受到维多利亚女王的礼遇。但他的臣民的命运则要悲惨得多，南非祖鲁人在英国人和土生白人的统治下遭受种族隔离制度的压迫。[PARAGRAPH:2]南非种族隔离制度直到20世纪90年代才最终取消，南非祖鲁人获得了完全的公民权。目前祖鲁语是南非最通用的语言，祖鲁族人口有1100万，是南非诸民族中最大的一个。[PARAGRAPH:2] </Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_BRENNUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Brennus[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Celtic Chieftain[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2:1][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Other than that he was a fearsome and successful warrior, little is known about the Celtic chieftain named Brennus. In 279 BC, he led an army of Celtic warriors on an invasion of Macedonia and northern Greece. They turned the Greek defense at the pass of Thermopylae and sacked the famous Oracle at Delphi - Brennus was wounded in the fighting. From there, the Celts penetrated into Epirus (roughly modern Albania) and looted the treasures stored at the temples of Zeus at Dodona and Olympia. After those triumphs the Greek resistance stiffened. Brennus retreated to Macedonia, where he died of his wounds. Without the leadership of their chieftain, the Celtic warriors split up and went in separate directions. Most of them returned to their homes in Gaul along with the treasure they had pillaged, while a few others headed east and settled in Asia Minor. This group came to be called the Galatians, and remained distinct from their surrounding neighbors for at least two centuries. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The name "Brennus" is more likely a title than a proper name - in fact the same title was later given to another Celtic chieftain who sacked Rome in 390 BC. It is very likely that the Welsh word "Brenin," meaning king, derived from that title. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]布雷努斯[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]凯尔特首领[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2:1][BOLD]背景:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]对于这位凯尔特人的首领布雷努斯，我们只知道他是一位令人敬畏的不败勇士。在公元前279年，他率领一支凯尔特人大军入侵马其顿与希腊北部。他们在温泉关突破希腊人的防御，并占领了著名的特尔斐神谕宣示所——布雷努斯本人在这场战斗中受伤。随后凯尔特人又攻入伊庇鲁斯（今属阿尔巴尼亚），洗劫了多东那和奥林匹亚的宙斯神庙。连续获得几场胜利后，希腊人的抵抗越来越强烈。布雷努斯因而退回到马其顿，并在那里伤重身死。失去了首领的凯尔特大军随即发生分裂，各自散去。大部分人带着他们劫掠的财宝返回高卢老家，也有一部分人继续向东，最终定居于小亚细亚。这部分凯尔特人后来又被称为迦拉太人，他们在此后两个世纪仍然保持着自己独特的文化。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]“布雷努斯”很可能并不是真正的名字，而是一个称号——事实上在公元前390年攻陷罗马城的另一位凯尔特人首领也被称为布雷努斯。威尔士语中的“布雷宁”（国王）一词很可能就源自于这个称号。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_HANNIBAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Hannibal Barca [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD]247 - 183 BC[PARAGRAPH:2:1][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Among the great captains of military history, few stand as high, and none higher, than Hannibal Barca. He was born the son of Hamilcar Barca in 247 BC, shortly before the Carthaginian defeat in the First Punic War. Hamilcar made it his mission to conquer new territory in Hispania (Spain) to make up for the loss of Sicily to the Romans; when Hannibal grew old enough, he joined his father and learned the art of military command. According to legend, at this time Hannibal swore an oath of eternal vengeance on Rome. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]After the death of his father and brother-in-law, Hannibal was acclaimed the commander of the Carthaginian forces in Hispania in 221 BC. He spent the next two years finishing the subjugation of the region, and then in 219 BC he attacked the town of Sagentum. Hannibal had been looking for a bigger fight: the city was under the protection of Rome and his attack was sure to spark a diplomatic incident. In fact, the situation boiled out of control and Rome declared war on Carthage, thus beginning the Second Punic War. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]As soon as he heard that war had broken out, Hannibal resolved to embark on a daring raid into Italy itself. He gathered together his most reliable soldiers from Africa and Iberia and set out to the east. After crossing the Pyrenees and evading a Roman army in southern Gaul, in 218 BC Hannibal led his troops on a heroic crossing of the Alps, an astonishing feat that no one at the time thought possible and which caught the Romans totally by surprise. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Once he emerged on the other side of the mountains, Hannibal found shelter among the Gauls of the Po River. With these new allies replacing the many soldiers who had died in the difficult crossing, Hannibal fought a Roman army at the Trebia River, cutting it to pieces by a surprise flank attack. The following year in 217 BC, he crossed the Apennine Mountains and headed into central Italy, where at the Battle of Lake Trasimene he fought and destroyed the main Roman army. Now there was no force in all of Italy which could stand in his way. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The road to Rome was now open, but Hannibal had no siege weapons and he knew that the had no chance to take the city. Instead, he headed into the south of Italy and ravaged the countryside of Campania and Apulia, hoping to pull the southern Italian cities from their alliance with Rome. Despite their many defeats, in 216 the Romans assembled yet another army to face Hannibal at Cannae. Although heavily outnumbered, Hannibal used an elaborate envelopment maneuver to annihilate yet another Roman army. An estimated 50,000 Roman soldiers were killed, and the whole of southern Italy went into revolt against the Romans. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]After this disaster, the Romans adopted a Fabian strategy (named after their commander Quintus Fabius Maximus) of avoiding battle with Hannibal and striking at his supplies. Despite receiving no assistance from Carthage, Hannibal continued to campaign across Italy holding together his ragtag army together in enemy territory for a decade. After his brothers Hasdrubal (207 BC) and Mago (205 - 203 BC) failed to relieve his army, however, any hope of successfully conquering Rome was lost. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Meanwhile, the Roman general Publius Cornelius Scipio had completed the Roman conquest of Hispania and invaded northern Africa. The Carthaginian government recalled Hannibal to Africa, where he was charged with defending the Carthage with untrained new levies. This was an all but impossible task, and after Hannibal's elephants failed to break the Roman lines at the Battle of Zama (202 BC), his infantry was routed and he had no choice but to surrender. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]The Roman victory put an end to the war. Hannibal returned to Carthage, and was elected to be a "soffet," or one of the chief magistrates of the city-state. He was so effective in reorganizing the government that Carthage was able to pay back the heavy tribute Rome demanded earlier than expected and without exceptional taxation. Alarmed at this development and fearing Carthage's resurgence, the Roman Senate forced Hannibal into exile; he found refuge at the court of Antiochus III of the Seleucid Empire until the Romans demanded that he be surrendered to them. Rather than be given over to his enemies, Hannibal committed suicide in 183 BC. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Although Hannibal's campaigns have been endlessly studied by military historians, we know very little about the man himself. All of the surviving accounts of the Second Punic War were written by the Romans, who detested Hannibal and had nothing complimentary to say about him (Hannibal's name was literally used as a bogeyman to scare misbehaving Roman children). Reading between the lines of their accounts, however, it is clear that Hannibal treated his foes with respect and was greatly admired by his soldiers. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Hannibal proved himself to be a fine political as well as military leader, a distinction that few men in history can claim. His success in defeating much larger Roman armies time and time again while operating in enemy country unquestionably ranks him as one of the greatest military commanders of all time. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]汉尼拔·巴尔卡[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]前247-前183年[PARAGRAPH:2:1][BOLD]背景：[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]历数世界军事史的诸多伟大统帅，没有一位能与汉尼拔·巴尔卡相提并论。他是哈米尔卡·巴尔卡的儿子，生于公元前247年，之后不久迦太基在第一次布匿战争中战败。哈米尔卡期望他将征服伊比利亚半岛作为自己的使命，以此弥补在战争中被迫割让西西里给罗马的损失。汉尼拔长大后，他加入了父亲的军队并且掌握了指挥作战的艺术。传说，汉尼拔曾立誓终生与罗马为敌。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]公元前221年,他的父亲和姐夫死后，汉尼拔被拥戴为伊比利亚半岛的迦太基军队最高统帅。他花了两年时间平息了当地的叛乱，并于公元前219年向萨贡托城发动了进攻。汉尼拔意在挑起一场大战：这座城市处于罗马的保护之下，他的进攻无疑是想要引发一起外交危机。事实上，局势很快恶化，罗马决定向迦太基宣战，第二次布匿战争爆发了。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]获悉战争爆发的消息后，汉尼拔立刻决定着手准备一个突袭意大利半岛的大胆计划。他召集了最可靠的非洲及伊比利亚士兵开始向东进军。公元前218年，越过比利牛斯山脉并巧妙绕过南高卢的一支罗马军团后，汉尼拔率领部队勇敢翻越了阿尔卑斯山脉，这一壮举当时无人能够想象，罗马举国上下为之震惊。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]当他出现在山脉另一边时，汉尼拔获得了波河流域高卢部落的支持。这些新盟友的军事援助使在艰难的翻越山脉过程中损兵折将的汉尼拔恢复了元气，他在特拉比亚河畔向一支罗马军团发动进攻，通过侧翼包抄战术一举将其击溃。在这之后的公元前217年，汉尼拔翻越亚平宁山脉，目标直指意大利中部，他在特拉西梅诺湖畔歼灭了罗马主力军团。现在整个意大利都没有力量能与之抗衡。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]通往罗马的道路正向他敞开，但汉尼拔缺乏攻城武器，他很清楚他没有机会攻占这座城市。因此他转而攻入意大利南部并洗劫了坎帕尼亚和阿普里亚地区的乡村，企图把南意大利各城邦都纳入对抗罗马的同盟。公元前216年，尽管经历了一系列失败，罗马人仍然集合了另一支大军在坎尼与汉尼拔对阵。汉尼拔的军队在数量上处于绝对下风，但他依靠计划周密的机动战术包围歼灭了这支罗马军队。据说此役五万罗马士兵战死，整个南意大利陷入叛乱。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]这场灾难之后，罗马开始采取费边战术——即避免与汉尼拔决战而是骚扰他的补给线（由罗马军队的新统师昆图斯·费边·马克西姆斯的名字命名）。尽管无法从迦太基本土获得任何援助，汉尼拔仍然率领其成份庞杂的部队在意大利这个敌国领土上转战了十年。他的弟弟哈斯德鲁巴尔（公元前207年）和马戈（公元前205至203年）的两次驰援行动失败后，征服罗马的希望终于完全破灭。 [PARAGRAPH:2:1]与此同时，罗马将军格奈乌斯·科尔内利乌斯·西庇阿完成了对伊比利亚的征服并开始入侵北非。迦太基元老院迅速把汉尼拔召回非洲，他被受命用未经训练的新兵保卫迦太基本土。这几乎是不可能完成的任务，在公元前202年的扎马之战中，汉尼拔用战象冲破罗马军团阵线的尝试失败后，他的步兵被击溃了，他别无选择，只得投降。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]罗马人依靠这次胜利结束了这场战争。汉尼拔回到迦太基当选为行政官，即城邦的最高文职长官。他立刻重组政府并维持其高效运作，在没有开征额外税收的情况下提前付清了罗马严苛的战争赔款。迦太基的迅速恢复使得罗马害怕这个国家会重新崛起，罗马元老院迫使迦太基流放汉尼拔，他在塞琉古王朝安条克三世的宫廷里得到了庇护，直到罗马要求将其引渡回国受审。公元前183年，决不愿向敌人投降的汉尼拔选择了自杀。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]尽管汉尼拔的诸多战役被后代的军事学家反复研究，但对于他个人我们知之甚少。所有关于第二次布匿战争的残存资料都是罗马人记载的，他们憎恶汉尼拔并吝于给他任何赞美的言辞（汉尼拔这个名字曾被用于吓唬顽劣的罗马儿童）。但从这些记载的字里行间可以发现汉尼拔博得了对手的尊敬，更获得了其部下的极大爱戴。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]作为一个军事领袖的同时，汉尼拔证明自己同样是个优秀的行政官员，史上少有人能与之比肩。他在敌国境内一次又一次地击败数量处于极大优势的罗马军团，这样的战绩使他能够毫无争议地位列有史以来最伟大的军事统帅名单之中。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_WANG_KON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Wang Kon [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of Korea, founder of the Goryeo dynasty [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 877 - 943[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Also known as "King Taejo," Wang Kon was the founder of the Goryeo dynasty, which would rule Korea for over four centuries. In 877 AD Wang Kon was born into a powerful merchant family in the city of Songdo, and his father Wang Yung was the wealthy leader of his clan. At this time Korea was divided between several different states struggling for dominance, and it was generally a period of disruption and chaos, as armies marched and countermarched across the war-ravaged peninsula. In 895 Songdo was occupied by a faction in rebellion against the main Korean state of Silla. The occupation forces were commanded by a man named Gung Ye. Young Wang Kon followed his father into Gung Ye's service, where he quickly demonstrated great military ability. [PARAGRAPH:2]Within a few years, Gung Ye had promoted Wang Kon to the rank of general. In 900, Wang Kon led a successful attack against the state of Hubaekje, and in 903 he launched a famous naval campaign against the southwestern coast of the same country. Wang Kon's mercy to the people he conquered won him a great deal of popularity and admiration even from his enemies. By 913, he was appointed the prime minister of the new state of Taebong, still under the service of (now king) Gung Ye. [PARAGRAPH:2]Unfortunately, Gung Ye proved to be a horrible ruler. Once in power he quickly turned into a religious despot, naming himself Buddha and executing those who challenged his religious claims. In a fit of rage, he executed his wife and two sons. Believing that their new king was quite mad, four of Taebong's major generals plotted to overthrow Gung Ye. Seeking a charismatic leader who would rally the people to their cause, they asked Wang Kon to become the movement's leader; Wang Kon agreed, and after Gung Ye was overthrown and killed in 918, he became the ruler of the kingdom. Once in power Wang Kon renamed his state "Goryeo." [PARAGRAPH:2]During his reign Wang Kon promoted Buddhism as the state religion, and oversaw the conquest of northern Korea and parts of Manchuria. When dealing with local clans, Wang Kon generally sought alliance and cooperation over conquest. When the rebel leader Gyeon Hwon attacked and captured the state of Silla, Wang Kon offered refuge to the deposed Sillan king. In return, the king surrendered his kingdom to Goryeo. In 936 Wang Kon's armies captured Silla and eliminated Gyeon Hwon's son and successor. Korea was united for the first time in recorded history. (It would remain united until at the end of World War II it was once again partitioned.) [PARAGRAPH:2]Wang Kon finally died of disease in 943. History sees him as both an excellent military commander and a skillful statesman who created a nation through a series of clever alliances and decisive military campaigns. Wang Kon's descendants would rule Korea until 1392. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]王建[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]高丽国王（高丽王朝太祖）[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份[\BOLD]877-943[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景：[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]王建（“太祖大王”）是统治朝鲜半岛四个世纪的高丽王朝的开国君主。王建于877年出生于松岳（今开城）一个专门从事商业活动的豪族。当时的新罗王朝国力衰退，整个朝鲜半岛处于四分五裂、战乱不休的状态。在895年，松岳城被一支与新罗朝庭为敌的叛军占据，其首领名叫弓裔。年轻的王建随父亲王隆建加入了弓裔的军队，此时的王建已经显示了出色的军事才能。[PARAGRAPH:2]数年之后，弓裔提拔王建为他的副将。900年，王建率军进攻后百济国获得大胜，903年，他又在朝鲜西南海滨的一场著名的海战中击败后百济军队。王建对待百姓非常仁慈，这使他赢得了民众的爱戴，甚至是敌人的尊敬。弓裔于913年称王，国号“泰封”（或称后高句丽），王建被任命为宰相。[PARAGRAPH:2]不幸的是，弓裔被证明是一位残暴的统治者。他称王之后大权独揽并神化自身，他自称佛祖再世，任何对此提出异议的人都被处以死刑，他甚至因一时癔症发作而处死了王后及两位王子。他的四位部将相信弓裔已是一个疯子，于是密谋推翻他，并决定拥立王建为新的国君。918年，王建杀死弓裔自立为王，定都开京（今开城），并改国号为“高丽”。[PARAGRAPH:2]王建将佛教定为官方信仰，派兵平定了朝鲜北部，还占据了今中国东北的部分地区。他对地方豪强势力实行恩威并用的两手策略，以巩固自己的统治。在后百济王甄萱攻占新罗都城的时候，他接受了新罗王的避难请求。作为回报，新罗王决定臣服于高丽的统治。936年，王建乘后百济内乱之机讨伐甄萱之子，最终平定后百济，统一朝鲜半岛。这是朝鲜第一次凭借自己的力量实现统一。（统一局面一直持续到近代被日本吞并为止。）[PARAGRAPH:2]943年王建因病去世。他被史家认为既是一位优秀的军事家，又是一位精明的政治家，他巧妙地运用建立同盟和采取武力相结合的方式统一了国家。王建的后代统治高丽直到1392年。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SHAKA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Shaka [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Zulu Chieftain [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1787 - 1828[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Shaka was a Zulu chieftain who is credited with transforming his tribe from one of many insignificant entities into the terror of southern Africa. Many historians consider him to be a military genius. During his tumultuous lifetime Shaka caused revolutionary changes to Zulu society and profoundly altered the history of his tribe forever. [PARAGRAPH:2]Shaka was born sometime around 1787 to Chief Senzangakona of the Zulus and the woman Nandi, who was the daughter of a nearby chieftain. In his early days, Shaka served as a warrior for another local chieftain named Digiswayo. When Shaka's father died around 1816, Digiswayo helped Shaka claim the chiefdom of the Zulus for himself. Shaka then murdered his half brother to secure his new position. [PARAGRAPH:2] Once Shaka had control over the Zulu, he began a series of reforms that would transform the Zulu military into the region's most powerful fighting force. First, Shaka replaced the traditional "assegai" (a javelin-like throwing spear) with the "lklwa," a short spear intended for stabbing. He also equipped his men with larger and heavier shields. This new weaponry allowed Shaka to dramatically alter his army's battle tactics, changing the very nature of warfare in the region. [PARAGRAPH:2]Before Shaka, among the tribes of southern Africa, combat was in large ritualized. The two forces would stand apart from one-another, chanting loudly and clashing their shields while hurling their spears at each other. Eventually one side's resolve would falter and they'd retreat, leaving the other side in possession of the field. Few warriors on either side were killed, and the battles rarely provided decisive results. [PARAGRAPH:2]With his military reforms, Shaka was to change all that. Shaka taught his army to close with the opponents' forces, fighting in hand-to-hand combat, where the new weaponry and shields provided Shaka's forces with a decisive advantage over their foes. Shaka invented a tactical formation called the "buffalo horns," under which his army had large wings (or horns) extending to the right and left of the main force. The main force would engage the enemy directly, while the horns outflanked the foe on left and right. Surrounded on three sides and facing a foe armed with better weaponry and shields, few armies could stand up to the Zulu attack. [PARAGRAPH:2]With the most powerful army in the region, Shaka unleashed a reign of terror upon the unsuspecting neighboring tribes of southern Africa. Shaka began his conquests with limited forces. However, through skilled diplomacy and the judicious use of assassination, he rapidly set up a system of alliances and vassal rulers to extend his control over a wide range of territory, rapidly increasing the forces under his command. Those who opposed him were slaughtered without mercy. Within a decade tribes began migrating out of the area, fleeing the Zulus in all directions. This movement of peoples has become known as Mfecane, or "the scattering." [PARAGRAPH:2]Although a great conqueror, Shaka was not an effective domestic ruler. His brutal regime was quite unpopular, and several assassinations and coups were attempted. Eventually, one of them succeeded, and in 1828 Shaka was mortally wounded by his two half-brothers. As he lay dying, Shaka is said to have told his half-brothers that they would not rule long, and that the white men would soon take the Zulu lands. Unfortunately for the Zulus, Shaka spoke truthfully, and within seventy years the Zulu would be conquered by the British. [PARAGRAPH:2]It is interesting to speculate what would have been the result if Shaka has still been alive when the British invaded Zululand. Shaka was a great military innovator, and it's possible that he would have much earlier understood the power of the British rifles, and he might have quickly tried to adopt the weapons for his own troops. However, the fact remains that his people would still have had no industrial base and little ability to import such weapons. He might have chosen to avoid open-field battle and adopt guerilla tactics; while this would have caused the invaders much more grief, it is likely that in the end he too would have been defeated by the British military-industrial juggernaut. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]沙卡[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]祖鲁部族首领[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1787-1828[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景：[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]沙卡是祖鲁部族的首领，他因为将祖鲁由一个毫不起眼的小部落发展成南部非洲的巨人的功绩而被人们铭记。许多历史学家认为他是一个军事天才。在他波澜壮阔的一生中，沙卡给祖鲁社会带来了革命性的变革，并且深刻而永久地改变了他的部落的历史。[PARAGRAPH:2]沙卡大约出生于1787年，他的父亲是祖鲁族首领辛赞格科纳，母亲兰蒂是附近另一部落酋长的女儿。沙卡早年曾在当地另外一位名叫丁吉斯瓦约的酋长手下作战。在沙卡的父亲于1816年去世以后，丁吉斯瓦约帮助沙卡夺取了祖鲁酋长之位。随后沙卡谋杀了他的半血缘兄弟，从而巩固了自己统治。[PARAGRAPH:2] 当沙卡完全控制祖鲁以后，他开始了一系列的改革，这些改革最后把祖鲁的军队变成了这个地区最强大的军事力量。首先，沙卡用一种刺杀型的短矛“伊基瓦”替代了传统的投掷型长矛“阿塞盖”，同时他给自己的战士配备了保护身体的长盾，这种新武器使得沙卡可以能够革命性的改变他的军队所使用的战术，从而真正的改变了在这个地区的战争的形态。[PARAGRAPH:2]在沙卡以前，在南部非洲的部落间的战斗还保存着某种仪式性质——交战双方吟唱歌谣，在远距离投掷标枪。最后战斗中一方的战斗意志崩溃，于是开始撤退并且远离在交战区中的另外一方。双方只有很少的战士在战斗中被杀死，这样的战斗也很少会带来决定性的战果。[PARAGRAPH:2]在沙卡的军事改革中，他彻底的改变了这一切。他教导自己的军队要靠近对方的军队进行白刃格斗，在这样的战斗中，沙卡装备的新武器给他的部队带来了压倒对方的决定性的优势。沙卡发明了一种被称为“牛角”的战斗队形，在这种战斗队形中他的部队有很大的侧翼（或者被称为牛角），它们一致延伸到了主力部队的左侧和右测。这里部队从正面和敌人交锋，而“牛角”则从左右两侧对敌人进行两翼包抄。在装备了更强的武器和盾牌的敌人的三面包夹下，很少有军队能抵抗祖鲁的进攻。[PARAGRAPH:2]通过其强大的军队，沙卡开始在南部非洲的相邻部落中推行恐怖政治。凭借其有限的军队，沙卡开始了他的征服行动。但是通过使用老练的外交手段和明智的运用暗杀，他迅速建立起了一个同盟和附庸相结合的系统来把他的控制力扩展到广阔的地区，并且迅速增加了可以由其指挥的军队的规模。他的反对者被毫不留情地屠杀。在十年之内，多个部落开始逃离这一区域，在每一个方向上远离祖鲁。这些人的迁徙活动史称姆菲卡尼，又名“弃土运动”。[PARAGRAPH:2]尽管沙卡是一个强大的征服者，但是沙卡并不是一个有效的内政管理者。他的领地并不和谐，几次有人试图发动暗杀和政变。最后有一次暗杀行动还是成功了，在1828年沙卡在他的半血缘兄弟的暗杀行为中受到了致命伤。据说在他弥留之际，沙卡告诉他的半血缘兄弟，他的统治不会持续太久，白人很快就会侵占祖鲁的土地。不幸的是沙卡说对了，仅过了70年，祖鲁即被英国人征服。[PARAGRAPH:2]如果当英国人入侵祖鲁兰的时候沙卡依然健在，历史将会如何发展？这是一个有趣的假设。沙卡是一个伟大的军事革新者，他有可能及早了解英国来复枪的威力，也许他会尝试更快的改变他的军队所使用的武器来适应新的形势。然而无法改变的事实是他的国家没有工业基地，并且通过进口来获取这些武器的能力也非常有限。或许他会选择避免正面冲突并使用游击战术；虽然这可能给入侵者带来更大的打击，但是恐怕最终他还是会被英国强大的军事工业击败。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEHMED_II_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Mehmed II [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Sultan of the Ottoman Empire [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1432 - 1481[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Mehmed II, also known as el-Fatih ("the Conqueror") was the sultan of the Ottoman Empire from 1451 - 1481 AD. He is best known for capturing the city of Constantinople, turning it into the new Ottoman capital and destroying the Byzantine Empire in the process. Mehmed was born in Edirne, which was then the capital of the Ottoman state, in 1432. He was fascinated by military matters from an early age; by the time that he reached maturity and ascended to the position of sultan (in 1451), Mehmed was prepared to begin the attack upon the city of Constantinople. [PARAGRAPH:2]During the thousand-year history of the Byzantine Empire, Constantinople had withstood sieges many times. It had only been captured once, by the Fourth Crusaders in 1204. But by the fifteenth century the Byzantine Empire was a battered shell of its former self: while it still held Constantinople, it retained only a few small territories outside the city's walls (mainly in Greece). [PARAGRAPH:2]Mehmed began the siege by constructing a pair of fortresses on both sides of the straights surrounding the city, thus preventing reinforcement by sea. When Mehmed attacked in 1453, the Byzantines were horribly outnumbered: there were only 7000 defenders to meet an army of roughly 100,000 Turks. Help was not forthcoming from the West, which remained hostile to the Byzantines because of the split between the Catholic and Orthodox churches. [PARAGRAPH:2]Using enormous primitive cannon, the Ottomans battered the walls of Constantinople for weeks (although the rate of fire was so slow that the defenders were able to repair much of the damage as it took place). On May 29 Mehmed finally ordered an assault at a damaged section of the walls. The assault was successful, and the attackers succeeded in breaking into the city streets. The city's fate was sealed. The last Emperor, Constantine XI, died in battle, and the ancient empire was extinguished forever. [PARAGRAPH:2]Mehmed gave his soldiers a day to loot the city (which was a customary practice at the time), during which a large portion of the populace was slaughtered, raped, or enslaved. After his soldiers' greed and lust were sated, Mehmed made every effort to rebuild the city and repopulate it with Turks. (Despite this odious "ethnic cleansing" at the beginning of his reign, Mehmed generally treated his non-Islamic subjects well, granting them permission to practice their religion freely, as well as a great deal of local autonomy.) The Byzantine administration was largely preserved intact and was given the task of running the Ottoman Empire. [PARAGRAPH:2]Upon consolidating his control over Constantinople, Mehmed finished off the last remnants of the Byzantine Empire by conquering some small states in Greece and in 1461 he conquered the tiny Empire of Trebizond on the Black Sea. He then tried to extend his empire into Europe, but in 1462 he was defeated by Prince Vlad III (the real Count Dracula) of Wallachia, and at the Battle of Vaslui in 1475 he suffered a major loss to the Moldavian Prince Stefan. These defeats put an end to that campaign. However, Mehmed still had ambition - and plenty of it. [PARAGRAPH:2]Believing that his conquest of Rome made him the legitimate ruler of the late Roman Empire, at the end of his life Mehmed embarked on an ambitious but foolhardy campaign to reunite his divided empire. The campaign began well; the Ottomans invaded Italy, and in 1840 the city of Otranto was easily captured. However, a rebellion in Albania the same year threatened the Ottoman supply lines, forcing the Ottomans to divide their forces. The following year a large Christian army led by the pope pushed the Ottomans from Italy. Mehmed died in 1481, putting an end forever to his dream of recapturing the ancient glory of Rome. [PARAGRAPH:2]In large, history has judged Mehmed kindly. He is recognized for his military success and his strong rule, and later Ottoman sultans would seek to follow his example. Mehmed's conquest of Constantinople was one of the most important events in Western history, signifying the end of the medieval period. His attack upon Italy may have been foolish, but it ultimately did little to harm the young Ottoman Empire that was his legacy. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]穆罕默德二世[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]奥斯曼帝国苏丹[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1432-1481[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景：[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]穆罕默德二世是1451-1481年间在位的奥斯曼帝国苏丹，又被称为“埃尔-法齐赫”（即征服者）。他以攻陷君士坦丁堡作为奥斯曼帝国的首都并灭亡了拜占庭帝国而名垂史册。穆罕默德1432年出生于埃迪尔尼（奥斯曼当时的首都）。他早年便热衷与军事；当他于1451年登基并掌控军队时，穆罕默德已经准备开始对君士坦丁堡的进攻。[PARAGRAPH:2]在拜占庭帝国的千年历史中，君士坦丁堡曾经受无数次的围城。仅在1204年第四次十字军东征期间被十字军所攻陷。但到15世纪时，拜占庭帝国仅剩千疮百孔的外壳：仅能控制除了君士坦丁堡及城墙之外的小片土地（主要在希腊）。[PARAGRAPH:2]穆罕默德首先在围绕城池的海峡两端筑起一对城堡，以断绝来自海上的补给。当穆罕默德于1453年开始进攻时，拜占庭已经陷入绝望境地：7000名守卫者面对着土耳其的100,000大军。而来自西方的援助也无法指望，天主教和东正教分裂导致的敌对仍然在持续。[PARAGRAPH:2]使用原始的大炮，奥斯曼人花费了数周时间轰击城墙（当时的大炮射速低下，两轮开火的间隙足够防守者修补城墙）。5月29日，穆罕默德最终下令从一处城墙被轰出的缺口发动总攻。突击获得成功，攻城者顺利突入了城内街道。这城市的命运已经注定。末代皇帝君士坦丁十一世战死，古老的帝国永远不复存在。[PARAGRAPH:2]穆罕默德允许他的战士劫掠城市一天（这在当时是个惯例），大量人口被屠杀，强奸，奴役。在战士们的贪婪得到满足后，穆罕默德开始尽全力重建城市并大量迁入土耳其人。（虽然在其在位伊始便进行过这样一场可怕的“种族清洗”行为，此后的穆罕默德对非伊斯兰的事物保持了宽容，允许他们以类似于区域自治的形式保有宗教自由。）拜占庭帝国的管理模式被最大程度地予以保留，以在新生的奥斯曼帝国运行。[PARAGRAPH:2]在他巩固对君士坦丁堡的控制之后，穆罕默德完成了对拜占庭遗存的希腊小邦的征服，1461年他最终征服了黑海沿岸的特拉比松。随即他尝试将帝国扩展至欧洲，但在1462年，他被瓦拉几亚大公弗拉德三世（著名的“德拉库拉伯爵”的原型）击败，又在1475年的瓦斯卢伊战役中遭到摩尔多瓦大公斯特凡的重创。这些失利阻止了他的扩张步伐。虽然穆罕默德仍然对此充满野心。[PARAGRAPH:2]他相信对东罗马的征服将使他成为罗马帝国的合法继承者，在他的晚年开始酝酿着宏大的计划来重组那分裂的帝国。奥斯曼开始入侵意大利，1480年奥特朗托被轻松夺取，然而同年在阿尔巴尼亚的一次起义威胁到了帝国的补给线，迫使奥斯曼帝国分兵应付。次年奥斯曼人被教皇召集的一支庞大的基督教联军赶出了意大利。穆罕默德死于1481年，最终未能实现其重现古罗马帝国般荣耀的梦想。[PARAGRAPH:2]历史对穆罕默德二世的评价在很大程度上是宽容的。他的军事成功及统治被认可，以后的帝国苏丹们都延续他的道路。穆罕默德二世对君士坦丁堡的征服是西方历史的重要事件，标志着中世纪的终结。他对意大利的攻击或许是卤莽愚蠢的，但从长远来看，这次失败对年轻的奥斯曼帝国并无损害。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_WINSTON_CHURCHILL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Winston Churchill [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Prime Minister of Great Britain [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1874 - 1965[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Winston Churchill, whose full name was, "Sir Winston Leonard Spencer-Churchill," was undoubtedly one of the most important people of the twentieth century. At various times a soldier, journalist, author, and politician, during his long life Churchill was known for both his intellectual brilliance and his outspoken support for what were often unpopular opinions. At various times he was either the most beloved or the most hated man in Britain. In the years since his death Churchill's reputation has grown to semi-legendary proportions. [PARAGRAPH:2]A descendant of the famous English general the Duke of Marlborough, Churchill was born in 1874 at Blenheim Palace in Oxfordshire. After a mediocre performance at the public school Harrow, Churchill joined the army, where he freely used his family connections to get assigned to several colonial wars, narrowly escaping death on a number of occasions - and by all accounts having a ripping good time while doing so. During this period Churchill became a very popular wartime journalist, writing numerous columns and several best-selling books about his experiences. Churchill's maneuvering and flagrant self-promotion alienated his fellow officers and essentially ended any chance of high promotion in the Army; however he was able to parlay his popularity to gain a seat in Parliament. [PARAGRAPH:2]In 1900 Churchill was elected to a Conservative seat in Parliament. However in 1904 his strong opposition to the Conservative policy of tariff protectionism led him to change parties and join the Liberals, who held power at the time. In the Liberal government Churchill held a number of different minor posts. In 1911 he was appointed First Lord of the Admiralty, overseeing the Royal Navy's ambitious modernization program. [PARAGRAPH:2]During the First World War, Churchill approved the disastrous Gallipoli invasion of Turkey. Churchill was soundly criticized for the failure, and in 1916 he resigned the Admiralty and left the government, rejoined the army and went off to the Western Front to fight in the trenches. [PARAGRAPH:2]Despite his many eccentricities and flaws, however, Churchill was widely recognized as one of the ablest men in Great Britain, and in 1917 he was back in government again, holding a number of important Cabinet posts. After the Liberal Government fell in 1923 Churchill swapped parties once again and joined the Conservatives, famously saying, "Anyone can rat [change parties], but it takes a certain ingenuity to re-rat." He was appointed Chancellor of the Exchequer in 1924 and presided over Britain's disastrous return to the Gold Standard, for which he was again soundly criticized. After the Conservative Government fell in the 1929 General Election, Churchill lost his government post and became estranged from the political power brokers in both parties. [PARAGRAPH:2]The rise of Nazi Germany also led to a resurgence of Churchill's political career. Although he had earlier praised Fascist Italy as a bulwark against communism, in the late 1930s Churchill became one of the few voices speaking out against the growing power of Hitler. When the British government adopted the policy of appeasement, Churchill was almost alone in voicing opposition, a position which gained him a number of admirers, but which also earned him a lot of public and political criticism. [PARAGRAPH:2]When the Second World War broke out, the public lost a great deal confidence in the government of Neville Chamberlain (who had spearheaded the policy of appeasing Hitler). To shore up support for his government Chamberlain asked Churchill to resume his post as First Lord of the Admiralty. Showing genuine greatness of character Churchill accepted the position, working tirelessly to improve the Royal Navy and absolutely refusing to criticize his Prime Minister during wartime. However by early 1941 it was clear that Chamberlain no longer enjoyed the confidence of the people or of Parliament, and Churchill was appointed Prime Minister of Great Britain. [PARAGRAPH:2]In the west the war began catastrophically for the Allies. The Germans launched their attack against the British and French forces in 1940. Supported by air power and infantry, the German tanks had outflanked the Allied positions, forcing the French and British into precipitous retreat, advancing so rapidly that the defenders didn't have enough time to reform a new line. The Germans came within inches of destroying the British army, forcing it to abandon all of its equipment and stage a chaotic evacuation at Dunkirk, leaving thousands of British soldiers behind to be captured. France was forced to surrender, and German soldiers occupied Paris. [PARAGRAPH:2]As past events had foreshadowed, Churchill was at his very best during adversity. Britain stood alone against Hitler. Her army was badly crippled; only the Royal Navy and Air Force stood between the British and the Germans. Churchill worked tirelessly to shore up Britain's defenses and to find allies against Hitler, and his brilliant rhetoric rallied the battered spirits of the British people and earned him the admiration of people across the world. Throughout the dark days of the Battle of Britain and the Blitz that followed, Churchill seemed to hold the empire together by sheer indomitable force of will. [PARAGRAPH:2]Diplomatically, Churchill was an opportunist. Despite his hatred of Communism and his extreme personal dislike of Stalin (who had earlier allied with Germany to gobble up Poland), when the Germans attacked the Soviet Union Churchill sought an alliance with the USSR, famously saying, "If Hitler invaded hell I would make at least a favorable reference to the devil in the House of Commons." His most important diplomatic task, however, was to cultivate the good will - and eventually the military intervention - of the United States. [PARAGRAPH:2]It can be argued that Churchill's friendship with American President Franklin Delano Roosevelt saved Great Britain from destruction. Facing strong internal opposition to becoming involved in the war, at first the President had to move slowly, maintaining at least a nominal appearance of neutrality while gradually shifting American public opinion from Isolation to Intervention. However when Japan attacked Pearl Harbor at the end of 1941, Germany stupidly declared war against the United States, allowing Roosevelt to openly bring the growing might of the US military and industrial complex to Great Britain's (and the USSR's) aid. [PARAGRAPH:2]Within a very short period the US Army Air Force was attacking German targets in Europe, and soon thereafter large numbers of American troops were staged in Great Britain, ending forever any chance of a successful German invasion. As the war progressed the growing English and American forces launched a major invasion of Europe while their air forces pounded German factories and cities around the clock, crippling the Nazis enough to allow the Soviet Union to annihilate the German army in the Eastern Front. [PARAGRAPH:2]After the war ended in victory Churchill lost power almost immediately - perhaps because the people thought he was too old, or because they didn't believe he was the correct leader to rebuild the shattered empire. Though he remained in Parliament for a number of years (and briefly regained the post of Prime Minister during the Korean conflict), by and large Churchill's direct participation in world events was at an end. [PARAGRAPH:2]After being voted out of office Churchill wrote a history of the Second World War, for which he received the Nobel Prize in Literature in 1953. In 1965 Churchill suffered a stroke and passed away at the age of 90. Churchill's death was mourned across the globe, and his funeral was attended by an enormous number of foreign dignitaries. His reputation has only grown in the years since his death, and today Churchill is possibly the most popular and revered figure in all of English history. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]温斯顿·丘吉尔[\H1]英国首相[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]1874-1965[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景：[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]温斯顿·丘吉尔的全名是：温斯顿·伦纳德·斯宾塞-丘吉尔爵士，他可以无庸置疑地位列20世纪里最重要的人物之一。他在不同时期从事过不同的职业，包括士兵、记者、作家和政治家，在他的一生当中，丘吉尔最为人所了解的是他对常常不受欢迎的见解表现出的聪明才智和坦率的支持。很多时候他在英国不是最受人爱戴的人，就是最令人讨厌的人。在他去世之后，丘吉尔的名声越发具有传奇色彩。[PARAGRAPH:2]作为英国著名将军马尔巴罗公爵的子孙，丘吉尔1874年出生于牛津郡布莱尼姆帕里斯。在哈罗公立学校获得普普通通的成绩毕业后，丘吉尔参军了，在那里他自主地利用他家庭的关系被指派到几个殖民战事当中，有多次差点丧命，而且据说都是在非常惊险的情况下逃离死亡的。在这个时期的丘吉尔成为一个很受欢迎的战地记者，并写了许多专栏和几本关于他的经历的畅销书。丘吉尔的肆意妄为和公然的自我晋升疏远了同行军官而且在本质上终止了在军中高升的任何机会。然而他却能够连本带利地提高他的声望来获得议会的一个席位。[PARAGRAPH:2]1900年丘吉尔取得在议会中保守党的一席。然而在1904年对于关税保护的保守党政策的强烈反对使他改变了党派并加入了自由党，该党派在当时很有权力。在自由党政府里丘吉尔担任许多不同的小职位。在1911年他被委派为英国海军大臣，监督英国皇家海军野心勃勃的现代化规划。[PARAGRAPH:2]在第一次世界大战期间，丘吉尔批准了导致损失惨重的土耳其加里波里登陆计划。丘吉尔因为这场失败受到强烈批评，并在1916年辞去海军部职务并离开政府，重新加入陆军并前去西线战壕里战斗。[PARAGRAPH:2]尽管他有许多怪僻和缺点，然而，丘吉尔被公认为英国最有才干的人之一，而在1917年他再次回到政府，在内阁中担任重要职位。1923年自由党政府下台后，丘吉尔再次改变党派并再加入到保守党，说了句著名的话“任何人都能变节（改变党派），但再变节需要一定的灵活性。”1924年他被委任为英国财政大臣，负责灾难性恢复金本位制计划，这导致了灾难性的结果，因此他再次受到强烈批评。保守党政府在1929年的大选下台后，丘吉尔失去他的政府职位并同两党的政治掮客疏远了。[PARAGRAPH:2]纳粹德国的崛起也使得丘吉尔的政治生涯得到苏醒。虽然他早期赞扬过作为对抗共产主义的防波堤的法西斯主义意大利，但在19世纪30年代末却成为其中少数大声反对力量在增长中的希特勒的人。当英国政府采取绥靖政策，丘吉尔几乎孤独的处在反对声音中，在这个形势下很多人敬慕他，但也受到很多公众和政治上的批判。[PARAGRAPH:2]当二战爆发，公众对尼维尔·张伯伦（对希特勒实施绥靖政策）的政府失去信心时。为维持对他的政府的支持，张伯伦邀请丘吉尔再度出任英国海军大臣。表现出性格真实伟大的丘吉尔接受了职位，不知疲倦地工作来改进皇家海军并在战争期间完全拒绝评论他的首相。然而到了1941年初张伯伦显然不再受人们和议会的信任，而丘吉尔就被委任为英国的首相。[PARAGRAPH:2]在西线，盟军的开局变成了一场灾难。德军在1940年对英法军队发动大规模进攻。在空军和步兵的支援下，德国坦克两翼包抄盟军的阵地，迫使英法两军紧急撤退，推进是如此的迅速，以致防守一方没有足够的时间去形成新的战线。德军几乎完全摧毁了英军的斗志，迫使他们在敦克尔克放弃所有的装备并实施了一场混乱的撤退，留下数千名士兵成为战俘。法国被迫投降，德军占领了巴黎。[PARAGRAPH:2]正如过往的事件所预示，丘吉尔在逆境下才会处于最佳状态。英国独力对抗着希特勒。英国陆军元气大伤，只有皇家海军和空军屹立在英国和德国入侵者之间。丘吉尔竭尽全力支撑英国的防御体系，并寻求同盟对抗希特勒，而且他出色的言辞重振了英国人崩溃的精神，并为他赢得了全世界人民的钦佩。在紧随的整个英国战役和闪电战的艰苦岁月里，丘吉尔似乎全靠意志中不屈不挠的力量把帝国紧紧团结在一起。[PARAGRAPH:2]外交方面，丘吉尔是个机会主义者。尽管他憎恨共产主义并十分不喜欢斯大林（他在早期和德国结盟吞并波兰），但是当德国人进攻苏联时邱吉尔就和苏联结盟，并说了一句名言：“即使希特勒入侵地狱，我也会在下院发表支持撒旦的声明。”不过他最重要的外交成就却是使美国最终下定参与军事干涉的决心。[PARAGRAPH:2]有人坚持认为是丘吉尔与美国总统罗斯福的友谊挽救了英国。由于国内强烈反对卷入战争，起初美国总统只能慢慢地鼓动，至少在名义上表现中立，然而却逐渐地使美国民意由孤立变为干预。然而当日本在1941年末偷袭珍珠港，德国愚蠢地向美国宣战，终于使得罗斯福能够公开地给予英国（和苏联）以充足的援助。[PARAGRAPH:2]在很短的时间内美国空军开始攻击德国在欧洲的目标，不久后大量美军登陆英国，永远结束了德国入侵英国的任何成功机会。随着战事的发展，壮大中的英美军队发动对欧洲的大反攻，同时他们的空军日以继夜地重击德国的工厂和城市，充分削弱纳粹以使苏联有能力消灭东线的德军。[PARAGRAPH:2]二战胜利结束后，丘吉尔几乎迅速地失去权力——也许是因为人们认为他年纪太大了，或者因为他们不相信他是重建破碎的帝国的好领导。虽然他留在议会里很多年（并在朝鲜战争期间暂时地恢复首相的职位），但基本上丘吉尔对世界政治的直接参与就到此为止了。[PARAGRAPH:2]卸任之后的丘吉尔撰写了一部二战史，他因此在1953年获得诺贝尔文学奖。1965年丘吉尔因中风而逝世，享年90岁。丘吉尔的去世令全球哀悼，大批外国政要参加了他的葬礼。他去世之后声誉日隆，时至今日丘吉尔可能仍是英国历史上最受欢迎和最受尊敬的人物。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_JOSEF_STALIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Stalin [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]General Secretary of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1878 - 1953[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]His birth name was Joseph Vissarionovich Dzhugashvili, but to the world he will always be known simply as Stalin ("man of steel" in Russian). Stalin was born in 1878 to a poor Georgian family. His father was a cobbler who often beat his wife and young son. At the age of eight, Stalin began his education in the Gori Church School, where instruction was conducted in Russian and he was mocked for his Georgian accent. Stalin graduated first in his class at the age of fourteen and began attending school next at the Tiflis Theological Seminary. Stalin had no interest in becoming a priest, but the seminary was one of the few institutions of higher learning permitted in Georgia by the repressive tsarist government. [PARAGRAPH:2]It was here that Stalin became involved in the revolutionary socialist movement of Russia; in 1899 he was kicked out of the school for his participation in the radical cause. For the next decade Stalin worked in the political underground of the Caucasus region, for which he was arrested and sent to temporary exile in Siberia several times. Over the years Stalin rose through the ranks of the socialist organizations, and in 1912 he gained a position on the central committee of the Bolshevik Party. He later was appointed as an editor of "Pravda," (meaning, "Truth") the main communist newspaper, which was a position with a great deal of influence. [PARAGRAPH:2]Stalin played little role in the events of the 1917 Bolshevik Revolution. He and the other editors of Pravda initially supported Keresnsky's Provisional Government, and even refused to publish Lenin's articles calling for it to be overthrown. (Later, Stalin would falsely claim that he had been part of a "Party Center" which directed the October Revolution.) During the Russian Civil War, Stalin served as a military commissar on various different fronts, but he seems to have been an indifferent military man at best. It was when that conflict ended that his star began to rise. [PARAGRAPH:2]In 1922 Stalin secured the position of General Secretary of the Communist Party, a post that no one else particularly wanted. Stalin recognized the potential power of this job, however, as it gave him control over appointments within the Party. Over time, Stalin built up a group of fiercely loyal followers, eventually becoming one of the most powerful men in the Party.  [PARAGRAPH:2]After the death of Lenin in 1924, Stalin formed a centrist ruling coalition along with Kamenev and Zinoviev. In doing so Stalin successfully outmaneuvered his enemy Trotsky, another strong contender for leadership of the USSR. In 1928 Trotsky went into exile and he was assassinated some time thereafter (it is assumed at Stalin's orders). Then Stalin turned on his former allies Kamenev and Zinoviev, driving them from power as well. By the beginning of the 1930s, Stalin had secured undisputed power over both the Communist Party and all of the Soviet Union. [PARAGRAPH:2]With his enemies out of the way, Stalin could begin a thorough transformation of Russia. Up until the First World War Russia had been primarily an agrarian society, but Stalin was determined to change it into an industrial powerhouse. In 1928 he implemented the Five Year Plans, designed to force rapid industrialization upon the country at any cost. To curb the power of the prosperous independent farmers (known as "kulaks") Stalin also nationalized individual farms, replacing them with larger collective farms. Stalin's collectivization of agriculture proved to be a disaster: output actually fell, and there was a great deal of peasant resistance (which was ruthlessly crushed by the Red Army). Despite the crop shortfalls Stalin sold off the agricultural produce of the USSR to get foreign currency to pay for further industrialization, deliberately engineering a mass famine which may have killed as many as 10 million people. [PARAGRAPH:2]Fearing an army plot against him, in 1936 Stalin embarked on the Great Purge, which quickly degenerated into a terrible witch hunt. Many of the old communist leaders were executed after bizarre show trials during which they confessed to outlandish crimes. At the same time the Red Army was gutted of its officer corps. Millions of innocent people died or were exiled to Siberia for no offense whatsoever. Stalin's paranoia claimed an untold number of lives before it had run its course. [PARAGRAPH:2]Stalin's Soviet Union was ruthlessly authoritarian, but it had achieved its goal of industrialization. Advances were made in science, and the free provision of certain state services - including education and housing - did provide new opportunities for many millions of former peasants (although the standard of living remained extremely low compared to Western countries). Freedom of expression was nonexistent, however, and the practice of any kind of religion was made illegal. [PARAGRAPH:2]During the 1930s, Stalin was convinced that Hitler's Nazi Germany was a terrible threat to the Soviet Union. He sought defensive pacts and alliances with England and France, but was soundly rebuffed by both countries. Hoping to stave off what he saw as the USSR's inevitable conflict with Germany until his country had a chance to arm itself, Stalin signed a Faustian bargain with Hitler to divide Eastern Europe between the two powers. In September of 1939 Nazi Germany invaded Poland and three weeks later the Soviet Union jumped into the conflict to claim the eastern half of the country. [PARAGRAPH:2] By doing so Stalin believed that he had earned Hitler's gratitude (if not friendship), and that a German attack on the USSR did not lay in the imminent future. However, like so many other leaders Stalin totally misread Hitler, and despite increasingly frantic warnings of German soldiers massing on the borders, he was totally caught off guard when in June of 1941 Hitler launched a massive invasion. In fact, for the first days of the invasion Stalin remained convinced that it was some kind of mistake and refused to let his troops counterattack for fear of provoking Hitler! Because of Stalin's blunders the Soviets suffered enormous losses in the first few weeks. [PARAGRAPH:2]With Stalin stunned into bewildered inaction by his miscalculations, it was only the sheer size of Russia that prevented the Germans from winning a quick victory. In December of 1941 winter - Russia's oldest and best ally - saved Moscow from capture. Regaining his composure, Stalin then led the Soviet Union in a bitter and gruesome struggle to the death against Nazi Germany, with countless atrocities on both sides. Stalin's transfer of heavy industry east into the Urals, combined with the unbelievable size and manpower of the Soviet Union - supported by heavy British and American fighting in the West - ultimately led to victory in 1945, when Soviet troops marched triumphantly into Berlin. The cost, however, was staggering: an estimated 10 million Russian soldiers and 20 million civilians died in the conflict. [PARAGRAPH:2]By the end of the war the Red Army had overrun Eastern Europe, and once there Stalin had no intention of leaving. Despite promising to allow free elections during wartime conferences with the Americans and British, Stalin had no intention of doing anything of the sort and he set up puppet communist regimes across the region. While Tito's government in Yugoslavia successfully broke away from Stalin's bloc, the rest of the countries in Eastern Europe would spend the next three decades under the oppressive rule of the Soviet Union. [PARAGRAPH:2]Despite their uneasy alliance during the recent war, the USSR remained on hostile terms with its erstwhile Western Allies. Stalin's support of the Communist Chinese and his blockade of West Berlin in 1948 helped led to the outbreak of the Cold War, a bitter period of proxy warfare and ever-growing nuclear arsenals that would drag on for fifty bleak years. [PARAGRAPH:2]During his reign Stalin encouraged the development of a sycophantic cult of personality where he was worshipped as little less than a god. When he finally died in 1953 there was an enormous outpouring of genuine grief across the Soviet Union. Later, after Khrushchev revealed the extent of Stalin's crimes in his secret speech of 1956, public opinion would become less favorable. Overall, it must be said that Stalin was successful in changing the backwards agricultural state of the tsars into a modern global superpower. No country deserves more credit for defeating Nazi Germany than the Soviet Union. However the truly appalling and barbaric methods used to achieve these successes must always be kept in mind, and Stalin will always remain a controversial character in history. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]斯大林[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]苏联共产党总书记[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份: [\BOLD]1878-1953[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景：[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]原名约瑟夫·维萨里奥诺维奇·朱加施维里，但以斯大林的名字闻名于世（斯大林在俄文中是“钢铁一样的人”的意思），斯大林诞生于1878年一个贫寒的格鲁吉亚家庭。他的父亲是个经常虐待妻儿的鞋匠。在八岁那年，斯大林开始在高里教会学校接受教育。在那里，教学使用俄语，斯大林的格鲁吉亚口音备受嘲弄。斯大林十四岁的时候以头名毕业，紧接着进入了第比利斯神学院。斯大林无意成为牧师，但神学院是在帝俄统治下的少数被允许的格鲁吉亚高等学府。[PARAGRAPH:2]斯大林在这里投身革命。1899年，斯大林因为参加激进运动而被开除。之后的十年斯大林在高加索地区从事地下活动，期间他被逮捕并流放至西伯利亚很多次。斯大林在组织中的地位不断提升，到了1912年他成为了布尔什维克中央委员会的一员。之后他成为了真理报的一名编辑，一个很有影响力的职位。[PARAGRAPH:2]斯大林在1917年十月革命中并没有起多大作用。他和其它编辑最开始支持克伦斯基临时政府，他们甚至拒绝刊载列宁号召推翻临时政府的文章（后来斯大林伪称自己是十月革命的领导核心之一）。在俄国内战期间斯大林作为政委出现在各个前线，但是他的作用无关紧要。从那时起，他时来运转了。[PARAGRAPH:2]1922年，斯大林坐稳了中央委员会书记的位子，这个位子并没有人想争。斯大林看到了这个职位的潜力，他利用这个职位在中央迅速取得权力。他开始培植羽翼，并成为党内最有权势的人。[PARAGRAPH:2]1924年列宁死后，斯大林、卡米涅夫以及奇诺维也夫组成了领导核心。由此斯大林成功排挤他的死敌托洛斯基。1928年托洛斯基遭到流放，并在国外被暗杀。在三十年代初，斯大林整肃了激活他所有的敌人，在党内取得空前的权力。[PARAGRAPH:2]肃清了他的政敌之后，斯大林开始改造他的国家。直到一战的时候俄国仍然处于农业社会，但斯大林决定实行全面工业化。在1928年，斯大林实行了第一个五年计划，不惜一切代价进行工业化。为了削弱自耕农的势力，斯大林国有化了私人农场。斯大林的农业政策被证明是一场灾难：粮食减产引起许多农民的反抗（都被红军无情镇压），尽管农业产量降低，斯大林仍然出售农产品换取外汇以支持工业化。由此引起的饥荒据估计造成了一千万人死亡。[PARAGRAPH:2]1936年斯大林为了粉碎军队内反对他的阴谋而进行了大清洗，进而转化为一场女巫狩猎。许多资深领导人在严刑逼供后承认罪行。同时军队的军官阶层造大巨大破坏，数以百万计的人被处决或被流放。[PARAGRAPH:2]斯大林的苏联实行冷酷无情的统治，但是他达到了工业化的目标。科学进步，教育和住房成为国家福利，上百万农民成为工人（尽管他们的生活条件跟西方相比仍然十分恶劣）。言论自由不复存在，任何宗教活动都被禁止。[PARAGRAPH:2]自30年代开始，斯大林相信纳粹德国将成为巨大威胁。于是他想跟英法结盟，但遭到冷遇。为了争取时间，斯大林和希特勒达成了瓜分东欧的协议。1939年9月，德国进攻波兰，三个星期后苏联介入战争并吞并波兰东部领土。[PARAGRAPH:2]斯大林相信通过这些举动能换来希特勒的善意而使德国的进攻不会很快发生。然而，跟许多其他领袖一样，斯大林没能读懂希特勒。尽管事先在边界地区收到大量警报，斯大林没有采取防御措施。实际上，再进攻的第一天，斯大林还相信这只不过是误会，而不让他的部队进行反击而触怒希特勒。由于斯大林的失误，苏联红军蒙受了巨大损失。[PARAGRAPH:2]在斯大林被弄懵了的时候，苏联的巨大版图组止了德国人赢得速胜。1941年12月，俄国古老的盟友“寒冬”保卫了莫斯科。恢复常态后，斯大林带领苏联人民对纳粹德国进行了殊死斗争。斯大林把重工业东移乌拉尔山区，结合苏联巨大的幅员和人力资源，加上西方盟国的支援，苏联红军进军柏林，赢得了最终的胜利。然而，苏联也付出了一千万军人和两千万平民生命的巨大代价。[PARAGRAPH:2]战争结束时，红军已经在东欧泛滥，斯大林也无意撤回他们。尽管在战时斯大林对英美许诺过自由选举，他无意实行，并在那里广泛地扶植傀儡政权。尽管铁托的南斯拉夫摆脱了苏联的控制，其他的东欧国家在未来的三十年里饱受苏联的压迫。[PARAGRAPH:2]战时的松散联盟并未缓解苏联对西方的敌意。斯大林对中国共产党的支持以及1948年对西柏林的封锁逐渐引发了冷战。世界在代理人战争跟核军备竞赛中度过了五十年。[PARAGRAPH:2]斯大林时期，他大搞个人崇拜。当斯大林在1953年终于死去的时候，苏联上下流露出真挚而巨大的悲痛。但到1956年，赫鲁晓夫通过秘密报告披露了斯大林的罪行，公众对他的态度也开始转变。总的来说，斯大林成功地把一个沙皇时代的农业国家变成一个世界级的工业强权。对于战胜德国纳粹，也没有任何其他国家比苏联更有功劳。然而实现这些成就的野蛮做法应该被铭记于心，斯大林也将永远作为一个争议人物名留史册。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_RAMESSES_II_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Ramesses II [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]Pharaoh of Egypt [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1302 - 1213 BC[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Also known as "Ramesses the Great," Ramesses was an Egyptian pharaoh of the Nineteenth Dynasty. He was the third king in his dynasty, the son of King Seti I and Queen Tuya. Ramesses was born around 1302 BC and ruled from approximately 1279 to 1213 BC. Among Ramesses' many wives, the most famous was Nefertari, who was his principal wife for over twenty years and was later deified and worshipped as a goddess. Ramesses seems to have enjoyed all of the benefits of his position as pharaoh, and he fathered about 100 children during his long rule. One of them, the Pharaoh Merneptah, became his successor. [PARAGRAPH:2]Ramesses was most famous for leading several military campaigns along the eastern Mediterranean coast. On one of these expeditions into modern-day Israel and Lebanon, Ramesses ran into the Hittite army of King Muwatallis. At the Battle of Kadesh in 1274, the two sides fought for control of the territory comprising modern Syria. It was probably the largest chariot battle ever fought, with some 5000 chariots engaged on both sides. The battle was largely inconclusive, and both sides claimed victory. However Ramesses lost more men than Muwatallis, so the Hittites probably got the best of the Egyptians. Two sides continued to struggle against one another for decades to come until they signed a peace treaty in 1258 BC - this is the first peace treaty ever recorded in history. At the other end of his domains, Ramesses also campaigned extensively south of the First Cataract of the Nile in Nubia, winning additional land for Egypt. [PARAGRAPH:2]Today Ramesses is one of the best-known Egyptian pharaohs, primarily because he had so many monuments and statues of himself erected. The renowned archaeological complex of Abu Simbel - one of the best-preserved sites from ancient Egypt - was built on his orders. Ramesses' mummy was discovered in 1881; it was moved to the Egyptian Museum in Cairo, where it is still proudly displayed to the public today. (His 3000-year old body is in surprisingly good shape.) [PARAGRAPH:2]Ramesses is often popularly identified as the pharaoh who confronted Moses in the Bible. However, Ramesses lived to the age of 90 after a long reign of 66 years; he did not drown in the Red Sea; and there is no mention in the records of a slave revolt during his reign - so this seems quite unlikely. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]拉美西斯二世[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]埃及法老[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]生卒年份：[\BOLD]前1302-前1213[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景：[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]拉美西斯二世即“拉美西斯大帝”，是古埃及第十九王朝的第三任法老（“拉美西斯”意为“拉的儿子”，即太阳神之子）。拉美西斯二世是法老塞梯一世和王后图雅之子。约生于公元前1302年，约前1279-前1213年在位。拉美西斯曾有多位王后，其中最著名的一位是尼菲塔利，她是拉美西斯的首任妻子，作为王后长达二十余年，后来她还被人们当作女神来崇拜。看起来拉美西斯充分享受着作为法老所拥有的权力和乐趣，在他漫长的统治期间，他生下了上百个孩子。其中一位成为他的继任者梅尼普塔法老。[PARAGRAPH:2]拉美西斯最著名的事迹是对地中海东岸地区的一系列远征。其中一次曾到达今以色列和黎巴嫩，并与穆瓦塔利斯国王率领的赫梯军队遭遇。双方在前1274年为争夺今叙利亚地区而进行的卡迪什战役也许是有史以来最大的一场车战，参加此役的战车约有5000辆之多。这场 战役没有决定性的结果，双方都宣称赢得了胜利。不过拉美西斯的损失比穆瓦塔利斯多，因此也许是赫梯人占据了上风。埃及与赫梯的战争持续了数十年，最终双方于前1258年缔结了和约——这也是有史以来第一份国际条约。（这份和约的埃及文本与赫梯文本均被保存下来，并为近代考古学者所发现。）在其国土的另一端，拉美西斯也越过位于努比亚的尼罗河第一瀑布向南扩张，为埃及赢得大片领土。[PARAGRAPH:2]时至今日，拉美西斯是最著名的埃及法老之一，他为自己建造了无数的纪念碑和雕像。著名的阿布辛贝神庙——这是古埃及遗迹中保存得最好的一处——就是他下令建造的。拉美西斯的木乃伊于1881年被发现，现存开罗埃及博物馆，历经3000年仍然保存完好。[PARAGRAPH:2]人们往往认为圣经旧约出埃及记里摩西见到的那位埃及法老就是拉美西斯。但是，拉美西斯并未在红海里淹死，而是活了90岁，统治埃及长达66年；而且在他统治期间也没有任何奴隶发动起义的记载——所以那不太可能是他。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_TREBUCHET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The trebuchet was a medieval siege weapon designed to throw a projectile a great distance through the air. The trebuchet originated in China sometime between the fifth and third centuries BC. From there it spread to the west, reaching Europe around 500 AD. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Although it is usually thought of as a type of catapult, the trebuchet is in fact a gigantic sling attached to a lever. The shorter arm of the lever carries a counterweight, while the longer arm carries the sling that throws the projectile. In operation the sling end is pulled towards the ground (lifting the counterweight in the process) and held in place by a trigger while a projectile is loaded into the sling. When the trigger is released, the counterweight falls and the sling flies up and above the machine, releasing the projectile at the top of its arc. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Constructed properly, trebuchets could fire very heavy loads. In modern reconstructions using trebuchets built with the original tools and materials, trebuchets have been able to throw projectiles weighing as much as 300 kilograms. Aiming the trebuchet was difficult and required some practice and knowledge of engineering - both of which were usually in short supply for medieval operators. Trebuchets were also extremely heavy and almost immobile; this, combined with their slow rate of their fire, made them impractical for anything except siege operations. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Although the Chinese were the first to develop the trebuchet, by the time of the Mongol invasions the Chinese had fallen behind other parts of the world in siege technology. This was due to the fact that China had been politically united for long periods of time, preventing the formation of strong fortresses across the country, and the traditional enemies of the Chinese were nomadic warriors - not fortified city-dwellers. Nevertheless, the Chinese were still far more advanced in siege warfare than the Mongols, and it was not until the Mongols adopted Chinese practices that they began to have success capturing enemy fortifications. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]Late in the conquest of Song China, Mongol leader Kublai Khan brought in Arab engineers from the Mongol holdings in Persia to build hinged counterweight trebuchets, which were more advanced than anything yet seen in China. With the aid of these powerful weapons, Kublai was able to take the previously-impenetrable fortress of Xiangyang in 1273, and from there rapidly take the rest of Song China's cities, completing his conquest of the Song Empire in 1279. [PARAGRAPH:2:1]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>抛石机是中世纪的一种攻城器械，能够通过抛掷方式攻击远距离的坚固目标。最早的抛石机约在前5世纪至前3世纪间产生于中国。后逐渐向西流传，约在公元500年左右传到欧洲。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]抛石机经常被视为一种大型的投石车，但其具体结构仍有所不同。抛石机实际上是由一个巨大的悬带与一个巨大的杠杆相连组成的。杠杆较短的力臂上挂有一个平衡锤，较长的力臂上则挂有安放抛掷物的悬带。操作抛石机时，先将杠杆的悬带一端置于地面（同时提升平衡锤），用大型扳机扣住，在悬带上安放抛掷物。然后释放扳机让平衡锤快速下落，通过杠杆作用以大抛物线发射抛掷物。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]制造完善的抛石机能够发射非常大质量的抛掷物。现代人使用旧式工具及材料复制的抛石机能够发射重达300公斤的抛掷物。抛石机要瞄准目标是非常困难的，需要足够的实验及工程学知识——两者在中世纪都十分缺乏。而且抛石机本身非常沉重，几乎不可移动；加上发射频率非常低下，因此它仅适用于围城战。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]虽然中国人最早发明了抛石机，但在蒙古入侵的时代，中国的攻城武器技术已经落后于世界其他地区。这是由于中国长时间的安定和平使其城市无须建造坚固的防御体系，中国传统上的对手都是一些游牧民族——也很少建设坚固的城防。尽管如此，中国人仍比蒙古人更擅长围城战，直到蒙古人也掌握攻城武器技术之事，才能够攻陷对手的坚城。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]在对中国宋朝的征服战争中，蒙古统治者忽必烈命令来自西域的阿拉伯技师制造了大型抛石机（回回炮），比当时中国的同类武器更先进。运用这种威力强大的新装备，忽必烈于1273年占领了曾经久攻不下的襄阳城，以此为突破口深入内地，最终于1279年完全征服了宋帝国。[PARAGRAPH:2:1]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CARTHAGE_NUMIDIAN_CAVALRY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Numidia was a Berber kingdom located in northern Africa to the west of Carthage. Originally nomadic tribesmen and well-versed in horsemanship, the Numidians were most famous for their cavalry, which was considered to be among the finest in the ancient world. These warriors were lightly-armed - riding on swift horses equipped with nothing more than a small shield and a fistful of javelins - but very tough customers nonetheless. Even after settling down in cities, the Numidians remained enamored with the horse warriors - the Numidians did eventually produce infantry, but it was always regarded as unreliable and substantially inferior to the cavalry. [PARAGRAPH:2]Numidian cavalry specialized in hit-and-run attacks, making excellent use of their javelins to harass and break up enemy formations. They were never intended to close with the enemy and fight hand-to-hand. Roman commanders were initially skeptical of the threat posed by such lightly armed cavalry, but they soon learned of the danger caused by a force that constantly would attack, retreat and regroup, and then attack again, always remaining out of range of melee weapons. Ancient authors compare the Numidian cavalry to a pack of dogs, because of the way that they savaged the flanks and rear of enemy formations. It required strict discipline for opposing infantry not to break ranks when they came under attack from Numidian cavalry, but in time the Romans learned from their mistakes and became more adept at combating them. [PARAGRAPH:2]Numidian cavalry was not the fastest, but since the riders wore no armor, they were nimbler than the opposition of the day and able to traverse terrain too difficult for heavier cavalry. Numidian cavalry is most famous for serving in Hannibal's cavalry wing during the Second Punic War. However, they were also employed by the Romans as mercenaries as well. Julius Caesar deployed Numidians during his campaigns - and also fought against them during the Roman Civil War. In short, Numidian cavalry was highly prized and among the best light cavalry in the ancient world. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>努米底亚是一个位于迦太基西面的北非柏柏尔人王国。努米底亚人最初是一个精于骑术的游牧民族，他们的骑兵非常有名，被认为是远古世界最强大的骑兵。努米底亚骑兵属于轻骑兵——仅配备一面小盾牌及几支标枪——但战斗力却极为出色。虽然后来的努米底亚人选择了定居城市的生活方式，他们还是习惯于骑马作战——努米底亚人也建立了步兵部队，但仍然认为步兵不如骑兵可靠，无法赖以制胜。[PARAGRAPH:2]努米底亚骑兵擅长袭扰战术，能够熟练地运用标枪打击并扰乱敌人的阵形。他们从不靠近对手进行肉搏战。罗马的将领起初对这样的轻装骑兵不以为意，但他们很快就发现这种连续攻击——撤退——返回战术的可怕，近战武器完全奈何他们不得。古代的文学家将努米底亚骑兵比作野狗，他们会从各个方向袭击敌人的战阵。步兵阵线需要严格的训练才不致在努米底亚骑兵的打击下崩溃，不过罗马人很快吸取了教训，开始发展出能够对付骑兵袭扰的灵活战术。[PARAGRAPH:2]努米底亚骑兵虽然不是最快速的骑兵，但由于他们没有护甲，因而拥有比当时的其他重装骑兵高得多的机动能力。最令努米底亚骑兵闻名于世的是在第二次布匿战争中作为汉尼拔大军侧翼的出色战绩。不过，他们也同样受雇于罗马军队。朱利乌斯·恺撒进行的各场战役中都有努米底亚骑兵的身影——在罗马内战期间，他也需要面对努米底亚骑兵的攻击。总而言之，努米底亚骑兵声名卓著，是古代世界最好的轻骑兵之一。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CELTIC_WARRIOR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The warriors of the Celtic tribes were widely feared by the inhabitants of the more civilized regions on the northern side of the Mediterranean. The Celts were known as tall, wild barbarians who fought with a savage fury. Conspicuous for their bravery, there are numerous accounts of Celts charging naked into battle with total disregard for their own safety. The Celts would often paint their bodies different colors to increase the intimidation factor. When clothed, the Celtic fighters wore brightly colored shirts and trousers, featuring striped or checkered patterns for decoration. They sometimes wore bronze helmets decorated with horns or wings in order to make themselves look even taller. The Celts were also head hunters, cutting off the heads of their defeated foes to serve as trophies. This was a way for a warrior to win great respect in Celtic society, and it may have served some religious purpose as well. The Romans were justifiably terrified of this practice and would often kill themselves rather than be taken captive by the Celts. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Celts are believed to have invented mail armor, which the Romans would adopt from them after the Gaulish sack of Rome in 390 BC. In battle, most Celtic warriors were probably equipped with spears, a simple weapon and easy to produce in large numbers. However, the Celts are much more famous for their use of large, two-handed iron swords. The Celts were the first to create these broadswords, which were used for slashing at the enemy (very different from the Roman short sword, which was entirely limited to stabbing). Celtic chieftains or other high-ranking figures were the ones most likely to carry these swords. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Celtic warriors were individually brave and fearsome fighters; however, they were also famously undisciplined. There was virtually no unit drill, and thus no unit cohesion: Celtic battles were wild melees in which every warrior fought as he thought best. Thus, while unmatched in personal combat, the Celtic warrior fared poorly against the group unity and strict discipline of the Roman legion. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Celtic tribes had almost no political unity either. Regarding each other with fear and suspicion and constantly engaged in petty internecine squabbles over territory, they were unable to pull together to face the approaching Roman threat. Facing this divided foe, General Julius Caesar was able to conquer Gaul in under a decade. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>凯尔特部族骁勇的战士总是令地中海北部沿海各“文明”国度的居民感到恐惧。凯尔特人被他们视为高大狂野的蛮族，对待敌人残酷无情。他们英勇无畏的民族性格为世人所公认，据记载凯尔特人总是赤裸身体冲锋陷阵，毫不顾及自己的安全。凯尔特人喜欢用各种颜料涂抹身体，使自己看起来更威武；或是穿着色彩鲜艳、带有条纹或方格的衣裤。有时他们头戴以牛角或翅膀装饰的青铜盔，看上去更显得身材高大。凯尔特人还喜欢砍下敌人的头颅作为战利品，这在凯尔特社会中是赢得众人尊敬的重要方式。因此被俘的罗马人宁可自杀，也不愿被凯尔特人斩首。[PARAGRAPH:2]据认为链甲是凯尔特人的发明，在前390年高卢人攻陷罗马之后，罗马人也从敌人那里学会了制做链甲的技术。大多数凯尔特人在战斗中使用矛作为武器，因为矛容易制造，适于大量装备。不过凯尔特人更著名的武器则是铁制的双手宽刃长剑。凯尔特人最早制造了这种以劈砍为主的宽刃大剑（与以刺杀为主的罗马短剑差异极大）。凯尔特人首领或其他大人物最喜欢佩带这种大剑。[PARAGRAPH:2]单独凯尔特战士的勇力是令人恐惧的，然而他们的最大弱点则是缺乏组织与纪律性。凯尔特军队实际上根本没有团队协作相互配合的概念：凯尔特人总是各自为战、自行其是。因此，虽然他们勇力无人能及，整体而言却是无法与训练有素、纪律严明的罗马军团相对抗的。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VIKING_BESERKER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Berserks (or berserkers) were Viking warriors who worked themselves up into terribles rage before going into battle. The word berserker comes from the Norse words "bjorn" (meaning bear) or "bare" (meaning naked) and "serkr" (meaning shirt); a berserk was either someone who went into battle wearing the "shirt" of a bear (i.e. someone who was bear-like in rage and strength) or someone who went into battle naked. Berserks thought that by wearing the fur of a bear they would be possessed by the spirit of the animal and possibly even shift into its form. Berserks were also known to have sworn allegiance to the Norse sky god Odin, and they believed that he would protect them and give them superhuman strength. The Vikings also believed that if death came while fighting as a berserk, the deceased would travel straight to the warrior paradise of Valhalla. [PARAGRAPH:2]No one is exactly sure how berserks induced the crazed state of violence described by contemporaries. Some theories speculate that the wild behavior was prompted by the taking of various hallucinogenic drugs, or was caused by mild epilepsy, or even a genetic disorder that caused overly large skull growth. Perhaps the most likely explanation is that before going into battle the berserks simply worked themselves into frenzies by painting their faces, howling like animals, beating helmets and drums - and drinking large quantities of alcohol. [PARAGRAPH:2]All stories about berserks agree that they fought with crazed strength and were immune to pain until battle was ended. Berserks were often portrayed as villains, slaying anything that moved - including their own family members. In battle even the Berserks' allies usually chose to keep them at arm's length and were never comfortable in their presence. Scandinavian kings refused to employ them as bodyguards for fear that they would forget who to protect in the fighting. [PARAGRAPH:2]In 1015 the berserks were outlawed in Norway, and Gr&#225;g&#225;s, the medieval Icelandic law code, sentenced berserk warriors to exile. After the widespread adoption of Christianity across Scandinavia, in 1100 AD the organization of berserk warbands disappeared. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>世人将凶悍好斗的维京战士称为“狂暴战士”（“berserk”或“berserker”）。这个词可能来源于挪威语“熊”（bjorn）或“赤裸”（bare）以及“衬衣”（serkr），因此其含义或是“披着熊皮的战士”（亦即“象熊一样凶猛狂暴的战士”），或是“赤身的战士”。狂暴战士认为身披熊皮就可以拥有熊的凶猛和力量，甚至成为熊的化身。狂暴战士只效忠于北欧神话中的天神奥丁，相信奥丁能赋予他们超人的力量。维京人认为阵亡的狂暴战士将能进入传说中的瓦尔哈拉神殿获得永生。[PARAGRAPH:2]现在我们无法确定是什么导致狂暴战士陷入当时人们所描述的那种狂暴状态。有人猜测是由于服用了某种致幻剂的结果，或者是中度癫痫症发作，甚至可能是遗传性疾病使头部发育出现异常。也许最合理的解释是因为狂暴战士在上战场之前会用颜料涂抹脸部，模仿野兽大声喊叫，伴随着战鼓的节奏用武器敲打头盔——并且会大量饮酒。[PARAGRAPH:2]有关狂暴战士的故事一致描述说：他们在作战时会变得极其疯狂、力大无穷而且刀枪不入。狂暴战士在发怒时会不分青红皂白地杀死任何活人——包括自己的亲人。甚至连处于同一阵线的战友也不敢同他们靠得太近，并时刻保持警惕。斯堪的纳维亚的国王们拒绝让他们做自己的贴身护卫，因为害怕一旦打起仗来，狂暴战士会忘记自己要保护的对象。[PARAGRAPH:2]挪威国王埃里克一世曾于1015年宣布禁绝狂暴战士，而中世纪的冰岛法典“格拉加斯”也规定对狂暴战士须加以放逐。随着基督教在斯堪的纳亚的传播，到1100年时，狂暴战士的团体已经销声匿迹了。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_OTTOMAN_JANISSARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Janissaries were an elite fighting force of infantry raised by the Ottoman sultans. They formed the sultan's household troops and bodyguard, eventually rising to a position of enormous influence before being disbanded in the nineteenth century. Murad I founded the Janissary corps around 1330; the troops were made up of non-Muslim boys who were captured in battle or bought as slaves and brought up as warriors. This was very similar to the Mameluk slave soldiers of Egypt, who may have been the inspiration for the Janissaries. Janissaries became the first infantry units in the Ottoman military forces, because at the time no free man would consent to fighting on foot. [PARAGRAPH:2]After 1380 the system for recruiting new soldiers into the Janissaries became standardized through a process called the "devshirmeh:" this was basically a "human tax" where each community had to contribute a certain number of young boys to the state. In practice these were almost always Christian slaves. [PARAGRAPH:2]The boys were sequestered in special barracks, where they would be converted to Islam and trained to become elite soldiers (a process very similar to that practiced by the Spartans of ancient Greece). Although slaves, the Janissaries received special privileges, including the right to bear weapons and higher pay than other soldiers. Although the Janissaries began their existence as a small bodyguard for the sultan, in time they came to comprise much of the Ottoman army, topping out at over 200,000 men at some points. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Janissaries originally were trained to be expert archers, but once firearms were invented they quickly adopted the new weapons, becoming fiercely proficient with muskets. They usually used axes or sabres for melee combat. Janissaries were present at all of the major battles in the early history of the Ottoman Empire, including the Siege of Constantinople in 1453. [PARAGRAPH:2]The very success of the Janissaries would eventually destroy them. Realizing their importance, they began demanding higher pay, threatening rebellion if their demands were refused. Their first rebellion took place in 1449, and it was followed by many more. By the eighteenth century, the Janissaries dominated the government. Through frequent palace coups they changed sultans as they wished, and they blocked much-needed modernization reforms in the Ottoman army. Many of the Janissaries Became corrupted, no longer training for battle but instead pursuing commercial ventures or political office, and the weakness of the Ottomans in the face of Russian and Austrian expansion soon became obvious to all. Desperate to regain control of their country, the Ottoman rulers made determined efforts to eradicate them. [PARAGRAPH:2]Finally, in 1826 Mahmud II was able to form a non-Janissary army strong enough to challenge the Janissaries. The Janissaries did not go down peacefully, and Mahmud II had to use artillery to shell the Janissaries' barracks and batter them into submission. This event - known as the "Auspicious Incident," ended the Janissaries. Their characteristic marching music is the only trace of them that remains today. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>苏丹亲兵（Janissary）是奥斯曼帝国苏丹下令组建的精锐步兵部队，最初是作为苏丹的贴身卫士，其势力和影响在日后变得越来越大，最终于19世纪被解散。穆拉德一世于1330年左右首次组建苏丹亲兵部队；其成员均为在战争中俘获、或是被卖作奴隶的非穆斯林男童经过专门训练而成。这种做法与埃及的奴隶战士“马穆鲁克”非常类似，很可能是受到后者的启发。苏丹亲兵是奥斯曼军队的第一支步兵部队，因为当时的奥斯曼自由人均不愿步行作战。[PARAGRAPH:2]1380年以后，苏丹亲兵的训练方式已成为固定的制度，称为“人税”（devshirmeh），每个村社都必须向帝国提供规定数量的男童。实际上“人税”通常都是卖为奴隶的基督徒。[PARAGRAPH:2]这些男童将被送往与世隔绝的特殊兵营，在那里他们必须改奉伊斯兰教，接受成为精锐战士的严格训练（训练方式与古希腊的斯巴达人非常相似）。虽然身为奴隶，苏丹亲兵也拥有许多特殊待遇，他们有权在平时佩带武器，薪金也比普通士兵高得多。这支起初作为苏丹贴身卫士的部队人数很少，但逐渐发展成为奥斯曼军队的主要组成部分，其人数曾经多达200,000人。[PARAGRAPH:2]苏丹亲兵部队起初接受的是成为优秀弓箭手的训练，但随着火器的引入，他们很快接受了这类新式武器，能够熟练地使用火枪。他们通常使用手斧和弯刀进行肉搏战。苏丹亲兵参加了奥斯曼帝国前期的所有重要战役，包括1453年围攻君士坦丁堡。[PARAGRAPH:2]苏丹亲兵的战功也导致了他们日后的毁灭。他们开始倚仗自己的力量要求更高的报酬，一旦得不到满足就威胁发动叛乱。首次苏丹亲兵叛乱发生于1449年，此后类似的叛乱层出不穷。到了18世纪，苏丹亲兵几乎掌控了帝国政府。他们甚至多次发动宫庭政变，拥立符合自己利益的新苏丹，并阻挠奥斯曼军队进行现代化改造的努力。苏丹亲兵部队的许多成员都变得腐化堕落，他们不再专心于军事训练，转而从事商业或政治活动，奥斯曼军队在面对俄国和奥地利军队时逐渐显露出明显的劣势。为了收回对国政的控制权，奥斯曼苏丹终于决定消灭这股力量。[PARAGRAPH:2]到1826年，穆拉德二世已经组建起一支足以同苏丹亲兵相抗衡的新军。苏丹亲兵不愿放弃现有利益，穆拉德二世不得不下令炮轰他们的兵营，迫使其就范。这一事件史称“吉祥事变”，苏丹亲兵部队就此解散。只剩下那一段富于特色的进行曲流传至今。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_KOREAN_HWACHA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The hwacha was an anti-personnel weapon developed by the Koreans, and it is believed to have been one of the first gunpowder-based anti-personnel weapons ever created. The hwacha was a platform constructed to launch large numbers of fire arrows (or "Shin Ki Chon") at enemy targets. Hwachas were mounted on carts and wheelbarrows. A typical hwacha platform held seven or more rows of fifteen arrows and could fire from 150 to 200 fire arrows at once. The fire arrows had hollow tips and the shafts were fitted with narrow pipes. The tips and pipes were filled with gunpowder and each was equipped with a fuse. [PARAGRAPH:2]When lit, the fire arrows' fuses would first ignite the powder in the pipes, causing the arrows to shoot off like rockets. The fuses would continue to burn until they reached the gunpowder in the arrows' heads, which would then explode - with luck, somewhere near enemy soldiers. However, the weapons were extremely inaccurate and the Koreans had to fire off huge volleys to ensure significant damage to their targets. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Shin Ki Chon fire arrows were first developed in Korea and China around 1400 AD, and the hwacha dates from shortly after this period. The fire arrows could travel as far as one kilometer, an amazing range for artillery weapons at that time. Given their famous inaccuracy, the hwacha was best used against massed enemy formations at medium range: even if not precisely on target when they exploded, shrapnel from the fire arrows could still significantly hurt the enemy. Hwacha also were useful shock weapons, due to the noise and light produced by the rocket-like exploding arrows, and even seasoned troops could break and run the first time they encountered the strange new weapon. [PARAGRAPH:2]The best-known use of hwacha historically was during the Japanese invasion of Korea in 1592-98. The Japanese samurai typically advanced in dense groups - easy targets for the hwacha. At the Battle of Haengju, 3400 Koreans were able to defeat 30,000 Japanese with the help of 40 hwacha. [PARAGRAPH:2]The hwacha eventually became obsolete when more efficient metal projectiles (like bullets and artillery shells) replaced the fire arrows. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>（塞爱维小提示：经查该所谓高丽“特色单位”实系盗版天朝火厢车。明何良臣《阵记》载有火厢车，亦名火柜车。内装火箭百枝，进攻冲敌之用。）[PARAGRAPH:2]火厢车是高丽人制造的一种人员杀伤型武器，据认为是史上最古老的基于火药技术的人员杀伤型武器。火厢车是用于向敌方目标大量发射火药箭（或称“神机箭”），靠人力推拉的轮式载具。普通的火厢车装载的火药箭在7排以上，每排15支，最多可同时发射150至200支火药箭。箭头及箭杆为空心，其中装满火药，外绑装满火药并插有导火索的圆筒。[PARAGRAPH:2]火药箭被引燃后，圆筒中的火药首先燃烧，向后喷射的气体推动火药箭向前飞行。最终导火索会引燃箭头中的火药并发生爆炸——幸运得话就能炸到敌人。但是，这种武器的精确度非常差，必须集中起来同时发射才能对目标造成有效的杀伤。[PARAGRAPH:2]在高丽和中国，“神机箭”最早于1400年左右出现，此后不久即发明了火厢车。火药箭的射程可达一公里，对当时的火器来说，算是非常了不起的射程了。由于其精确度很低，火厢车最适于在中距离对付敌人的密集阵形：即使不能直接命中目标，爆炸的碎片也能对敌人造成有效的杀伤。火药箭尖锐的呼啸声和爆炸的火光也具有相当的威慑力，甚至久经战阵的勇士，在首次遭遇这种武器的攻击时也可能会惊慌奔逃。[PARAGRAPH:2]在1592-98年的日本侵朝战争（“壬辰倭乱”）中，火厢车大显身手。由于日本武士经常排成密集阵形发动冲锋，往往成为火厢车的理想靶子。在海州之战中，3400名朝鲜军凭借40辆火厢车，击败了30,000日本军的进攻。[PARAGRAPH:2]随着威力更强大的金属弹丸（例如子弹和炮弹）开始取代火药箭，火厢车逐渐退出了历史舞台。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_ZULU_IMPI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The Zulu spearmen were warriors without peer in southern Africa, dispatching every force that they encountered until running up against the superior technology of the Europeans. The Zulus were organized for the first time by Shaka, who began forming spearmen into groups called "impi" even before he became the chief of his tribe. Impi warriors began training as early as the age of six, serving first as porters and servants, and when of age, the cadets were trained in the use of weapons. When Zulu males reached adulthood at age twenty, they would become full members of their warband. [PARAGRAPH:2]Zulu spearmen were expected to be able to outrun a horse, travel 50 miles a day on foot, and move silently through rough terrain. The difficult training that the Zulu warriors went through made them tougher and stronger than their opponents, who frequently outnumbered the Zulus in battle. [PARAGRAPH:2]When going into battle, the Zulu spearmen painted their faces with chalk and red ochre to make themselves more intimidating. They carried spears (called "ilkwa") made of wood with a long iron point. The ilkwa was a stabbing weapon, unlike its predecessor the javelin-like "assegai," which had been used for throwing. Along with the spear, Zulus would carry a medium-sized shield. As contact with Europeans became more frequent later in the nineteenth century, Zulu warriors also made use of muskets and rifles captured from the British, although the Zulus did not have the training to use them properly. [PARAGRAPH:2]Tactically, the soldiers of a Zulu impi often used Shaka's "bull horns" formation, which consisted a main force ("isifuba" or chest) and two wings on the sides ("izimpondo" or horns) designed to outflank the enemy. A fourth group of veterans would remain as a reserve in the rear. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Zulu spearmen formed an effective and highly-versatile army which proved to be almost invincible when facing other African forces. They traveled lightly and could move very fast (if not the 50 miles a day that they claimed), but they also packed enough force to disrupt heavy enemy formations. Shaka used hit-and-run techniques against the numerically-superior Ndwandwe in the 1820s and achieved complete victory in a series of engagements. [PARAGRAPH:2]However, the Zulu spearmen were no match for the Martini-Henry rifles and Maxim guns of the British army when they went to war in 1878. The technological rift could not be overcome with Zulu valor. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>祖鲁是南部非洲最强悍的战士，他们能够横扫所遇到的每一个对手，直到面对掌握先进军事科技的欧洲人才失去了力量。祖鲁人是在沙卡的领导下开始崛起的，沙卡在继任部族首领之前即组建了新型的矛兵部队，称为“伊姆皮”（impi）。这支部队的战士从六岁起就开始训练，起先是担任仆役，然后才学习使用武器。祖鲁男子到20岁成年并正式加入战斗团队。[PARAGRAPH:2]祖鲁矛兵宣称在崎岖地形下的行进速度能与野马媲美，凭借双脚一天能走50英里。虽然经常面对占据数量优势的敌人，祖鲁战士所经受的严格训练使他们比对手更强壮、更凶悍。[PARAGRAPH:2]在战场上，祖鲁矛兵用白垩与赭石涂沫脸部，使自己看起来更加威武。他们的武器是矛（“伊基瓦”），矛杆为木制，装有长长的铁制矛尖。“伊基瓦”是刺杀型的武器，而其前身“阿塞盖”则是类似标枪的投掷型武器。祖鲁战士还配备一面中型盾牌。到19世纪后期，随着与欧洲人的接触日益频繁，祖鲁战士也开始使用从英军手里缴获的火枪和来复枪，但他们没有经过正规的火器训练。[PARAGRAPH:2]祖鲁军队通常使用沙卡所创造的“牛角”阵形作战，该阵形由担任主力的中央（“伊西弗巴”，即前胸）和负责包抄敌军的两翼（“伊基彭多”，即尖角）构成。另外还有一批老兵殿后作为预备队。[PARAGRAPH:2]祖鲁矛兵组成了一支具有强大战斗力和灵活性的大军，在面对其他非洲土著军队时几乎百战百胜。作为轻装部队，他们能以极快的速度行进（虽然可能达不到他们宣称的每天50英里），并能突破防御严密的敌方战阵。在19世纪20年代，沙卡采取袭扰战术对付拥有数量优势的恩德万德韦人，并赢得了辉煌的胜利。[PARAGRAPH:2]然而，在1878年对英国的战争中，祖鲁矛兵则完全不是装备马蒂尼-亨利式来复枪和马克沁式机枪的英军的对手。军事技术方面的巨大鸿沟是无法靠个人的勇气来弥补的。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
