<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- freesand -->
<!-- GameText Civilopedia Techs -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<!-- TECH INFOS -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MYSTICISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]People of the ancient world were fascinated and awed by the forces of nature surrounding them. Earthquakes, storms and other phenomena were generally regarded as signs from heaven. Individuals and groups arose to formulate explanations for these events, and pass the knowledge along to the tribe. The priests and priestesses of mysticism, who were often called oracles, claimed union with the divine through meditation and trance-like contemplation. Primitive mysticism offered mankind the first, tenuous links with the powers that shaped their world, and represented the first move toward the organized polytheistic and monotheistic religions to come.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]远古的人们对自然力量充满好奇与敬畏。地震、暴雨和其他自然现象往往被视为神力的体现。不少个人和群体开始尝试对这一切提出解释，并将这些解释在部落中流传下去。神秘论信仰的祭司常被称为先知。他们宣称能通过冥想或附体等方式与神灵沟通。这种原始的理念引导着人们对创世之力的模糊信仰，并成为之后的多神论及一神论宗教的基础。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MEDITATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Meditation is the practice of relaxing the body while calming and focusing the mind. Many religions - Buddhism, for example - see meditation as a religious ritual, but it is also widely used outside of religion. [PARAGRAPH:2]According to Buddhism, meditation is a path to spiritual enlightenment. It allows one to gain wisdom and it provides refuge from the burden of karma and the toils and misery of daily existence. The Buddha himself gained great wisdom and knowledge of the nature of human suffering from meditating under a humble Bo tree. [PARAGRAPH:2]Many people use meditation as a way to relieve the stress and strain of daily life. The Hindu practice of "yoga" is a formalized form of meditation that enjoys popularity across the globe. Meditation is widely believed to have healing powers, as it allows one's mind to aid the body in overcoming injury and infirmities.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]冥想是通过放松身体来使心灵宁静并集中注意力的练习。很多宗教——比如佛教——把冥想视为一种宗教仪式，但在宗教以外它也被广泛运用。[PARAGRAPH:2]就佛教而言，冥想是使灵魂获得启迪的途径。冥想给予人们智慧，也庇护人们渡过因果报应的重担和生活本身的痛苦和不幸。佛祖在一棵菩提树下冥想时顿悟了无穷的智慧和人类受苦的本源。[PARAGRAPH:2]很多人通过冥想来缓解日常生活的紧张和压力。印度教的“瑜伽”也是冥想的一种方式，全世界的人们都热衷于此。很多人相信冥想有治疗人的力量，人们可以借此用心灵的力量战胜身体的虚弱和伤痛。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POLYTHEISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Polytheism is the belief that the world and the environment is ruled or controlled by a number of different gods or divinities. Many ancient religions were polytheistic, notably those of the Egyptians, the Greeks, the Norse, and the Romans. Often, polytheistic religions have different gods for each force of nature and earthly phenomenon; for instance: a sun god, a moon god, a god of thunder, a god of the forests, and so forth. The reason for such diversity in divine beings probably stems from ancient civilizations attempting to find explanations for natural events they could not understand.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]多神论的基本理念在于世间的一切都由一些各不相同的神灵所掌握。许多远古信仰都是多神论的，埃及、希腊、挪威和罗马的众神尤为著名。通常每一种大自然的力量和现象都被认为是一种神灵的体现，如：太阳神、月亮神、雷神、森林之神等。这种众神统治世界观念的形成，可能缘起于远古的人类试图解释他们无法理解的自然现象。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PRIESTHOOD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A priest is a person who leads worshippers in performing religious ceremonies and rituals. The position was of extraordinary importance in early cultures, since men believed that their day-to-day survival depended upon the favor of the gods. The earliest priests were probably elderly men and women too infirm to hunt and gather, but revered for their holiness and wisdom. As the lines between the spiritual and physical were much less rigid than today, priests might also be the tribal healers or leaders. [PARAGRAPH:2]Many branches of Christianity, Hinduism and Buddhism still employ priests, and though their secular power is greatly diminished, in recent years priests have played important roles in getting societies to adopt social changes that benefit the people. In South America, priests are famous (or infamous) for their active participation in politics, while the late Pope John Paul II, the highest-ranking Roman Catholic priest, is given credit for hurrying the demise of the Soviet Union.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]祭司（或牧师、神甫等神职人员）是在宗教仪式中负责引导信众进行祭拜的人。自从人类开始相信他们的生存须仰仗神灵的眷顾，祭司的地位就变得越来越重要。早期的祭司通常是部族中的老人们，衰弱的身体使他们无法参加捕猎和采集，但凭借名望和智慧而受到普遍的崇敬。在那个时代，精神和肉体之间的界线还不像今天那么明确，所以祭司有时也担任本部族的医生和领袖。[PARAGRAPH:2]基督教的各分支教派以及印度教、佛教都有自已的“祭司”，尽管现其权力和影响已经不象过去那样巨大，但他们仍在促进社会发展、造福普通民众方面扮演着重要的角色。在南美各国，许多神职人员因积极参政而声名远扬（或臭名昭著）。已故教皇约翰·保罗二世，罗马天主教会的最高“祭司”，也被认为在加速苏联的解体进程方面发挥了关键的作用。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MONOTHEISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Monotheism is the belief that there is only one God. Perhaps the oldest monotheistic religion is Judaism. The original Israelites were polytheistic in a sense, since they did not deny the existence of other gods in addition to their own. However, after being exiled to Babylonia in 586 BC, the Judeans turned to a truly monotheistic religion, where the God of Israel was seen as the universal God ruling the destiny of all nations. The scriptures of Judaism became part of the teachings of the two most widespread monotheistic religions, Christianity and Islam. More developed than earlier polytheistic beliefs, monotheistic religions tend to encompass and structure the entire lifestyles of the people who practice them.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]一神论的主旨在于世上只有一个神。最古老的一神论宗教可能是犹太教。但早期的犹太人信仰多神教可能更为合理，因为在相信自己的神之外，他们并没有拒绝其他的神。但自从公元586年被流放到巴比伦之后，犹太教转变为真正的一神教。以色列人的神掌管着一切国家的命运。而犹太教的早期典籍则在后来演变为流传最广的两大宗教——基督教和伊斯兰教的教义。比多神教更进一步的是，一神教更倾向于全面指导和组织信徒的生活方式。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MONARCHY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Rule by monarchy developed as a logical extension of the absolute rule of tribal chieftains. Many of the earliest monarchs, such as those in ancient Egypt, claimed that they ruled by divine right. In the spread of European monarchy during the Middle Ages, however, rulership was generally conveyed upon a leader who could most effectively raise and command an army.[PARAGRAPH:2]Monarchies are dynastic, with rule of the country passing to the eldest son when the king dies or retires. Monarchs had absolute rule over their subjects, severely limiting the personal and economic freedom of all citizens except for nobility and the rich upper class. Although monarchies ruled most of Europe for centuries, the unhappiness of lower-class citizens eventually grew intolerable, causing several major revolutions. By the mid-18th century, the power of the European monarchs had been severely limited, paving the way for participatory systems of government.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]君主制可视为原始的部落酋长制的一种发展。许多早期的君主，例如古埃及的法老就宣称其统治权是神灵所授予的。而当君主制在中世纪欧洲传播开来时，统治权则在那些能够有效供养和控制军队的人士间传递，一般君主总在退休或死后将统治权交给长子。君主们拥有对臣民的极大权力，严格的管束着人民的个人自由和经济权利，却往往对贵族和其他富有的上层阶级束手无策。尽管君主制在整个欧洲顺利运行了数个世纪，但下层人民的愤怒最终仍爆发出来，导致了几次大规模的革命。到18世纪中期，欧洲君主们的权力已受到严格限制，逐渐形成权力制衡的政体。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LITERATURE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The art of writing as literature, bodies of works written thematically, is at least as old in the western world as Greek culture. Surviving records of Babylonian culture refer to at least two epic tales, which infers that literature as a comprehensive body is much older, but neither survive to this day. The development of a living body of literature became indicative of an advanced culture and are always correlated with advances in science, philosophy, theology, and art.[PARAGRAPH:2]Literature in the western world has survived in the forms that the Greeks and Romans established, but the expense and effort of hand copying texts ensured that only the wealthy had access to literate education. Libraries, which served as storehouses of these bodies of text, also became centers for education and the proliferation of ideas.[PARAGRAPH:2]Unfortunately the loss of many such libraries, such as the Great Library of Alexandria in a civil war in the 3rd century AD, also heralded the loss of many of these irreplaceable texts. It wasn't until the invention of the printing press by Johannes Gutenberg that books were printed rather than transcribed. That single advance in literature opened the field up to those other than monks and the wealthy, birthing a proliferation of literature that spread across the world.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]围绕固定主题撰写文献著作的历史在西方可能要追溯到希腊文明时代。根据历史记录，古巴比伦文明的两部史诗的产生时间还要更早，可惜没能流传至今。文献的撰写与传播是和科学，哲学，宗教和艺术的发展相互关联并互相影响的。[PARAGRAPH:2]早期西方文献多以希腊文和拉丁文传世，但由于人工抄写的巨额耗费，使得阅读成为富人的特权。图书馆作为书籍文献的集中地，也因此成为新思想的集中地。[PARAGRAPH:2]不幸的是，大多数古代图书馆并没有保存下来，尤其令人遗憾的是亚历山大图书馆毁于公元前3世纪一次内战，很多珍贵的文献著作因此而失传。直到约翰尼斯·古登堡发明印刷机之后印刷品才取代了手抄本，阅读也由僧侣和富人的专利转变为普通大众的享受，书面文献从此得以遍及世界。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CODE_OF_LAWS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The earliest tribal civilizations were bonded together by mutual needs and beliefs. A tribal chieftain, who acted as an advisor and enforcer of the will of the gods, ruled these groups. No formal laws existed in these early cultures, but fear of the gods and a sense of tribal customs and morality kept order in the tribe. As societies became larger and more diverse, the need arose for established rules of conduct. The earliest known codes of laws existed in Babylon, India, and Palestine. The Twelve Tables of Rome, written in 500 BC, and its successors such as the Justinian Code, were the first codes of law to distinguish between public law, which involves the state, and private law, which concerns disputes between citizens. Roman law was the first formalized written system of laws, and went on to influence many of the legal systems of the modern world.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]早期的部落往往由其共同的需求和信仰联合在一起。部落首领，作为神意的传达者和执行者掌握着整个部落的全部权力。早期文明并不存在成文法。对神的敬畏、部落风俗和道德感维持着整个部落的秩序。而随着社会的泛化和分化，对更严谨的社会准则的需求就逐渐浮出水面。现存最早的法典出现在巴比伦，印度和巴勒斯坦。制订于公元前500年左右的罗马十二铜表法，和作为其后继者的查士丁尼法，最早区分了适应于不同国家之间的国际法和适用于本国人民间的国内法这两个概念。罗马法作为最早形成的法律体系，对现代社会的法律制度具有深远影响。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DRAMA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Alfred Hitchcock once said, "Drama is life with the dull bits cut out." If he'd been alive during ancient times, he might have uttered these same words when facing a play from Euripides. Reflecting the interesting (and often) tragic parts of "life" on the stage was an important part of the ancient world, and helped to shape our modern culture.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]阿尔弗雷德·希区柯克曾经说过：“戏剧就是生活，但把乏味的部分去掉。”如果他活在古代，当他看到欧里庇得斯的悲剧时，想必会说出同样的话。在舞台上反映“生活”中有趣的戏剧性段落是古代世界的重要组成部分之一，这同样有助于塑造我们当代的文化。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FEUDALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In the unsettled times following the collapse of Charlemagne's Frankish empire, a new social and political system arose in Europe called feudalism. Derived from the concept of monarchy, feudalism was a hierarchical system in which each descending stratum owed allegiance to those above. The king, whose authority was second only to God, granted tracts of land, or fiefs, to his barons. The barons might then grant smaller estates to knights, who swore to protect and serve the baron. The knights, in turn, might then grant fractions of their fiefs to subordinates who would serve the knights. At the bottom of the feudal pyramid were the serfs, who could not own land, and acted essentially as slave laborers who worked the land for their masters. Feudalism began to decline in the 13th century, when standing armies and mercenaries began to fulfill the protective role once served by the vassals and knights.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]查理曼帝国崩溃后的动乱时期中，欧洲出现了一种名为封建制的全新的社会和政治模式。封建制由君主制发展而来，前者的特点在于它将社会分为多个层次，每一层均须向上一层宣誓效忠。国王的权威仅次于神。他将土地或者采邑赐给手下的封臣（封建领主），而封臣们又将土地分配赐给手下的骑士。骑士宣誓服从并保护封臣，并由此得到小块的采邑和仆人来服侍自己。在这个等级金字塔的最底层是农奴，农奴没有自己的土地，只能像奴隶般地为他的主人工作。大约在13世纪，封建制开始衰落，封臣和骑士曾经担任的角色逐渐被常备军和雇佣军所代替。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_THEOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Theology is the study of God and religious truth. Theologians take a more or less scientific approach to questions of religion, deeply studying the underlying meaning of scriptures and religious teachings rather than "taking them on faith". Theological seminaries teach courses of study in theology to prepare people as priests and clergymen. Many of the earliest colleges of the western world were originally established for this purpose. Theological study helped to remove some of the superstitions that had surrounded religion for so long, and brought religious study into a more enlightened age.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]神学的研究对象是神灵以及信仰的本质。神学家在探讨宗教问题时在一定程度上秉持着科学的态度，他们努力探寻经文与教义内在的、深层的含意，而不是单纯而无条件地“相信”。为了让即将成为牧师或教士的人充分掌握神学知识，许多神学院陆续建立起来。它们成为西方世界最早的一批大学。神学帮助人们摆脱了长久以来笼罩于宗教之上的迷信之雾，使对宗教信仰的研究进入一个更加理性的时代。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MUSIC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Music finds a comfortable parallel with that of human language. Much as language has words, sentences, and stories, music has tones, melodies, and songs. The theory of music emphasizes the elements from which music is composed. One such structure is the melody, which is a grouping of musical notes that combine into a basic, but immensely flexible structure. Another is the chord, which is two or more notes played simultaneously to create a harmony. The impact of music throughout history can be clearly seen, as both entertainment and an art.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]音乐与人类的语言有许多共同之处。正如语言有词汇、句子和故事，音乐也有音调、旋律和乐曲。音乐理论强调了音乐得以产生的元素。例如旋律将音乐符号组成了一个基本但却有极大灵活性的结构。其次是和弦，通过在同时演奏两个音符来造成和声。作为娱乐和艺术的结合体，在整个人类历史中，音乐均拥有巨大的影响力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GUILDS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A guild is an association of people who practice the same trade. The guilds seek to protect their members' incomes, maintain standards of performance, and train new workers in the trade. Guilds have often built hospitals, orphanages and schools to serve their members. Guilds seek to expand their membership to include all who practice their profession. Such monopolies allow guilds greater control over the fees their members can charge for their services. [PARAGRAPH:2]Many of the earliest guilds - Roman professional organizations, for instance - had strong religious components. One of the earliest known Muslim guilds were formed by the "warraqeen," or "those who work with knowledge." In the ninth century these professional writers and printers worked together to ensure the quality of published material and to stop other printers from making illegal copies of the material. [PARAGRAPH:2]The European guilds came into being around 1000 AD. They included a rigid hierarchy of skilled workers - apprentice, craftsman, journeyman, master and sometimes grandmaster. The higher in the hierarchy a member was, the more the payment he could demand. This structure greatly increased the guilds' memberships, since one could not attain the higher statuses without belonging to a guild.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]行会是做同样生意的人们组成的协会。行会的目的是保护会员的利益，维持贸易的规模，以及锻炼新加入的工人。行会通常建有为会员服务的医院、孤儿院和学校。行会希望扩张自己的规模，吸引所有做这类生意的人加入。这样的垄断使得行会更容易控制会员提供服务所获得报酬。[PARAGRAPH:2]很多早期的行会——例如罗马人的行会——有着很强的宗教成分。已知的早期穆斯林行会之一是以“沃拉钦”（意即“为智慧工作的人”）的形式建立的。这些专职作者和出版商共同工作以确保出版物的质量，并迫使其他出版商停止对这些出版物的非法复制。[PARAGRAPH:2]欧洲的行会在公元1000年左右出现。这些行会对参与其中的工人按照技能水平严格分级——学徒、技工、满师技工、熟练技工甚至技术大师。越高等级的会员，可以要求越高的报酬。这样的结构大大增加了行会的规模，因为一个人如果不加入行会就很难达到更高的地位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_SERVICE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Civil Service is the technology of bureaucracy - organizing and running a government. A successful civil service requires standard procedures, division of responsibility, hierarchy, and advancement through merit. Clearly record-keeping is crucial to the successful management of a government, as well. While some early cultures kept records on clay or wax or stone tablets, the advent of paper was a boon to the advance of bureaucracy and a civil service. [PARAGRAPH:2]One of the oldest known civil services is found in China, during the Tang dynasty (600-900 AD). This was created largely in response to the Confucian demands for honest government; among other innovations, the Tang civil servants were hired based upon the results of a written examination, rather than through the more common methods of bribery and patronage, and thus had fewer ties to the wealthy and powerful nobility. [PARAGRAPH:2]The English followed the Chinese civil service model when they created a bureaucracy to manage their growing colonies. Though successful, the practice did not spread to Europe until the mid-18th century.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]文官制度（或者叫做“公务员制度”）是官僚机构的制度基础——即政府机构的组织和运作规范。有效率的文官制度要求制定标准的办事流程、明确的责任划分、等级设置和评价提拔体系。实现成功的行政管理，非常重要的一点就是保留清晰完整的文件记录。早期的文明是用粘土、蜡或者石板作为书写载体的，而纸的发明无疑为官僚体系和文官制度的发展带来了极大的便利。[PARAGRAPH:2]已知最早的文官制度出现在中国的唐朝（7至10世纪）。这种新制度的建立在很大程度上是由于儒家学说非常强调政府的诚信廉洁。唐朝规定行政官员（“公务员”）的选拔方式是通过科举考试，而不再是通过贿赂和推荐，这样就减少了官员与有权势的贵族间的瓜葛。[PARAGRAPH:2]后来英国人在管理其遍布全球的殖民地时也效仿了中国的文官制度。尽管英国人的实践非常成功，但是直到18世纪中叶，文官制度才在欧洲各国得到普及。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DIVINE_RIGHT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The divine right theory of royal legitimacy holds that monarchs rule by direct sanction from God; accordingly, they are not accountable to any authority other than God. Legislatures, courts, judges, and the governed have no right to restrain the king's exercise of his authority, according to this theory. When kings who proclaimed their divine right to rule disagreed with the Church on political or religious matters, the results were often interesting (and violent). Ironically, the theory of divine right was partly responsible for the rise of the idea of separation between church and state, since divine-right rulers claimed that their godly sanction entitled them to impose rules on the ecclesiastical authorities in their kingdoms (regardless of what the Church thought), and to ignore those authorities' instructions on how they ought to govern. The divine right doctrine began during the late Middle Ages, when rulers sought to rein in feudal lords whose support came with a few too many strings attached. It had begun to lose its luster around the 17th century, although Napoleon Bonaparte drove what was perhaps the final nail into its coffin when, at his imperial coronation ceremony, he seized the crown from the Pope's hands and placed it on his own head -- thereby denying God's prerogative to name rulers, and seizing that power for himself.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]君权神授论宣称君主的统治必须得到神的同意；同样，他们不向任何其他权力负责。根据这个理论，立法者、法庭、法官以及平民都没有权力限制君王的行为。但是如果君王一方面宣布他因神的权力而可统治，而另一方面却在政治和宗教事务上反对教会，那么结果往往非常有趣（并且暴力）。讽刺的是，教会与国家间意见的分歧的出现一部分要归功于神权理论，因为神权统治者宣称授予君王在教会权威下统治王国 (无论教会本身是如何想的)，而忽略了指导他们如何治理国家。神权教条始于中世纪晚期，当时的统治者试图控制封建领主，因为他们的支持似乎过多了。教会从17世纪开始失去了他们的光环。拿破仑·波拿巴将苟延残喘的教会统治彻底送上了归路，在他的加冕仪式时他迫不及待地从教皇的手中夺过了皇冠把它戴在自己的头上——这就意味着拒绝了以上帝的名义授予统治权的特权，并牢牢地将权力掌握在自己手中。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATIONALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Nationalism is the belief that the affairs of the nation are the primary concern of its citizens. A recent political phenomenon (the first major application taking place after the French Revolution), it has nonetheless become the overriding paradigm for modern world politics. It is important to know that nationalism can come in a variety of forms, some permutations bearing little resemblance to each other. Many early nationalistic leaders preached the superiority of their country over all others. While this type isn't extinct today (as evidenced by the ethnocentric nationalism in the former Yugoslavia), most promote national determinism. Sanctioned by the United Nations, this is the belief that each nation should be responsible for its own growth and independence. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]民族主义的主旨在于国家事务应当作为人民心中的第一要务而存在。作为一种近代以来世界政治的一个普遍现象（民族主义思潮最早兴起于法国大革命之后），它已成为现代世界政治体系中一个令人头疼的问题。值得注意的是，民族主义往往以截然不同的方式体现出来。许多早期的民族主义领袖喜欢鼓吹本民族的优越性。到今天此种理念仍未消失（例如前南斯拉夫地区的民族主义浪潮），甚至演化为民族决定论。但正如联合国相关决议所指出的：民族主义应当只发挥推动民族独立和发展的作用。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MILITARY_TRADITION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]With the fall of the feudal system in Europe and the creation of standing armies, a new military tradition was born. Organizing soldiers based on their skill, experience, and understanding of tactics rather than their position of birth, the armies of post-feudal Europe were markedly different from their predecessors.[PARAGRAPH:2]This change in the position of warfare also necessitated a change in the definition of the soldier, and with this transformation also came a strict code of conduct based on the old ideals of chivalry. The life of a professional soldier came to appeal to many who saw it as a career filled with opportunity for advancement, and now ordinary citizens were able to distinguish themselves in any number of specialized positions in military conflict.[PARAGRAPH:2]The European military tradition arguably reached its highest point during the reign of Napoleon Bonaparte in France when, through military might, France gained control of the majority of European soil.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]随着欧洲封建制的崩溃以及常备军的建立，一种新的军事制度诞生了。士兵地位的提升主要依靠他们的技能，经验，和对战术的理解程度，而非其血统出身，这使得后封建时代的欧洲军队与过去有了很大的区别。新的军事制度改变了战争的面貌，也改变了军人的定义，并促使传统的骑士制度演变为严格的军人行为准则。成为职业军人也被许多年轻人看做是出人头地的理想途径。而且，在军队里，任何人都有机会因战功而得到晋升.[PARAGRAPH:2]欧洲军事制度在拿破仑统治时代已发展完善，当时的法国通过军事征服占据了欧洲大部分地区。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CONSTITUTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A "constitution" is a system that establishes the fundamental rules by which a nation is governed. Generally, a constitution describes the relationship between the government and the people, and the relationships between the various parts (or branches) of the government. A constitution will lay down how the rulers of the country are chosen and describe the limits of their power. Many nations, such as the United States, have written, codified constitutions, while some, such as the United Kingdom, have unwritten constitutions. [PARAGRAPH:2]Aristotle invented the concept of constitutions in the 3rd Century BC. In 622 AD, the Prophet Muhammad created the first written constitution, the "Constitution of Medina." King Henry I of England proclaimed the "Charter of Liberties" in 1100 AD, and in 1215 the English nobility forced King John to sign the "Magna Carta." [PARAGRAPH:2]The most important part of the Magna Carta, Article 39, established the concept of "habeas corpus" (literally, "you should have the body") which constrained the king from exiling, imprisoning, or killing anyone without "due process" of law. The "due process" clause of the Fifth Amendment in the US Constitution is directly descended from Article 39.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]宪法的设定建立了这样一套系统，它定义了一系列国家治理的最基本的规则。通常，宪法描述了政府与人民之间的关系，以及政府各部门之间的关系。宪法规定了国家领导人的产生办法，并且规定了他权限。许多国家，例如美国，采用成文宪法；而另一些国家，例如英国，则采用不成文宪法。[PARAGRAPH:2]亚里士多德在公元前3世纪首先提出宪法这个概念。在公元622年，先知穆罕穆德创造了第一部成文宪法，“麦地那宪法”。英国国王亨利一世在公元1100年宣布了“自由宪章”，在1215年英国新兴贵族强迫约翰国王签署了“大宪章”。[PARAGRAPH:2]大宪章中最要的部分，第39条建立了“人身保护权”这个观念（字面上说就是人应该拥有身体），这就限定了国王在没有通过法律正当程序下不可放逐、监禁或杀害任何人。美国宪法第五修正案的正当程序条款，也是直接取自于大宪章的第39条款。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LIBERALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Liberalism is a political philosophy that states that a government's primary purpose is to protect its citizens' personal liberty and property. Personal liberty usually includes freedom of religion and expression. Modern liberalism is a child of the "Age of Enlightenment" in the 18th century, which sought to free the world of irrationality, superstition and tyranny. [PARAGRAPH:2]"Liberalism" has meant many different things in different times and places. In its early European incarnation, liberalism saw itself in opposition to the rule of absolute monarchs and (often) the Church. Later, liberalism's great enemies were communism and fascism. In the modern United States, liberals are opposed to the policies of "conservatives," whom the liberals believe seek to restrict personal freedom and favor the wealthy over the poor. Of course, conservatives have an entirely different view on the matter...</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]自由主义是一种政治哲学，这种哲学认为政府的主要目的是保护公民的个人自由和权利。个人自由通常包括信仰和言论的自由。现代自由主义是18世纪“启蒙时代”的产物，当时的有识之士努力寻求消消除所有专断、迷信和暴政的方法。[PARAGRAPH:2]“自由”在不同的时间和地点有着不同的含意。欧洲早期自由主义思想所反对的目标是君主专制及教会统治。后来，自由主义的最大的敌人则是共产主义和法西斯主义。而在现代美国，自由主义者是“保守主义”政策的反对者，他们认为保守主义政策限制了个人自由，并有“劫贫济富”之嫌。当然，保守主义者对此问题有完全不同的看法……</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DEMOCRACY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Democracy is a ruling system where the citizens have a great deal of control over the actions of the government, either directly or through elected representatives. Democratic governments can be traced back to the city-states of ancient Greece and Rome. Citizens would gather in a public forum, and each one would have the opportunity to speak and vote on issues affecting the community. This direct democracy system was possible due to the relatively small populations of the city-states. Starting in the 17th century, the monarchs of Europe began to be stripped of their absolute power, and by the end of the 19th century the citizens had a strong voice in government in many European nations. Large populations made public forums impractical, so the people elected groups of representatives to carry their views to the ruling powers. Strictly speaking, this type of system more closely resembles a republican system rather than a true democracy. This type of representative democracy is considered the best governing system in the modern world because of the personal and economic freedom enjoyed by the citizens.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]不论是直接选举还是间接选举，民主政治使人民获得了极大的参政权。民主主义的历史可以回溯至古希腊与罗马的城邦制。人们在公共场合集会，就社会事务发表各自的意见并投票表决，但这种直接民主制仅适用于人口较少的城邦。从17世纪开始，欧洲君主的权力渐渐萎缩。到了19世纪末，普通民众的力量则已经强大到无法忽视的程度。而由于大量的人口使公共集会变得不切实际。人们便选出一部分人来代表他们就国家事务发表看法。严格地来说，这样的体制已经不是真正的民主体制而是共和体制了。这种代议民主制被认为是现代国家的最佳管理模式，因为它保障了公民的人身自由和经济自由，从而得到人民的拥护。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FASCISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Unlike other forms of government, there is no concrete definition of fascism. The word "fascism" comes from the fasces, the bundle of sticks used as a symbol of authority in ancient Rome - appropriately, since the first fascist government, that of Benito Mussolini in Italy, aspired to regain Rome's glory.[PARAGRAPH:2]Some common elements of fascism include strong nationalist sentiment, xenophobia, subordination of individual interests to the community, militarism and glorification of the army, secret police forces that enforce secret laws, informer networks, suppression of civil liberties and independent media, and economic policies that tightly tie business and commerce to government. (Note that many of these features are common in communist states as well.)[PARAGRAPH:2]Fascist states need not be authoritarian, although they usually are; when fascist leaders are democratically elected (as Adolf Hitler was), they often try to modify or abolish the democratic institutions that placed the leaders in power.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]与其它政体形式不同的是，对于法西斯政体并没有一个非常具体的定义。“法西斯”一词最初来自于象征古罗马统治者权威的束棒。与之相对应的是，第一个法西斯政府的元首，意大利的贝尼托·墨索里尼，也热切渴望重建罗马的荣耀.[PARAGRAPH:2]法西斯政体有一些共同特点：强烈的民族情绪、极端仇外、强调整个社会的利益而将个人利益放在次要地位。军事上大力鼓吹军国主义，通过秘密警察暗中执法，在社会上广布密探，压制公民自由和媒体独立性。经济方面政府严格控制工商业。（以上许多特点在历史上的许多共产制国家中也相当普遍。）[PARAGRAPH:2]法西斯国家不一定都实行独裁，尽管通常情况下它们都是如此。当一位信奉法西斯主义的领导人经由民主选举产生后（例如阿道夫·希特勒），他们往往会修改或干脆废除民主制，自己大权独缆。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CORPORATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]As businesses grow, they often find it necessary to raise large amounts of operating capital in order to expand their operations beyond a certain point, or to meet operating expenses. In these cases, one option available is to form a corporation and "go public", or sell shares of the business to investors. This arrangement allows the business to expand rapidly, while spreading the risks of the expansion among many people, reducing individual risk. Corporations also have legal advantages such as the right to sue, and the limitation of liability for the corporation's debt to the amount originally invested by the owners. Corporations as legal entities have existed since ancient Rome, although the joint-stock company as it is known today didn't begin operating until sometime in the 16th century.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]随着商业的发展，商人们往往发现自己正面临着缺乏进一步扩展业务的资本。为了解决这种状况，便出现了组建有限公司和上市等解决方案。公司制度使商人们能够迅速扩展自己的业务，并将快速拓展的风险分散到许多人身上，以减少其个人风险。有限公司还具有包括诉讼权以及投资人以初始投资额为限对公司的债务承担有限责任等有利条件。作为一个合法实体，合伙制商业模式在古罗马就已存在。而为人们所熟知的有限责任公司则直到16世纪才开始出现。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UTOPIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Communism is a conceptualized system of government in which resources and production facilities are the property of the entire society rather than individuals. In a communist society, labor is shared equally as well, and the benefits of labor are distributed according to need. Under such a system, all people would be equal, without class stratification.[PARAGRAPH:2]Although the basic idea of communism has existed since the time of Plato, modern communism is identified with the system of government described by Karl Marx and Fredrich Engels in the "Communist Manifesto". They believed that capitalistic systems, in which the rich upper class prospered through the exploitation of the powerless lower class, were bound to destroy themselves. At this point, the poor would rebel against their former oppressors and form a classless society. This prophecy has never come true, and countries that have attempted to base their governments on communism have ultimately failed to achieve the utopia described by Marx and Engels.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]共产主义是一种所有资源和生产设施应归全社会公有而非个人私有的政治制度理念。在实现共产制的社会中，人们各尽所能，按需分配。在这种体制下，人人完全平等，没有阶级差别。[PARAGRAPH:2]尽管具有共产主义性质的一些理念在柏拉图的时代就已存在，但完整的现代共产主义思想的产生则是以马克思和恩格斯发表“共产党宣言”为标志的。他们认为：在资本主义社会中，居于统治地位的资本家通过剥削下层人民的剩余劳动而获得财富。基于这一点，穷困的下层人民必然会反抗并推翻上层压迫者，并建立一个没有阶级的新社会。这个预言一直未能成为现实，许多以共产主义作为指导思想建设国家的尝试最终都失败了。先哲们所描绘的美好大同世界到今天仍然遥不可及。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MASS_MEDIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Mass media refers to any form of communications that reaches a large number of people. Printing was an important early form of mass media; later additions include the radio, cinema, television, and internet. [PARAGRAPH:2]Mass media can be an extremely powerful force which can be used in a variety of savory and unsavory fashions. In many times and places, most or all outlets of mass media have been controlled by the state. In the United States, on the other hand, virtually all major forms of mass media are privately owned. The Internet is a new and special form of mass media which is difficult to control, as ownership is shared by everyone who has access to it. [PARAGRAPH:2]In the Second World War, nations employed sophisticated print, radio and film mass media campaigns to dispense propaganda and to aid their war efforts. Leaders like Adolf Hitler, Winston Churchill and Franklin Roosevelt were masterful speakers whose words - spread through the mass media - changed the world forever.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]大众传媒是指一切能够与民众接触的通讯方式的总合。纸质媒体（报刊杂志）是大众传媒早期的重要形式，之后又出现了广播、电影、电视以及因特网等。[PARAGRAPH:2]无论是采用柔和还是强硬的方式，大众传媒都有着非常强大的作用。在多数时代和国家，大部分（甚至全面）媒体都是由国家控制的。不过美国的情况则正相反，大众传媒主要是由私人所拥有。因特网是一种新的大众传媒，它非常特别，不容易进行管制，因为它由一切能够接触它的人所拥有。[PARAGRAPH:2]在第二次世界大战期间，国家运用发展成熟的报刊、广播以及电影等媒体开展宣传活动，以作为辅助战争的手段。阿道夫·希特勒、温斯顿·丘吉尔和富兰克林·罗斯福等领导人都是出色的演说家，他们的言论通过大众传媒永远地改变了世界。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ECOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]For centuries, human society has taken the gifts of nature for granted. As civilizations grew, humans spread out across the face of the planet, taking what they needed from the land and producing more and more waste materials with little regard for the future. In the late 1960s, a growing number of people became concerned about the growing problems of pollution and the destruction of natural habitats. This movement led to the formation of groups like the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).[PARAGRAPH:2]The EPA's aim is to reduce all types of pollution. To this end, the agency has imposed strict laws and guidelines concerning the disposal of hazardous materials, set clean water standards, and studied more effective techniques of solid waste disposal. The primary goal of the environmental movement as a whole is to make sure that the environment is safe and intact for future generations to enjoy.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]人类几千年来享受着自然的恩惠却不以为意。当文明不断成长，人类遍布了这个星球表面每一个角落，他们不顾自然界的承受力，拿去他们想要的，扔出更多他们不需要的垃圾。在20世纪60年代后期，越来越多的人开始关注污染以及破坏自然环境所引起的越来越多的问题。这个运动导致了如美国环保局等团体的形成。[PARAGRAPH:2]美国环保局的目标是减少各种各样的污染。为了这个目的，该局订制了一系列严格的法律和方针，涉及到有害物质的处理、清洁水的标准以及鼓励固体废弃物处理技术的研究等。环境运动的基本目标是使环境保持安全完好，能够让子孙后代享受。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FISHING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Man has long relied on the sea to provide sustenance. The most primitive peoples gathered mollusks and crabs from the sand; eventually they learned to make spears to capture the rich foodstuffs out of reach of hand. The fishing technology allows sophisticated advancements in fishing: building small coastal fishing vessels, weaving and deploying large fishing nets, constructing crab traps, and so forth. [PARAGRAPH:2]Fishing is a major industry in the world today, and hundreds of thousands of pounds of fish are taken from the sea every day. However, this has put a serious strain on the ocean's ecology, and continued unfettered fishing may soon overwhelm and destroy this precious resource.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]人类一直以来靠海为生。最原始的人类就在海滩捡拾贝壳和螃蟹，最终他们学会了制造矛去捕捉他们双手所不能采到的食物。渔业技术的发展造就了更复杂的捕鱼方式：建造小渔船、编织大渔网、制作捕蟹笼等。[PARAGRAPH:2]直到今天，渔业仍是世界上的一项主要产业，每天都会自海洋捕捞数十万吨鱼类。但是这却使海洋生态出现了一系列的问题，持续而无限制的捕捞很可能会压垮和摧毁珍贵的渔业资源。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_THE_WHEEL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The invention of the wheel represented a major turning point in human civilization. The first wheels, disks carved from solid wood, may have been built as early as 3500 BC. The earliest use of this device was the potter's wheel, used to spin and shape clay pottery. It was not long before the true potential of the wheel was discovered, and wheeled carts soon replaced the sledge as a means of transportation. Rapid developments, such as wheels consisting of a ring with radial spokes, made the wheel even more practical by reducing its weight. By using the wheel, mankind gained the ability to work more efficiently and travel more quickly. Besides its use in transportation, the wheel went on to become the basic principle behind almost every mechanical device.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]轮子的发明或可被视为人类文明的一个重大转折点。最早的轮形工具是一个由实心木块雕刻而来的圆盘，大约早在公元前3500年就出现了。这种工具的早期应用是陶工转轮。用来旋转灰泥并方便将之塑造成一定形状。而真正意义上的车轮亦在不久之后被发明出来。人力推车很快取代了滑橇运输方式。而轮轴、轮辐和轮盘的设计也很快出现，使轮子变得更加实用而轻巧。人类也得以更加高速而高效的移动。除了用于运输，轮形工具的基本原理也应用到了几乎所有机械设备中。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AGRICULTURE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Agriculture is the science of cultivating soil, planting and harvesting crops. It can be argued that the mastery of agriculture was the single most important step towards creating a civilization, as agriculture allowed people to stop hunting and gathering and settle down in one place. Villages and cities would be unviable without some form of agriculture. [PARAGRAPH:2]Evidence of plant cultivation dates back as far as 6000 BC. Apparently, grains were some of the earliest crops cultivated. Grains are incredibly useful foodstuffs; they can be ground into flour and turned into bread, they can be fed to livestock and, perhaps most importantly, they can be stored for months without spoiling. [PARAGRAPH:2]Over time a number of important tools were invented to aid in cultivation and preparation of grains. The sickle was an early innovation; it allowed the grain to be harvested far quicker than by hand. Hand mills and mortar and pestles were created to grind the finished product, and pots to store it. As man learned about fertilization and irrigation, it became possible to get consistently larger yields, which lessoned the chances of famine and increased the numbers that could be fed from each field.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]农业技术是有关培土、作物种植与收获的综合性科学。有一种观点认为农业是促成人类文明形成的一个最关键因素，因为农业使人类不再依赖狩猎和采集方式获取食物，从而能够转入定居生活。[PARAGRAPH:2]早在公元前6000年就有人类培育植物的痕迹。显然，谷类作物是人类最早培育出的农作物。谷物是人类最基本的食物来源：可以用来磨成面粉、做成面包，可以用来喂养牲畜。更为重要的是：谷物可以储存数月之久而不会变质。[PARAGRAPH:2]在很长的时期内，人们发明了许多重要的工具，用于培植和收获谷物。最早的农业技术创新是镰刀的发明，它使收获谷物的效率大大提高。后来人们又发明了手推磨和臼槌进行加工，并用陶罐进行储存。当人们学会了施肥和灌溉后，持续的丰产也成为可能，这显著减少了饥荒的发生率，增加了单位面积农田所能供养的人口。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POTTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The invention of pottery was essential to the development of agricultural societies. To get the most out of seasonal crops and domesticated animals, a tribe needed sturdy, waterproof containers in which to store and protect surplus food. The discovery of the properties of clay, and the invention of the kiln and the potter's wheel made it possible to build such containers. The earliest examples of Western pottery date back to as early as 6500 BC. Most of the examples from this period were strictly utilitarian. Although use continued to be primarily practical, decorative pottery soon became a ritualistic and aesthetic art form in cultures all over the world. Some of the most impressive examples of artistic pottery comes from the pre-Columbian cultures of South America, and from the Ming dynasty in 14th century China.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]陶器的发明应该是农业社会发展的必然结果。为了保存换季收获的粮食，储存牲口饲料，人们不得不寻找更加坚硬而不透水的容器以存放粮食。粘土、烧窑和陶工转轮的发明使人们得以制造这样的容器。西方制作陶器的记载可上溯至公元前6500年。早期的陶器产品都是毫不花俏的实用性产品。而随着其应用越来越广泛，就逐渐带上了礼仪和美学成分，变成了一项世界范围的共通艺术。其中最好的陶器艺术品来自哥伦布发现新大陆之前的南美以及14世纪的中国明朝。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SAILING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The first sails were probably just a square sheet of animal skin hung from a horizontal pole, while later woven cloths were stretched between poles. While this does allow sailing, there are several problems with these designs. First, the boat can only sail downwind, meaning movement is only possible in the direction the wind is blowing; secondly, this only allows the boat to travel at the speed of the wind. Sail design evolved slowly over the centuries, and eventually the concepts of tacking and trimming started to be understood, allowing sailing to be against the wind and faster than the wind speed. These advancements enabled the exploration and settlement of far off lands, as ships were able to return from uncharted waters.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]最早的帆可能只是挂在一根横杆上的一方兽皮，之后则演变成延伸于两根桅杆间的织物。尽管这样的帆可以使船航行，但此种设计也有几个缺陷。首先，这样的船只能顺风行驶，这是指当风对着帆直吹时船才能移动。其次，这使得船速只能取决于风速。帆船的设计在几个世纪内发展缓慢，直到人们懂得抢风行驶和曲线前进的概念，才使船可以逆风航行，船速也比风速快了。这些进步使探索和殖民远方大陆变得可行，因为大型船只可以往返于未知海域。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_WRITING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The development of writing is considered one of the most important advances of civilization. The earliest forms of writing were simple symbols and marks, used to keep accounts and inventories. Some cultures developed pictographic symbols to tell stories and record events. Eventually, complete systems of writing were developed, capable of conveying any thought that could be expressed orally. At this point, scribes replaced the oral historian as the chief keepers of records. Writing allowed the presentation of information in a form that could be reliably transmitted from person to person and made it possible for ideas, history, and knowledge to be stored permanently and passed between cultures more reliably than through oral recitation.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]文字是人类文明最重要的进步之一。早期的文字只不过是用于计数的简单符号标记。部分文明随后发明了象形文字以撰写故事和记录事件。而最后，当文字体系发展完备并可以被用来记录那些之前只能经口头传达的讯息时，书面史籍就逐渐取代了口口相传的史诗。文字的发明让人们得以准确无误的传递信息，并使得思想、历史和知识得以通过比口头转达更加可靠的方式记录和流传下去。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MATHEMATICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Rudimentary arithmetic was purely quantitative, used to keep track of quantities and measurements in trade. Building on this fundamental base, ancient civilizations began to formulate more complex mathematical concepts. As early as 1800 BC, the Egyptians had developed a system for working with fractional numbers and simple algebraic problems. They also formulated geometric formulae for finding area and volume, and came up with a constant for determining the area of a circle that was very close to the value of pi. By about the 5th century BC, the mathematicians of Greece had greatly contributed to both geometry and algebra. Around the same time, advanced mathematics was applied to other sciences and fields of study such as astronomy and mechanics. One of the earliest applications of mathematical principles was in the construction of complex weaponry such as the catapult.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]初期的数学只用于货物贸易的简单计数。在此基础上，各远古文明开始发明更加复杂的数学概念。早在公元前1800年，古埃及就已经发明了小数，并开始计算一些简单的数学问题，为了计量面积和体积，他们还发明了简单的几何学，并且发现圆周长与一个固定数字紧密相关，他们把这个数字叫做π。公元前5世纪，古希腊在几何与代数上都前进了一大步。于此同时，数学亦开始被应用于天文、机械等各个领域中。数学原理的早期应用领域还有制造较复杂的武器——例如投石车。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ALPHABET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The ancestors of modern alphabets were the iconographic and ideographic symbols developed by ancient man, such as cuneiform and hieroglyphics. The first known alphabet, a combination of a number of early pictographic symbols known as North Semitic, was developed between 1700 and 1500 BC. Four other alphabets - South Semitic, Canaanite, Aramaic, and Greek - had evolved from the North Semitic alphabet by 1000 BC. The Roman alphabet, used by all the languages of Western Europe including English, was derived from the Greek alphabet sometime after 500 BC. The Roman alphabet became one of the most widespread due to the extensive use of the Latin language during the reign of the Roman Empire. The development of alphabets was significant in the development of advanced civilizations because it allowed history and ideas to be written down, rather than memorized and passed along orally.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]现代字母的原型是由古人发明的图形和表意符号，例如楔型文字和象形文字。由北闪族人在公元前1700-前1500年间发明的一套象形文字符号，被认为是最早的字母系统。南闪族语、迦南语、亚拉姆语和希腊语字母表均由这套系统发展而来，在公元前1000年，逐渐成型。而现代西方语言的基础罗马字母，则是由希腊字母发展而来，大概出现在公元前500年。在罗马帝国统治期间，随着拉丁语应用范围的推广，罗马字母也被越来越多的人所认知并使用。字母表的发明对文明发展的影响非常深远，因为人们得以纪录历史和其他思想而不用再依靠记忆和口口相传。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CALENDAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Calendars played an important role in the development of human culture. Their earliest uses may have been mystical - to chart the courses of the stars and to determine the most auspicious days upon which to perform religious sacrifices - but they were also critical for determining when the best time was to plant and harvest crops. [PARAGRAPH:2]All that is needed to create a calendar is careful observation and record-keeping. After watching the skies for a long time, one might notice that the days gradually get shorter and then longer, and that this process takes 365 days to repeat. This would give the length of a year - the great cycle of life on the planet. Further observations on the movement of the moon and stars would provide further details. [PARAGRAPH:2]Perhaps the most difficult aspect of creating an accurate calendar is that a year takes 365 and a quarter days rather than exactly 365. If one does not take this into account (say, by the inclusion of an extra day every four years as currently), over the years one's calendar will get more and more out of date with the natural world. [PARAGRAPH:2]The earliest known Egyptian calendar was created in 4000 BC. The earliest known Sumerian calendar was invented around 1000 years later, and the first Chinese one was invented around 1400 BC. The Olmecs invented the first American calendar some time between 1200 BC and 300 AD.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]在人类文明的演化过程中，历法扮演了重要的角色。它最早应用于神秘学——比如占星术或者为宗教祭奠仪式选择吉日——但它确定的播种和收割日期也很准确。[PARAGRAPH:2]创制历法之前必须进行细致的观察和详实的记录。一个人观测天空很长一段时间后，可能会发现白昼一天一天变短，之后再一天一天变长，这个过程每365天重复一次。由此确定了一年的长度——这个星球最大的时间周期单位。对月球和其他星球的观测越细致，就能获得越细致的数据。[PARAGRAPH:2]也许制定一种精确历法最困难的方面是一年实际上是365又1/4天，而不是准确的365天。如果有人不把这计算在内（现在的方法是每四年多一天），几年后，他的历法就会慢慢脱离自然世界的实际日期。[PARAGRAPH:2]已知最早的历法是埃及人于公元前4000年创制的。1000年后，苏美尔人发明了他们最早的历法，中国人最早的历法则于公元前1400年发明。奥尔梅克人在公元前1200年至公元300年发明了美洲的第一部历法。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CURRENCY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]As cities grew, their internal economies became more complicated. People became specialists, some primarily producing grain, some pottery, some bricks, etc. A system of barter developed, so that one individual's wares and services could be exchanged for those of another. Gold and silver were widely used in such transactions, but the pieces needed to be weighed and tested for purity each time they changed hands.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 600 BC, the Lydians found a way around this problem. They began the practice of shaping electrum, an alloy of gold and silver, into pieces of predetermined weight and purity, stamped with an official symbol. This idea caught on, and within 50 years all the important trading centers of the world had adopted similar practices. The widespread use of currency created universal standards of value, allowing people from various societies to conduct business almost anywhere without being forced to bring along bulky goods for trade and barter.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]随着一个城市的成长，其内在的经济活动也随之复杂化，出现了社会分工，一些人种植谷物，一些人制作陶器，一些人生产砖瓦等。以物易物的交易方式由此产生，人们可以相互交换其产品。金银在这样的交易活动中得到普遍使用，但每次交易都要称量并确定其纯度。公元前600年左右，吕底亚人找到了一个解决方法：他们尝试将用于交换的贵金属按照固定的形状、重量和纯度进行熔铸，并打上官方印记。这个方法很快流行开来，在不到50年的时间里，各大贸易中心都采用了类似的方法。货币的广泛应用确定了统一的估值标准，使人们可以摆脱物物交换的诸多限制，进行远距离的大宗贸易活动。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ASTRONOMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Astronomy originated as simple observation and recording of regular celestial movements for the purpose of time keeping and determining directional bearings. The ancient Greeks were among the first to study astronomy in detail. They described the use of stars for navigation at sea, and recorded the position of constellations during each season of the year for purposes of determining times for planting and harvesting.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Greek astronomer Aristarchus developed the theory that celestial motion could be explained by the fact that the Earth revolved on its axis once every 24 hours, and revolves around the sun along with the other planets. This theory was rejected at the time, only to be rediscovered nearly 2000 years later by Copernicus. These early students of astronomy compiled data that became the cornerstone for modern astronomical research.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]为了确定季节变迁和方位，古人对天体的运行规律作了长期而简单的观测和记录，由此导致了天文学的诞生。古希腊学者最早将这项研究加以细化。他们讲述了观星在确定海上方位中的应用价值，同时，为了确定收获和播种的最好时机，他们也纪录了每个季节星体的不同位置。[PARAGRAPH:2]希腊天文家阿里斯塔克斯发现了行星的运动理论，许多天文现象都可归结为地球绕轴作以24小时为周期的自转，同时和其他行星一起绕太阳公转。这个理论在当时被人嗤之以鼻。直到几乎两千年后，才由哥白尼再次发现。但不管怎样，这些早期的天文观察记录为现代天文学的诞生奠定了基础。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PHILOSOPHY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The word "philosophy" comes from a Greek term meaning "love of wisdom." In ancient Greece, literacy and an interest in the natural world were common in a burgeoning upper class. In their leisure time, these people contemplated principles of thinking and being, logic and mathematics, and the natures of reality and existence. In ancient times, the study of philosophy was indistinguishable from the study of science, and many of the theories formulated by the early philosophers became the basis for studies in the fields of astronomy, medicine, chemistry, and physics. The teachings and writings of the ancient philosophers of Greece and the Orient also, in part, laid the groundwork for many of the world's oldest organized religions.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]西方的“哲学”一词来源于希腊语，其本义为“爱智慧”。在古希腊，上层社会对科学文化极感兴趣。他们将闲暇时间应用于思考意识和存在的基本法则。逻辑，数学和自然界的物质存在也在他们的思考范围之内。古代的哲学研究和其它科学研究结合在一起，互不分离。这些哲学理论后来也成为天文、医学、化学和物理的基础。古希腊和东方哲学的理念及相关著作也成为后来许多宗教的基础。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PAPER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]When discovered, paper revolutionized information technology. Before the advent of paper, scholars and writers used a number of different materials upon which to record their words. These included clay tablets, animal skins, silk, and others. These suffered from many shortcomings. Clay was bulky and fragile, animal skins were expensive, silk was expensive and fragile, and so forth - and none of them would have been suitable for use in a printing press. [PARAGRAPH:2]Papyrus was the earliest form of paper. It was created by cutting the stem of the papyrus plant into strips, which were laid in an overlapping pattern and pounded into a sheet. The material was then dried and polished. While serviceable, the resulting sheet is fairly thick and, more importantly, subject to rot in damp climates. [PARAGRAPH:2]Paper as we know it today was invented in China in around 100 AD. Wood and other fibrous material is mixed with liquid and mashed into a pulp, which is then poured onto fine screens. The liquid drains away, leaving a thin layer of fibrous material on the wire. When this material dries, it becomes paper. The Chinese official Cai Lun is credited with adding cotton rags to the pulp; the resulting paper was far sturdier than earlier versions. The Chinese process spread slowly throughout the world, reaching Europe around 1300 AD. [PARAGRAPH:2]When paired with the printing press - yet another Chinese invention - paper exponentially increased the spread of information and art.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]纸一经发明便革命性地改变了信息传播技术。在纸出现之前，学者和作家用了很多种材料来记录他们的话语：泥板、兽皮、丝绸等。这些材料有很多缺点。泥板太大且易碎，兽皮很贵，丝绸又贵又易撕裂——所有的这些材料都不适用于印刷。[PARAGRAPH:2]纸草是最早一种纸。把纸草的茎削成很薄的长条，再把这些长条重叠在一起用力捶打成片状。如此一来这种材料就变得干燥而光滑。尽管它很耐用，纸草仍然很厚，更要命的是，在潮湿的气候下它会腐烂。[PARAGRAPH:2]我们现在知道的纸是公元100年左右在中国发明的。把木头和其他含纤维的材料混合在水中捣成纸浆，再把这些纸浆刷在平滑的墙上。水分排干之后，就留下了一层纤维材料。等这层材料干后，就变成了纸。中国官员蔡伦把棉絮加入到纸浆中，这样造出的纸比早期的产品更坚韧。中国的造纸术传播得很缓慢，直到公元1300年左右才传播到欧洲。[PARAGRAPH:2]当造纸和印刷术（又一项中国人的发明）相配合时，信息与艺术的传播速度便获得了指数级的提升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BANKING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Many of the services performed by banks today can be traced back to medieval Europe. Certain families, such as the Medicis of Italy, were known for the banking duties they performed. These wealthy merchants pooled their surplus money into a bank, then loaned cash (with interest) to other commercial enterprises. The availability of this capital for investment made many new businesses possible, accelerating economic growth.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first modern banks were established in Europe during the late 1600s. The primary function of today's banking system is the granting of loans to consumers and businesses. In addition to loaning money and safeguarding deposits, banks also invest in government and private securities and bonds. Both the loan and investment functions of banks not only make profits for the bank itself, but also stimulate the economy by providing funds for business growth and consumer purchases.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]许多现代银行的服务项目都可以回溯至中世纪一些欧洲家族。例如意大利的美第奇家族，因最早提出了利息的概念而著称于世。这些富有的商人将他们多余的钱放进银行，银行则再转贷给其他商业企业并收取利息。这种投资行业引发了许多商业契机，并加速了经济增长。[PARAGRAPH:2]最早的现代银行于17世纪晚期出现于欧洲。现代银行体系的基础在于借钱给消费者和商人。在这之外，还包括存款、发行政府或私人的有价证券。银行的这种行为，不只为银行自身带来利益，同时也通过为生产者提供发展资金，以及加强消费者购买力而刺激了经济增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EDUCATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Education is the process of passing on the knowledge of previous generations to future ones. The impact of this simple process is not to be underestimated, and in a fundamental way permitted mankind to dominate the planet. Originally a privilege solely of males, it soon became a fundamental right in the United States. Schools of all types began to specialize in certain fields and/or student demographics, allowing people of all kinds the benefit of this wealth of information. Modern curriculums surprisingly cover many of the same subjects taught throughout history, such as literature, language, and mathematics. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]教育是将前人的知识和经验传递给下一代的过程。这一看似简单的工作实际具有无比的效用。教育让人类得以确立对这个星球的控制权。它最初是属于男性的特权，后来首先在美国普及成为任何人都享有的基本权利。针对特定领域或学生群体的学校大量开设，允许各类人群学习知识并获得裨益。令人惊讶的是：现代教育所包含的课程与往昔各个历史时期在许多方面都大同小异，例如文学、语言和数学等。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PRINTING_PRESS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The principle behind printing is not very complicated, but immense amounts of complexity are invested in the mass production of printed documents. Invented by Johannes Gutenberg in the mid-15th century, the early printing presses used a flat tray of inked type. Once paper was placed over the type, a surface was applied and the ink was pressed into the paper. While an improvement over the traditional duplication methods of the time (being meticulous hand-scribing of volumes), it was a slow and tedious process to use. Around 1800 the first cylinder press was created, followed by the large and immensely fast rotary presses.[PARAGRAPH:2]Today, computers have taken this ancient art out of the craftsman's workshop and placed it on the desktop. Desktop publishing revolutionized the creation of printed documents, not only from the standpoint of speed and accuracy, but also by enabling anyone to mass-produce the printed word without investing the many years it takes to learn the trade. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]印刷的原理并不复杂，但大批量生产印刷品则需要相当复杂的技术。欧洲的印刷术最早由古登堡于15世纪中叶发明。早期的印刷机是一个圆盘型的打字器。纸被放置其上，并留下墨迹。虽然仍十分简陋，使用起来十分乏味枯燥，但对于手工抄写而言，已经是一个了不起的进步。在1800年左右滚筒式印刷机出现，使得印刷速度得以大大提高。[PARAGRAPH:2]时至今日，电子计算机已经能使人们在书桌上完成过去的工匠们在作坊里才能完成的工作。桌面出版技术革命性地改变了印刷品的生产方式，并使其速度和精确度大为提高，使得任何人都可以大量制作印刷文本而无需通过多年的专业训练。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ECONOMICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The ideas of supply and demand, and philosophies concerning trade and the production and consumption of goods and services, are concepts that have existed since the dawn of mankind. As societies became more complex, however, people began to study these abstract concepts in a more formal way. The first recorded study of economics as a science, rather than a philosophical or political concept, was the book "The Wealth of Nations" by Scottish economist Adam Smith. This book represents the first attempt to fully analyze sources of income and the distribution of wealth. Smith's analysis of economics served as a guide by which many of the governmental economic policies of the present day were formed.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]供给和需求的概念以及整个生产、交换、消费体系自人类文明初期便已存在。随着社会的复杂化，人们开始更加认真地看待这些抽象概念。最早将经济视为一项科学进行系统化研究，而不是将其仅仅视为哲学或政治观念的，则是苏格兰经济学家亚当斯密。在其《国富论》一书中，他试图分析收入的来源和财富的分配。亚当斯密对经济现象的分析已成为当代世界各国政府制订经济政策的重要指南。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SCIENTIFIC_METHOD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Mankind has always pursued an understanding of the universe that surrounds them. The scientific method lays down the blueprints for transmuting a theory into scientific law. The first step is to identify a process or phenomenon and begin to gather information about it. From this data, the scientist forms a hypothesis about the workings of the process observed. He or she then proceeds to run a series of experiments to gather additional information that substantiates or disproves their theory. If the theory can co-exist with the findings, it can then be called a scientific law. This is not to say that it cannot be disproved, as many such laws have become false as technology and new ideas are brought to bear.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]人类一直试图了解整个宇宙的奥秘，科学方法则指导着人们将科学理论转化为科学定律。人们首先要对自然现象进行观察，收集各种相关信息，再根据这些信息中归纳出能够解释该现象的理论假设，然后通过一系列的实验搜集更多的信息以证明或否定这一假设。如果理论假设能够与实际观察结果保持一致，就能成为一项科学定律——但这并不意味着科学定律不能被否定，实际上，有许多科学定律在新的科技和理论诞生后被证明是错误的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CHEMISTRY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The earliest practical use of chemical processes was by metal smiths of the ancient world. These artisans learned how to use heat to melt various naturally occurring metals together to form alloys such as bronze. Early manufacturers of cloth also used primitive chemical processes to set dyes. In the following centuries, chemical processes were studied through the pseudo-science of alchemy, which attempted to change base metals into gold. Although alchemists were, of course, unsuccessful, they did develop many valuable chemical processes as a result.[PARAGRAPH:2]The manuscripts produced by alchemists were studied by succeeding generations, and an effective knowledge of chemistry had been accumulated by the late 13th century. In the 17th century, the ideas of alchemy finally died out as an increasing body of true chemical knowledge was gained through experimental analysis, leading to the modern science of chemistry.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]化学的应用最初是由古代的金属工匠实现的。这些工匠们通过实践学会了如何将某些金属熔化以形成合金，如青铜等。而早期的纺织业在染色时也自然而然的用到了基本的化学知识。在之后的世纪中，化学由于炼金术的盛行而得到了极大的发展。尽管那些炼金术士们从未炼出金子，但他们确实发现了很多极有价值的化学反应。[PARAGRAPH:2]一代代的炼金术士不断研究着前人流传下来的研究手稿，由此保证了化学知识的不断积累和传递。终于在17世纪，炼金术渐渐消亡，通过实验和分析所积累起来的大量知识则为现代化学的产生奠定了基础。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PHYSICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Physics is the study of the many forms of matter and energy and the way they interact with themselves and each other. A number of ancient races made observations about certain aspects of physics, such as planetary motion, but were unable to develop theories as to the reasons for these motions. Some of the earliest applications of physics were by the Greek mathematician Archimedes, who applied physics to create such devices as levers and screws. It was not until the 17th century that experimental methods and scientific measuring devices led to a true understanding of many fundamental physical laws. Early scientists such as Johannes Kepler and Sir Isaac Newton began to disprove the theories of the ancient Greek philosophers and scientifically prove their theories concerning the laws of physics. Discoveries in physics rarely have direct applications, however they do provide a basic understanding of the laws governing the universe, thus forming the basis for practical advances in technology.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]物理学研究的是各种物质和能量的形态，以及他们相互作用的过程与结果。很多古代学者都通过观察提出了包括天体运行在内的一些物理学的基本问题，虽然在当时，他们还无法回答自己提出的问题，但却能以之解决一些实际问题。例如古希腊的数学家阿基米德，他通过应用物理学原理而制造了包括杠杆和螺旋在内的一系列工具。但直到17世纪，随着实验技术和科学测量的发展，一些基本的物理理论才得以建立起来。早期的科学家，例如开普勒、牛顿开始否定一些古希腊哲学家的错误见解，并建立起自己的科学理论。理论物理的发现很少能应用于实际，但却是我们理解宇宙万物的基础，也是发展实用科学技术的重要指南。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Biology is the study of living organisms, and it has been around since man began to think. The biology technology specifically refers to the study of bacteria, viruses and cells that became possible once the first powerful microscopes were invented. [PARAGRAPH:2]The benefits to humanity from this research are incalculable. The basic knowledge of how germs spread and the importance of cleanliness has saved untold millions of lives, inside of hospitals and out. Antibiotics, such as penicillin, have saved countless more, as have vaccinations. This study of biology has also led to increased food production, as ways are learned to create better and more disease-resistant plants and livestock. [PARAGRAPH:2]Great strides continue to be made in biology. The study of genetics alone has the potential to do great things for mankind ... or to destroy it, if the new technology is not used with the respect and caution it deserves.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]生物学研究有机体的生长过程，自人类文明产生以来即已出现。当第一种强大的显微镜发明之后，生物学就开始专注于研究细菌、病毒和细胞。[PARAGRAPH:2]人类从生物学研究中受益匪浅。细菌传播的基础知识和卫生知识的重要性挽救了几百万条生命，无论是在医院内或医院外。抗生素（如青霉素）和种痘法拯救了无数生命。生物学的研究同样提升了食物产量，比如养殖更健康，抗病虫害能力更强的林木和牲畜。[PARAGRAPH:2]未来生物学会取得更大进步。遗传学很有潜力，研究它对人类大有益处……但如果这项新科技不用在正途，则可能将人类毁于一旦。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MEDICINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Primitive man attributed the onset of serious disease as the influence of the gods, or possession by evil spirits. Over time, however, it was found that such "possessions" could be treated through the use of elixirs made from plant extracts. Methods were also developed to clean and treat wounds, and set fractured bones. The ancient Greeks established the first schools to teach medical sciences circa 500 BC. The texts produced by the students of these schools, most notably Hippocrates, who is considered the father of medicine, based his theories of the human body on observation and reasoning rather than supernatural intervention.[PARAGRAPH:2]Continued study of diseases over the years, combined with the dissection and study of the human body in the 13th century, pointed out flaws in early Greek theories, and led to more accurate medical texts based on detailed analysis rather than conjecture. By the 18th century, the same methods of analysis and observation used by scientists in other fields were applied to the study of medicine. This paved the way for the increasingly effective methods of treatment and surgery that have prevailed over the last 200 years.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]远古的人们将疾病发作视为某种神力的作用或受到了邪恶神灵的影响。随着时代的发展，人们发现可以使用某些植物成分来对付这种“恶灵”，并发明了医治外伤和骨折的办法。大约在公元前500年左右，古希腊人建立了第一所传授类似医疗科学的学校，并留下了许多相关的纪录。而其中最著名的当属医学之父希波克拉底。借助他的理论和观察，人们终于摆脱了疾病是某种超自然影响的观念。而随着13世纪人们将解剖视为医学研究的一个重要组成部分后，人们得以摆脱主观臆断，并推翻古希腊医学中的不确之处。到了18世纪，这样的观察与分析的方法，被科学家们应用于医学的相关领域中，使外科治疗在之后的两百年间逐渐发展成型。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRICITY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Humans have witnessed the phenomenon of electricity in the forms of lightning, static electricity, and magnetism since the dawn of time. Electricity was not seriously studied, however, until the 17th century. Early electrical pioneers studied various electrical phenomena, and built devices both to generate and to measure electrical charges. In 1892 Hendrik Antoon Lorentz, a Dutch physicist, advanced the electron theory. This theory, which explains electricity as a reaction between positively and negatively charged electrons, formed the basis for modern electrical theory. Based on Lorentz's work, early engineers such as Thomas Edison pioneered methods allowing the widespread use of electricity as a power source.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]人类很早就通过闪电、静电、磁力现象等认识到了电的存在。而对这一现象的严肃研究则迟至17世纪才得以展开。早期的研究者们观察了大量的电现象，并制造了产生和测量电能的装置。1892年，荷兰物理学家亨德里克·安东·洛伦兹提出电力是正负极电子运动的产物。并由此奠定了现代电力学理论的基础。基于洛伦兹的理论，通过托玛斯·爱迪生在内的许多科学家的努力，终于使得电作为一种能源而得到了广泛的应用。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMBUSTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The development of internal combustion was a great advance of the Industrial Age. German engineer Nikolaus Otto built the forerunner of today's internal combustion engine in 1876. Refinements on Otto's design over the next ten years led to more efficient and powerful engines. The internal combustion engine forever changed world transportation. Early automobiles utilizing steam engines had proven to be both underpowered and impractical, but the fuel efficiency and compact size of the internal combustion engine allowed the automotive industry to flourish. Several variations, including the diesel engine designed by Rudolf Christian Karl Diesel, went on to revolutionize propulsion in shipping and other transportation industries.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]内燃机的发明是工业时代的巨大进步。德国工程师尼古拉斯·奥托于1876年制造出了现代内燃发动机的原型。在接下来的十年中，奥托的原型不断地得到改进和完善，并最终完全改变了整个世界交通运输的面貌。先前的蒸汽机在实用中存在动力不足，较大的体积使其使用环境有诸多限制。内燃机的小型化和高效化则完全解决了这个问题。内燃机的出现，使汽车工业得以繁荣昌盛。内燃机和它的一些变型，如由鲁道夫·克里斯蒂安·卡尔·狄塞尔发明的柴油机极大地推动了航运和其它运输方式的变革。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FISSION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]According to Einstein's theory of relativity, even the smallest bit of matter is equivalent to a tremendous amount of energy. For instance, two pounds of matter, if converted completely into energy, would produce energy equivalent to the explosive force of 22 megatons of high explosives. In 1939, based on German experiments that successfully split the uranium atom, physicists were able to explain the process of nuclear fission.  When a large, unstable atomic nucleus splits (fissions) it results in two or more smaller, more stable nuclei accompanied by the release of tremendous amounts of energy and lingering, deadly radioactivity.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first application of this powerful technology was in warfare. A top-secret research effort in the U.S. known as the Manhattan Project studied the fission process, and eventually produced the first atomic bombs, which were dropped on the Japanese cities of Hiroshima and Nagasaki in 1945. These relatively small bombs, the only atomic weapons ever used in a war, each produced an explosion equivalent to more than 20,000 tons of TNT. The nuclear weapons of today are capable of producing explosions thousands of times more powerful.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]根据爱因斯坦的相对论，极小的物质蕴藏着巨大的能量。如果两磅的物质完全转化为能量的话，将会产生相当于2200万吨高爆炸药的爆炸力。1939年，德国科学家在实验中成功实现了核原子的裂变。当一个较大的不稳定的原子核分裂成两个或更多较小的较稳定的原子核时，会同时产生极巨大的能量及持续不散的致命辐射。[PARAGRAPH:2]这项技术首先被应用于军事领域，二战期间美国进行了一项名为曼哈顿计划的绝密研究，并最终造出了原子弹。这两枚炸弹于1945年被投掷在日本的广岛和长崎，分别产生了相当于2万吨TNT炸药的威力，而现代核武器的威力更是数千倍于此。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FLIGHT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The idea of flight has tantalized humans since the dawn of time. Early investigations of flying machines date back to the 13th century. In the 16th century, Leonardo da Vinci proposed a number of inventions that eventually came to pass, including the propeller and the parachute. Throughout the 19th century, various engineers experimented successfully with gliders, and experiments with compressed air and steam engines attempted to produce self-powered flight with limited success.[PARAGRAPH:2]The key to success in powered flight was the invention of the internal combustion engine. Just after the turn of the 20th century, Orville and Wilbur Wright made the first four controlled, sustained human flights at Kitty Hawk, NC. The technology of flight advanced rapidly from this landmark event, and within a relatively few years, aircraft were circling the globe, safely delivering passengers and mail at record speeds.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]自古以来，人类每时每刻都梦想着飞行。早期的飞行研究始于13世纪。到16世纪，列奥纳多·达·芬奇已完成出包括螺旋桨、降落伞在内的一系列超越时代的发明。19世纪，许多工程师都在制造滑翔机上取得了成功，而通过压缩空气和蒸汽机动力制造自动飞行器的尝试则始终未能取得多少进展。[PARAGRAPH:2]有动力的飞行在内燃机发明之后才取得突破。20世纪初，莱特兄弟在北卡罗莱纳州小鹰镇成功造出高度、速度和方向可控制、可持续飞行的载人飞行器。航空技术由此得到了迅猛发展，短短数年时间，飞机就飞遍了世界的各个角落，高速而又安全地运送着旅客和邮件。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PLASTICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The creation of plastics in the 1860s revolutionized product manufacturing throughout the world. In the middle of the 19th century, scientists were looking for an inexpensive synthetic substance that could be used to replace natural materials which were expensive and difficult to procure. For example, ivory was used in many goods - utensils, fans, piano keys, and so forth. Ivory was attractive and comfortable to the touch, but it was becoming very expensive as the animal populations were depleted. [PARAGRAPH:2]A plastic-like substance called "parkesine" was created in England in 1862, but the material proved unsatisfactory; it became very brittle in a short period of time. In 1863 an American inventor named John Hyatt discovered a way to improve the flexibility and longevity of parkesine; he called his new product "celluloid." Celluloid first gained widespread use as a material for making shirt cuffs and collars; but it soon spread into other areas, including as a material for making movie and photographic film. [PARAGRAPH:2]Over time, more advanced plastics were created; these would see use as everything from fabric to eyeglass lenses to artificial hearts. In fact the modern world is largely built on plastic. This too has a price; plastic's very durability makes it increasingly difficult to dispose of without damaging the world's fragile ecostructure.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]在19世纪60年代发明的塑料使世界范围内的产品制造业发生了革命性变化，19世纪中期，科学家们致力于寻找一种人工合成的物质，以取代昂贵而难以加工的天然物质例如象牙，象牙的用途广泛——器具、扇子、钢琴键等。虽然象牙外观迷人、手感舒适，但随着大象这种动物的数量锐减而价格昂贵。[PARAGRAPH:2]1862年，英国出现了一种塑料类的物质，名为“帕克赛恩”（parkesine），但这种硝化纤维材料难以令人满意，它在使用一段时间后会变得非常易碎。1863年美国发明家约翰·哈耶特发现一种途径可提高帕克塞恩的韧性和使用寿命; 他将这种新产品命名为“赛璐珞”（Celluloid），赛璐珞广泛用于制作衬衣袖口和衣领；不过很快其用途就扩展到其他领域，例如作为电影和照相底片。[PARAGRAPH:2]随着时间的推移，更先进的塑料不断被发明出来。现在塑料被用于制造各种物品，从合成纤维到眼镜架，乃至人工心脏。实际上现代社会很大程度上是建立在塑料的基础之上的。不过这也是有代价的：塑料难以降解，这使得难以在不破坏这个世界脆弱的生态环境的情况下处理它们。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPOSITES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The term "composite" refers to any object that is made up of more than one material. Composites were used quite early in human history; composite bows have been discovered dating back to 1300 BC. The composite technology refers the late 20th Century invention of various metal and plastic composites with greater strength, lightness, and other special properties than the base materials. [PARAGRAPH:2]Kevlar, the modern battle armor, is a composite material. Modern tanks are constructed of steel-boron nitride composites. Stealth airplanes use composite materials that are much more difficult to spot on radar. The tungsten-carbide composite is used in drill bits and wedding rings. [PARAGRAPH:2]Composite materials often demand extremely complex and precise manufacturing processes. However expensive the process may be, the resulting material may have superior qualities that make them more than worth the expense.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]复合材料这个术语是指任何由不止一种材料制成的物体。复合材料在人类历史上很早就产生了，复合弓的出现可追溯到公元前1300年。20世纪末，复合材料科技的进展产生了许多金属和塑料的复合材料，它们相比于基体材料，具有强度更大、密度更轻等特殊性质。[PARAGRAPH:2]用于防弹的凯夫拉纤维，就是复合材料。现代坦克也是由铁、硼和氮的复合材料制成的。隐形飞机也使用复合材料以使其更难被雷达发现。碳化钨硬质复合材料用于制造钻头和结婚戒指。[PARAGRAPH:2]复合材料一般需要极其复杂精密的加工工艺。不过不管工艺多么昂贵，所得到的材料的优异性能与所花费的费用相比总是值得的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GENETICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The field of genetics involves the manipulation of deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA). DNA contains the genetic "code" which determines the inherited traits of living organisms. Removing a section of an organism's DNA and replacing it with that of another organism can alter the characteristics of the organism. Since its inception, genetic engineering has produced a number of important benefits, such as isolating the gene for interferon, a rare substance that may be of great value in the treatment of viral diseases and cancer. Genetic manipulation may someday also provide a cure for birth defects and inherited diseases. Unfortunately, there are also potential dangers involved in this technology. Genetically engineered diseases, more communicable and virulent than any occurring in nature, could potentially be created in the laboratory by accident or maliciously. Such viruses could be used as a dreadful biological weapon. Domestic and international regulations regarding genetic experimentation exist to prevent such a situation from occurring.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]遗传学的关键重点是对于脱氧核糖核酸（DNA）的研究。DNA中包含着决定生物特性的遗传基因“代码”。删除部分该生物体的基因片段，或用另一生物体的基因片段取而代之，将会相应的改变该物种的遗传特性。自该学科诞生以来，基因工程师们已经取得了一系列重要的进展。例如确定了产生干扰素的基因位置，为许多由滤过性病毒引起的疾病及癌症的治疗铺平了道路。或许有一天，基因工程方法使人们可能避免先天性缺陷与疾病。但令人担忧的是，这项科技也存在着极大的危险性。通过基因工程制造出的病毒将会比一切现存自然病毒传染得更快且更致命。这些病毒可以被用作生物武器。而现存的国内与国际间基因实验法正是为了防止这一状况的出现而存在的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FIBER_OPTICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Fiber optics is the technology of creating fibers that transmit light. Fiber optic cables are used to transmit information - computer data, telephone signals, cable television, and so forth. They have many advantages over traditional wire cables: fiber optic cables are lighter than wire cables, they can carry huge amounts of data and transmit that data faster than wire, and they don't lose signal over distance. In short, fiber optics make a nation's information network far more efficient. [PARAGRAPH:2]Fiber optics have other interesting uses, as well. They can be used to make extremely small cameras, such as endoscopes which allow physicians to see precisely what's going on inside a patient's body without requiring surgery. Law enforcement agencies find such cameras extremely useful as well, particularly in hostage situations. And they can be used to make decorative jewelry, sculptures, and Christmas trees. [PARAGRAPH:2]Fiber optics were first conceived in the 1960s. The first useful cable was created in 1970, and the first trans-Atlantic fiber optic cable was laid in 1988. They are now in common use the world over, and many modern cities have begun to replace their existing wire cables with the new optical cables.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]光纤技术用来制造传输光的纤维。多束光纤制成的光缆可用于传输信息——计算机数据，电话信号，有线电视等。它与传统缆线相比有很多优势：光缆比它们更轻，而能传输更多的数据，传输速率也更快，并且，长距离传输中,光缆不会丢失数据。一句话，光缆使国家信息网络更有效率。[PARAGRAPH:2]光缆还有别的有趣的用途。它们可以用于制造极小的镜头，比如内窥镜。这使外科医生们不必进行手术就可以准确了解患者身体内部的情况。执法部门也发现这种镜头极为有用，特别是处理人质危机时。光纤还可用于制造装饰用珠宝，雕像以及圣诞树等。[PARAGRAPH:2]纤维光学创立于20世纪60年代，第一根实用光缆诞生于1970年，第一根跨越大西洋的光缆铺设于1988年。现在光缆在世界范围都得到了广泛应用，许多现代城市也开始用光纤取代已有的金属导线电缆。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FUSION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Nuclear Fusion is the process by which two atomic nuclei combine to form one heavier atomic nucleus, giving off tremendous energy as a by-product. This type of nuclear reaction, which is the process by which stars such as the sun produce heat and light, requires very high temperatures and an enormous amount of pressure to initiate, and a reliable system of fuel containment to sustain. Fusion reactions have been produced in artificial environments on Earth by bombarding deuterium with high-energy particles accelerated in a cyclotron. Unfortunately, the amount of energy released in the reaction was considerably less than the energy required to accelerate the particles. Brief fusion reactions have been demonstrated in the detonation of thermonuclear weapons, but these reactions are useless for power generation because they cannot be controlled. If a way can be found to produce a controlled fusion reaction, this technology offers great promise as a source of electric power. The combination of abundant fuel sources and no harmful byproducts makes fusion power a safe alternative to the dangerous side effects produced by nuclear fission.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]核聚变是指两个原子核在一定条件下互相聚合，生成一个更重的原子核，并伴随着巨大的能量释放的过程。这种核反应形式也是恒星（如太阳）光和热能的来源，它的激发需要极高的温度和极大的压力，以及稳定可靠的燃料供给系统。在人工环境下可以通过环形加速器产生的高能粒子轰击氘原子来激发核聚变反应。可惜，在这种方式下核聚变所释放的能量要少于加速粒子所需要的能量。热核武器（氢弹）爆炸显示了核聚变可释放的巨大能量，但这是无法控制的，不能用作能源生产。如果人类能找到一种技术实现受控核聚变，就等于掌握了取之不尽的电力来源。由于可用作燃料的资源极为丰富，并且不存在有害的副产品，安全的受控核聚变技术一旦出现，将迅速淘汰会产生各种有害副产品的核裂变技术。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HUNTING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In its most general sense, Hunting is the pursuit of a target. For ancient societies, before the widespread domestication of animals and the creation of "livestock", hunting was vital to survival in the hunter-gatherer way of life. Hunting provided an important source of protien to augument the foraged plants and vegetables that made up the majority of a hunter-gatherer's diet. Hunting also provided significant exercise and challenges to these advancing people that improved communication and teamwork skills. Not only did hunting provide diet potential, but it also served as a way for early man to protect itself against cold weather through the use of furs and animal hides from the fallen beasts. The amount of energy that early humans put into hunting forced them to constantly discover new and creative ways to use every part of the animal.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]简单地说来，捕猎就是追击野生动物。在驯养动物尚未普及，“家畜”这个词尚未出现的远古社会，捕猎是狩猎-采集生活方式中至关重要的大事，是早期人类最重要的蛋白质来源，与谷物和蔬菜一起构成了人类饮食的主体。捕猎还为进化中的人类提供了极好的练习和挑战，这改进了他们的联络方式和团队合作技巧。捕猎不仅丰富了食物来源，而且为早期的人类提供了御寒的方式：动物的毛皮和它们的藏身洞穴。早期人类投入到捕猎中的能量很多，使得他们不得不不断地寻找新的创造性方式来利用动物的每一部分。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MINING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]There is evidence of surface mining dating back to prehistoric times. The first mining was probably for flint, which was used for knives, scrapers and arrowheads. The oldest known underground mine was in Swaziland over 40,000 years ago, to mine for ochre to use as a body pigment in ceremonies. During the Neolithic Age shafts were dug to extract flint from deeper in the earth. Gold, copper and silver were other minerals mined early in history.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]有证据表明，开采地表矿物可上溯到史前时代。第一种开采的矿物可能是燧石，用于制造刀具、刮削器和箭头。已知最早的地下矿井于40,000年前出现于瑞士，用于开采赭石，一种在举行仪式时涂抹身体的涂料。在新石器时代，出现了向更深的地下挖掘燧石的矿道。金、银、铜也是历史上较早期开采的矿物。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARCHERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]An important technological innovation, bows were perhaps the first machines built to store energy slowly and then release it quickly. Bows and arrows have been in existence for 30,000 years. The original bows were made of springy wood - yew, bamboo, palm, and so forth. By 1300 BC, bows were made of composite material - wood, horn, and sinew. The first arrows were probably straight wooden sticks with one end sharpened and fire-hardened. Stone tips were added once man learned to sharpen flint. [PARAGRAPH:2]The bow was a crucial element of ancient warfare, and remained so through the Middle Ages. The English longbow was a formidable weapon in the hands of a well-trained archer, who was able to punch through light armor at a distance. Compared to a longbow, the crossbow was slower and less accurate; however, a crossbowman could be trained to use his weapon in far less time than it took to train a good archer. [PARAGRAPH:2]The bow and arrow were eventually supplanted by the musket. The bow has all but vanished now, used mostly for sport by a few enthusiasts, but for thousands of years it ruled the battlefield.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]弓箭是一项重要的技术发明，弓可能是最早的缓慢储存能量而快速加以释放的设备。弓箭早在30,000年前就已经出现。早期的弓由有弹性的木头制成——紫杉木、竹子、棕榈等。公元前1300年左右，出现了复合材料的弓——使用木，兽角以及肌腱制成，最早的箭可能是一头削尖并用火烧硬了的笔直树枝。当人类学会打磨削尖燧石之后，立刻出现了石制箭头。[PARAGRAPH:2]弓是远古时代重要的战争装备，在中世纪也是如此。在训练有素的弓箭手手中，英格兰长弓是一种令人生畏的武器。它可以在一定距离上击穿轻甲。与长弓相比，弩射速较慢，也不太准确；然而，训练一个弩手比训练一个好弓箭手所要花费的时间少得多。[PARAGRAPH:2]弓箭最终被火枪取代。不过弓箭尚未彻底消失，虽然今天弓箭主要是用于运动中。但几千年来，它一直统治着战场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MASONRY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The early dwellings of most tribal cultures were built of materials that were readily available and easy to work with, such as bricks of clay and mud. As tribes gave up their nomadic ways and settled the first cities, they soon found that they had a need for more permanent and durable structures. The skill of masonry was developed to fill this need.[PARAGRAPH:2]The earliest stone structures consisted of little more than rocks that were stacked atop one another to form crude walls. Artisans soon began to square off the rocks, forming them into regular shapes and stacking them. These early examples of masonry used no mortar; the weight of the stacked stones provided overall strength and stability. Without the use of mortar and knowledge of architectural techniques, masonry was used primarily for simple structures such as fortifications. However, some examples of early masonry are quite spectacular, including the Great Pyramids in Egypt, which are still standing after thousands of years.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]大多数原始部族都使用较为简单易用且随处可得的材料，例如粘土砖和泥浆来建造他们的住所。而当这些部族放弃游牧生活，转而建造最初的永久性城市时，便发现需要采用一种更加坚固耐久的建筑材料。石工术就此应运产生。[PARAGRAPH:2]最早的石质建筑不过是用岩石简单堆叠而成的粗糙墙壁。工匠们很快学会将岩石进行切割，做成规整的形状，以便于进行堆叠。这种早期的石工并不使用灰泥；只靠石块本身的重量来确保其稳固。没有灰泥和相关建筑技巧的辅助，石工术在当时只应用于建造要塞之类的简单建筑。然而，某些早期的石工建筑仍然相当出色，例如埃及的大金字塔，在历经千年风霜依然屹立不倒。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BRONZE_WORKING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Evidence of the use of bronze, an alloy of copper and tin, dates back to Thailand in 4500 BC. Several hundred years later, bronze working was discovered in the Middle East. Artifacts from this period show that bronze was initially used for decorative purposes only. This is because tin was not readily available. It wasn't until approximately 2000 BC, when tin was regularly imported from neighboring regions, that bronze replaced copper in the construction of larger items. Bronze was harder and less brittle than copper, and it held a sharper edge. Tools, weapons, and armor made from bronze were also cheaper to produce and more durable. The period of time when bronze was the metal of choice for such items was known as the Bronze Age. The Bronze Age lasted until iron working became prevalent in approximately 1200 BC.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]青铜是一种铜锡合金，目前最早的青铜器是在泰国发现的，年代为公元前4500年，几百年后，中东也出现了青铜器。考古证据表明青铜最初仅用于制作装饰品，可能是由于原料锡较难获得。后来随着远距离贸易的发展，锡的来源得到了解决。约在公元前2000年，青铜取代了铜在大型铸件上的地位。由于青铜较之纯铜更为便宜、坚固和耐用，很快就被用于铸造盔甲和武器。青铜时代由此开始，并一直持续到约公元前1200年，铁器逐渐取代了青铜的位置后才宣告结束。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Animal husbandry possibly started as early as 9000 BC with the domestication of dogs, goats and sheep. During the Neolithic period as people started to settle into fixed agricultural communities this domestication intensified. Originally kept mainly for their meat, sheep and goats became valuable also for their milk and wool. Cattle were domesticated both for meat and skin and as work animals for agriculture; their milk production was not a factor until much later in history when breeding for high milk production produced suitable cows. Horses were also domesticated and became important for transportation and came to play a major part in warfare.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]家畜的驯养可能早在公元前9000年即已出现，起初驯养的动物是狗、山羊和绵羊。在新石器时代，人类开始习惯定居的农业社会，这使驯养业进一步发展。起初养家畜只是为了吃肉，但山羊和绵羊的羊毛和奶也很有价值。牛除了提供肉食，它的皮也很有用，而且还是能用于农业劳动的大牲口。但牛奶的生产直到很久以后，培育出高产奶量的品种才成为一个考虑因素。马也在这个时期被驯化并成为重要的运输工具，也在战争中扮演了重要的角色。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_IRON_WORKING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Some examples of iron ornamentation date back to 4000 BC, but the use of iron for tools, weapons, and other practical purposes did not become common until much later. Prior to this time, bronze was the most widely used metal for such purposes. Although the term "Iron Age" denotes a period of time starting around 1000 BC, iron replaced bronze as the metal of choice at different times in different places.[PARAGRAPH:2]Iron is more common than copper and tin, the component metals of bronze, but iron is seldom found in a free state; it is most commonly found mixed with other minerals and elements. In order to be used, the iron must be separated from the ore. Once this technique was developed, and forges hot enough to melt the iron were developed, iron working became commonplace. Worked iron was harder, less brittle, and could hold a much sharper edge than bronze. Iron has remained an important metal throughout history, and is one of the major components in the production of steel.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]早在公元4000年之前，就出现了铁制的饰物。而铁被大规模应用于工具、武器和其他实用目的则远在青铜时代之后。尽管铁器时代大概始于公元前1000年。但各个地方这个转变的时间仍各不相同。[PARAGRAPH:2]铁在自然界的含量比铜和锡多得多，但极少以纯铁的形式存在，而是经常和其他矿物混合在一起。因此，直到将铁和其他矿物分离的方法更加切实可用时，铁器才得到普遍使用。经过煅造的铁比青铜更加坚硬且不易断裂，可被用以制造更加锋利的兵器。因此一直作为不可或缺的资源活跃在历史舞台上，时至今日，仍作为炼钢的主要原料而被广泛应用。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_METAL_CASTING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Metal casting is a way to fabricate metal objects. When subjected to extreme heat, metal melts into a liquid. The molten metal is poured into a mold, where it cools and returns to a solid state, holding the shape of the space inside the mold. Once the object is removed, the mold can be reused to make an identical object. [PARAGRAPH:2]Metal casting is a complex process. First the mold is created. The "lost wax" process is an effective way to create a mold which has been in use since the Bronze Age. In this process the artisan creates in wax a replica, or "positive" copy, of the object to be cast. Then the artisan covers the wax object in clay. When fired in a kiln, the clay hardens around the wax, creating a "negative" image of the object. This is the mold. (The original wax positive melts during the process; thus its title.) Molds are often created in two or more pieces so that the cast metal can be removed without destroying the mold. [PARAGRAPH:2]Metal casting has some important advantages over earlier methods of working metals like blacksmithing. In blacksmithing, a smith heats and pounds metal until it achieves the required shape. This is a difficult process which requires a lot of skill. It's also quite time-consuming, as the smith can only work on one object at a time. Metal casting, on the other hand, is much more efficient. Once a skilled craftsman creates a mold, it can be used over and over again by less-skilled workers, with a large degree of certainty that the finished objects will be identical. Indeed, a mold can be created that will produce multiple copies of smaller objects, such as spearheads and daggers.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]金属铸造是加工金属物体的方法之一。在极高的温度下，金属融化为液体。将融化的金属倒入模子，冷却后它又回到固态，但保持了模子内部的形状。当取走金属铸件后，模子还可以用于再铸造同样形状的物品。[PARAGRAPH:2]金属铸造是一项复杂的工艺。首先要制造模子，“失蜡”法从青铜时代起就是制造模子的一种有效的方法。这种工艺中，工匠们先制造一个和所需要的物品形状一样的蜡制品，也叫“阳模”，然后工匠们用粘土糊裹起这个蜡制品。当在窑里加热之后，包裹着蜡的粘土变硬了，形成了物品的一个镜像，也就是“阴模”。这就是铸模。（起初的蜡制阳模在烧制的过程中融化流失，失蜡法也因此而得名。）模子常被做成两块或者更多块，这样可以取走金属铸件而不必损坏模子。[PARAGRAPH:2]金属铸造比早期的许多金属加工方法，例如锻造，具有一些重要的优势。在锻造中，工匠需要加热并锻打金属直到获得所需的形状。这是一种要求熟练技巧的高难度工艺，还需要花费大量的时间，而且工匠同一时间只能加工一件物品。相比之下，金属铸造的效率要快得多。一旦一个熟练的工匠制造了一个模子，它可以由技术较差的工人们反复地使用，而产品能在很大程度上保证其相似性。实际上，注模可以用于大量制造较小物品的复制品，比如矛头和匕首。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CONSTRUCTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The development of masonry led to a widespread use of stone in simple structures such as fortifications, but due to the weight and cumbersome nature of stone blocks, more complex structures had to be made of simpler materials. The need for the widespread use of more durable and permanent materials eventually became apparent, forcing ancient artisans to learn new techniques. The biggest problem to overcome was finding a stable way to span the distance between two upright columns or walls using stone blocks. To solve this problem, fundamental architectural elements such as the arch and vault evolved. These basic construction techniques allowed larger and more elaborate buildings to be created from stone and mortar. Many of the buildings erected by these early builders are still standing, a testament to the sound construction techniques employed in their construction.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]石工技术的发展使得石材在防御要塞等简单的建筑中得到了普遍的应用。但由于石块的重量和敲石所需要的繁重劳作，人们必须采用尽量简单的材料构筑更加复杂的建筑。对更加耐用而易用的材料的需求，迫使古代工匠们研究新的技术。需要解决的最大问题是寻找一个可靠的方法，使构件能够跨越两根柱子或两堵墙壁。为解决这个问题，古典建筑的基本元素——拱券和拱顶开始产生。这些基本的建筑构造技术使人们得以用石块和泥灰建造更大更精致的建筑。许多古老的建筑至今仍然屹立不倒，证明了这些基本建筑结构的可靠性。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HORSEBACK_RIDING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Tribesmen on the Asian steppes first domesticated the horse for transportation and warfare. These tribesmen used their superior mobility and speed to overwhelm the proto-civilizations just rising in southeast Europe and the Middle East. In approximately 2000 BC, domestic horses were introduced into Babylonia. Within the next several centuries, horses had spread throughout much of Europe and northern Africa. It was not long before nearly every civilization had put horses to work as field animals and as a means of transportation. Horses also went on to play an important role in the military conflicts of nearly every civilization in the world, both as mounts for horsemen and cavalry, and as draft animals for pulling war chariots and heavy weapons into battle.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]亚洲的游牧民族最早开始驯养马匹并将之应用于运输与军事。这些游牧民族依靠马匹提供的强大的机动性和速度狠狠地打击了刚刚在南欧和中亚出现的原始文明。大约在公元前2000年，巴比伦人学会了骑术。在接下来的几个世纪中，骑术传遍了欧洲和北非。不久之后，几乎所有文明都将马匹应用在农耕和运输当中。在文明间的军事冲突中，马匹也扮演了极为重要的角色。不但导致了各种马上作战兵种的产生，还被用来拖拉战车和其他重型装备。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPASS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The ancient Greeks, Romans, and Chinese knew the phenomenon of magnetism. They observed that lodestone, an iron-bearing ore, attracted other iron. They also noted that pieces of iron that came into contact with lodestone gained magnetic properties as well. The electromagnetic force of attraction and repulsion between various substances is due to the motion of positively and negatively charged electrons. Every magnet has positive and negative sides, called poles. Poles with a like charge repel one another, and poles with opposite charges attract one another.[PARAGRAPH:2]The study of magnetic phenomena soon showed that a free-floating magnet aligns itself with the Earth's magnetic field, one pole pointing north, the other south. This was an important discovery, and led to the invention of the compass in the early 13th century. The use of the compass revolutionized sea travel by reducing the reliance on landmarks and stars for navigation.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]古代希腊人、罗马人和中国人都已了解了磁力的特性。他们发现磁铁矿石能够吸引其他铁器，并注意到与磁铁矿石接触过的铁器也同样具有了磁力。这种物质之间相互吸引和排斥的力量来自于正负电荷之间的作用。任何磁体都有正负两端，称为磁极。同性的磁极相互排斥，异性的磁极则相互吸引。[PARAGRAPH:2]磁力现象的研究者很快发现，一根自由漂浮的磁体将会感应地球的磁场而转动自身方向，一极指北方，另一极指南。这是一项非常重要的发现，最终在13世纪早期导致了罗盘的发明。罗盘的应用对航海业来说是一场革命，它使得航海者不必再完全依赖地理标志物和星辰的位置进行导航。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MACHINERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A machine is an object constructed of several parts that assists in the performance of a task. The machinery technology allows construction of fairly complex machines with metal components that store, modify and transmit energy in a useful fashion. A windmill is a machine of this type, as is a printing press. [PARAGRAPH:2]Man has used primitive machines throughout much of history. A bow can be considered a simple machine, as can a mortar and pestle. More complex machines came into being in the Middle Ages - at least in Europe. The Persians had windmills back in the seventh century BC. [PARAGRAPH:2]The earliest machines consisted of gears, driveshafts, levers, pulleys, screws, winches and so forth. Some of these elements could be satisfactorily created of wood or stone, but those substances tend to be both fragile and very difficult to work with, particularly in small sizes. Once metallurgy provided stronger and more precise metal components, machines rapidly grew in sophistication and utility.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]机械工具是由多个部件所组成，可用于完成特定任务的装置。机械技术的发展使得人们可以用金属部件制造结构较为复杂的机器，并针对特定用途进行能量的储存、调节和传递。风车、印刷机等都属此类。[PARAGRAPH:2]历史上人类使用过各种初级的机械工具。例如弓、臼和槌等。更为复杂的机器则直到中世纪才开始出现——至少在欧洲是如此。而波斯人在公元前七世纪时已经开始使用风车。[PARAGRAPH:2]早期的机器由齿轮、驱动轴、杠杆、滑轮、螺旋和绞盘等部件组成。此类部件可以使用木材和石材制作，但这些材料强度不高，且难以用来制作更为小巧的部件。冶金技术的发展使更高强度和精度的金属部件开始出现，大大促进了机器复杂程度的提升和应用范围的扩展。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ENGINEERING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Engineering is the application of scientific and mathematical principles to the design and/or manufacture of theoretical systems and physical objects. Prior to the mid-18th century, military engineers carried out all engineering functions. Their work involved the construction of roads, bridges, fortifications, and the performance of other duties relating to the military. In the late 18th century, civil engineers took over all non-military engineering functions. Other fields of engineering prior to the 20th century included mining engineers, who designed mines and methods of mining, and mechanical engineers, who dealt with the design and construction of machinery. As new technologies developed, new fields of engineering developed along with them. Today, there are engineers specifically trained in nearly every field, from electronics and computers to chemistry and atomics.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]工程学是科学和数学原理在设计和建造各种实用系统和产品中的应用。早在18世纪中叶前，军事技师们为工程学的建立奠定了基础。他们的工作包括修筑道路、桥梁、要塞以及其他军事设施等。到18世纪晚期，民用工程师广泛从事各种非军事工程技术活动。而其他的工程学专门领域，例如钻井采矿、机械设计制造等也在20世纪初叶前即已初具规模。随着新技术的发展，新的工程学领域也不断出现。时至今日，从电子学、计算机、化工到原子能等都已拥有相应的专业工程师。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_OPTICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Optics is the study of the behavior of light. In Civilization IV, the optics technology refers specifically to the branch of optics that concentrates upon improving human sight through the creation of optical instruments such as eye glasses, telescopes and microscopes. Advancements in optics had profound effects upon man's interaction with the world around him. [PARAGRAPH:2]It is not certain when the first working telescope was created. A number of lens-shaped crystals were found in a Viking grave dating from the 10th Century, but there is debate over whether these were purely decorative or were used to enhance vision. In 1609 Galileo created a "telescopium," which he used to study the stars. Accurate star charts allowed sailors to better chart their courses while at sea. [PARAGRAPH:2]The Janssens, a family of Dutch spectacle makers, are claimed to have built the first working microscope in 1590; but once again, there is debate over that claim. And once again, Galileo is another candidate, credited with constructing his "occhiolino" in 1609. Anton van Leeuwenhoek famously used an early microscope to examine cells, bacteria, and other extremely small living creatures. This research was to revolutionize man's understanding of biology and medicine.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]光学是研究光的特性的学科。在文明IV中，光学科技则特指通过光学设备提升人类观察能力这一光学分支领域的研究，例如眼镜，望远镜和显微镜等。光学科技的发展极大提升了人类观察周围世界的能力。[PARAGRAPH:2]第一台望远镜的发明时间尚无法确定。考古学者在10世纪的维京墓穴中发现了许多透镜形状的水晶，但对于这些水晶究竟是仅仅属于装饰品还是用于增强人类观察力尚存争议。1609年时伽利略制造了一台“望远镜”并用以研究星空。望远镜使人们能绘制更精确的星图，帮助海员更准确地进行海上定位。[PARAGRAPH:2]据认为，从事眼镜制造业的荷兰简森斯家族在1590年发明了第一台显微镜，但这一点同样存在争议。同样的，伽利略也被认为可能是显微镜的发明者，他在1609年制造了一台“显微镜”。安东·范·列文虎克则因使用显微镜研究细胞，细菌和其他微生物而闻名于世。这些研究革命性地促进了人类对生物学和医学知识的了解。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GUNPOWDER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Gunpowder is a chemical mixture of saltpeter, sulfur, and charcoal. When ignited, it burns rapidly and explodes if contained to any degree. Gunpowder is believed to have been developed by the Chinese, who used it in fireworks as early as the 9th century, but it did not reach Europe until the 14th century. Europeans immediately saw the potential of this substance, and manufactured it for use in weapons as early as 1334. The discovery of gunpowder led to the invention of firearms, such as the musket, which led to the replacement of archers in most armies of the world by the late 1500s. Gunpowder marked one of the major technological turning points in military history; significantly changing the way wars were fought.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]火药是硫磺、硝石和木炭的一种化学混合物。它燃烧极为迅速，如果燃烧过程中被限于一定空间内的话，还会导致爆炸。早在9世纪，中国人就已发明了火药，并将之应用于焰火。而直到14世纪，火药才传入欧洲。欧洲人很快意识到这项技术的潜在意义，在1334年就开始将之应用于制造武器。火药的发明导致了火器的诞生，例如火枪，它在16世纪晚期的一些军队中已完全取代了弓箭手的地位。火药意味着军事史上的一个重大转折。它完全改变了战争的形式。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REPLACEABLE_PARTS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]With the advent of machine manufacturing, craftsmen were able to set manufacturing to exacting specifications. One advantage of this was being able to manufacture complex objects, such as guns, in separate pieces. The benefit of this was realized when manufacturers replaced only the broken parts of the objects that they made rather than replacing or repairing the entire instrument. By setting machine manufacturing guidelines, manufacturers were able to make large quantities of the components of their products and then later assemble the finished product, increasing efficiency greatly. Replaceable parts revolutionized nearly every industry in the industrial age, paving the way for mass production and assembly line manufacture.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]借助机器生产带来的便利，技工们能够将产品的规格控制在一个统一的范围之内。这样做的一个好处在于能够制造更加复杂的产品。例如枪，可以被分成多种部件制造出来。而当有部件损坏时，只要将损坏的部件置换并修理好就可以了。通过制定生产标准，生产者们得以分门别类的制造产品部件并在随后组装，由此大大的提高了效率。可更换部件对几乎所有的制造业都带来了深远的影响。并为大规模生产和流水线作业的诞生铺平了道路。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RIFLING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]"Rifling" is the term describing the practice of putting helical grooves in the barrel of a "long gun" to impart a spin to the projectile. This spin greatly increases the bullet's accuracy at distance. [PARAGRAPH:2]Muskets, the original long guns, were "smoothbores"; these lacked rifling and the bullets were significantly smaller than the barrels of the weapons. When fired, the projectile would bounce against the sides of the weapon's barrel, giving it an uncertain direction upon exiting the barrel. [PARAGRAPH:2]Experimentation with muskets with grooved barrels and tighter-fitting projectiles began as early as the 15th Century, but mass-produced rifled muskets did not appear in great numbers until the mid-1800s. The rifled musket was the standard infantry weapon during the American Civil War; some cavalrymen were armed with breech-loading rifles, the weapons' accuracy and rate of firing giving them a powerful advantage in combat. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]“膛线”或称“来复线”，是指“长管火器”内膛中加入螺旋状凹槽，使其所发射的弹丸能够高速自转。自转能极大的提升弹丸的远距离射击精度。[PARAGRAPH:2]最早的火枪是没有膛线的“滑膛枪”，其弹丸的直径远小于枪管口径。发射时弹丸会在枪膛内多次反弹，因此其射出枪口后的前进方向难以确定。[PARAGRAPH:2]在枪管中加入膛线及加大弹丸适应枪管口径的尝试早在15世纪就已开始，但真正实用的线膛枪“来复枪”直到19世纪中期才大规模生产并装备部队。来复枪在美国南北战争中成为步兵的标准武器；部分骑兵部队也开始使用后膛装弹的来复枪，这种武器由于射击精度和发射速度的提高，在战场上具有极大的优越性。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEAM_POWER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The steam engine is a device that uses steam to generate power. Water, heated by burning fuel (usually coal or wood), turns to steam. The steam is contained in a chamber where it builds up pressure, causing a piston to move. The piston drives a turbine, the rotation of which produces power, which can be use for such purposes as producing motion or generating electricity. The early principles of this device were understood as early as the late 17th century, but it wasn't until 1769 that Scottish engineer James Watt patented a practical design for what was to become the basis for the modern steam engine. The invention of the steam engine led to a number of landmark developments, including the steam locomotive and the earliest examples of automobiles. Steam engines remained the chief means of motive power in the transportation industry until the invention of the more powerful and compact internal combustion engine. Steam turbines are still in use today in a number of applications including the generation of electrical power.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]蒸汽机是一种通过蒸汽来产生动力的机械。水在被加热后变成蒸汽，而汽缸内的蒸汽则产生压力并带动活塞运动。活塞推动涡轮，涡轮的转动产生能量，推动物体运动或者产生电能。17世纪晚期，人们就已经认识到这种机械的基本原理。但直到1769年苏格兰工程师詹姆斯·瓦特申请了蒸汽机的专利，才奠定了现代蒸汽机构成的基础。蒸汽机的发明带来了一系列决定性的发展。包括作为早期机动车辆原型的蒸汽机车，在内燃机发明之前，蒸汽机车一直在运输行业中占据着极其重要的地位。时至今日，蒸汽机仍在包括发电在内的许多部门中得到应用。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEEL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The iron alloys produced up until about the 14th century were made by heating a mixture of iron ore and charcoal in a forge, then pounding the molten metal to drive out the impurities or "slag". Occasionally, the iron mixture would absorb more carbon, creating steel rather than wrought iron. Because steel proved to be less brittle and more resistant to corrosion than iron, techniques were developed to produce steel. Blowing a coal derivative called coke through molten iron did this. Most modern steel making utilizes the "blast furnace", developed by Henry Bessemer in 1855, to accomplish this task on a large-scale basis. The strength and other qualities of steel make it the material of choice for warships, planes, and many other vehicles.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]在14世纪左右，人们开始将铁矿石和木炭混合在熔炉内加热，通过煅打熔化的金属以除去其中混杂的矿渣，以制造“熟铁”。而在此过程中，铁水有时会吸收更多的碳元素并转变成钢。因为钢比铁更坚韧，也不容易生锈，所以广受欢迎，使制钢工艺不断发展。人们采用特制的“焦炭”与铁混合加热生产钢。现代钢铁厂大量使用的“鼓风熔炉”则是由亨利·比斯梅尔在1855年发明的，鼓风熔炉使人们能够大规模地生产钢材。钢所具有的高强度和其他优良特性使之成为制造战舰、飞机和各种车辆的首选材料。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RAILROAD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The predecessors to modern railroads were wagonways, which were constructed in England starting in the 16th century. Wagonways were roads of parallel planks upon which coal wagons were pulled by horses at a greater speed than would have been possible on dirt roads. Wagonways were gradually improved by adding cross-ties and iron strips to reinforce the track. Eventually, the planks became metal rails, and evolved into the type of rails used on today's railroads by the start of the 19th century. Soon after the steam locomotive was introduced in 1829, it replaced horse-drawn wagons, giving birth to the railroad. Originally developed in Britain and the eastern United States as a method of hauling heavy mining ores and freight, railroads outshone canals in their ability to operate across any ground and in nearly any weather. When railroads started carrying passengers as well as goods, the potential for safe, fast,  inexpensive transport became clear. Railroads led to a dramatic increase in the amount of cargo,  passengers, news, and troops that could be moved quickly over great distances.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]现代铁路的前身是英格兰在16世纪开始建造的矿车轨道。矿车轨道是供马拉运煤车厢通行的木质双轨，其速度比普通马拉货车快得多。此后的矿车轨道还采用了横向枕木和加强铁条等改进措施。最终木质轨道被金属轨道所代替，并在19世纪初叶演化成为现代铁路所使用的铁轨。蒸汽机车在1829年出现并迅速淘汰了畜力车，铁路也由此正式诞生。铁路系统首先在英国和美国东部建立起来，用于采矿与货运。铁路相比运河具有更强的适应性，能用于大多数地形与气候。除了运送货物，铁路也开始运送人员，在提供更安全，快速且费用低廉的客运服务方面展现出巨大潜力。铁路的普及使远距离的大宗客货运输、新闻出版及军事调动活动出现了戏剧性的高速增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTILLERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The term "artillery" is used to describe any weapon that throws large missiles and requires more than one person to operate. In Civilization IV, the artillery technology refers specifically to the invention and production of large and powerful breech-loading weapons that fire shells rather than balls. Production of these weapons began in the latter half of the 19th Century. [PARAGRAPH:2]Artillery is defined in a number of ways. One is by the weapon's trajectory: a "direct fire" weapon has a relatively flat trajectory, while an "indirect-fire" weapon has a high arc, allowing the missile to be dropped on targets behind walls, hills or even mountains. Artillery is also defined by its mode of transport; some are "fixed" weapons that cannot be moved, others are "towed" by separate vehicles, and others are "self-propelled." [PARAGRAPH:2]Today's artillery is extremely lethal. The weapons can fire missiles at targets miles away, their targets spotted from airplane or even satellite. Artillery shells may contain high explosives, shrapnel, fueled-air explosives, mines, or even poison gas. The primary limitation of artillery in modern warfare is its relative slowness; the big guns cannot keep pace with the fast-moving armor and mechanized infantry forces. Jet planes are often used in artillery's traditional role now.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]火炮，这个术语以往一直定义为一种需要多人操作，可以按照要求发射大型抛射物的武器。在文明IV中，火炮科技特指发明并与制造后膛装填式，可以发射大型强力炮弹的武器，而不是指仅能发射实心弹丸的老式大炮。这样的火炮最早在19世纪中后期被发明。[PARAGRAPH:2]火炮有几种分类法。按照弹道轨迹来分，“直射火炮”（如加农炮）的弹道相对平直，“曲射火炮”（如榴弹炮，迫击炮）的弹道则成一个大弧形，可以绕过高墙、小山丘甚至高大的山脉命中目标。另一种分类法根据火炮的运送方式：不能移动的称为固定火炮，使用独立交通工具的是牵引火炮，然后是自行火炮。[PARAGRAPH:2]今天的火炮极具毁灭性，可以通过飞机甚至卫星定位，在数英里之外准确命中目标。炮弹也包括了高爆弹、榴霰弹、云爆弹、地雷弹甚至毒气弹。在现代战争中，炮兵的主要问题是移动缓慢，重型火炮无法跟上现代主战坦克与机械化步兵的移动速度。现在，喷气式飞机渐渐取代火炮在战争中的角色。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ASSEMBLY_LINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The idea of mass production began to take shape along with the factory system. The automation of production greatly increased productivity with a corresponding decrease in price for manufactured goods. In 1913, automobile manufacturer Henry Ford introduced the idea of assembly lines in his automobile plants. Products being built were conveyed from one work station to another along the line.  At each station, a worker expertly repeated a discreet segment of the assembly process. The product then moved to the next station, and so on until the finished product rolled off the end of the line. This innovative combination of specialization of labor and the use of automation revolutionized production of complex goods. Word of Ford's assembly line technique spread quickly, and this production method soon came to be used in most of the industrialized nations of the world.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]伴随制造体系的显著发展，一个大规模生产的灵感诞生了。在自动化生产极大的提高生产力的同时，也相应的减少了人力成本。1913年，福特汽车在它的生产线中提出了组装流水线这一概念。生产中的产品沿着流水线从一个工作点送到另一个工作点，每一个工作点上，工人熟练地重复独立的工作段流程，直到产品全部完工。这个创新的专业化工作形式和自动化的使用彻底改革了复杂产品的生产制造。福特式的生产线技术推广得十分迅速，很快，世界上大多数工业化国家都采用了这种制造模式。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_INDUSTRIALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Industrialization involves the use of machines to dramatically increase productivity. Production of goods became concentrated in factories, where the combination of specialization of labor and automation reduced labor costs and, ultimately, the cost of the final manufactured product to the consumers.  Industrialization revolutionized living standards, both positively and negatively. The rapid growth of production industries and the reduced cost of production have led to the prosperity of some of the richest families in history. Industrialization has also led to the creation of a blue-collar working class. In newly industrialized nations, these workers, skilled only in their chosen trade, are often underpaid and forced to endure abominable working conditions.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]工业化通过大量运用机器大大地提升了生产力。工厂成为组织生产的中心，通过劳动的专业化以及生产的自动化，生产过程中劳动的成本大大降低，并最终减少消费者购买产品的花费。工业化革命性的改变了人民的生活水准。持续增长的工业生产和持续减少的生产消耗带来了历史上许多实业家族的持续繁荣。但也同样导致了蓝领阶层的诞生。在新兴的工业化国家中，工人们因为只熟悉他们所从事的工种，而不得不忍受过低的薪酬和极差的工作环境。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RADIO_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Prior to Guglielmo Marconi's invention of the radio in 1896, long-distance communication was carried out either by mail or over miles of cable via telegraph. Marconi's first demonstration of the radiotelegraph transmitted a message just over one mile without the use of wires. Continued improvements increased transmission range to over 200 miles by early 1901, and by the end of the year a single letter ("A") had been transmitted across the Atlantic Ocean. By 1905, many ships were equipped with radiotelegraphs for ship-to-ship and ship-to-land communications, and by 1915 the invention of the three-element vacuum tube, or triode, made it possible to regularly transmit voice messages over the airwaves. Throughout the years, radio has been refined not only for communication, but for detection and ranging (Radar) and astronomy.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]1896年马可尼发明无线电之前，长距离通讯依靠邮件或有线电报得以实现。尽管马可尼的第一次无线电实验只实现了一英里范围内的无线传播，但到了1901年，飞速发展的技术就已经把这个距离提高到了200英里。而在那一年晚些时候，人们通过大西洋传递了一个字母“A”。1905年，许多船只装备了无线电通讯系统以实现船对船，船对陆的联络。1915年，真空电子管的发明让通过电波传递声音的想法得以实现。今天，无线电不仅用于通讯，还应用在侦察和测距（雷达）以及天文观测中。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REFRIGERATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Refrigeration is the technology of cooling objects to temperatures below the current ambient temperature. In addition to its most obvious function of chilling or freezing foods to delay spoilage, refrigeration plays a vital part in modern human civilization. Air conditioners allow people to live and function in environments that would otherwise be too hot. And many mechanical and electronic devices require cooling to function properly. [PARAGRAPH:2]A number of advanced technologies are heavily dependent upon refrigeration. Superconductors, for instance, function best at extremely low temperatures. Space ships and suits must be refrigerated if their inhabitants are to survive in direct sunlight. And the interruption of a nuclear reactor's cooling system is likely to have extremely unfortunate consequences for those nearby. [PARAGRAPH:2]The invention of the first modern refrigeration system is in dispute, with scientists from England, Australia, Germany and the United States laying claim to the honor. The earliest refrigeration machines were built to make ice; they were constructed in the 1850s. The first home refrigeration systems were constructed around 1900, and the first air conditioning systems were implemented several years later. Residential air conditioners began to gain widespread use in the United States in the 1950s. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]制冷技术是一项将物体冷却至低于环境温度的科技。除了能够采用低温储藏，使食物的保质期更长之外，制冷技术更是现代人类文明的重要组成部分之一。空调让人们可以在过热的环境中生存和工作，其他众多的机械及电子设备也依赖制冷技术来运作。[PARAGRAPH:2]大量的现代科技依赖制冷技术。例如超导材料，只有在极低的温度环境下才能够运作良好。太空船和航天服在阳光直射下，必须通过制冷科技才能够让其乘员生存。而一个核反应堆的制冷系统对于其周围的居民来说，更是生死攸关的大事。[PARAGRAPH:2]对于到底是谁发明了第一个制冷系统的问题仍充满争议，英国、澳大利亚、德国以及美国的科学家都认为他们应当得到这个荣誉。最早的制冷机器是用于制冰，建成于19世纪50年代。第一个家庭制冷系统制成于1900年，第一个空调系统则于数年后制成。家用空调系统在20世纪50年代开始在美国普及。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPUTERS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A computer is a device capable of performing a series of repetitive arithmetic or logical functions far more quickly than the human brain. The earliest computers were designed to solve complex mathematical equations. British mathematician Charles Babbage conceived such a machine, called the Analytical Engine, in the 19th century. Many variations of analog, or mechanical, computing devices were built during the first half of the 20th century, and were used for such tasks as computing torpedo tracking in submarines and controlling bombsights.[PARAGRAPH:2]The growing study of electronics in the late 1940s led to the invention of the digital computer. The first all-electronic computer, containing 18,000 vacuum tubes and capable of hundreds of multiplications per minute, was built in 1946. Further advances in electronics rapidly reduced the size and increased the speed and efficiency of computers. Today, computers are commonplace, and are used in virtually every field of endeavor. Significant advances in computer technology continue to take place at an amazing pace.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]计算机能够以人脑远所不及的速度进行一系列重复的算术和逻辑运算。早期的计算机被用来求解复杂的数学方程。19世纪，英国数学家查尔斯·巴贝奇设计了这样的机械并将其命名为数字分析机。20世纪中叶，又产生了许多类似的机械式计算装置，并用于计算潜艇鱼雷轨迹和飞机投弹瞄准等领域。[PARAGRAPH:2]20世纪40年代，电子学取得的巨大进步导致了电子计算机的发明。1946年，最早的电子计算机诞生了，它由18000个电子管组成，并能在一分钟内进行几百次运算。电子技术的飞速发展很快缩小了电子计算机的体积并提高了其运算速度，今天电子计算机已被应用在几乎所有领域之中，而其发展仍以不可思议的速度持续着。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ROCKETRY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Rockets are projectiles that are propelled by the expulsion of gases generated in a combustion chamber. The first solid-fuel rockets, invented by the Chinese in the 13th century, used a mixture similar to gunpowder for fuel. Although rockets were used in warfare to set fire to buildings and the sails of ships for nearly 500 years, it wasn't until the early 19th century that the first crude explosive rockets were used in battle.[PARAGRAPH:2]Research and design efforts by scientists such as Robert Goddard in the 20th century refined rocket design to produce faster, better controlled rockets. During World War II, this new technology was used to create the German V-2, the first true guided missile. Scientific developments since World War II have been applied to adapt the rocket for use in even more powerful and accurate weapons with incredible range. The rocket is also used in peaceful application such as the launch of satellites and the exploration of space.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]火箭通过燃烧舱产生的气体推进飞行。中国人早在13世纪就发明了最早的固体燃料火箭，他们使用一种类似火药的混合物作为燃料。在之后的500年间，火箭作为一种纵火武器被用来焚毁敌方建筑和船只。到19世纪早期，装有可爆炸弹头的火箭开始用于实战.[PARAGRAPH:2]20世纪，罗伯特·戈达德在制造更快、更精确的火箭方面取得了极大的进展，第二次世界大战中，这项新科技被应用于制造最早的制导导弹——德国的V-2。二战后的科学进展使得火箭成为射程更远、破坏力更强的武器。当然，它也应用在包括宇宙探索及卫星发射等和平目的上。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SATELLITES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Artificial satellites are spacecraft that maintain an orbit around a celestial body. What differentiates an orbit from other types of space flight is it doesn't require any additional propulsion. Satellites can hold a number of different orbits. One type is a polar orbit, which causes the spacecraft to pass over the north and south poles. Another is an equatorial orbit, which causes the satellite to circle the Earth's equator. The farther the orbit from the surface of the earth, the longer it takes to complete a circuit of the earth. If the vessel uses an equatorial orbit at a distance of 22,300 miles from Earth, it can achieve geo-synchronous orbit, which causes the satellite to remain stationary over a specific area. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]人造卫星按一定轨道环绕地球飞行，其不同于其他航天器的地方在于不需要任何形式的推进力，卫星可以籍由多种轨道绕地飞行。极线轨道人造卫星通过南北极上空绕地飞行。赤道轨道人造卫星环绕轨道圈飞行。人造卫星离地面越远，绕地飞行一圈所需的时间就越长。如果人造卫星在距离地面22300英里的赤道轨道——即同步地球轨道上飞行，就会以和地球自转速度相同的速度运转，从而相对地球保持固定的位置。第一颗人造卫星是苏联于1957年10月发射的“伴星”1号。在今天，人造卫星扮演着包括科学观察，天气预报，个人和商业通讯以及军事侦察等功能在内的诸多角色。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ROBOTICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The creation of machines to assist in, and increase the efficiency of, the manufacturing process gave birth to the factory system of production and started the Industrial Revolution. The invention of digital computers in the late 1940s, and their refinement over the next several decades, took factory automation one step further. Computer-controlled machines, called robots, were designed to perform repetitive or dangerous tasks more quickly than humans. Experimental robots capable of simple manipulation of objects were in operation by the late 1960s. General Motors commissioned the first robots used on an assembly line in the 1970s. Constant improvements in the computer field have allowed the production of incredibly versatile robots, capable of performing a wide variety of tasks under virtually any environmental condition. Robots today are widely used in manufacturing, scientific research, and space exploration.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]在制造中使用机械，增加机械效率等一系列举措带来了工业系统的诞生，并引发了工业革命。而50年代晚些时候，电子计算机的发明及发展使工厂的自动化更进一步。由电子计算机控制的机械称为自动机器或是机器人，被设计来进行高速的、重复性的或者危险的任务。60年代末期，试验性的机器人就已经能完成简单的动作。到70年代，通用汽车公司首先将自动机械应用于流水作业上。电脑领域的不断革新带来了可在诸多环境下完成许多复杂任务的机器人的诞生。于是，机器人被广泛应用在生产，科研和宇宙探索等诸多领域中。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FUTURE_TECH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Since the dawn of mankind, human needs and desires have combined to produce ideas and inventions that make life easier and more productive. New technological breakthroughs have become an almost daily occurrence in the modern era, and new ideas will continue to drive human knowledge to higher and higher levels well into the future.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[TAB]自人类诞生起，从来都需要并期望通过发明和创造，使生活变得更美好。每一个新时代的每一天都可能出现新的科技进展，新的想法将继续驾驭着知识的列车向更高的层次行进，直到未来。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
