<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- freesand -->
<!-- Gametext Civilopedia Concepts -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<!-- GAMEPLAY CONCEPTS -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_ANIMALS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Animals[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]At the start of a game of Civilization IV, predatory animals may be found roaming about the world. These animals will attack any units they encounter; unarmed settlers and workers are especially at risk. Animals can be fought and destroyed just like any other unit in the game. Animals will not appear in or move into areas within a [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]National Border[\LINK]; they will gradually disappear as more and more of the world is claimed.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]野兽[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在文明IV游戏的早期，掠食类野兽会在世界上四处游荡。这些野兽会攻击所遇到的任何单位；使没有武装的移民和工人处于危险境地。野兽单位可以象其他单位一样被消灭。野兽不会出现或进入[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]国界[\LINK]范围之内；并会随着无主之地的日益减少而逐渐消失。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_AIR_UNITS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Air Units[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]First seeing widespread military use in World War I as unarmed reconnaissance vehicles, over the next half-century aircraft would become the most versatile and powerful part of the modern army. Indeed, as recent events have shown, a military with air superiority can now cripple opposing ground forces before the first infantryman or armored vehicle ever sees an enemy soldier.[PARAGRAPH:2]There are two different categories of air units in Civilization IV: rotary-wing aircraft and fixed-wing aircraft.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Rotary Wing Aircraft[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_GUNSHIP]Gunships[\LINK] are heavily armed and armored helicopters. These powerful modern units are especially adept at destroying enemy tanks and vehicles.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Gunship Movement:[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Gunships move like other land units, except that they pay 1 Movement Point to enter all land spaces, including peaks (which are impassable to other land units). Gunships cannot enter water spaces except when carried aboard a [LINK=UNIT_TRANSPORT]naval transport[\LINK] unit.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Gunship Combat:[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Gunships fight like any other land unit: if it moves into a space containing an enemy unit, it attacks that unit. If an enemy unit moves into its space, it attacks the gunship.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Fixed Wing Aircraft[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There are two categories of fixed-wing aircraft in the game: fighters and bombers.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Fighters:[\BOLD] Fighters are proficient at attacking enemy naval units - they can attack land units as well - and intercepting enemy fighters. Further, fighters can be based on [LINK=UNIT_CARRIER]aircraft carriers[\LINK]. Fighter-types include the aptly-named [LINK=UNIT_FIGHTER]Fighter[\LINK] and [LINK=UNIT_JET_FIGHTER]Jet Fighter[\LINK] units.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Bombers:[\BOLD] Bombers are useful for [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]bombarding[\LINK] enemy cities and tile improvements. Further, bombers have a powerful attack against enemy land units. They can attack naval units, as well, but they are less effective when doing so. Bombers cannot be based on aircraft carriers. Bomber units include [LINK=UNIT_BOMBER]Bombers[\LINK] and [LINK=UNIT_STEALTH_BOMBER]Stealth Bombers[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Fixed-Wing Aircraft Movement[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Fixed-wing aircraft are based in cities (or aboard aircraft carriers for fighters). They cannot begin or end a turn elsewhere. Fighters and bombers can "rebase" to another city (or carrier) during their turn. The city can be anywhere on the map, but it must be owned by you or by a civilization you have an [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Open Borders[\LINK] agreement with. If an aircraft rebases, it can do nothing else during that turn.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Fixed-Wing Missions[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When not rebasing, fixed-wing aircraft can perform a variety of different missions. Each aircraft can perform only one mission per turn.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Mission Range:[\BOLD] Each fixed-wing air unit has a "mission range" rating. An aircraft can perform missions in any space within this range.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Air Strike:[\BOLD] A fixed-wing unit can be ordered to attack any ground unit within its range.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Recon:[\BOLD] An aircraft can be ordered to perform a recon mission. Click on a space within the unit's range and all units/improvements for the number of spaces equal to half of the units movement will be revealed.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Air Bomb:[\BOLD] Air units can be ordered to [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]bombard[\LINK] enemy city fortifications and tile improvements within their mission range.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Intercept:[\BOLD] Fighter units can be ordered on "intercept" missions. They then have a chance to attack any enemy air units that try enter their mission range. [PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Ground Unit Interception of Aircraft[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Some ground units - [LINK=UNIT_SAM_INFANTRY]SAM Infantry[\LINK] and [LINK=UNIT_MECHANIZED_INFANTRY]Mechanized Infantry[\LINK], to name two - have a chance of intercepting enemy air units when the air units attack their square OR an adjacent square.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]空中单位[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]飞机最初是作为没有武装的侦察工具，在第一次世界大战中首次广泛用于军事，经过半个世纪的发展，飞机已成为现代军队中获得广泛应用的重要单位。确实，近来的事实表明，一支有空中优势的部队可以在步兵或者装甲车辆看到敌军士兵之前就削弱地面部队的作战能力。[PARAGRAPH:2]在文明IV中，空中单位分为两类：旋翼飞机和固定翼飞机。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]旋翼飞机[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_GUNSHIP]武装直升机[\LINK]武装直升机是装有厚重护甲和重型武器的直升机。这些强大的现代化单位特别擅长于摧毁敌人的坦克和其他车辆。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]武装直升机的移动:[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]武装直升机的移动像其它地面单位一样，武装直升机的移动方式与其它地面单位一样，但他们进入任何陆地区域均只耗费1移动力。武装直升机不能进入水域，除非由[LINK=UNIT_TRANSPORT]运输舰船[\LINK]运载。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]武装直升机的战斗:[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]武装直升机的战斗方式和其它的地面部队一样：如果它进入一个敌军单位占据的区域，它将攻击该单位。如果敌军单位进入武装直升机的区域，也将攻击武装直升机。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]固定翼飞机[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在游戏中固定翼飞机分为两类：战斗机和轰炸机。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]战斗机:[\BOLD]战斗机擅长攻击敌方海军单位——也可以攻击地面单位——以及截击敌方战斗机。此外，战斗机可以[LINK=UNIT_CARRIER]航空母舰[\LINK]作为基地。战斗机单位包括普通[LINK=UNIT_FIGHTER]战斗机[\LINK]和[LINK=UNIT_JET_FIGHTER]喷气式战斗机[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]轰炸机:[\BOLD]轰炸机适用于[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]轰炸[\LINK]敌方城市和区域设施。而且，轰炸机对敌方地面部队杀伤力极强。它们也可攻击海军单位，但效果较差。轰炸机不能以航空母舰作为基地。轰炸机单位包括普通[LINK=UNIT_BOMBER]轰炸机[\LINK]和[LINK=UNIT_STEALTH_BOMBER]隐形轰炸机[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]固定翼飞机的移动[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]固定翼飞机以城市为基地（战斗机也可以航空母舰为基地）。它们不能在别处开始或结束一个回合。战斗机和轰炸机可以在一个回合中“转场”到其他城市（或航空母舰）。转场目标城市可以位于任何地点，但是该城市必须属于你的文明或与你签有[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]开放边境[\LINK]条约的文明。在飞机转场的回合中，不能再做其他任何操作。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]固定翼飞机的任务[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当不进行转场时，固定翼飞机可执行多种不同的任务。每个飞机单位一回合内只能执行一种任务。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]活动范围:[\BOLD]特定固定翼飞机单位有一定的“活动范围”。一架飞机可以在此范围之内的任何区域执行任务。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]空袭:[\BOLD]固定翼飞机可以攻击活动范围内的任何敌方地面单位。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]侦察:[\BOLD]飞机可以执行侦察任务。点击活动范围内的任一区域，飞机移动区域的半数区域中的所有单位和设施将显示出来。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]轰炸:[\BOLD]在活动范围内，空中单位可[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]轰炸[\LINK]破坏敌方城市的防御或区域设施。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]截击:[\BOLD]战斗机单位可以执行“截击”任务。它们有一定几率攻击进入其活动范围的敌方空中单位。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]地面单位对飞机的拦截[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]一些地面单位——[LINK=UNIT_SAM_INFANTRY]防空步兵[\LINK]和[LINK=UNIT_MECHANIZED_INFANTRY]机械化步兵[\LINK]——均有一定几率拦截攻击其所在地块或相领地块的敌方空中单位。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_BARBARIANS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Barbarians[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Barbarians can appear as individual units or as cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Barbarian Units[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Barbarian units are generated randomly in map spaces that no non-barbarian units can see. Barbarians may attack any units and cities they encounter. They in turn can be attacked and destroyed like any other units in the game. Barbarian units will not be generated within a [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]nation's borders[\LINK], but they can move into such territory at will. This is in contrast to [LINK=CONCEPT_ANIMALS]Animals[\LINK], who will not enter the territory of a civilization. [PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Barbarian Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Occasionally Barbarians will settle down and form cities. These cities are like any other city in the game: the Barbarians can build [LINK=BUILDING_WALLS]walls[\LINK] and other fortifications; they can fill the cities with defending units; they can even build [LINK=UNIT_WORKER]Workers[\LINK] to improve the territory around their cities.[PARAGRAPH:2]Barbarian cities can be attacked, conquered or destroyed like any other city in the game.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]蛮族[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]蛮族会以单位或城市的形式出现。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]蛮族单位[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]蛮族会在地图的文明不可见区域中随机出现。蛮族可能攻击他们遇到的任何单位和城市。他们也和游戏中的其它单位一样可以被攻击和消灭。蛮族不会在[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]国界[\LINK]范围内产生，但是可以进入任何文明的国界。这与[LINK=CONCEPT_ANIMALS]野兽[\LINK]单位不同，后者不会进入文明的领地。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]蛮族城市[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]有时蛮族也会定居下来形成城市。这些城市和游戏中的其它城市一样：蛮族可建造[LINK=BUILDING_WALLS]城墙[\LINK]和其他防御设施；他们会在城市中驻扎部队；他们甚至可以生产[LINK=UNIT_WORKER]工人[\LINK]来改造城市周围的土地。[PARAGRAPH:2]蛮族的城市和其他城市一样可以被攻击，占领或者摧毁。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_BORDERS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Borders[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The land that your civilization controls - that is, the land within its "borders" - is determined by the number and cultural strength of your cities. When you first construct a city, its borders usually extend to the squares directly adjacent to it; as the city's [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]cultural value[\LINK] grows, its borders extend to squares farther away, eventually merging with the borders of  your other nearby cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Seeing Borders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Squares within each civilization's borders are lightly tinted different colors. [LINK=CONCEPT_BARBARIANS]Barbarian-controlled[\LINK] squares are tinted black. If unsure of a square's status, put your mouse on that square and look at the "pop-up help."[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Borders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Borders have a number of important effects. Your cities can draw sustenance only from spaces within your borders, and your workers can only [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]"improve"[\LINK] such squares as well (except for roads and railroads, which they can build anywhere). Your units heal faster within your own borders, more slowly in neutral (unclaimed) territory, and even slower when in foreign borders. Further, other civilizations' units (with a few exceptions) cannot enter your territory without declaring war, nor can you enter theirs. Barbarians can enter your territory, but animals cannot.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Clash of Borders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When you have a city near another civilization's city, the two will compete for [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]cultural control[\LINK] over the squares between them. Generally, if the square is equidistant from both cities, the city with the highest culture will have control over it. It is important to keep in mind that the earlier a city begins producing culture, the more difficult it will be for a rival city to dislodge the tiles it controls. Cities are not guaranteed to control a certain number of tiles; if one city's culture greatly exceeds the other's, its control may extend to squares closer to the other city and possibly to the squares directly adjacent to it. Since a city can draw sustenance only from squares within its cultural borders, this may greatly limit the city's growth and possibly lead to [LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]starvation[\LINK] or even to the city switching sides and changing its allegiance to the encroaching civilization. See [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]culture[\LINK] for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Capturing Enemy Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When you capture an enemy city, that city must begin producing culture to expand its borders from square one, and this can only take place after [LINK=CONCEPT_RESISTANCE]"resistance"[\LINK] has ended in that city. It is not unusual for newly captured cities to have control of very few tiles until the conqueror begins producing culture in them.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]国界[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]你的文明所控制的领地——“国界”范围内的区域——它取决于你的城市的数量和文化强度。当你新建一座城市，它的边界通常立即扩展到四周相邻的格子；随着城市[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化等级[\LINK]的增长，其边界将向外扩展，最后和邻近的城市相融合。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]国界视野[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]每个文明的国界范围将显示较亮的特定颜色。[LINK=CONCEPT_BARBARIANS]蛮族控制的[\LINK]区域则颜色较暗。如果一块土地的归属尚不确定，将鼠标放在该区域将“弹出帮助信息”。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]国界作用[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]国界有一些重要的作用。你的城市只能从你国界范围内的区域获得资源，你的工人也只能[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]“改造”[\LINK]本国区域（除了道路和铁路，可以在任何地方修建）.在国界单位恢复得更快，在中立（未被占据）区域较慢，在别国边界内则更慢。此外，其他文明的单位（有少数例外）非经宣战不能进入你的领土，你也不能进入他们的领土。蛮族可以进入你的领土，但是动物不能。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]国界争议[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当你有一个城市和其它文明的城市相邻时，两座城市之间会进行[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化控制权[\LINK]的争夺。通常，如果某个区域和两座城市的距离相等，文化等级较高的城市会控制它。记住在早期，城市的文化积累是十分重要的，将文化值高的对手从某个区域中驱逐出去会更加困难。城市不能保证确定数量的区域；如果一个城市的文化大大超过其它的城市，它的范围可能会扩大到其它城市的近旁。由于城市只能在它控制范围之内取得产出，所以这可能极大地限制城市的成长，导致[LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]饥荒[\LINK]甚至可能叛离，投靠邻近的文明。请查看[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化[\LINK]词条了解详情。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]夺取敌方城市[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当你夺取了一座敌方城市，那个城市必须从头开始进行文化积累以扩张边界，而且此过程只能在该城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_RESISTANCE]“抵抗”[\LINK]停止之后开始。通常在征服者开始积累文化前，一个刚被占领的城市只控制很小的区域。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_BUILDINGS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Buildings[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]When first constructed, a [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]city[\LINK] is little more than a wide place in the road with several rude huts scattered about. In order for the new city to function effectively, you must construct "buildings" in it. Buildings serve a wide variety of purposes in Civilization IV - walls protect military units during combat, temples make the citizens happier, barracks train troops created in the city, markets increase a city's wealth, and so on. Determining which buildings to construct when - and balancing the need to improve your cities versus the need to create units - will often spell the difference between a successful, prospering civilization and a weak and helpless one.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]How to Produce Buildings[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Production Menu:[\BOLD] When a city has completed its current production and is ready to build something else, the "City Production Menu" will appear on the screen. This menu displays everything that the city can produce, and may include workers, settlers, military units, buildings, wonders, gold, and so forth. At the top of the menu are displayed two "recommended" items that the game itself thinks you might want to create - but you never have to follow these recommendations. If you are uncertain what to build, highlighting each item with the mouse will display information about what they do. Click on the item you want to produce: construction will begin immediately, and you will be informed when it is complete.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]On the City Screen:[\BOLD] The city screen appears when you double-click on a city on the main map. The city production menu appears at the bottom of this screen (in a different format from the pop-up menu above); double-click on the building you wish to produce. Moving the mouse over the different icons will provide more information about them here as well.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Building Availability[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Not all buildings are available for you to construct at the start of the game. Building availability is determined by a number of factors:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Tech Requirements[\BOLD]: Many buildings have "tech requirements" - that is, you have to have discovered a certain technology before you can build a particular building. For instance, you cannot build a Granary until you have learned the Pottery technology.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Location Requirements:[\BOLD] Some buildings can be only constructed in cities in certain locations. These are usually fairly obvious: harbors, for example, may be built only in coastal cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Previous Construction Requirements:[\BOLD] Certain buildings cannot be built in a city unless other buildings have been constructed first. A city must contain a market and a grocery before you can build a bank there.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Religious Requirements:[\BOLD] Some buildings have religious prerequisites. For example, you cannot build a temple in a city until that city has acquired religion.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Time to Produce[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The time to produce a building is dependent upon the city's production output (see [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK] for more details) and the production cost of the building itself. For instance, if a city with a production output of 20 begins work on a building with a production cost of 100, it will take that city 5 turns to complete the building.[PARAGRAPH:2]Other factors may speed the time of production. Some civilizations get bonuses when constructing certain buildings. And access to specific resources - copper, stone, marble - may speed production on certain buildings; for example, the Pyramids can be built much faster with the stone resource. Further, certain [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] affect building production times.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Maintenance Costs[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Unlike previous Civilization games, there are no maintenance costs associated with buildings in Civilization IV. Maintenance costs are attached instead to [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]cities[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Capturing Buildings[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When you capture a city, some of its buildings may be destroyed, but others may remain intact for your use. Captured buildings function just like other buildings.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]建筑[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在初建时，[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]只是散布于道路两旁的几座粗陋茅屋而已。为了使新建的城市有效地运作，你必须在城市中建造“建筑”。在文明IV中，建筑物有很多种用途——城墙在战争中提供保护，寺庙使市民更快乐。兵营训练在城市建立的军队，市场增加城市的健康度等等。决定在什么时候建造什么建筑，从而平衡展城市的和建立军队之间的需要，这些不同的选择常常导致一个成功强大的文明，或是一个弱小无助的文明。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]如何建造建筑[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市建设菜单:[\BOLD]当城市完成了当前的建设项目，准备开始下一项目时，城市建设菜单会出现在屏幕上。这个菜单显示了该城市现在可以建设的所有项目，包括工人，移民，军事单位，建筑物，奇观，财富等等。在菜单最上方有两个“推荐”项目，这是电脑认为你应当建设的，但是你可以作出自己的选择。如果你不确定建造什么，把鼠标移到每个选项上会显示关于它们效果的信息。点击你想要建造的项目：建设工程将立即开始，当它完成时将会有提示。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市界面:[\BOLD]双击主地图上的城市，可以进入城市界面。城市建设菜单在这个界面的下方（上文提到的弹出菜单的另一种形式）；双击你想要建造的建筑物。在这里把鼠标悬停在不同的图标上也会提供更多相关信息。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]建造可行性[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在游戏开始的时候，不是所有的建筑物都是可以建造的。建造的可行性取决于很多因素:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]科技前提[\BOLD]：许多建筑物有科技前提，就是说你必须获得相关的科技才能建造特定的建筑物。比如你只有在发现制陶之后才能建造粮仓。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]位置前提:[\BOLD]有些建筑物只能建造在处于某种特定位置的城市。这通常是相当显而易见的：比如海港，应当建造在沿海的城市。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]已有建筑前提:[\BOLD]某些建筑物只有在特定建筑物已经建造完成之后才能建造。例如一座城市必须已建有市场和杂货店才能建造银行。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]宗教前提:[\BOLD]有些建筑物需要特定的宗教。例如，城市必须存在某种宗教信仰才能建造寺庙。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]建造时间[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]建造一个建筑物的时间取决于城市的工业产出（详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]一节）和这个建筑物所需要的工业值。例如，一个城市要建造需100单位工业值的建筑，如城市工业产出为20，那么就需要5个回合完成这个建筑。[PARAGRAPH:2]另一些因素可以减少建造的时间。一些文明在建造某些建筑物时可以获得加成，获得特殊资源——铜、花岗石、大理石——可以加快某些建筑物的建造；例如，如果拥有花岗石资源，金字塔会建造得更快。此外，某些[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]也会影响建造的时间。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]维护费[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]与前代不同，文明IV中的维护费与建筑无关，而是与[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]数量相关联。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]占领建筑[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当你占领一座城市，某些城市建筑可能被摧毁，其它保存完好的则可以为你所用。被占领建筑物的作用和其它建筑物相同。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_CITIES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Cities[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities are vital to your civilization's success. They allow you to build units, buildings and wonders. They allow you to gain wealth and research new technologies. They allow you to dominate terrain. Given this importance Cities are fairly complex entities, and a good deal of your time will be spent on their maintenance and management. You cannot win without powerful, well-situated cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Building Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities are built by [LINK=UNIT_SETTLER]settler[\LINK] units. If the settler is in a place where a city can be built (see next), the "build city" action will appear in the settler's [LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]order box[\LINK]. Simply click on build city and the settler will disappear, to be replaced by the new city. At this time you will also be given the opportunity to name the city. [PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Where to Build Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A city's ultimate success or failure will depend greatly upon where it is constructed. Determining the best site is complex, and must take into account the availability of [LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]food[\LINK], [LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]production[\LINK], [LINK=CONCEPT_COMMERCE]commerce[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]resources[\LINK], your transportation network, and the proximity to friendly cities as well as to potential enemies. Though cities are usually sited to expand one's borders and to take the best advantage of local resources, a city may also be built for purely geopolitical reasons - to obstruct another civilization's expansion, for instance.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Where You Can't Build Cities [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities cannot be constructed within two spaces of another city. Cities cannot be constructed in impassable spaces. Cities cannot be built in another civilization's [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]territory[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2] [BOLD]Tips for Finding Good City Sites[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2] Consider building cities in the following locations:[PARAGRAPH:2]On or near [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]resources[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2]On or near rivers.[PARAGRAPH:2]On coastlines, especially on the mouths of rivers or near aquatic (water) resources.[PARAGRAPH:2] Near a variety of terrain types, including hills and grassland.[PARAGRAPH:2]About 4 to 5 spaces away from your existing cities. (This allows each city to access all spaces within their "city radius" (see below) with little or no overlap.[PARAGRAPH:2]Astride chokepoints. (It's often extremely useful to build cities to block other civs' expansion.)[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Capturing Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You can capture barbarian cities or cities belonging to civilizations that you are at war with. To do so you must enter the city with a military unit; this usually involves destroying the enemy units defending the city. When you capture an enemy city you have the option of destroying the city or installing a new governor. If the city has a population size of 1 or no culture, you will automatically destroy the city. If you choose to destroy the city, it and everything it contains is done away with. If you choose to install a new governor, the captured city will usually go through several turns of  [LINK=CONCEPT_RESISTANCE]resistance[\LINK] before joining your civilization.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]City Defenses[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities are defended from capture by the units inside them. Some units (see [LINK=UNIT_ARCHER]archers[\LINK]) get a defensive bonus (see [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]combat[\LINK]) when defending inside cities; this makes them particularly good choices for garrisons.[PARAGRAPH:2]In addition to the military units, you can construct a number of [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]buildings[\LINK] that enhance a city's defense: [LINK=BUILDING_WALLS]walls[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_CASTLE]castles[\LINK], and [LINK=BUILDING_BUNKER]bunkers[\LINK] , for example.[PARAGRAPH:2]Finally, a city with a high [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]cultural value[\LINK] will give a defensive bonus to the units defending the city.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]The City Screen[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]To get to a city's city screen, double-click on the city on the main map. You can also hold down the Shift key and click the city to select it. The city screen contains a number of important elements to aid you in managing the city. (See the city screen diagram in the manual for more information on the city screen's layout.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Unit List[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The unit list displays all of the units that currently occupy the city. You can activate a unit by clicking on its icon in this list.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Production Display[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The city production display tells you what is currently being produced in the city and the number of turns until completion.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Build Menu[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The city build menu contains all of the military units and buildings that can be constructed. You can change a city's current production by clicking on an item in the list. Buildings that appear greyed out have been unlocked but can not currently be built. Mouse over the grey building button to get popup help about why it can not be built.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Management Menu[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The city management menu has a variety of functions. It allows you to "hurry" city [LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]production[\LINK] (if you have the appropriate civics). It allows you to "automate" your city's production (see the manual for details). It allows you to tell your city to emphasize [LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]food[\LINK], [LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]production[\LINK], [LINK=CONCEPT_COMMERCE]commerce[\LINK], [LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]research[\LINK], the creation of [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]great people[\LINK], or force the governor to avoid growth.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Culture Display[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The culture display shows you how many [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]culture points[\LINK] your city is generating. It also tells you what your city's current cultural "rank" is. The ranks are poor, fledgling, developing, refined, influential, and legendary.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Building Roster[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The city building roster displays what buildings you have constructed in your city. The roster also displays how much culture, happiness, gold, production, and other assets the buildings provide. View the popup help for information on the special abilities the building performs.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Cultural Defense Bonus[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]This displays the cultural defense bonus your units get from the city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Nationality[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]This displays the nationality breakdown of the city: what percentage of the population is your nationality, and what percentage is other nationalities. Cities with high foreign nationalities are more likely to [LINK=CONCEPT_RESISTANCE]revolt[\LINK] and "flip" to that nationality, and they suffer greater [LINK=CONCEPT_WAR_WEARINESS]war weariness[\LINK] unhappiness if you go to war against that nationality.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Maintenance[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]This displays the city's current [LINK=CONCEPT_MAINTENANCE]maintenance[\LINK] cost to your civilization.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Religion List[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]This tells you what religions are present in the city, and what percentage of the population worships each.[PARAGRAPH:2]The following two bars are also located on the city bar that appears on the main map.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Food Bar[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]This shows you how much food your city currently has in storage, and how long until the city's population expands.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Production Bar[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]This shows you how much production your city currently has in storage, and how long the current production assignment will take.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Health and Happiness Displays[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]These displays show you how [LINK=CONCEPT_HEALTH]healthy[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]happy[\LINK] your city is.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Trade Income List[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]This displays any cities that this city is regularly trading with, and the income the city is getting from that trade.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Specialist Display[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]This shows you if any of your population has been assigned to be a [LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]specialist[\LINK] and how many specialist slots are still open.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Resource Box[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]resource box[\LINK] displays what resources your city has access to - including local, national, and trade-based resources.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]The City Map[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]In the center of the city screen is the "city map." It displays your city in the center and the "city radius" - the area around your city that your city's population can work. (See below for more details on the city radius.) The map shows which of the squares are currently being worked - these are indicated by circles around the square.[PARAGRAPH:2]If given no particular orders, a city will assign its populace to work squares that provide it a balanced supply of commerce, food and production. You can change the city's priorities by clicking on entries in the [BOLD]City Management Menu[\BOLD] (see above). Clicking a circled city square stops the population from working the square and places them in the [BOLD]Specialist Display[\BOLD] as a [LINK=SPECIALIST_CITIZEN]citizen[\LINK]. If a citizen is available you can then click on any square in the [BOLD]city radius[\BOLD] to start working it. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Radius[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]As described above, the "city radius" represents the area around the city that the city's population can "work." When first created, a city radius consists of the city's square and the nine adjacent squares. When a city's culture grows enough to expand the city's [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]borders[\LINK], the city's radius will expand as well. The radius expands one space in each direction, except the direct diagonal spaces, resulting in a "fat cross" shaped radius. (See the manual for a diagram.) [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Foreign Borders and City Radii[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]A nearby civilization's borders may extend into the squares that would normally be part of the city's radius. Spaces under foreign control cannot be worked and they are not part of a city radius.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]We Love the King Day![\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities of size 8 and higher which have no unhappy citizens and no food loss to health can enter "We Love the King Day!" from time to time. The effect is that the city pays no maintenance for one turn.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]城市[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]城市与你的文明之成败息息相关。城市可以建造单位，建筑物和奇观，为你赚取金钱，研究科技，控制地域。城市的地位非常重要，是一种相当复杂的实体，你会花大量的时间来维护和管理它们。没有强大的而位置良好的城市，就无法赢得胜利。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]建立城市[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]城市由[LINK=UNIT_SETTLER]移民[\LINK]建立。如果移民处在可以建立城市的地域（见下文），“建立城市”选项将出现在移民的[LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]命令清单[\LINK]中。只需点击“建立城市”，移民就会消失，取而代之的是一座新的城市。这时你可以命名这座城市。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]城市的选址[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]一个城市最终的成败在很大程度上取决于建城的地点。决定最佳的地点需要考虑复杂的因素，要能取得[LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]食物产出[\LINK]，[LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]工业产能[\LINK]，[LINK=CONCEPT_COMMERCE]商业收入[\LINK]和[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]奖励资源[\LINK]，你的交通网络，与友好城市和潜在敌人之间的距离。虽然城市通常位于能扩展国界和最大程度地从当地的资源中取得好处，但是一个城市的建立也可能出于纯粹的地理原因——例如为了阻碍其它文明的扩张。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]不能建城的位置[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]在距离其它城市两格之内不能建城。城市不能建在无法通行的地方，不能在其它文明的[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]领土[\LINK]范围内建城。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]寻找建城地点的小技巧[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]考虑在以下位置建立城市:[PARAGRAPH:2]处于或邻近[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2]处于或临近河流。[PARAGRAPH:2]处于海滨，特别是河口或邻近水产资源。[PARAGRAPH:2]附近存在多种地形，包括丘陵和草原。[PARAGRAPH:2]距离你的现有城市4至5格。（这将允许每个城市各自取得“城市范围”（见下文）内的空间而不至相互重叠。[PARAGRAPH:2]控制战略要地。（在能阻止其他文明扩张的位置建立城市将非常有效.）[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]占领城市[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以占领野蛮人的城市，或你正与之交战的文明所拥有的城市。你必须有军事单位进入城市才能做到这一点；这通常需要消灭守城的敌军。当你占领一个敌人的城市时，你可以选择摧毁或者任命新市长。如果城市人口规模只有1或者没有文化积累，会自动被摧毁。如果选择摧毁城市，那么它和它所包括的一切都将不复存在。如果任命一位新市长，这个城市通需要经历数回合的[LINK=CONCEPT_RESISTANCE]抵抗[\LINK]才会融入你的文明。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]城市防御[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]城市凭借其中的单位抵御进攻者。某些单位（如[LINK=UNIT_ARCHER]弓手[\LINK]）在保卫城市时拥有防御加成（见[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]战斗[\LINK]）；这使他们特别适用于守卫城市。[PARAGRAPH:2]除了军事单位，你可以修建各种[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]加强城防:[LINK=BUILDING_WALLS]城墙[\LINK]，[LINK=BUILDING_CASTLE]城堡[\LINK]，和[LINK=BUILDING_BUNKER]地堡[\LINK]等等。[PARAGRAPH:2]最后，拥有高[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化值[\LINK]的城市可为守城单位提供防御奖励。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]城市界面[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]要进入城市界面,在大地图上双击城市即可。也可以按住Shift键并点击城市。城市界面包含了大量重要的信息，它可以帮助你管理城市。（查看手册中的城市界面图表了解详情.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]单位清单[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]单位清单显示了当前驻扎在城市中的所有单位。你可通过点击它在清单中的图标来激活一个单位。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市生产信息[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]城市生产信息告诉你当前城市正在建设的项目以及完成项目所需要的回合数。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市建设菜单[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]城市建设菜单包含了所有你可以建设的军事单位和建筑物，可以通过点击菜单中的选项来改变当前的生产。呈灰色的建筑物表明你可能建造但目前无法建造。把鼠标移动到灰色建筑上弹出的帮助信息会告诉你不能建造的原因。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市管理菜单[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]城市管理菜单有多种功能。它允许你“加速”城市[LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]建设[\LINK]（如果实行相应的内政法令）。它允许你“自动”管理城市建设（查看手册了解详情）。它允许你命令城市专注于[LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]食物[\LINK]，[LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]工业[\LINK]，[LINK=CONCEPT_COMMERCE]商业[\LINK]，[LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]科研[\LINK]，产生[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]，或命令市长避免人口成长。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]文化信息[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]文化信息告诉你城市所积累的[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化点数[\LINK]。它也告诉你城市当前的文化“等级”。城市文化分贫乏可怜、初步成形、正在发展、精致优雅、影响深远以及辉煌永恒六个等级。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市建筑选项[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]城市建筑选项显示城市中所有你已经建造的建筑物。它也显示文化值、快乐度、金钱、生产和建筑提供的其它效果。查看弹出的浮动提示了解各建筑的作用。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市文化的防御奖励[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]这显示你的单位从城市文化等级所获得的防御奖励。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市的民族构成[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]它显示了城市居民的民族构成：总人口多少属于本民族，多少属于其他民族。如果城市的外来民族过多，就容易[LINK=CONCEPT_RESISTANCE]暴乱[\LINK]并“叛离”到其他文明，并在与该文明发生战争时增加因[LINK=CONCEPT_WAR_WEARINESS]厌战情绪[\LINK]而导致的不满。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市维护费[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]这显示了你的文明为城市所支出的[LINK=CONCEPT_MAINTENANCE]维护费[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]宗教清单[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]这显示城市中现有的宗教，以及各宗教信徒所占人口比例。[PARAGRAPH:2]下面的两个信息栏也同时会在大地图的城市信息栏中显示。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]食物信息栏[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]这显示当前积存的食物，以及城市将在多久之后再次成长。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]生产信息栏[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]这显示了当前积累的工业产能，以及城市将在多久之后完成当前工程。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]健康度与快乐度信息[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]这显示城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_HEALTH]健康[\LINK]和[LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]快乐[\LINK]程度。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]贸易收入清单[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]显示所有与你贸易的城市，以及从贸易中获得的收入。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]专业人员信息[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]这显示你的人口中有多少转化为[LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]专业人员[\LINK]以及还有多少可用专业人员空位。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]资源列表[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源列表[\LINK]显示城市获取的资源，包括本地的，本国的和来自于贸易的资源。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市地图[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]城市界面的中央是“城市地图.”显示城市及其“城市范围”——即城市人口可以工作的区域范围。（城市范围详情见下文.）地图显示正在工作的区域——以圆环标示的方格。[PARAGRAPH:2]如果没有特别的指令，城市人口工作的区域会平均化地提供商业，食物和工业产出。你可以点击[BOLD]城市管理菜单[\BOLD]（见上文）中的选项调整城市的专注目标。点击一个圆环标示的区域将终止人口在其上工作，并将该人口移至[BOLD]专业人员信息[\BOLD]成为[LINK=SPECIALIST_CITIZEN]普通市民[\LINK]。如果有可用市民，点击[BOLD]城市范围[\BOLD]内的空白区域使其开始在区域中工作。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市范围[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如上文所述，“城市范围”代表城市周围可由城市居民“工作”的地方，在初建时，城市范围包括城市所在方格及周围相邻的九个方格。随着城市文化的积累，城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]边界[\LINK]将逐渐扩张，城市范围随之扩展。城市半径每次扩大一格，对角线方向除外，最终形成一个“胖十字架”形的范围。（查看手册了解详情）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]国家边界与城市范围[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]邻近文明的边界可能扩展到原属城市范围的区域。处于外国控制下的区域将不能工作，不再属于城市范围。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]我们爱国王日！[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]规模8或更大的城市如果没有不满的市民，也没有因缺乏食物而降低健康度，将不时举行“我们爱国王日！”活动。其作用是免除城市在该回合的维护费。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_CITY_NETWORK_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]City Network[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]To work at peak efficiency, all of your cities should be linked together in a "trade network" (symbolized by [ICON_TRADE]). This allows the cities to receive the full benefits of your civilization's resources - both domestic resources and those received through trade.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Elements of the City Network[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Your city network can be made up of roads and railroads, rivers, coastal squares, and ocean squares.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Roads and Railroads[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities may be linked together by road and railroads, as long as the road/rails stay within your borders or neutral territory. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Rivers[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities on the same river are linked together as long as the river between them stays within your borders or in neutral territory.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Coastal Squares[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities on the coast are linked together as long as the coastline between them stays within your borders or in neutral territory and you have the [LINK=TECH_SAILING]Sailing[\LINK] technology.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Ocean Squares[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities can always connect via ocean squares in your territory. If the ocean squares are in neutral territory, then you need the [LINK=TECH_ASTRONOMY]Astronomy[\LINK] technology in order to use them in your network.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Combined Networks[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Your network may consist of a combination of the above types of links. City A may link to City B via coastal waters. Then City B links to City C via road. City C links with City D via river. And so on. In the above example, all of the cities are linked.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Resources and the City Network[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]In order for resources to be shared by multiple cities, they must be connected by road, rail, or river to a city network - then, all cities on that network share the resource.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Trading Resources[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]All resource trade must go through your capital city. If you wish to trade one of your resources to another civilization, then that resource must be connected to the capital city via a network link. If you receive a resource in trade from another civilization, that resource is assumed to be in your capital city. Only cities that are connected to your capital can enjoy the benefits of that resource.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Connection to the City Network[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities that are connected to the city network will have the [ICON_TRADE] symbol displayed next to them on the world map. If this icon does not appear next to one of your cities, it is not sharing in the benefits of the rest of your civilization![PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]城市网络[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]要获得最大的效益，你的所有城市必须联成一个“贸易网络”（用[ICON_TRADE]图标表示）。这可使所有城市均能获得奖励资源带来的收益——包括本国资源和通过对外贸易获得的资源。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]城市网络的要素[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你的城市网络可通过道路，铁路，河流，海滨和大洋联接。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]道路与铁路[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]城市之间可通过道路与铁路相连，只要其处于本国领土或中立区域之内。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]河流[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]与同一条河流相邻的城市可相互联通，只要其处于本国领土或中立区域之内。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]海滨区块[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]处于海滨的城市可相互联通，只要海滨区块属于本国领海或中立区域之内，并且已获得[LINK=TECH_SAILING]航行术[\LINK]科技。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大洋区块[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]城市可以由属于本国领海的大洋相互联通。如果大洋区块为中立区域，则需要获得[LINK=TECH_ASTRONOMY]天文学[\LINK]科技。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]复合网络[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你的城市网络可以由多种联接方式构成。例如A城与B城通过海滨相连。B与C城通过道路相连。C城与D城通过河流相接，如此等等。在上述例子中，所有城市均已连入网络。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]资源与城市网络[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]要使资源能为多个城市所利用，必须通过道路，铁路或河流等连入城市网络——这样网络中的所有城市便可共享资源。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]资源贸易[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]所有对外资源贸易都必须通过首都进行。如果你希望同其他文明开展资源贸易，则资源必须与首都相连。如果你从其他文明获得一种资源，则视同你的首都拥有该种资源。只有与你的首都相连的城市才能享受该种资源。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]连接城市网络[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]连入城市网络的城市将在大地图上显示[ICON_TRADE]图标。如果你的某个城市没有这个图标，说明它没有享受到文明所共同拥有的利益![PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_CIVICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Civics[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Civics represent the various forms of government available in Civilization IV. Are you a despot or a king, a democratically-elected ruler or a theocrat? Does your civilization have open markets or closed? Do you have trial by jury, or trial by fire? These and other possibilities are available to you.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects in Play[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The civics you choose to employ have a great effect upon the character and success of your civilization. Some civics increase your cities' productivity. Others increase their wealth. Some civics make it easier to create and maintain standing armies. Others help you to export your religions to other nations. There are no "best" civics in the game: all are potentially very useful in different situations.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]The Civics Screen[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Go to the Civics Screen to review your current civics, to see which other civics are available to you, and to learn about other as-yet undiscovered civics.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Acquiring Civics[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You begin play with the most primitive civics: despotism, tribalism, and so forth. You acquire other civics through technological advances: the Hereditary Rule civic requires that your civilization master the Monarchy technology, for example, while Mercantilism requires Banking. (In addition, the [LINK=BUILDING_PYRAMID]Pyramids[\LINK] wonder makes all "government" civics available.)[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Categories of Civics[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There are five different categories of civics, each controlling a certain aspect of your civilization: Government, Legal, Labor, Economy, and Religion.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Upkeep[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Each civic type has an "upkeep" cost associated with it: no upkeep, low upkeep, medium upkeep, and high upkeep. This represents the relative amount of gold that your civilization must pay each turn to employ that civic. In general, the more useful a civic is, the higher its upkeep. The actual cost in gold per turn of civics varies according to the size of your civilization: the more cities you have and the larger your population, the higher the upkeep cost for any and all civics.[PARAGRAPH:2]If you are considering changing a civic, go to the Civics Screen. Check the Upkeep/Turn value on this screen - it represents your current ongoing civic outlay - then click on the civic you are considering. The Upkeep/Turn value will change to show what your upkeep will become if you change to that civic.[PARAGRAPH:2]Be careful about changing over to civics with high upkeep costs; they are often powerful, but can put a real strain on your treasury. Some civics may be desirable simply because they have no upkeep cost![PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Changing Civics[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When you acquire a new civic, a screen will pop up asking if you want to change civics. At any other time you want to change civics, you need to go to the Civics Screen by clicking on the icon in the top-right corner of the screen. Once on the Civics screen, click on the civic or civics you want to change to, then click on the "Revolution" button in the bottom-right corner. You may experience a period of "anarchy" (see below); when that passes you will be employing your new civics. (If you decide to keep things as they are and not change any civics, click on "Exit Screen" rather than "Revolution.")[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Revolution[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Changing civics can be difficult for your loyal citizens, particularly if you are changing multiple civics at once. Your civilization may undergo a number of turns of "anarchy," during which chaos will reign: your citizens will cease gathering food, treasure, and production materials, and your cities will halt production and your income may well plummet precipitously. Your units will still respond to orders. Eventually things will settle down and return to order. When contemplating changing civics, go to the Civics Screen and click on the civics you would like to change to. The "Turns for Revolution" display will tell you how long the anarchy will last once you begin the Revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2]Incidentally, certain civilizations are immune from anarchy: they can change civics any time they want without suffering any disruption.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Delay Period[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There is a delay period after changing civics before you can carry out another revolution. Your citizens can only change from one system of rule to another so often! Be aware before changing civics that you will have to wait a couple turns before being able to switch them again, should you not like the result.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]内政法令[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]文明IV中的内政法令代表不同的政府体制。你是一位专制君主还是一位封建国王，是一位民主选举的元首还是政教合一的领袖？你的国家实行市场开放还是设置贸易壁垒？是实行陪审制度还是继续保留火刑？所有这些都可以由你来选择。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]对游戏的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你所选择的内政法令对文明的兴衰具有重要的影响。有的内政法令可提升城市的生产力。有的可增加财富。有的更便于组建和维持常备军。还有的更便于你向别国传播你的宗教信仰。游戏中并不存在“最佳的”内政组合：不同选项可在不同情况下更好地发挥作用。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]内政法令界面[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在内政法令界面可查看当前的内政组合，并了解其他可用及尚不可用的内政法令信息。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]获得可用内政法令[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏开始时你只能采用最原始的内政法令：专制制度，部落分工等等。其他内政法令需要获得相应科技后才能启用：例如，世袭制度需要君主制科技，重商主义需要银行科技。（此外，建造[LINK=BUILDING_PYRAMID]大金字塔[\LINK]奇观将启用所有“政府体制”类内政法令.）[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]内政法令的分类[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]内政法令分为五种类型，每种类型反映文明在某一领域的制度：政府体制，法律制度，劳工制度，经济制度和宗教制度。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]内政经费[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]每种内政法令都所需的“内政经费”支出水平：包括无经费，较低经费，中等经费和较高水平。表示实行某种内政法令每回合需要支出的金钱数量。总的说来，效率越高的内政法令，经费水平也越高。每回合实际支出的内政经费还受文明规模的影响：城市数量越多，人口规模越大，内政经费额度越高。[PARAGRAPH:2]如果你要改变内政法令，可打开内政法令界面。先查看其中的内政经费/回合数值——这表示当前的内政经费支出水平——然后点击要采用的内政法令。内政经费/回合数值将即时调整以反映改变后的支出水平。[PARAGRAPH:2]在采用高经费水平的内政法令时要特别注意；虽然它们具有很高的效率，但也可能消耗大量国库储备。有时为了节省金钱，不得不采用无须经费的内政法令![PARAGRAPH:2][H2]改变内政法令[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当有新的内政法令可选时，将弹出一个对话框询问你是否希望改变内政法令。在其他情况下要改变内政法令，你点击屏幕右上角的相应按钮需要打开内政法令界面。在其中点击你希望采用的内政法令，然后点击右下角的“革命”按钮。你可能要经历一段时间的“无政府状态”（见下文）；无政府状态结束后新内政法令将开始实行。（如果你不希望改变内政法令，请点击“退出”按钮）[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]革命[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]改变内政法令会使臣民们感到一时无法接受，特别是同时改变多项内政法令时。你的文明可能进入几个回合的“无政府状态”，国家将陷入混乱：市民停止进行农业，商业和工业生产，城市建设项目将停滞不前，收入急剧下降。但你仍可指挥单位。最终局势会恢复平静。当你想要改变内政法令时，在内政法令中点击你希望采用的内政法令。将可查看“革命持续时间”预先了解改变将造成的结果。[PARAGRAPH:2]此外，某些文明对是革命免疫的：他们可随意改变内政法令而无须经历无政府状态。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]延迟时期[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]改变内政法令之后会存在一段延迟时期，期间无法再次发动革命。你的臣民无法承受过于频繁的法令更改！如果希望再次改变内政法令，需要等待延迟时期结束。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_COMBAT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Combat[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Conflict is an integral part of human history. For as long as there have been people, there has been conflict. At first this conflict was individual - where one man fought another for food, or water, or because the first man didn't like the way the second man looked at his mate. But as human society has advanced in organization and sophistication, so has conflict. When men organized in tribes, they fought other tribes. Once the tribe's group of huts became a city, the citizens of opposing cities spent much time, effort, and energy beating each other up. And so on, up to today, when nations fight other nations on land, sea, air, and (soon) in space.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]When Combat Occurs[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Combat occurs whenever a unit attempts to enter a space occupied by a "hostile" unit. Barbarians and animals are always hostile; other civilizations' units are only hostile if you are at [LINK=CONCEPT_WAR]War[\LINK] with them. Unlike previous Civilization games, your units can occupy the same tile as foreign units if you are in neutral territory or have an [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Open Borders[\LINK] agreement. (But see special rules for air units and invisible units.)[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Combat Strength[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Each unit in the game has a "combat strength." When one unit fights another, the computer applies any combat strength modifiers to the units' combat strengths and then determines the odds for the combat.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Injured Units[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If a unit is injured when combat begins, the computer uses the unit's injured combat strength to determine the odds.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Combat Strength Modifiers[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A variety of things can modify a unit's combat strength. Modifications are listed as percentage bonuses. If the unit gets more than one combat modifier, all modifiers are added together and then applied. (Example: a unit gets a 50%% terrain bonus and a 25%% bonus for experience. The two percentages are added together and then applied, giving the unit a final bonus of 75%%.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Bonuses for Combat vs. Particular Units[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Some units get bonuses when fighting particular units. A [LINK=UNIT_SPEARMAN]Spearman[\LINK] for instance gets a 100%% bonus when fighting a mounted unit. Healthy spearmen have strengths of 4; when fighting [LINK=UNIT_HORSE_ARCHER]Horse Archers[\LINK] units their strength is increased to 8.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Terrain Defensive Bonuses[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]Terrain[\LINK] gives bonuses to many (but not all) units. A spearman being attacked while occupying a forested hillside gets a 75%% bonus, raising his combat strength from 4 to 7. Units also get bonuses for defending against units attacking across rivers.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Defense Bonuses[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Certain units get bonuses for defending in cities. City buildings like [LINK=BUILDING_WALLS]Walls[\LINK] provide bonuses except against gunpowder units. Culturally-advanced cities give defending units [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cultural Defensive Bonuses[\LINK], as well.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Fortification Bonuses[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Each turn that a unit is fortified on the same square, it gains a 5%% bonus to its strength, up to a maximum of 25%%. As soon as the unit moves to another tile, this fortification bonus is lost.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Promotion Bonuses[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Experienced units may receive bonuses from [LINK=CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS]Promotions[\LINK]. Promotions may add to overall strength or add to a unit's strength under particular circumstances (such as against certain unit types or when defending in certain terrains, etc.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Examples[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]These combat strength modifiers can make a very significant difference when they are added together. A [LINK=UNIT_MACEMAN]Maceman[\LINK] with combat strength 8 will almost always defeat an [LINK=UNIT_EXPLORER]Explorer[\LINK] of strength 4 without modifiers, but the odds can change drastically under the right circumstances. If the Explorer is fully fortified (+25%%) on a forested hill tile (+75%%) and possesses the Guerilla II (+50%% on hills) and Woodsman II (+50%% in forests) promotions, the Explorer suddenly has his strength increased 200%% to 12 overall! The Maceman may be in for an unpleasant surprise if he tries to attack.[PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_ARCHER]Archers[\LINK] and [LINK=UNIT_LONGBOWMAN]Longbowmen[\LINK] are difficult to dislodge from cities for the same reason. Archers get a natural 25%% city defense bonus, which can be further improved with City Garrison promotions, and can also take advantage of a city's defensive bonus from walls and/or culture. An archer that is fully fortified (+25%%) in a city with walls (+50%%) and has the City Garrison I promotion (+45%% total city defense) will have a strength not of 3, but of 6.6! This is the reason why those pesky archers can defeat more powerful units like Horse Archers when they are protecting cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Combat Odds[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]At the beginning of a combat, the computer determines the combat strengths of each unit (see above) and then determines the odds for the combat. If two units of equal modified combat strength battle, each unit has a 50-50 chance of winning each combat "round" (see below) and inflicting damage on its opponent. If  one unit's modified combat strength is twice that of the opposing unit, the stronger unit has a 2-to-1 chance of winning each round and inflicting damage on its opponent.[PARAGRAPH:2]Note that the combat odds determined at the opening of combat remain throughout the entire combat. Odds are not updated to reflect damage inflicted during a round.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Combat Rounds[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Combat is fought in rounds. During each round the computer makes a random "combat check" against the odds, and the losing side takes damage. Combat continues until a unit is destroyed or "withdraws" from combat (see below).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Damage Amounts[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The amount of damage that can be inflicted in a round is determined by the combat odds. If two equal units fight, the losing unit takes 20%% damage per round. (In this type of battle, the first unit that loses five rounds will have taken 100%% damage and thus will be destroyed.) If one unit's strength is bigger than the other, the bigger inflicts proportionately more damage when it wins a round, while the smaller inflicts less.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Victory or Defeat[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If the defending unit wins the combat, the attacking unit is destroyed. If the attacking unit wins, the defender is destroyed. If the space is now vacant, the attacker moves into the space. If other units still occupy the space, the attacker remains where it was when it launched the attack. If one unit is destroyed, the surviving unit gains experience (see [LINK=CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS]Promotions[\LINK]).[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]战斗[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]整个人类历史始终伴随着武装冲突。武装冲突自有人类以来即已发生。起初此类冲突只是个体行为——一个人对另一个人拳脚相向，可能是为了争夺食物，水源，或是因为他不喜欢那个人看他的伴侣的眼神。随着人类社会日益组织化和复杂化，冲突的形式也不断发展。当人类开始结成部落，部落之间时起冲突。当部落村庄发展为城市，敌对城市之间不断争战。直到今天，国家和国家之间仍在陆地，海洋，天空，以及（即将）在外层空间中展开武力争夺。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]战斗的发生[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当一个单位试图进入“敌对”单位所占据的区域，就会发生战斗。蛮族和野兽必然是敌对的；其他文明的单位则在与你发生[LINK=CONCEPT_WAR]战争[\LINK]是敌对的。与前代游戏不同，你的单位可以与异国单位处于同一区块，只要是在中立区域或双方签有[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]开放边界[\LINK]条约。（但空中单位与隐形单位有特殊规则.）[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]战斗力[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏每个单位都具有“战斗力”数值。双方进行战斗时，电脑将根据单位基准战斗力和一系列修正因子计算双方的胜率。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]受损的单位[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果单位在战斗时受损，电脑将根据受损的战斗力计算双方的胜率。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]战斗力修正因子[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]许多因素能够影响单位的战斗力。修正因素将显示为百分比加成。如果单位受多个战斗力修正因子影响，所有百分比将累加计算。（例如：某个单位拥有50%%的地形加成和25%%的经验加成。两个百分比将累加计算，单位最终获得的加成为75%%.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]对特定类型单位的战斗奖励加成[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]某些单位在对特定类型单位的获得奖励加成。例如[LINK=UNIT_SPEARMAN]矛兵[\LINK]对骑乘单位拥有100%%加成。一个满员的矛兵单位战斗力为4；在对[LINK=UNIT_HORSE_ARCHER]骑射手[\LINK]单位时其战斗力将升至8。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]地形防御奖励加成[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]地形[\LINK]能为许多（但不是所有）单位提供奖励加成。矛兵如果在覆盖有森林的丘陵地带遭受攻击，将获得75%%加成，使其战斗力从4升至7。单位在遭受河流对岸单位攻击时也可获得奖励加成。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城防加成[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]某些单位在防守城市时可获得奖励加成。某些城市建筑例如[LINK=BUILDING_WALLS]城墙[\LINK]也能提供防御加成（对火器单位除外）。文化等级高的城市还能为防御单位提供[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]文化防御奖励加成[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]驻防奖励加成[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]一个单位在同一区块驻防，每一回合将获得5%%的防御加成，此加成上限为25%%。一旦该单位移至其他区块，此加成将消失。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]晋升奖励加成[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]富有经验的单位可通过[LINK=CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS]晋升[\LINK]获得奖励加成。晋升可能提升单位整体战斗力，或是在特定环境下的战斗力（例如针对特定单位类型或防御特定地形等等.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]实例[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]所有战斗力修正因子在累加后可能极大提升单位战斗力。一个[LINK=UNIT_MACEMAN]钉锤手[\LINK]单位的基准战斗力为8，在没有修正因素影响的情况下几乎肯定能击败一个战斗力为4的[LINK=UNIT_EXPLORER]探险家[\LINK]，但在特定环境下，胜负几率可能发生极大变化。如果探险家充分驻防（+25%%），位于覆盖有森林的丘陵（+75%%），拥有游击二级（在丘陵+50%%）及林地二级（在森林+50%%）晋升，则探险家的实际战斗力将增长200%%，达到12！钉锤手如果发动进攻恐怕凶多吉少。[PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_ARCHER]弓手[\LINK]和[LINK=UNIT_LONGBOWMAN]长弓手[\LINK]非常适于防守城市也是由于这些修正因子。弓手天然可获得25%%的城防加成，还可加上城防类晋升，还可加上来自城墙和文化等级的奖励。如果一个弓手单位充分驻防（+25%%），占据有城墙的城市（+50%%），拥有城防一级晋升（城防水平+45%%），其战斗力将不再是3，而是6.6！这就是弓手能在防守城市时击败强大得多的骑射手等单位的原因。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]战斗胜率[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在战斗开始时，电脑将根据双方单位的实际战斗力（见上文）计算战斗的胜负几率。如果双方单位战斗力相当，则双方在一个战斗“轮次”（见下）中成功打击对方的几率就是50-50。如果一方战斗力为对方的两倍，该单位每轮成功打击对方的几率就是2-1。[PARAGRAPH:2]注意战斗胜率在整个战斗持续过程中保持初始值。而不会每个轮次更新以反映双方的损伤状况。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]战斗轮次[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]一场战斗可分为多个轮次。每个轮次电脑将根据双方胜率随机进行“战果判断”，负方将遭受损伤。战斗将持续到一方被消灭或“撤退”为止（见下文）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]损伤程度[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]单位在一个轮次中可能遭受的损伤程度由双方胜率决定。如果双方战斗力相等，负方每轮将遭受20%%损伤。（在此情况下，首先遭受五轮失败的单位将被消灭.）如果一方战斗力强于对方，则赢得一轮可给对方更大的损伤，输掉一轮则遭受的损伤也较小。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]战斗的胜负[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果防御方赢得整场战斗，进攻方将被消灭。如果进攻方获胜，防御方将被消灭。如果防御方区块再无守军，进攻方将移至该区块。如果该区块仍有守军，进攻方将留在原地。如果一个单位被消灭，获胜的单位将获得经验值（见[LINK=CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS]晋升[\LINK]）。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_COMMERCE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Commerce[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Commerce is the lifeblood of a civilization. It allows you to pay for your cities, and for the people and buildings inside them. Commerce lets you maintain standing armies. It lets you purchase trade goods from other civilizations, and it can also let you bribe those civilizations to keep them from grinding you into a pulp. Money matters.[PARAGRAPH:2]See [LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]Wealth[\LINK] for an in-depth look at money in Civilization IV.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Commerce Summary[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Generating Commerce:[\BOLD] Your civilization generates commerce when your citizens work the lands around your [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK]. Tiles that bring in commerce are represented by a coin icon on the city screen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Terrain:[\BOLD] Some [LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]Terrain-Types[\LINK] generate more commerce than others. Water tiles and the land next to rivers tend to generate the most commerce.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Improvements:[\BOLD] Your [LINK=UNIT_WORKER]Workers[\LINK] can [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Improve[\LINK] land to make it generate additional commerce. The [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COTTAGE]Cottage[\LINK] improvements are one of the best ways to bring in more commerce.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Resources:[\BOLD] Some [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK] also provide commerce, once improved and connected to your cities. Gems, gold, and incense in particular are worth a great deal of commerce.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Buildings and Wonders:[\BOLD] Constructing certain [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Buildings[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK] can increase commerce in a city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Trade:[\BOLD] You can [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Negotiate[\LINK] trade deals (particularly [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Open Borders[\LINK]) to increase commerce.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Expending Commerce:[\BOLD] You spend your money in a variety of different ways. See [LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]Wealth[\LINK] for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]商业[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]商业是文明活力的源泉。商业收入可用以支付城市维护费，以及居民生活和建设事业的日常花销。商业收入使你能够维持常备军队。使你能够与其他文明进行交易，还使你能够贿赂其他文明，以避免卷入更大的麻烦。[PARAGRAPH:2]关于文明IV中金钱概念的详情可见[LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]财富[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]商业概念[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]创造商业收入:[\BOLD]当你的市民在[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]及周围区域工作时将创造商业收入。能创造商业收入的区域在城市界面中将显示金币图标。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]地形:[\BOLD]有的[LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]地形[\LINK]能创造更多的商业收入。水域和与河流相邻的区域具有最大的商业价值。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]区域设施:[\BOLD]你的[LINK=UNIT_WORKER]工人[\LINK]可以[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]改造[\LINK]地形以产生额外的商业收入。修建[LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COTTAGE]农舍[\LINK]设施是创造商业收入的最佳途径之一。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]资源:[\BOLD]某些[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]也能带来额外商业收入，前提是建有相应设施并连接到你的城市。其中宝石，黄金和薰香具有极高的商业价值。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]建筑与奇观:[\BOLD]建造某些[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]与[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]可能提升城市的商业收入。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]贸易:[\BOLD]你可以通过贸易[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]谈判[\LINK]（特别是[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]开放边界[\LINK]协议）拓展商业。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]商业收入的支出:[\BOLD]需要支出金钱的场合很多。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]财富[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_CULTURE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Culture[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]In Civilization IV, "culture" refers to a civilization's accomplishments in literature, the arts, and so forth. Civilizations with high cultures are respected or envied by lesser civilizations. These civilizations tend to intellectually dominate their neighbors, which can be very useful when two civilizations are striving for control over limited terrain.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Generating Culture[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Culture is generated in [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK], and each city has its own cultural value. A new city, containing just a few citizens intent more upon survival than on anything else, generates very little culture. But once the city grows and begins to construct [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Buildings[\LINK] dedicated to religion, arts, literature, and so on, its cultural output will increase. The city can further increase its cultural output by creating certain [LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]Specialists[\LINK], as well as by using [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great People[\LINK]. However, the greatest increase in culture can be gained through the construction of [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Culture Button[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Once you have discovered the [LINK=TECH_DRAMA]Drama[\LINK] technology, you can devote a certain percentage of your civilization's commerce to culture using the Culture Button. This can allow you to create culture in cities that have no buildings in them (although it may be expensive to do so!) The Culture Button also provides [LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]Happiness[\LINK] in addition to culture; see the related Civilopedia entry for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Building Culture[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]After discovering the [LINK=TECH_MUSIC]Music[\LINK] technology, you can devote a city's production to the creation of culture. The city will not build anything, but it will produce culture.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Culture and City Defense[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]People fight harder when defending particularly holy, beautiful, or otherwise culturally-important cities. To reflect this, cities with high cultures get a "city defense bonus." This bonus increases as the city's culture grows. See [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]Combat[\LINK] for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Culture and Borders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A city's cultural value determines the size of the land it dominates. See [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Borders[\LINK] for details on this important effect.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Cultural Conversion of Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If a culturally-superior city is near to another civilization's city which has little going for it culture-wise, the superior city will tend to dominate the inferior. This usually results in the superior city gaining control over the land between the two cities, and sometimes of all the land surrounding the inferior city. This can lead to starvation and, in extreme cases, of the inferior citizens [LINK=CONCEPT_REVOLUTION]Revolting[\LINK] from their civilization and joining the superior city's civilization.[PARAGRAPH:2]A city must revolt twice before it flips to the dominating civilization's control. The first time that the city revolts, it will eventually return to the original owner's control. The owner may then try to pump up the city's culture to avoid a second revolution: but if the owner is unsuccessful and the city revolts again, it will flip and join the dominant civilization's empire. When a city "flips" to your control, you automatically gain all of that city's buildings and great wonders, making this a far more profitable (if perhaps less satisfying) way of conquering a city than through direct force of arms.[PARAGRAPH:2]There is one exception to the above rule about cultural conversion: a city that has been captured militarily will never flip back to its original owner, no matter how much cultural pressure the original owner brings to bear (although it may be near-useless to the conqueror due to constant revolts).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Barbarian Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Barbarian cities have cultural values just like other cities. They too can be converted through cultural dominance.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]文化[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在文明IV中，“文化”指文明在文学和艺术等领域所达到的成就。文化等级高的文明将得到其他文明的尊敬和羡慕。这样的文明将在深刻支配其邻国的思想潮流，在对有限生存空间的争夺中获得优势。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]创造文化[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]文化在[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]中创造，每座城市有单独的文化等级。新建立的城市，居民人数有限，除去为生存而劳作，没有更多精力去发展文化。但随着城市的成长，各种宗教，艺术，文学领域的[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]的建造，其产生的文化将不断增加。要进一步促进文化发展，还可将部分人口转化为[LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]专业人员[\LINK]，并催生[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]。但是，积累文化最重要的一种方式是建造[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]文化按钮[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]当你获得[LINK=TECH_DRAMA]戏剧[\LINK]科技之后，你将可通过文化按钮，将商业收入按一定比例投入文化事业。这样即使没有文化建筑也能提升城市文化等级（虽然这样代价昂贵!）文化按钮还能增加[LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]快乐[\LINK]程度；详情见相应文明百科词条。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]生产文化[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]当你获得[LINK=TECH_MUSIC]音乐[\LINK]科技之后，可以将城市的工业产能转化为文化点数。类似于建造其他工程。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]文化与城市防御[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]人们往往会更加努力地保卫特别神圣，特别美丽，具有特殊文化价值的城市。为了反映这一现象，拥有高文化等级的城市可获得“城防奖励.”奖励幅度随着城市文化等级的提升而提升。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]和[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]战斗[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]文化与国界[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]城市的文化价值决定其对周围区域的影响力。相关详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]国界[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]城市文化的转换[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果一座拥有更强文化优势的城市邻近其他文明的城市，拥有优势的一方将对另一方造成文化上的压力。这使得拥有文化优势的一方控制两城之间的更多土地，有时文化劣势一方城市周围的土地甚至会被全部蚕食。导致城市的饥荒，在极端情况下，劣势方城市将发生[LINK=CONCEPT_REVOLUTION]暴乱[\LINK]并加入优势一方的文明。[PARAGRAPH:2]一座城市在叛离到另一文明前需要发生两次暴乱。第一次暴乱将最终平定。统治者必须努力提升城市文化等级以避免第二次暴乱：如果努力失败引发第二次暴乱，城市将最终加入更强势一方的文明。当一座城市转投到你的统治之下时，你将可获得城市的所有建筑与大奇观，因此比武力征服更为有利（但也许缺乏满足感）。[PARAGRAPH:2]上文所述的文化转换也有例外规则：通过武力征服的城市不会叛离回原来所属的文明，不论其受到原属文明多大的文化压力（但可能造成持续暴乱）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]蛮族城市[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]蛮族城市与其他城市一样拥有文化值。也可能因文化压力而加入其他文明。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Diplomacy[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]As Civilization IV progresses and your units [LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]Explore[\LINK] the world around them, you will meet the leaders of the other civilizations around you. Each leader is different: some are warlike; others, peaceful. Some are backstabbing liars; others are (usually) honest. You'll have to learn how to deal with these characters: some you'll fight right away; others you'll negotiate with - at least until it's time to destroy them...[PARAGRAPH:2]You can accomplish a lot through diplomacy. You can trade technologies, resources, maps, gold, and even cities. You can form mutual protection pacts; you can declare war; you can negotiate peace settlements. Success in Civilization IV depends as much on your diplomatic skills as it does on your martial and management prowess.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Leaders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Each leader has his or her own agenda. They, too, seek to achieve victory - some through force of arms, others through technological prowess, others through cultural domination. You'll get clues to their intentions as the game progresses - the more warlike leaders will usually not trade anything of military value, the knowledge-focused leaders will seek advanced technologies, and so forth. See [LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]Leaders[\LINK] for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2] [BOLD]Leader Attitudes:[\BOLD] During the game, each leader will form an opinion of you: how great a threat you are to their civilization, whether you have fought them in the past, whether you have allied with their enemies, how much you can be trusted to keep your word, etc.[PARAGRAPH:2]Leader attitudes come in five flavors: friendly, pleased, cautious, annoyed, and furious. The more a leader likes you, the more likely he or she is to be willing to trade with you, and the better deal you'll get. You may be able to trade with hostile leaders, but you're likely to pay a stiff price for whatever you get.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Refusing to Talk:[\BOLD] Sometimes a particularly angry leader won't speak to you at all. This occurs most often when your civilizations are at war. Check back again in several turns - by then he or she may have cooled off enough to be willing to speak, especially if his or her military situation has declined.[PARAGRAPH:2] [H2]Opening Diplomacy[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You can open diplomacy from the diplomacy screen, or by clicking on the leader's name in the "score box" on the main screen. Occasionally, a leader might open negotiations with you. When diplomacy begins, the diplomacy screen appears.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Diplomatic Options[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When diplomacy opens, you (and the other leaders) usually have several choices available:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Declare War:[\BOLD] The polite way to open hostilities. (The less polite way is to march your units into the enemy's territory without an open borders agreement.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Offer Peace:[\BOLD] Available only if you're at war.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Trade:[\BOLD] Try to trade stuff with the other civilization. This takes you to the trade table.[PARAGRAPH:2] [BOLD]Review Ongoing Deals:[\BOLD] Some "annual" deals continue over time (see below). This option lets you review any such deals you have in place with the leader.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Exit:[\BOLD] End the diplomatic session.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Making Trade Offers[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]On the trade table, all of your tradable items are listed in the right-hand column, while the other leader's stuff is in the left-hand column. To make an offer, click on one (or more) items in your column, and one (or more) items in the other leader's column, and then click on the "make offer" button. If the leader agrees, the deal is done. If not, you can exit diplomacy or try another deal. [PARAGRAPH:2]If you click only on an item in the other leader's column but not on anything in your column, you are "demanding tribute:" ordering the leader to give you the item for free. He or she may decline, of course, and in either case, his opinion of you will probably decline. If you click only on an item in your column but none in the other leader's, you are giving the leader that item for free, as a "goodwill gesture." Leaders never refuse goodwill gestures. Goodwill gestures often cause the leader to raise his or her opinion of you.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Responding to Offers[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When another leader makes you an offer, you must choose to refuse or accept the offer. If you accept, the trade occurs immediately. If you decline, the other leader may ask you to make a counter-offer, may end diplomacy, or may declare war on you.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Untradeable Items[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Often you will see items in the leader's column that are colored red. This indicates that the leader will not (or cannot) trade these items with you, so don't bother asking.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Technical Requirements for Trade[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You need access to certain technologies to trade some items; at the beginning of the game, your diplomatic options are severely limited. Both sides do not need to know the required technology, but at least one of the traders must. You cannot trade technology, for example, until either you or your trading partner knows the [LINK=TECH_ALPHABET]Alphabet[\LINK] technology.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Trading Types[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There are two distinct kinds of items you can trade: "immediate" items or "annual" items. Immediate items can only be traded for other immediate items, and annuals only for other annuals. You are free to trade any items within a group - technology for gold and a world map, for instance, since they're all immediate items - but you can't trade an immediate item or items for one or more annuals.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Immediate Items:[\BOLD] These are items that are exchanged immediately. That is, the deals have no duration. Immediate items include: lump sum of gold, maps, technology, peace treaties, cities, and so on.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Annual Trade Items:[\BOLD] Annual trades last for a minimum of 10 turns. They can continue for longer than 10 turns if both sides agree, but neither side can cancel an annual trade before 10 turns are up, except by declaration of war. Annual items include: resources, gold per turn.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Tradable Things[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Gold, Lump Sum - Immediate[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]A chunk of gold. 1 gold. 15 gold. A billion-billion gold.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Gold, Per Turn - Annual[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]A certain number of gold per turn: 2 gold/turn. 30 gold/turn. This lasts a minimum of 10 turns. Note that you are obligated to pay this gold no matter what: empty treasury, anarchy, etc. Your treasurer will automatically disband units and buildings as necessary to fulfill your obligations.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]World Map - Immediate[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]All of the territory explored by your partner is now visible on your main map and vice versa. (See [LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]Exploration[\LINK].)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Open Borders - Annual[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Your units can now move freely through your partner's territory, and vice versa. If you declare war against a civilization you have an open borders agreement with, all of your units are removed from his territory, and all of his units are removed from yours.[PARAGRAPH:2]Furthermore, your cities' trade routes extend to include those civs which whom you have Open Borders. Since foreign trade routes are much more lucrative than domestic ones, signing Open Borders can significantly increase the commerce of your cities. Various [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Buildings[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] can increase this income even more.[PARAGRAPH:2] [BOLD]Defensive Pact - Annual[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If either of your civilizations is attacked by a third party, the other civilization automatically declares war on the attacker. This agreement is nullified if either of the signatories attacks anybody.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Permanent Alliance - Immediate[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Your two civilizations essentially become one nation with two rulers. You each continue to have control over your units and cities, but you share everything else: resources, technologies, maps, and victory or defeat. If one declares war, the other automatically does so as well. If one signs a treaty, the other is bound by it.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Technology - Immediate[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]You immediately learn the technology that has been traded to you.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Resources - Annual[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If a resource is traded to you, you get all of its benefits for as long as the agreement is in place. The trader loses all of the benefits, unless he or she has more than one. (For instance, if somebody trades you iron, you can then construct any military unit that requires iron. The trader can no longer produce such units, unless he's got another source of iron.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Declare War with - Immediate[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]One civilization asks another to declare war on a third. A leader can ask another leader to declare war on a civilization that the first civilization is not at war with, but the other leader will usually charge through the nose for doing so.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Cities - Immediate[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Your opponent agrees to give you one or more of his or her cities. If you have open borders with the other civilization, all units remain in place. If not, the units in the city are shifted back to their own territory. It is extremely rare for a leader to give up a city unless under great duress.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Adopt - Immediate[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]One civilization asks another to change civics. Each leader has a favorite civic-type - Catherine, for example, likes Hereditary Rule. Leaders like you better if you are employing their favorite civic.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Convert - Immediate[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]One civilization asks another civilization to change its state religion to match the first civilization's state religion. Religious differences between civilizations cause a lot of tension: adopting another civilization's religion is an excellent way to firm up relations with that civilization.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Declare Peace - Special[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Peace breaks out between you and your opponent. All units are immediately vacated from each other's terrain. Peace lasts for a minimum of 10 turns. You can only trade peace for gold or technology.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Declare Cease Fire - Special[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Peace breaks out between you and your opponent. All units are immediately vacated from each other's terrain. There is no duration for this cease fire - either side can immediately declare war again. Nothing can be combined with a cease fire deal.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]外交[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]随着游戏的进展，你的单位不断[LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]探索[\LINK]周遭的世界，你将遇见其他文明的领袖。每位领袖都各不相同：有的侵略成性；有的爱好和平。有的笑里藏刀；有的（通常）诚实守信。你需要知道如何同这些对手打交道：有的必须立刻拔刀相向；有的则应以谈判为先——至少在最终翻脸以前..。[PARAGRAPH:2]你可以通过外交达到许多目标。你可以交换科技，资源，地图，金钱，甚至城市。你可以签署共同防御协定；可以宣战；可以媾和。文明IV中要赢得胜利，除了军事和管理方面，在很大程度上也取决于你的外交能力。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]文明领袖[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]每位领袖都有自己的计划和目标。他们都在寻求赢得胜利——有的通过武力，有的通过科研，有的通过文化扩张。随着游戏的进展你将觉察出他们的意图——好战的领袖通常不愿进行有重要军事意义的交易，专注科研的领袖会寻求先进的科技，如此等等。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]文明领袖[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]领袖外交态度:[\BOLD]在游戏期间，每位领袖将根据各种因素，形成对你的态度：你在多大程度上对其文明构成威胁，你是否曾经对其文明发动战争，你是否与其敌人结成同盟，你是否信守自己的承诺等等。[PARAGRAPH:2]领袖的外交态度分为五级：亲密的，热情的，谨慎的，不悦的，狂怒的。某位领袖对你的态度越好，越愿意同你进行交易，交易条件也越对你有利。你也可能同敌对的领袖进行交易，但你往往需要付出高昂的代价才能达到目的。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]拒绝谈判:[\BOLD]某些领袖如果对你非常愤怒，可能拒绝同你谈判。这种情况通常是发生在双方处于战争状态时。可以等待数回合再与其接触——那时对方可能已经冷静下来，愿意进行谈判了，特别是当其军事态势恶化时。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]进行外交谈判[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以在外交顾问界面进行外交谈判，或点击主界面右下角“积分列表”中的领袖名字。其他领袖也可能不时主动同你进行外交谈判。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]外交选项[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]开始外交谈判后，你和对方通常会有多个外交选项:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]宣战:[\BOLD]以礼貌的方式进入敌对状态。（不礼貌的方式是在没有开放边界条约的情况下直接将你的部队开进对方的领土.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]提议和平:[\BOLD]处于战争状态时可选。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]贸易:[\BOLD]与其他文明展开各种交易。这将打开贸易谈判桌。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]复核当前条款:[\BOLD]某些“持续性”条款会延续一段时间（见下）。该选项使你可重新与对方就此类条款进行谈判。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]退出:[\BOLD]结束外交谈判。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]提出贸易条件[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在贸易谈判桌上，已方可交易项目列于右侧边栏，对方可交易项目列于左侧边栏。要提出条件，点击本方边栏中的一个（或多个）项目，以及对方边栏中的一个（或多个）项目，再点击“提出条件”按钮。如对方接受，交易即完成。如不被接受，你可回退并尝试其他条款。[PARAGRAPH:2]如果你只选择对方提供的项目而不选择已方提供的项目，即在“要求贡礼”：命令对方免费向你提供该项目。当然对方可能拒绝，无论其拒绝与否，他对你的态度将会恶化。如果你只选择已方提供的项目而不选择对方提供的项目，即免费向对方提供项目作为“善意的表示”。对方绝不可能拒绝这种善意。善意的表示往往能改善对方与你的态度。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]回复提议[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当其他领袖向你提出一项条件，你必须选择拒绝或是接受。如果你接受，交易即完成。如果你拒绝，对方可能要求你提出自己的条件，或是结束外交谈判，甚至可能对你宣战。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]不可交易项目[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你经常会在谈判时发现对方边栏中的某些项目显示为红色文本。这表明对方不愿（或不能）与你交易此项目，因此不可在你的条件中选择此项目。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]交易的科技前提[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你需要获得特定的科技才能进行某些项目的交易；在游戏开始时，外交的选择非常有限。科技前提不必双方同时达到，只需其中一方符合条件即可。例如，开始时不能进行科技交易，直到某一方获得[LINK=TECH_ALPHABET]字母表[\LINK]科技。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]交易类型[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]可交易项目分为两种类型：“立即”型或“持续”型。立即型项目只能交换其他立即型项目，持续型项目只能交换其他持续型项目。你可以任意交换同一类型的项目——例如以科技换取金钱和世界地图，因为这些都是立即型项目——但你不能以一个立即型项目换取一个或多个持续型项目。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]立即型交易项目:[\BOLD]此类项目是可立即交换的。也就是说，交易没有时间持续性。立即型项目包括：一次性支付的金钱，地图，科技，和平条约，城市等等。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]持续型交易项目:[\BOLD]持续型交易至少要延续10个回合。如果双方一致同意，交易持续时间可超过10个回合，但除非宣战，任何一方均不能在10回合内取消交易。持续型项目包括：资源，分期支付的金钱等。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]可交易对象[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]金币，一次性支付——立即型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]一笔金钱。1金币。15金币。一百万亿金币等等。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]金币，每回合支付——持续型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]每回合一笔金钱：2金币/回合。30金币/回合。条款至少持续10回合。在任何情况下你都必须进行支付：包括国库赤字，无政府状态等等。为履行支付义务，必要时将自动解散单位或拆毁建筑。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]世界地图——立即型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]对方已知区域将在已方主地图上显示，对方亦然。（见[LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]探索[\LINK].）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]开放边界——持续型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你的单位将可自由进入对方领土，对方亦然。如果你向签有开放边界条约的文明宣战，你的单位将立即移出对方领土，对方亦然。[PARAGRAPH:2]此外，你的城市商路将扩展到签有开放边界条约的文明。国际商路比国内商路更有价值，因此签订开放边界条约将显著提升城市的商业收入。多种[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]和[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]还能进一步提升商业收入。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]共同防御——持续型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如签约双方之一遭受第三方进攻，另一方自动对进攻方宣战。如果签约双方之一主动对第三方宣战，此条约自动中止。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]永久同盟——立即型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]签约双方将成为一个整体。双方仍然各自控制自己的单位和城市，但其他领域则全面共享：资源，科技，地衅，胜利或失败。如一方向第三方宣战，另一方自动参战。如一方签订条约，另一方也受其约束。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]科技——立即型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]立即获得所交易的科技。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]资源——持续型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]通过交易某种资源，你可在条约有效期内享受资源带来的利益。资源提供方失去该资源带来的利益，除非对方拥有多个该种资源。（例如，如对方向你提供铁，你将可以组建需要铁资源的军事单位。对方将不能再组建此类单位，除非他有额外的铁资源.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]宣战——立即型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]一方要求另一方对第三方宣战。某位领袖可以要求另一位领袖对其他文明宣战但自己不参战，但这往往必然会将战火引向自身。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市——立即型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]对方同意将其一座或多座城市移交给你。如果双方开放边界，对方单位将留在原地。否则对方单位将移回本国领土。文明领袖们极少会愿意放弃自己的城市，除非迫不得已。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]实行——立即型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]一方要求另一方改变其内政法令。每位文明领袖都有其内政倾向——例如叶卡捷琳娜倾向于世袭制度。如果你选择实行其倾向的内政法令，对方对你的态度将会更好。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]改宗——立即型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]一方要求另一方改变其官方信仰，以与其保持一致。文明间宗教信仰的差异会导致关系紧张：信仰其他文明的国教是加强双方关系的最佳手段。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]宣布和平——特殊型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]敌对双方实现和平。在对方领土上的单位立即移出边境。和平状态将持续至少10回合。你只能以金钱或科技换取和平。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]宣布停火——特殊型[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]敌对双方实现和平。在对方领土上的单位立即移出边境。停火状态没有持续时间限制——任何一方可以立即再次宣战。停火协议不能附加任何其他条件。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_DRAFT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Draft[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=CIVIC_NATIONHOOD]Nationhood[\LINK] civic allows you to "draft" three units each turn. When you draft a unit in a city, some of the city's population is turned into a military unit.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Unit Type[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The drafted unit is the best "standard" foot-soldier available to your civilization: in early eras this might be a swordsman, while later it might be a maceman, musketeer or infantry.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Unit Experience[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Drafted units begin with half as much experience as a standard unit trained in the same city would receive.[PARAGRAPH:2] [H2]Unhappiness[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Employing the draft causes [LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]Unhappiness[\LINK] in the city where you drafted the unit. This unhappiness isn't permanent: it dissipates over time. Drafting the same city multiple times will increase the unhappiness duration further.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]强制征召[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=CIVIC_NATIONHOOD]民族国家[\LINK]内政法令允许你每回合“强制征召”三个单位。当你强制征召单位时，将损失部分城市人口。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]单位类型[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]强制征召的单位是本文明目前最好的“标准”步战士兵：在游戏早期可能是剑士，以后可能是钉锤手，火枪手或现代步兵。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]单位经验值[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]强制征召的单位经验值只有正常组建单位的一半。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]不满[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]进行强制征召会造成所在城市[LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]不满[\LINK]情绪。不满情绪会随时间流逝而消失。如果在同一城市连续强制征召，不满情绪会持续更长的时间。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_EXPLORATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Exploration[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]At the beginning of a game, most of the world is unknown to you. It is important to explore the world, to discover resources and sites to build new [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK] and to encounter other civilizations. You explore your world by sending units out into the unknown: the spaces become visible once your units can "see" them.[PARAGRAPH:2]There are three different kinds of spaces in Civilization IV: unexplored spaces, visible spaces, and explored spaces.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Unexplored Spaces[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Unexplored spaces are black. You don't know what terrain they contain, whether they are occupied by units, or anything else.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Visible Spaces[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Visible Spaces are very bright. They are all the spaces that your units and cities can currently "see." Spaces within your cultural borders are always visible. Your units and cities can always see the squares they occupy and those directly adjacent to them; if on hills, if looking across water, or if you have certain technological advances, they can often see farther. When you look at the map, you can see everything that any of your units or cities can see: other units, visible resources, improvements, cultural borders, and so forth.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Explored Spaces[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Explored spaces are darker than visible spaces, but not as black as unexplored spaces. These are spaces that you have seen in the past, but which none of your units or cities can see at present. Explored spaces are displayed on the map in the state you last saw them: you do NOT see any changes (new cities, improvements, roads, so forth) which have taken place since you last actually saw that space. You cannot see units in explored spaces.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Map Trading[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When you trade [LINK=CONCEPT_MAPS]Maps[\LINK] with another civilization (see [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomacy[\LINK]), all of the newly-visible territory is "explored" to you - you see the territory as your trading partner last saw it, but you don't see any units occupying those spaces. If your trading partner then builds new cities or improvements in these spaces after trading you his or her map, you will not see the changed conditions unless you trade for their map again.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]探索[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在游戏开始时，世界的大部分区域都是未知的。你的一项重要任务就是探索周遭世界，寻找各种资源，建立新的[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]并与其他文明进行联系。为此你需要派遣单位前往未知区域：你的单位视野所及的区域将显现出来。[PARAGRAPH:2]文明IV中的地图区域有三种状态：未探明区域，可见区域，以及已探明区域。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]未探明区域[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]未探明区域呈黑色。你不知道该处属于何种地形，是否存在单位等等。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]可见区域[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]可见区域呈亮色。即你的城市和单位目前能够“看到的”区域，你的文化边界范围之内始终为可见区域。你的单位和城市的视野必定能达到其所在方格及相邻方格；如果处于丘陵地形，或是与河流相邻，或是拥有特定科技，视野将会延伸得更远。在地图上，你可以获得你的单位和城市视野范围内的所有信息：非本国单位，可见资源，区域设施，文化边界等等。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]已探明区域[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]已探明区域呈暗色。即你曾经完成探索，但你的单位和城市目前视野所不能达到的区域。已探明区域在地图上显示你最后一次探索时看到的状态：你无法看到在此之后发生的变化（新的城市，区域设施，道路等等）。你也不能看到其中的单位。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]交换地图[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当你与其他文明交换[LINK=CONCEPT_MAPS]地图[\LINK]（见[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交[\LINK]），地图的更新将显示为“已探明”区域——你可以看到对方视野曾经达到的区域，但你不能看到其中的单位。如果对方在此之后建立了新的城市或区域设施，你也不能看到这些变化，除非再次交换地图。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FOOD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Food [\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities need food to survive. The more food available, the larger the city can grow. Cities get food by working the lands around them (spaces that are both within the national [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Borders[\LINK] and within their [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City Radius[\LINK].)[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Food Consumption[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Each citizen (population point) in a [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City[\LINK] consumes two food per turn to survive.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Excess Food:[\BOLD] If a city generates more food than its citizens consume, it stores the excess food. Once it has enough stored food, all of its stored food disappears and the city's population increases by one. As a city grows larger, it takes more stored food to increase its population. The [LINK=BUILDING_GRANARY]Granary[\LINK] stores half of the food needed to grow to the next size, thus accelerating the speed at which the city's population increases.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Insufficient Food:[\BOLD] If a city does not produce enough food to support its population, the city will begin to lose stored food. When a city loses all of its stored food, one of its citizens starves. Starvation will continue until the city is producing enough food to support the population.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Health[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A city's [LINK=CONCEPT_HEALTH]Health[\LINK] has a large effect on its food production; when a city slips into unhealthiness, it requires additional food to feed all of the citizens. See that section for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2] [H2]Working the Land[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Each type of [LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]Terrain[\LINK] generates a specific amount of food, as does each [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resource.[\LINK] You can often increase a square's food output by [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Improving[\LINK] it with your workers; for example, grassland tiles next to fresh water can be irrigated with farms to produce additional food.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Buildings and Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Some [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Buildings[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK] can increase a city's food output (for example, the [LINK=BUILDING_LIGHTHOUSE]Lighthouse[\LINK] building adds more food to water tiles).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Civics[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=CIVIC_STATE_PROPERTY]State Property[\LINK] civic increases the food output of certain improvements.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Technology[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Some [LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]Technological Advances[\LINK] allow your workers to construct improvements increasing your land's food output, while other advances make already-existing improvements more efficient.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]食物[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]城市需要食物才能保持存在。食物产出越多，城市可达到的规模越大。城市通过在周遭区域工作获得食物（处于国家[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]边界[\LINK]及本身[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市范围[\LINK]之内的区域.）[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]食物消耗[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]中的每一单位居民（人口值）每回合需要消耗两单位食物。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]富余食物:[\BOLD]如果城市产出的食物多于本身的消耗，富余的食物将储存起来。达到一定程度，则食物存量清空，人口值增加一个单位。随着城市规模的成长，人口值增加所需的食物存量也将增加。[LINK=BUILDING_GRANARY]粮仓[\LINK]可保存所需食物存量的一半，因此可以加速城市人口的增长。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]食物不足:[\BOLD]如果城市的食物产出不足以支持城市人口，城市食物存量将减少。当食物存量耗尽时，将因饥荒而减少一单位人口。如果城市仍然无法产出足够食物，饥荒也将持续。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]健康[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_HEALTH]健康[\LINK]程度对食物产出有很大影响；如果城市健康度过低，则将会消耗更多的食物。详情见相应小节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]在区块上工作[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]每种[LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]地形[\LINK]可产出特定数量的食物，特定[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]可增加食物产出。你可以通过命令工人[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]改造[\LINK]地形以增加食物产出；例如，与淡水相邻的草原地形可建设农场进行灌溉，以产出更多的食物。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]建筑与奇观[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]某些[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]与[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]可以提升城市的食物产出（例如，[LINK=BUILDING_LIGHTHOUSE]灯塔[\LINK]可使水域产出更多食物）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]内政法令[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]实行[LINK=CIVIC_STATE_PROPERTY]国营经济[\LINK]内政法令可提升特定区域设施的食物产出。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]科技[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]某些[LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]科技进展[\LINK]允许你的工人修建新的区域设施，提升食物产出，还有一些科技可提升现有区域设施的效率。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_GOLDEN_AGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Golden Ages[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]During certain periods of time, some civilizations seem to burst with energy and creativity. The civilization's people become increasingly productive; technological advances come easy to the civilization; and its culture is the envy of the world. Italy during the Renaissance is one such example, and Great Britain in the 19th century another. In Civilization IV, such periods are called "golden ages."[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Entering a Golden Age[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Wonders:[\BOLD] A civilization can enter a golden age by constructing the [LINK=BUILDING_TAJ_MAHAL]Taj Mahal[\LINK] wonder.[PARAGRAPH:2] [BOLD]Great People:[\BOLD] A civilization can combine 2 or more [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great People[\LINK] of different types to start a golden age. The cost of this method escalates: the first golden age costs two great people, the second costs three, and so on.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Golden Ages[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]During a golden age, your civilization greatly increases its output of production and commerce, meaning faster build times and research rates. (In game terms, every space within your cities' radii that provides commerce produces an extra commerce, and every space that provides production now produces an additional one.)[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Duration of Golden Ages[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Golden ages last eight turns. If you achieve another golden age while in the midst of one already, the eight additional turns are tacked onto the end of the present golden age (meaning that the two ages will last a combined total of 16 turns).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]The End of the Age[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Once the golden age ends, your civilization's commerce and production return to normal levels.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]黄金时代[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在一段特定的时期，有些文明会突然爆发出巨大的能量和创造力。社会生产力持续提升；科研进展层不出穷；昌明的文化为整个世界所羡慕。文艺复兴时期的意大利和19世纪的大不列颠都是这样的例子。在文明IV，这样的时期被称为“黄金时代”。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]进入黄金时代[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]奇观:[\BOLD]一个文明可以通过建造[LINK=BUILDING_TAJ_MAHAL]泰姬陵[\LINK]进入黄金时代。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]历史伟人:[\BOLD]一个文明可以凭借两位或更多不同类型的[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]开创黄金时代。所需的数量是逐次累进的：第一次黄金时代需要两位历史伟人，第二次需要三位，以此类推。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]黄金时代的作用[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在黄金时代中，你的文明工业和商业产出将大为提升，这意味着更快的工程建造和科学研究速度。（具体而言，在城市范围之内有商业收入的区域将额外增加1单位商业收入，有工业产能的区域将额外增加1单位工业产能.）[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]黄金时代的持续时间[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]黄金时代的持续时间为八个回合。如果你在黄金时代持续过程中再次达到开创黄金时代的条件，则现有黄金时代结束时立即开始下一个黄金时代（即黄金时代共持续16回合）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]黄金时代的结束[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]黄金时代结束后，文明的商业和工业产出将恢复正常水平。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Great People[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Time and again through history, there have arisen men and women who have profoundly changed the world around them - artists, scientists, prophets and others whose genius sets them head and shoulders above the rest. In Civilization IV, such visionaries are called "Great People."[PARAGRAPH:2]There are five different kinds of great people in the game: Great Prophets, Great Merchants, Great Artists, Great Scientists, and Great Engineers. Each has a special ability.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Generating Great People[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Great people are generated in cities. Each city generates a separate pool of "great people points" - when the city has earned enough points, it will generate a great person. The cost of generating a great person escalates throughout the game: the first great person costs 100 great people points, the second costs 200, and so forth. (The number of points needed to produce a great person is different on the Quick and Epic game speeds.)[PARAGRAPH:2]The first civilization to discover certain technologies will also receive a free great person in their capital city. For example, the first civ to discover [LINK=TECH_MUSIC]Music[\LINK] receives a Great Artist.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Great People Points[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A city generates great people points in a number of ways: by constructing [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK], by assigning citizens to be specialists, and by choosing certain [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Wonders:[\BOLD] A wonder will generate a certain number of great people points each turn. Further, some wonders can increase a city's (or entire civilization's!) great people point generation significantly (see the [LINK=BUILDING_PARTHENON]Parthenon[\LINK] for an example). Like specialists (see next), some wonders increase the chances of generating a specific type of great person in their city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Specialists:[\BOLD] In each [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City[\LINK] you can assign citizens to be "specialists." Each specialist provides some kind of production bonus to its city; in addition, most generate great people points (the citizen specialist being the sole exception). Further, the kinds of specialists you have in a city determine which great people you generate: if all of your specialists in a city are priests, when that city generates a great person, he or she will be a great prophet. If half the specialists are merchants and the other half artists, you'll have a fifty-fifty chance of generating a great artist or great merchant.Moving the mouse over the great person points bar will display the percentage of getting each type of great person.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Civics:[\BOLD] Some [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] increase the speed at which you generate great people.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Great People Characterists[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]As mentioned above, there are five types of great people. Each type has its own special abilities, but they all share some characteristics:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Can Discover New Technologies:[\BOLD] You can expend a great person to discover a new technology. Typically this technology will be in the great person's area of expertise (prophets will usually discover religious technologies and so on), but not always. Once all of the relatively inexpensive technologies have been discovered, the great person may not be able to entirely discover a new tech, but he or she can dramatically decrease the time it takes you to discover it.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Golden Ages:[\BOLD] You can expend two or more great people to start a [LINK=CONCEPT_GOLDEN_AGE]"Golden Age"[\LINK]; see that section for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Settling in Cities:[\BOLD] All great persons also have the ability to settle in a city as a sort of "super-specialist". Settling a great person in a city will add certain bonuses to that city each turn; for example, a Great Prophet will add 2 production and 5 gold to the city it settles in. [PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Special Abilities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] In addition to their common abilities, each great person type has other unique abilities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Artists:[\BOLD] Great Artists can create great works of art in a city; this immediately gives that city additional [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Culture[\LINK] points (from 2,000 to 6,000, depending upon game speed). This is extremely useful if a city is under cultural threat from a neighbor (or you wish to culturally attack those cities!). Great Artists can also "permanently settle" in a city, providing a continuing large cultural and small research boost to the city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Engineers:[\BOLD] Great Engineers can "hurry" a city's production, greatly speeding up the creation of whatever the city is presently constructing. Most early wonders can be completed in a single turn by Great Engineers, and later ones can be sped up dramatically. Great Engineers can permanently settle in a city, providing a continuing large production and small research boost to that city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Merchants:[\BOLD] A Great Merchant can conduct a "trade mission" which will immediately give you a whole bunch of gold. To conduct a trade mission, first move the merchant to a wealthy and powerful city as far away from your cities as possible. When the merchant reaches the target city you'll be able to conduct the mission; trade missions can ONLY be carried out in foreign cities. The value of the mission increases the further away and wealthier the target city is. Great Merchants can also settle permanently in a city, providing a continuing large commerce and small food boost to the city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Prophet:[\BOLD] Great Prophets can create religious shrines - the [LINK=BUILDING_JEWISH_SHRINE]Temple of Solomon[\LINK] and the [LINK=BUILDING_CONFUCIAN_SHRINE]Kong Miao[\LINK], for example. However, Great Prophets can create religious shrines ONLY in a city where a religion was founded. Using a Great Prophet is the only way to build a religion's shrine. Great Prophets can also settle in a city, providing a continuing large commerce and small production boost to that city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Scientist:[\BOLD] Great Scientists can construct an [LINK=BUILDING_ACADEMY]Academy[\LINK], a building which greatly boots a city's scientific research as well as its culture. Great Scientists can also settle permanently in a city, providing a large research and small production boost to the city.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]历史伟人[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在历史长河中，出现了许多对世界产生过深刻影响的天才人物——艺术家，科学家，预言家等等，他们的成就远远超越常人。在文明IV中，这样的人物被称为“历史伟人”。[PARAGRAPH:2]游戏中共有五种历史伟人：大预言家，大商业家，大艺术家，大科学家，大工程师。每种伟人都有特殊的作用。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]产生历史伟人[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]历史伟人在城市中产生。每座城市都可积累一定的“历史伟人点数”——当城市积累了足够的点数，将产生一位历史伟人。产生历史伟人所需点数会随着游戏的进程而提升：第一位历史伟人需要100历史伟人点数，第二位需要200，以此类推。（具体需要的点数在游戏速度设为快速和史诗时会有变化.）[PARAGRAPH:2]率先发现特定科技的文明可自动在首都产生一位历史伟人。例如，率先发现[LINK=TECH_MUSIC]音乐[\LINK]的文明可获得一位大艺术家。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]历史伟人点数[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]城市产生历史伟人点数的途径包括：建造[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]，将市民转化为专业人员，选择特定[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]奇观:[\BOLD]奇观可在每回合产生一定的历史伟人点数。此外，某些奇观还可大大增加所在城市的（或整个文明的所有城市!）历史伟人点数（例如[LINK=BUILDING_PARTHENON]帕特农神庙[\LINK]）。除了专业人员（见下文），某些奇观也能增加所在城市产生特定类型历史伟人的几率。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]专业人员:[\BOLD]每座[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]可以将部分市民转化为“专业人员.”每种专业人员能为城市提供特定的产出加成；此外，他们还能产生历史伟人点数（市民型专业人员除外）。而且，城市中专业人员的类型还会影响所产生的历史伟人类型：所以城市中所有专业人员都是神学家，则城市产生的历史伟人将会是大预言家。如果城市专业人员中半数为商业家，半数为艺术家，则产生大艺术家和大商业家的几率就是一半对一半。将鼠标移动到历史伟人点数栏，将可查看现有历史伟人点数的类型分布。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]内政法令:[\BOLD]某些[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]可提升历史伟人出现几率。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]历史伟人的特性[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如上所述，共有五种类型的历史伟人。每种类型都有特殊的作用，但他们也有一些共同特性:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]能够发现新科技:[\BOLD]你可让历史伟人发现一项新科技。具体的科技通常与历史伟人的类型相关（如大预言家会发现宗教类科技等），但不是必然如此。如果相关的主要科技已经发现完毕，历史伟人可能无法发现新科技，但仍可以大大减少发现其他新科技所需的时间。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]黄金时代:[\BOLD]你凭借两位以上的历史伟人为开创一个[LINK=CONCEPT_GOLDEN_AGE]“黄金时代”[\LINK]；详情见相应小节。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]定居于城市:[\BOLD]任何历史伟人都可以在城市中定居，成为“超级专业人员”。让历史伟人在城市中定居，可每轮获得一定利益；例如，定居的大预言家可使城市工业产能+2，金币收入+5。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]特殊能力[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]除了共同的特性，每种历史伟人还拥有一定的特殊能力。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大艺术家:[\BOLD]大艺术家可在城市中创作一项艺术杰作；这将使城市获得大量[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化[\LINK]点数（具体数值根据游戏速度2,000至6,000不等）。这特别有助于帮助城市摆脱外来文化影响（或是对外国城市施加文化影响!）。大艺术家还可在城市中“永久定居”，提供大量文化点数，并促进科学研究。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大工程师:[\BOLD]大工程师可能“加速”城市的建设，使城市当前进行的工程项目迅速完成。许多早期奇观如果有大工程师帮助，一个回合就可完成，后期的奇观也可大大加速。大工程师可在城市中永久定居，提供大量工业产能，并促进科学研究。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大商业家:[\BOLD]大商业家可开展“贸易事业”获得大量金钱收入。要开展贸易事业，先将大商业家移至尽可能遥远而且富庶的异国大城市。即可在当地开展贸易事业；贸易事业只能在异国城市开展。具体收入由目标城市的遥远程度和富庶程度决定。大商业家可也在城市中永久定居，提供大量商业收入，并促进科学研究。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大预言家:[\BOLD]大预言家能建立宗教圣坛——例如[LINK=BUILDING_JEWISH_SHRINE]所罗门圣殿[\LINK]和[LINK=BUILDING_CONFUCIAN_SHRINE]孔庙[\LINK]。但是，大预言家只能在创立宗教的城市建立相应宗教的圣殿。大预言家是唯一能建立宗教圣殿的单位。大预言家也能在城市中永久定居，提供大量商业收入，少量工业产能，并促进科学研究。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大科学家:[\BOLD]大科学家能建立[LINK=BUILDING_ACADEMY]科学院[\LINK]，大幅度促进所在城市的科学研究和文化发展。大科学家也能在城市中永久定居，提供大量科研点数，少量工业产能。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_HAPPINESS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Happiness[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]If he wants to be successful in Civilization IV, even the most ruthless dictator must give some thought to his people's happiness. A happy citizen is a productive citizen. An unhappy citizen is a useless drag on his [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City[\LINK], producing nothing but still eating as much as anyone else.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Unhappiness[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Each citizen in a city has a job to do. Many are employed working the land around the city, and some few may be [LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]Specialists[\LINK], performing various other critical work. When a citizen is "unhappy" he or she refuses to work, thus reducing the city's laborers or specialists by one. This slacker still consumes two food each turn, however, and a city with too many unhappy citizens faces loss of productivity, commerce, a slowdown of the generation of great people, and perhaps [LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]Starvation[\LINK]. [PARAGRAPH:2]Rather than allowing a city to grow until it is unhappy, it is often a good idea to use specialists or the "Avoid Growth" governor command to halt a city at the size just before it would become unhappy. When more happiness is added later, the city can then go back to growing again.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Determining Happiness[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Each city has its own individual happiness level. There are many factors which can cause unhappiness in a city, with overpopulation and war being two of the most common (see below for a full list). Each source of unhappiness generates one or more "unhappy faces" (see [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK]). There are also many factors which produce happiness in a city, with religion and access to certain resources being two of the most important. Each of these generates one or more "happy faces."[PARAGRAPH:2]To determine a city's happiness, compare the number of happy faces to unhappy faces. If a city has as many or more happy faces as it has unhappy ones, all of the citizens in that city are happy. If the city has more unhappy faces than happy ones, a number of citizens equal to the difference will be unhappy. (Thus, if a city has five happy faces and seven unhappy faces, two of the city's citizens will refuse to work.)[PARAGRAPH:2]If a city has at least one unhappy citizen, an unhappy face will appear next to the city's name on the main map.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Causes of Unhappiness[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Overpopulation:[\BOLD] Every citizen in a city generates one unhappy face. The bigger the population, the more unhappy everybody is.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]War Weariness:[\BOLD] As a war continues, more and more citizens become unhappy about it. This is especially true in cities that you have recently captured from the civilization you're fighting.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Cultural Inferiority:[\BOLD] A city will become unhappy if it is being "culturally dominated" by a nearby foreign city (see [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Culture[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Borders[\LINK]).[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Undefended:[\BOLD] A city becomes unhappy if you have no military units in that city. The type of unit does not matter, so make sure to have at least one unit in every city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Slavery and the Draft:[\BOLD] Citizens are unhappy if you work them to death (see the [LINK=CIVIC_SLAVERY]Slavery[\LINK] civic). They don't much like it either if you forcibly draft them into the military (see the [LINK=CIVIC_NATIONHOOD]Nationhood[\LINK] civic).[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Emancipation:[\BOLD] Citizens become unhappy if other civilizations have adopted the [LINK=CIVIC_EMANCIPATION]Emancipation[\LINK] civic and you have not. The more civilizations that have adopted emancipation, the more unhappy become the citizens of the remaining holdouts.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Causes of Happiness[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There are plenty of them. Here are a few:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Resources:[\BOLD] Many [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK] produce happiness: [LINK=BONUS_FUR]Fur[\LINK] and [LINK=BONUS_GOLD]Gold[\LINK], to name two.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Buildings:[\BOLD] Temples, [LINK=BUILDING_COLOSSEUM]Colosseums[\LINK], and [LINK=BUILDING_THEATRE]Theatres[\LINK] are some early buildings which produce happiness. The [LINK=BUILDING_JAIL]Jail[\LINK] removes some unhappiness caused by war weariness.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Wonders:[\BOLD] The [LINK=BUILDING_GLOBE_THEATRE]Globe Theatre[\LINK] removes all unhappiness in the city where it is built. [LINK=BUILDING_ROCKNROLL]Rock-n-Roll[\LINK] produces the Hit Singles resource, which generates one happiness.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Civics:[\BOLD] The [LINK=CIVIC_POLICE_STATE]Police State[\LINK] civic negates all war weariness. [LINK=CIVIC_FREE_SPEECH]Free Speech[\LINK] produces happiness (in combination with [LINK=BUILDING_BROADCAST_TOWER]Broadcast Towers[\LINK]).[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Culture Button:[\BOLD] After discovering the [LINK=TECH_DRAMA]Drama[\LINK] technology, you can devote a percentage of your civilization's commerce to the [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Culture Button[\LINK], which increases both culture and happiness. Certain buildings like [LINK=BUILDING_THEATRE]Theatres[\LINK] and [LINK=BUILDING_COLOSSEUM]Colosseums[\LINK] increase the happiness effect from the Culture Button even further.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]And More:[\BOLD] As you play, you will discover many other factors that can increase or decrease a city's happiness.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]快乐[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]要想在文明IV中获得胜利，即使是最残酷无情的独裁者也需要考虑臣民的幸福。快乐的市民将富于生产力。而不满的市民则是[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]的负累，不从事任何生产，吃得却和别人一样多。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]不满的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]每位城市居民都需要进行。有的在城市周围的地块从事体力劳动，有的作为[LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]专业人员[\LINK]，进行更专业的工作。如果一位居民感到“不满”，将会拒绝工作，减少城市可用的劳力或专业人员。但是每回合仍然要消耗两单位食物，如果一座城市不满的居民过多，城市收入将大为降低，历史伟人产生数量也将减少，甚至可能导致[LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]饥荒[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2]注意不要让城市过度成长而不顾及居民快乐度，应该将人口转为专业人员或采用“避免成长”市政命令来控制城市规模。等到快乐度出现增长时，再扩大城市规模。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]决定快乐度[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]每座城市都有各自的快乐度。造成不满的因素有很多，最常见的是人口过多和厌战情绪（其他因素见下）。每种不满的来源将产生一个或多个“红脸”图标（见[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]）。此外也有很多因素能增加快乐度，最主要的是宗教和特定资源。每种快乐的来源将产生一个或多个“笑脸”图标。[PARAGRAPH:2]城市的快乐度由笑脸和红脸的数量对比决定。如果笑脸比红脸多或同样多，则所有城市居民都会保持快乐。如果红脸比笑脸多，则多出相应数量的不满居民。（因此，如果城市拥有五个笑脸七个红脸，将有两单位人口拒绝工作.）[PARAGRAPH:2]如果城市至少存在一个不满的居民，主地图的城市上将显示一个红脸图标。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]导致不满的原因[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]人口过多:[\BOLD]每单位城市人口将产生一个红脸。人口越多，红脸越多。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]厌战情绪:[\BOLD]随着战争的持续，会有越来越多的居民产生厌战情绪。从当前的敌人手中夺取的城市将出现特别严重的厌战情绪。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]文化劣势:[\BOLD]城市会因遭受邻近文明的“文化侵略”而导致不满（见[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化[\LINK]与[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]边界[\LINK]）。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]未设防:[\BOLD]城市如果没有负责防御的军事单位将导致不满。单位的数量和类型则没有关系，确保城市中有一个单位即可。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]奴隶制度和强制征召:[\BOLD]如果采用制度手段强迫居民劳动将导致不满（见[LINK=CIVIC_SLAVERY]奴隶制度[\LINK]内政法令）。强制征召居民加入军队也会导致不满（见[LINK=CIVIC_NATIONHOOD]民族国家[\LINK]内政法令）。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]人身自由:[\BOLD]如果其他文明实行[LINK=CIVIC_EMANCIPATION]人身自由[\LINK]内政法令而你不实行会导致不满。实行人身自由的文明越多，没有人身自由的居民就越不满。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]导致快乐的原因[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]快乐的原因也很多。部分因素如下:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]资源:[\BOLD]许多[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]都可增加快乐：例如[LINK=BONUS_FUR]毛皮[\LINK]和[LINK=BONUS_GOLD]黄金[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]建筑:[\BOLD]寺庙，[LINK=BUILDING_COLOSSEUM]竞技场[\LINK]，和[LINK=BUILDING_THEATRE]剧场[\LINK]是游戏早期可增加快乐的建筑。[LINK=BUILDING_JAIL]监狱[\LINK]可消除厌战情绪导致的不满。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]奇观:[\BOLD][LINK=BUILDING_GLOBE_THEATRE]环球剧场[\LINK]可消除所在城市的所有不满。[LINK=BUILDING_ROCKNROLL]摇滚名人堂[\LINK]可提供热门单曲资源，可以产生一个快乐点数。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]内政法令:[\BOLD][LINK=CIVIC_POLICE_STATE]强化监控[\LINK]内政法令可消除所有厌战情绪导致的不满。[LINK=CIVIC_FREE_SPEECH]言论自由[\LINK]也增加快乐度（结合[LINK=BUILDING_BROADCAST_TOWER]广播塔[\LINK]的作用）。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]文化支出:[\BOLD]在获得[LINK=TECH_DRAMA]戏剧[\LINK]科技后，你可将收入部分比例投入[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化支出[\LINK]，提升文化等级和快乐程度。特定建筑例如[LINK=BUILDING_THEATRE]剧场[\LINK]和[LINK=BUILDING_COLOSSEUM]竞技场[\LINK]能进一步增加文化支出的作用。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]其他:[\BOLD]随着对游戏熟悉程度的深入，你将能发现更多影响城市快乐度的因素。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_HEALTH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Health[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]A [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City's[\LINK] health affects the rate at which the city accumulates [LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]Food[\LINK], and thus the rate at which the city grows (or starves). A healthy city will grow larger, faster, while an unhealthy city will languish.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Factors Affecting Health[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Many factors affect a city's health: the [LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]Land[\LINK] around it and its access to water and [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK], the city's population, its [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Buildings[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK], and the [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] that the civilization is running. Health-giving objects provide one or more "positive health points," displayed as little red crosses in white circles. Unhealthy objects provide one or more "negative health points," displayed as green unhealthy faces. [PARAGRAPH:2]Further, a city's population can be a major source of negative health points. The larger a city is, the more positive health points it needs to cancel out its population-based unhealthiness. Certain buildings, especially ones dealing with industry, will also add unhealthiness. And, finally, if you engage in any unpleasant nuclear exchanges with your neighbors, the resulting fallout can be extremely unhealthy for the few battered survivors.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Determining a City's Overall Health[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If a city has as many or more positive points as it has negative points, that city is healthy. If the city has fewer positive points than it has negatives, that city is unhealthy. The healthy and unhealthy icons are displayed at the top of the city screen, above the happy and unhappy face icons.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Unhealthiness[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A city loses one food for each point of excess unhealthiness. In other words, if a city has two positive health points and four negative points, the city will lose two food each turn. This will at the least slow the city's growth, and at the worst cause the city to [LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]Starve.[\LINK][PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Correcting Early Bad Health in a City[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There are a number of steps you can take to improve the health of your cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Site the City by a River:[\BOLD] A city sited on or near to fresh water gains health points from the river spaces its citizens work. You can check whether a tile is on fresh water or not by moving the mouse cursor over it.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Improve Food Resources:[\BOLD] Various food resources - [LINK=BONUS_DEER]Deer[\LINK], [LINK=BONUS_BANANA]Bananas[\LINK] and [LINK=BONUS_CRAB]Crabs[\LINK], to name three - provide positive health points once your workers build the appropriate [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Improvement[\LINK] on them. And if the improved resource is connected to more than one city by your road, river, and ocean trade network, all of your cities will gain the health bonus. Note that you can never get more than one health bonus from a single kind of resource; if you have two or more of the same resource, you still get only one health point (so you might as well trade the excess resources to your neighbors in return for his or her excess resources).[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Construct Buildings and Wonders:[\BOLD] Some buildings and wonders provide positive health points. The early [LINK=BUILDING_AQUEDUCT]Aqueduct[\LINK] provides positive health points, as does the [LINK=BUILDING_GRANARY]Granary[\LINK]. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Research Healthy Technologies:[\BOLD] Research the technologies which allow you to construct the healthy buildings. For instance you need to know both [LINK=TECH_MATHEMATICS]Mathematics[\LINK] and [LINK=TECH_MASONRY]Masonry[\LINK] to build an Aqueduct. There are a few late-game technologies that also add health to all of your cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Build Near Woodlands:[\BOLD] Cities receive extra health from having [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Forest[\LINK] tiles in their city radius. Chopping down these forests will reduce the health of the city - be careful not to send the city into starvation![PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Change Civics:[\BOLD] Certain civics add additional health to your cities. [LINK=CIVIC_ENVIRONMENTALISM]Environmentalism[\LINK] is one such example.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]健康[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]一座[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]的健康度会影响城市积累[LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]食物[\LINK]的速度，并进而促进城市的成长（或萎缩）。健康的城市能成长得更大，更快，而不健康的城市将陷入衰退。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]影响健康的因素[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]许多因素能影响城市的健康度：周围的[LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]地形[\LINK]，淡水，[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]，城市的人口数量，[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]和[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]，以及实行的[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]等等。促进健康的因素将增加一个或更多“健康点数,”显示为白底红十字图标。损害健康的因素将带来一个或更多“疾病点数,”显示为绿脸图标。[PARAGRAPH:2]此外，城市的人口是疾病点数的主要来源。城市规模越大，人口数量导致的疾病点数越多，也就需要更多的健康点数抵销其影响。特定的建筑，特别是工业类建筑，也会增加疾病点数。最后，如果你与邻国爆发核战争，核爆炸造成的辐射将严重影响城市的健康度。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]城市整体健康度的决定[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果城市的健康点数多于或等于疾病点数，城市即保持整体健康。如果健康点数少于疾病点数，则城市处于不健康状态。健康与疾病图标将显示在城市界面顶部快乐与不满图标的上方。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]不健康的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]疾病点数相比健康点数每多出一点，城市每回合将减少一单位食物。也就是说，如果一座城市拥有两个健康点数和四个疾病点数，城市每回合将减少两单位食物。这至少会减缓城市的成长，严重时则会导致[LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]饥荒.[\LINK][PARAGRAPH:2][H2]城市不健康状态的早期消除[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]有许多办法可提升城市的健康度。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市选址邻近河流:[\BOLD]城市位于淡水河畔或附近，可从有居民工作的沿河区域获得额外健康点数。你可以通过鼠标浮动提示查看某一地块是否与淡水相邻。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]获取食物资源:[\BOLD]各种食物资源——例如[LINK=BONUS_DEER]野鹿[\LINK]，[LINK=BONUS_BANANA]香蕉[\LINK]和[LINK=BONUS_CRAB]螃蟹[\LINK]——如果其上修建有相应的[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]区域设施[\LINK]将能提供健康点数。如果资源通过道路，河流和海洋构成的贸易网络与所有城市相连，所有城市都可获得健康奖励。注意一种资源只能增加一次健康点数；如果你有两个以上的相同资源，仍然只能获得一个健康点数（因此你应该用多余资源向邻国换取对方的另一种多余资源）。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]建造建筑与奇观:[\BOLD]某些建筑与奇观可增加健康点数。例如早期的[LINK=BUILDING_AQUEDUCT]引水渠[\LINK]，以及[LINK=BUILDING_GRANARY]粮仓[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]研究健康相关科技:[\BOLD]研究可启用增进健康类建筑的科技。例如你需要获得[LINK=TECH_MATHEMATICS]数学[\LINK]和[LINK=TECH_MASONRY]石工术[\LINK]才能建造引水渠。某些游戏后期的科技还能增加所有城市的健康度。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]邻近森林:[\BOLD]如果城市范围内存在[LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]森林[\LINK]将获得额外健康点数。砍伐这些森林会降低城市健康度——小心爱护城市周围的森林![PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]改变内政法令:[\BOLD]某些内政法令可额外增加城市健康度。[LINK=CIVIC_ENVIRONMENTALISM]绿色经济[\LINK]就是这样的例子。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_HURRY_PRODUCTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Hurry Production[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]There are various ways to increase a city's [LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]Productivity[\LINK], some permanent, some of limited duration. Here are some examples: [PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Increasing Productivity[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Population Growth[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The bigger a city, the more population that is available to work the land and thus generate hammers. It is generally a good idea to grow your [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK] as large as the health and happiness of the city will allow.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Improvements[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Tile improvements such as [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MINE]Mines[\LINK] increase the productivity of a hill or certain [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK]. A [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_WATERMILL]Watermill[\LINK] will increase the productivity of squares next to a river. And there are others, as well.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Buildings and Wonders[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Many buildings and wonders increase your productivity. For example, a [LINK=BUILDING_FORGE]Forge[\LINK] increases a city's productivity by 25%%, while the [LINK=BUILDING_GREAT_DAM]Three Gorges Dam[\LINK] wonder increases all of your cities' productivity by 10%%.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]The Great Engineer[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]A [LINK=UNIT_ENGINEER]Great Engineer[\LINK] can be sacrificed for a large number of production points, but this act consumes the unit. Great Engineers are useful for rushing early wonders.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Specialists[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The Engineer [LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]Specialist[\LINK] increases his city's productivity by two hammers. Other specialists may increase productivity as well.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Civics[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] [BOLD]Organized Religion:[\BOLD] The [LINK=CIVIC_ORGANIZED_RELIGION]Organized Religion[\LINK] civic increases a city's productivity by 25%%, but ONLY when that city is constructing a building and only if your state religion is present in the city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Universal Suffrage:[\BOLD] [LINK=CIVIC_UNIVERSAL_SUFFRAGE]Universal Suffrage[\LINK] increases [LINK=CIVIC_UNIVERSAL_SUFFRAGE]Town[\LINK] productivity by 1. It also allows you to spend gold to complete construction of a unit or building.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Bureaucracy:[\BOLD] [LINK=CIVIC_BUREAUCRACY]Bureaucracy[\LINK] increases the production (and commerce) in your capital by 50%%.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Slavery:[\BOLD] [LINK=CIVIC_SLAVERY]Slavery[\LINK] allows you to sacrifice a city's population to complete production on an item.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Nationhood:[\BOLD] [LINK=CIVIC_NATIONHOOD]Nationhood[\LINK] allows you to "draft" a city's population for military service. Drafting military units causes unhappiness and a reduction of population in the drafted city.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]加速生产[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]要提升城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]生产能力[\LINK]有许多方法，有的长期有效，有的存在持续时间。以下是一些例子:[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]增加生产能力[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]人口增长[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]城市规模越大，可工作的人口越多，城市工业产能越高。让你的[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]在健康度和快乐度允许的情况下尽可能地成长通常都是个好主意。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]区域设施[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]某些区域设施例如[LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MINE]矿井[\LINK]可提升丘陵地形或特定[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]的工业产能。[LINK=IMPROVEMENT_WATERMILL]水力磨坊[\LINK]可提升邻近河流地块的工业产能。如此等等。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]建筑与奇观[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]许多建筑与奇观可提升你的工业产能。例如，[LINK=BUILDING_FORGE]煅造场[\LINK]可使城市工业产能+25%%，而[LINK=BUILDING_GREAT_DAM]三峡大坝[\LINK]可使所有城市的工业产能+10%%。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大工程师[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]一位[LINK=UNIT_ENGINEER]大工程师[\LINK]可用于大量增加工业产能，但这会使其消失。大工程师适用于早期加速奇观建设。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]专业人员[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]工程师类型的[LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]专业人员[\LINK]可使所在城市工业产能+2。其他专业人员也可能提升工业产能。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]内政法令[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]信仰控制:[\BOLD]实行[LINK=CIVIC_ORGANIZED_RELIGION]信仰控制[\LINK]内政法令可使城市工业产能+25%%，但是只能作用于建筑工程，前提是城市信仰国教。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]普选制度:[\BOLD][LINK=CIVIC_UNIVERSAL_SUFFRAGE]普选制度[\LINK]可使[LINK=CIVIC_UNIVERSAL_SUFFRAGE]小镇[\LINK]的工业产能+1。并允许你以金钱为代价加速单位或建筑进度。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]官僚制度:[\BOLD][LINK=CIVIC_BUREAUCRACY]官僚制度[\LINK]可使首都的工业产能（及商业收入）+50%%。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]奴隶制度:[\BOLD][LINK=CIVIC_SLAVERY]奴隶制度[\LINK]允许你以人口为代价加速工程进度。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]民族国家:[\BOLD][LINK=CIVIC_NATIONHOOD]民族国家[\LINK]允许你“强制征召”城市人口加入军队。强制征召军事单位会导致所在城市的不满及人口减少。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Improvements[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Human settlements survive on the natural resources available to them from nearby terrain. At first they may do this without "working the land" - they may glean nearby forests for nuts and berries, while hunters bring in whatever local animals are at hand. However, these local resources tend to be finite, and as a settlement's population expands they must improve their ability to gather sustenance or starve.[PARAGRAPH:2]Over time, Man has developed sophisticated techniques for obtaining ever-increasing resources from the land. He builds farms to increase his food supply. He builds mines to obtain metals and fuels. He builds water mills to harness the power of rivers. He "improves" the land, making it capable of supporting ever-larger populations. In fact, Man's ability to gather greater resources with fewer people is the basis for all of civilization:  if one man can create enough food for two, the second man is free to create writing, or paint a picture, or build a cathedral.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Location of Improvements[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Improvements directly benefiting specific cities must be within that city's [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City Radius[\LINK], while improvements allowing your civilization access to certain [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK] can be anywhere within your civilization's [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Cultural Borders[\LINK] (though it is usually good if they are also within a city's radius).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Availability of Improvements[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Many improvements can be built only in specific locations: mines, for instance, must be built on hills (or atop certain [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK]), while farms can be built only where fresh water is available (until researching [LINK=CIVIC_CIVIL_SERVICE]Civil Service[\LINK]). Further, all improvements have a technology requirement; for example, you cannot build farms until your civilization has discovered [LINK=TECH_AGRICULTURE]Agriculture.[\LINK]  Finally, some improvements require that you have access to specific resources. [LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]Railroads[\LINK] require coal, for example.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Workers[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]In Civilization IV, most improvements are built by [LINK=UNIT_WORKER]Workers[\LINK] created in cities. These units cannot fight, nor can they create new cities, but they can build the farms, roads, and mines needed to support ever-bigger and more powerful cities. A civilization cannot flourish and grow without enough Workers.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Work Boats[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_WORKBOAT]Work Boats[\LINK] are similar to Workers in that they can construct improvements on water; they can build fishing boats, whaling boats, and, later on, offshore platforms. There is one major difference between Work Boats and Workers, however; a Work Boat is consumed when it creates an improvement. You'll need to build one Work Boat for every at sea improvement you wish to accomplish. (Workers are not consumed when building improvements.)[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Constructing Improvements[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] To build an improvement, move a Worker to the space you want to improve. The actions available to that Worker are displayed in the "unit button" section of the main screen; if your civilization meets the technology and resource requirement for an improvement and if that improvement can be built on that space, it will appear in the Worker's unit button. Click on the improvement and your Worker will begin construction. (If the improvement is greyed-out, you cannot make that improvement at that time. Mouse over the improvement to see what you are missing.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Constructing Roads and Railroads:[\BOLD] You can build [LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]Roads[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]Railroads[\LINK] in one of two ways: you can manually build the road one space at a time, or you can use the "Route To" command, in which you click on "Route To" and then on the target space. The Worker will figure out the shortest route to the target space and construct the road to that space without further orders. (Beware: this method requires less work from you, but your Workers sometimes may not choose what you would consider the most optimal route.) See [LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]Movement[\LINK] for the effects of roads on movement.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Time of Construction[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Improvements take one or more turns to complete. Time of construction varies, depending upon the [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] you have in place,  and certain [LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]Technologies[\LINK] will shorten construction time as well. Finally, two or more workers can construct the same improvement simultaneously, cutting the time of construction roughly in half.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Interrupting Construction[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You can stop working on an improvement at any time: simply click on the Worker building the improvement and give him new orders.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Pillaging Improvements[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Military units can destroy improvements in neutral territory or in the territory of a civilization you are at war with. To do so, move the unit to the target improvement and then click on the "Pillage" button (this will use up one of the unit's movement points). You may even be rewarded with plunder for your act of vandalism! If there are multiple improvements in a space (a road and a mine, for example) your unit will destroy one of them per turn. Note that roving [LINK=CONCEPT_BARBARIANS]Barbarians[\LINK] will happily pillage your improvements if they get the chance.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]区域设施[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]人类定居点的存在需要依靠附近地域的自然资源的支持。起初他们并不“在土地上劳作”——他们可能在附近的森林采集坚果和浆果，捕捉当地的野生动物。但是，本地的资源总是有限的，随着居民点人口的增长，们们必须改进获取资源的方式，否则就要挨饿。[PARAGRAPH:2]随着时间的推移，人类发展出了从周遭环境中获取资源的各种复杂技术。他们修建农场增加食物供给。他们修建矿井开采金属与燃料。他们修建水力磨坊利用河流的力量。他们“改造”土地，使其能够支持更多的人口。实际上，人类提升个人获取资源的能力是所有文明发展的前提：如果一个人能生产足够两个人吃的食物，第二个人就可以从事写作，绘画，或是建造大教堂之类的工作。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]区域设施的位置[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]为特定城市服务的区域设施必须位于其[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市范围[\LINK]以内，用于获取特定[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]的区域设施则只需位于本文明的[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]文化边界[\LINK]以内（但最好也位于城市范围以内）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]建造区域设施的条件[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]许多区域设施只能建造于特定位置：例如矿井必须修建于丘陵地带（或是特定[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]之上），而农场必须修建在与淡水相邻的地方（直到获得[LINK=CIVIC_CIVIL_SERVICE]文官制度[\LINK]）。此外，所有区域设施都有特定的科技前提；例如，修建农场的前提是发现[LINK=TECH_AGRICULTURE]农业[\LINK]科技。最后，有些区域设施需要已拥有特定资源。例如修建[LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]铁路[\LINK]需要煤炭。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]工人[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在文明IV中，大多数区域设施均由[LINK=UNIT_WORKER]工人[\LINK]修建。工人单位不能作战，也不能建立新的城市，而是用于修建农场，道路和矿井等为城市服务的设施。如果没有足够的工人，文明就无法发展繁荣。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]工船[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_WORKBOAT]工船[\LINK]与工人类似，用于修建水上设施；他们可修建渔船，捕鲸船，在后期还可以修建海上平台。工船和工人也有很大的不同；工船完成设施的修建后将会消失。每修建一个水上设施都需要新建一艘工船。（工人完成设施修建后不会消失.）[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]修建区域设施[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]要修建区域设施，需将工人移至目标区域。工人可进行的操作将显示为主界面的“单位命令清单”按钮；只要你的文明达到相应科技和资源前提，修建特定设施的命令将显示在这里。点击相应设施的按钮即开始修建。（如某一设施按钮呈灰色，则暂时无法修建。查看鼠标浮动提示可获知具体原因.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]修建道路与铁路:[\BOLD]你可以通过两种方式修建[LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]道路[\LINK]与[LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]铁路[\LINK]：或是一格一格地手动修建，或是使用“修筑道路到”命令，先点击该命令，再点击目标区域。工人将找出最近的连接路线并开始修建道路，无须进一步的命令。（注意：这个方式虽然比较省心，但有时工人可能不会选择你所认为的最佳路线.）有关道路对移动力的影响见[LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]移动吧[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]修建时间[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]修建设施需要一个或更多回合。具体的修建时间还受你实行的[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]的影响，特定的[LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]科技[\LINK]也可能缩短修建时间。最后，两个或更多的工人可以同时修建一个设施，大大减少完工所需的时间。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]中断修建[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你可在任何时候中断设施的修建：只需点击正在工作的工人下达新的命令即可。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]劫掠区域设施[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]军事单位可以摧毁中立区域或是敌国境内的设施。只需将单位移至目标设施并点击“劫掠”按钮即可（该命令将消耗一个移动点数）。你还可因此破坏行为获得收益！如果同一区块存在多个设施（例如道路和矿井）则每回合只能破坏其中一个。注意[LINK=CONCEPT_BARBARIANS]蛮族[\LINK]如果有机会，将十分乐于破坏你的区域设施。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_LEADERS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Leaders[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Each civilization in Civilization IV has one or two leaders available to lead it. When you start a game of Civ, you will pick which civilization you want to lead; if that civilization has two available leaders, you pick which of them you want to play. Each computer-controlled civilization has a leader as well.[PARAGRAPH:2] [H2]Leader Personalities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When you control a leader, you determine how your leader interacts with the world around him or her. Is the leader honest or shifty? Is the leader open, or paranoid? Is the leader aggressive or peaceful? It's up to you. When the computer controls a leader, the computer determines the leader's behavior. Often, the leader behaves like his or her historical counterparts - but don't count on it. Gandhi will USUALLY be peaceful and friendly, but he may from time to time turn out to be a warmongering backstabber. You have been warned!.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Leaders and Diplomacy[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A leader's personality and his or her interpretation of the current game situation will determine how the leader negotiates with you. Further, leaders have long memories; if you deal fairly with them, they'll remember it. And if you betray them, they'll remember that, as well. Check out [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomacy[\LINK] for more information on this topic.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Leader Traits[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Leaders in Civilization have "traits" which help determine the kind of civilization they are best at running. Each leader has two of the following traits:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Aggressive[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Free "Combat I" [LINK=CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS]Promotion[\LINK] for melee and gunpowder units.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Creative[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]+2 [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Culture[\LINK] per city per turn.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Expansive[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]+2 [LINK=CONCEPT_HEALTH]Health Points[\LINK] per city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Financial[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]+1 [LINK=CONCEPT_COMMERCE]Commerce[\LINK] on any squares which normally produce two or more commerce.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Industrious[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]+50%% [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDER]Wonder[\LINK] production.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Organized[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]-50%% [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civic Upkeep[\LINK] cost.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Philosophical[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]+100%% [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great Person[\LINK] birth rate.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Spiritual[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]No anarchy from changing civics.[PARAGRAPH:2]Each trait also allows civilizations that possess it to construct some buildings at double speed; for example, leaders with the Philosophical trait build [LINK=BUILDING_UNIVERSITY]Universities[\LINK] twice as fast.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Leader List[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Check out the [LINK=LEADER_ALEXANDER]Leader List[\LINK] for a complete list of the leaders in Civilization IV, their game traits, and historical backgrounds.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]领袖[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在游戏中，每个文明有一位或两位领袖。在开始新游戏时，你先要选择一个文明；如果文明有两位领袖，则需要再选择一位代表你的领袖。每个电脑控制的文明也由一位领袖所领导。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]领袖的个性[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当你控制某一位领袖时，就由你决定其对待周遭世界的方式和态度。这位领袖是诚实守信还是狡诈善变？是宽宏大度还是独断偏执？是强悍好斗还是热爱和平？一切都由你决定。当电脑控制一位领袖时，则由电脑决定其行为方式。通常，电脑领袖会的行为方式会与其历史原型保持一致——但并不保证如此。例如甘地——通常来说——会是爱好和平，温和友善的，但有时他也会变成一位笑里藏刀的战争狂。你要警惕这一点![PARAGRAPH:2][H2]领袖与外交[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]领袖的个性及其对游戏形势的判断会影响其同你进行谈判时的态度和意图。此外，领袖们的记性都很好；如果你同他们进行公平的交易，他们会记住。如果你背叛了他们，他们也会记住。相关详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]领袖特质[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]各文明的领袖拥有不同的“特质”，会影响其所领导文明的方方面面。每位领导人均拥有以下特质中的两种:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]侵略成性[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]肉搏单位和火器单位自动获得“格斗一级”[LINK=CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS]晋升[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]崇尚创新[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]每座城市每回合+2[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]开拓进取[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]每座城市+2[LINK=CONCEPT_HEALTH]健康[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]擅长理财[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]原有商业收入在2以上的区域+1[LINK=CONCEPT_COMMERCE]商业[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]勤奋刻苦[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]+50%%[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDER]奇观[\LINK]建造速度。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]组织严密[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]-50%%[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]经费。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]富于思辨[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]+100%%[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]出现几率。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]虔信神灵[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]改变内政法令时不经历无政府状态。[PARAGRAPH:2]此外每种特质还使相应文明建造某些建筑的速度加倍；例如，拥有富于思辨特质的领袖能使[LINK=BUILDING_UNIVERSITY]大学[\LINK]建造速度加倍。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]领袖清单[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]点击[LINK=LEADER_ALEXANDER]领袖清单[\LINK]查看文明IV中的所有领袖，性格特质以及历史背景介绍。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_MAINTENANCE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Maintenance[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]As a civilization grows, it requires an ever-larger infrastructure to support it. Entire new layers of bureaucrats appear to handle the increasingly complex business of empire. And with every new layer of bureaucracy comes new inefficiencies, as well as increased opportunities for corruption. In Civilization IV, this is reflected in your civilization's "city maintenance cost."[PARAGRAPH:2]Two factors determine a civilization's basic city maintenance cost: the number of cities you possess, and the distance of individual cites from a seat of government.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Number of Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]As you add cities to your civilization, the cost of managing EVERY city increases. Thus, as your civilization grows, adding new cities will quickly drive up your city maintenance costs. For instance, let's assume that the first city costs one gold to manage, and every new city increases the cost of managing your cities by one. So you pay one gold in management expenses when you have one city. When you build another city, you are now paying two gold PER city, so your overall costs goes up to four. Adding a third city will increase your maintenance costs to nine, and so on. (Note that these numbers are for example only; the actual formula for determining maintenance is more complex.)[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Distance from Seat of Government[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A city's maintenance cost is also affected by its distance from a "seat of government." At game start the [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE]Palace[\LINK], which appears automatically in the first city you build, is your seat of government. Cities farther away from the palace are more expensive to maintain than closer cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Lowering Maintenance Costs[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Courthouses[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Building a [LINK=BUILDING_COURTHOUSE]Courthouse[\LINK] cuts a city's maintenance cost in half. Courthouses are also required to build the Forbidden Palace national wonder (see below). If your civ finds itself choking under high maintenance costs from expanding too far afield, make sure to build courthouses as quickly as possible.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Move Your Palace[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If your palace is out on the edge of your civilization, you can construct it in a more centralized position. Warning: the original palace disappears when the new one appears.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Add Seats of Government[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Two wonders, the [LINK=BUILDING_GREAT_PALACE]Forbidden Palace[\LINK] and [LINK=BUILDING_VERSAILLES]Versailles,[\LINK] act as additional seats of government. Cities pay maintenance based upon their distance to the NEAREST seat of government, so spreading these about your empire will do wonders for lowering your maintenance costs. Although the Forbidden Palace is a [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]National Wonder[\LINK] and always available to your civ, be aware that only one civilization in the world will be able to construct Versailles.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]State Property[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=CIVIC_STATE_PROPERTY]State Property[\LINK] civic removes all distance-based maintenance costs.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Make More Money![\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You can, of course, counter the rising costs of city maintenance by simply making more money. See [LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]Wealth[\LINK] for further suggestions.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]维护费[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]随着文明的不断成长，需要更多制度方面的支持。例如处理国家事务庞大官僚机构将相应膨胀。官僚机构的膨胀会导致效率的降低，以及腐败现象的增加。在文明IV中，这些现象通过文明的“城市维护费”来体现。[PARAGRAPH:2]城市维护费的基本决定因素有两个：城市的数量，以及城市与中央政府所在地的距离。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]城市的数量[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]一个文明的城市数量越多，单个城市的维护费越高。因此随着文明的成长，城市的扩张将使城市维护费不断上升。例如，假设第一座城市的维护费为一个金币，每新建一座城市，所有城市的维护费都增加一个金币。则在一座城市的情况下维护费为一，在两座城市的情况下维护费为四，在三座城市的情况下维护费为九，以此类推。（注意此数值仅为举例；实际计算公式要更为复杂一些.）[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]城市与中央政府所在地的距离[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]城市的维护费还与距离“中央政府所在地”的远近有关。在游戏开始时，[LINK=BUILDING_PALACE]宫殿[\LINK]将自动出现在你建立的第一座城市，此即中央政府所在地。距离宫殿较远的城市维护费将高于较近的城市。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]降低维护费[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]法庭[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]建造[LINK=BUILDING_COURTHOUSE]法庭[\LINK]可使城市维护费降低一半。法庭还是建造紫禁城国家奇观的前提（见下）。如果你的文明因领土范围过广而导致维护费居高不下，就要尽快建造法庭。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]迁移宫殿[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你的宫殿位于国土的边缘，你可以在较中心的位置建造一座宫殿。注意：新宫殿完成后，原先的宫殿将消失。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]分设中央政府所在地[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]以下两种奇观，[LINK=BUILDING_GREAT_PALACE]紫禁城[\LINK]和[LINK=BUILDING_VERSAILLES]凡尔赛宫[\LINK]可以起分设中央政府所在地的作用。城市的维护费由与最近的中央政府所在地的距离决定，因此分设中央政府所在地将极大地降低维护费总额。虽然紫禁城属于[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]国家奇观[\LINK]，可以在任何时候建造，但要注意只有一个文明能建造凡尔赛宫。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]国营经济[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]实行[LINK=CIVIC_STATE_PROPERTY]国营经济[\LINK]将消除距离因素对城市维护费的影响。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]赚更多的钱![\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你当然可以通过赚更多的钱抵销城市维护费上升的影响。详见[LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]财富[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_MAPS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Maps[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]There are three different kinds of maps in Civilization IV: the main map, the mini map, and game maps. The main map and the mini map are sections of Civ IV's interface; see the manual for details on them. This entry deals specifically with game maps.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Game Maps[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Game maps are maps of portions of the world. You can acquire game maps from friendly villagers, or from other civilizations.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Maps from Villagers[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]When one of your units enters a village, the villagers may respond by giving you a map of local territory. When they do so, your main map is updated to display the newly-revealed territory. This territory is "explored" (see [LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]Exploration[\LINK] for more details).[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Trading Maps[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=TECH_PAPER]Paper[\LINK] technology allows you to trade maps with other civilizations. When a civilization trades you a map, all of the territory that civilization has [LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]"Explored"[\LINK] is updated on your main map. When you trade another civilization your map, that civilization learns about all of the territory that you have explored.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]地图[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在文明IV中有三种不同的地图：主地图，小地图，游戏地图。主地图和小地图是文明IV界面的两个部分；详情参见手册。本小节专门介绍游戏地图。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]游戏地图[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏地图是即文明IV世界地图的一部分。你可以从友好的部落村庄，或是其他文明那里获得游戏地图。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]从部落村庄获得地图[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]当你的单位进入部落村庄，村民可能向你提供附近区域的地图。在此情况下，你的主地图将即时更新以反映可见地图范围的改变。这一区域即被“探明”（详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]探索[\LINK]一节）。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]交换地图[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]获得[LINK=TECH_PAPER]造纸[\LINK]科技将允许你同其他文明交换地图。当其他文明同你交换地图，你的主地图将显示该文明已[LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]“探明”[\LINK]的所有区域，对方文明也将获知你所探明的区域。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_MOVEMENT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Movement[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]In Civilization IV, much of your time is spent moving your [LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]Units[\LINK] around on the map - you send them out to [LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]Explore[\LINK] new territory; you march them off to battle; and so forth. The basic rules of movement are simple; each unit in the game has a certain number of "movement points" (MPs) which they can expend each turn. Units spend MPs entering a new square; some terrain is more difficult to move through (and thus costs more MPs to enter), some less so, and some is impassable. Certain [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Improvements[\LINK] cut down the cost of entering certain spaces.[PARAGRAPH:2]There are three basic unit types in the game: land, sea, and air units.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Land Movement[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Land units may move only onto land [LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]Terrain[\LINK]. They may not move onto water (unless [LINK=CONCEPT_TRANSPORT]carried[\LINK] aboard a sea transport unit). Further, land units may not enter [LINK=TERRAIN_PEAK]Peak[\LINK] spaces.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Movement Speed:[\BOLD] Generally, foot soldiers have 1 MP, while horses and powered units have 2 MPs or more. Workers and settlers have 2 MPs. See [LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]Units[\LINK] for details.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Terrain Costs:[\BOLD] Open terrain - grassland, plains, desert, tundra and ice - cost 1 MP to enter. Hills, jungle, and forests cost 2 MP.[PARAGRAPH:2] Note: A unit can always enter a space if it has any MPs left. Thus, a 1 MP unit could enter a forest space, but its move would end there. (See [LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]Terrain[\LINK] for details.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Roads and Railroads:[\BOLD] [LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]Roads[\LINK] negate the movement costs of terrain; all spaces cost 1/2 MP to enter. (When you acquire the [LINK=TECH_ENGINEERING]Engineering[\LINK] technology, the cost goes down to 1/3 MP.) This benefit occurs only when a unit is moving from one road square to another, and only when the square the unit is entering is not within a hostile civ's [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Borders[\LINK]. [LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]Railroads[\LINK] are similar to roads, except that railroad squares cost 1/10 MP to enter from other railroad squares.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Rivers:[\BOLD] Rivers negate the effects of roads until you get the [LINK=TECH_CONSTRUCTION]Construction[\LINK] technology; in other words, moving across a river will act the same as if a road is not there at all.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Cities[\BOLD] All city spaces are considered to have roads in them. When you have acquired the ability to build railroads, city spaces will have railroads as well.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Water Movement[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Water units can enter only ocean, coastal, and coastal city squares. They cannot move onto land spaces. Water units cannot enter ice spaces.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Sea Unit Type Limitations:[\BOLD] Early water units - galleys and work boats - cannot enter ocean squares unless those squares are within your cultural borders (or another civilizations's cultural borders if you have an [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]"Open Borders"[\LINK] agreement). Otherwise they are limited to coastal and city spaces.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Movement Speed:[\BOLD] Early water units have 2 MPs; the fastest and most modern water units have as many as 8 MPs. The first civilization to circumnavigate the globe will also receive a +1 MP bonus to all of its water units.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Terrain Costs:[\BOLD] All coastal/ocean spaces cost 1 MP to enter. Ice spaces are impassable.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Air Units[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]In general, air units can enter both land and water spaces, including impassable ice and peak spaces. All spaces cost 1 MP for air units to enter. See [LINK=CONCEPT_AIR_UNITS]Air Units[\LINK] for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Promotions[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Certain [LINK=CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS]Promotions[\LINK] allow units to move faster through certain terrain types or grant them extra MPs altogether. For example, the Mobility promotion allows mounted and armored units to move faster through rough terrain and the Navigation promotions grant water units extra MPs.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Borders on Movement[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Your units can move freely within your territory and unclaimed territory, as well as through territory of civilizations with whom you have an [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Open Borders[\LINK] treaty. If you enter territory of a civilization without such a treaty, you declare war on that civ. You do not get the benefits of roads or rails when moving into enemy territory.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Other Units on Movement[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Other friendly or neutral units do not affect your units' movement at all; in other words, your units can move onto the same space as a foreign unit without attacking it. However, if your unit enters a space containing an enemy unit, your unit will initiate [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]Combat[\LINK] with the enemy.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Controlling Your Units[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You can use your mouse or keyboard to move your units. See the game controls section of the manual to learn how to "activate" units and tell them where you want them to go.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]移动[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在文明IV中，你将花费许多时间在地图上移动你的[LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]单位[\LINK]——你派遣他们去[LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]探索[\LINK]新的地域；你派遣他们参加战斗；诸如此类。移动的基本规则非常简单；每种单位在一回合内都有特定的“移动点数”（MP）。单位进入新区块时需要消耗移动点数；有的地形较难通行（进入时需要消耗更多移动点数），有的地形较容易，有的完全不能通行。特定[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]区域设施[\LINK]可以减少进入区块需消耗的移动点数。[PARAGRAPH:2]在游戏中有三种基本单位类型：陆地单位，水上单位和空中单位。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]陆上移动[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]陆地单位只在陆地[LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]地形[\LINK]中移动。它们不能进入水域（除非由海上运输单位[LINK=CONCEPT_TRANSPORT]运载[\LINK]）。此外，陆地单位也不能进入[LINK=TERRAIN_PEAK]山峰[\LINK]地形。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]移动速度:[\BOLD]通常，步行单位移动力为1，骑乘单位或机动车辆移动力为2或更高。工人与移民移动力为2。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]单位[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]地形消耗:[\BOLD]平坦地形——草原，平原，沙漠，冻土和冰原——消耗移动力为1。丘陵，丛林和森林消耗移动力为2。[PARAGRAPH:2]注意：单位只要还有移动力，就可以移动。因此，移动力为1的单位仍可进入森林地区。（地形相关详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]地形[\LINK]一节.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]道路与铁路:[\BOLD][LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]道路[\LINK]可减少地形对移动力的消耗；使进入任何地形只需消耗1/2移动点数。（如果已获得[LINK=TECH_ENGINEERING]工程学[\LINK]科技，消耗的移动点数还将降至1/3.）道路要发挥作用，起点和目标格都要有道路，而且目标格不能位于敌对文明的[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]国界[\LINK]以内。[LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]铁路[\LINK]作用与道路类似，在铁路上移动一格只消耗1/10移动点数。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]河流:[\BOLD]河流会抵销道路的作用，除非已获得[LINK=TECH_CONSTRUCTION]建筑构造学[\LINK]科技；也就是说，进行跨越河流的移动时道路将不起作用。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市[\BOLD]城市所在区块视为存在道路。当能够修建铁路时，城市区块视为存在铁路。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]水上移动[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]水上单位只能进入大洋，海滨以及沿海城市区块。它们不能在陆地上移动。水上单位也不能进入冰区。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]水上单位通行限制:[\BOLD]早期水上单位——桨帆船和工船——不能进入大洋水域，除非其处于你的文化边界之内（或其他文明的文化边界之内，如果双方签有[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]“开放边界”[\LINK]条约）。此外它们只能在海滨和沿海城市区块移动。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]移动速度:[\BOLD]早期水上单位移动力为2；最先进最快速的水上单位移动力可达8。最先完成环球航行的文明，其所有水上单位还将获得移动力+1的奖励。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]区域消耗:[\BOLD]进入海滨/大洋水域消耗移动力为1。冰区则不可通行。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]空中单位[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]一般来说，空中单位可在陆地或水域上移动，包括冰区和山峰地形。空中单位进入任何地形消耗移动力均为1。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_AIR_UNITS]空中单位[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]晋升[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]特定[LINK=CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS]晋升[\LINK]允许单位能更快速地通行于特定地形，或提升其移动力。例如，机动能力晋升可使骑乘单位和装甲单位在非平坦地形上更快地移动，导航能力晋升则可增加水上单位的移动力。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]国界对移动的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你的单位可以在本国领土和未划定边界的中立区域自由移动，也能进入与你签有[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]开放边界[\LINK]条约的国家的领土。如果你未签订此种条约而强行进入别国领土，则将引发战争。在敌方领土上移动时无法获得道路和铁路提供的便利。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]别国单位对移动的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]其他友好或中立单位完全不会影响你的单位移动；也就是说，你的单位可以进入别国单位所在的区域而不会引发战争。但是，如果你的单位要进入存在敌对单位的区域，则将发生与该单位的[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]战斗[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]控制你的单位[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以使用鼠标或键盘移动你的单位。有关如何“激活”与命令单位移动的操作请查看游戏手册。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_NUKES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Nukes[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]"Nukes," also known as "[LINK=UNIT_ICBM]ICBMs[\LINK]" (intercontinental ballistic missiles), can ruin a leader's whole day. These are the ultimate weapons available in Civilization IV, and they are extremely potent.[PARAGRAPH:2] [H2]Acquiring Nukes[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]To build nuclear weapons, you need the following: [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]The Manhattan Project Wonder[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Someone in the game must have built the [LINK=PROJECT_MANHATTAN_PROJECT]Manhattan Project[\LINK] wonder. It needn't be you; once anybody has built the Manhattan Project, everyone can build nukes (if they meet the other requirements).[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Rocketry and Fission[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]You need to know the [LINK=TECH_ROCKETRY]Rocketry[\LINK] and [LINK=TECH_FISSION]Fission[\LINK] technologies before you can construct nukes.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Uranium[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]You need access to the [LINK=BONUS_URANIUM]Uranium[\LINK] resource to build nukes. Uranium is uncovered by the [LINK=TECH_PHYSICS]Physics[\LINK] tech.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Constructing Nukes[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You build nukes in a city, just like any other unit.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Launching a Nuke[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Nukes have unlimited range: they can reach any [LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]Explored[\LINK] space on the map. Once launched, nukes reach their target space and detonate immediately.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Area of Effect[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Nukes are "area of effect" weapons; when detonated they cause damage in their target square, but they also cause damage to the eight squares that are adjacent to the target square. In fact, the eight adjacent squares get hit just as hard as the target square.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Damage Effects[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Buildings[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If a nuke detonates in or adjacent to a city, the computer makes a "kill check" against each building; if the building passes the check, it emerges unharmed. If the target building fails, it is destroyed (but see "bomb shelters," below). Wonders cannot be destroyed by nukes![PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Units[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The computer makes a "kill check" against each unit; if the unit fails, the check it is destroyed. If the unit passes the check, it may emerge damaged or unscathed. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Improvements[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If a nuke detonates on top of or adjacent to an improvement, that improvement too must go through a "kill check." (Exception: nukes never damage roads or rails.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Fallout[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]A nuclear detonation may produce "fallout" - radioactive debris - in any of the target squares. Fallout makes the space totally unworkable; in other words, a nearby city cannot draw food, commerce, production, or resources from a square damaged by fallout.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Scrubbing Fallout[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Once you have discovered the [LINK=TECH_ECOLOGY]Ecology[\LINK] technology, your workers can "scrub" (or clean) fallout. Scrubbing fallout is like any other worker action; multiple workers can scrub a space simultaneously to speed the job up; certain [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK] may cause workers to scrub fallout faster, and so forth. [PARAGRAPH:2][H2]SDI and Nukes[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=PROJECT_SDI]SDI[\LINK] project has an excellent chance of intercepting any nukes targeted at your territory.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Bomb Shelters and Nukes[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] A bomb shelter in a city reduces damage by 75%%.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Diplomatic Penalties[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There are serious diplomatic penalties attached to using nukes. Relations with other civilizations are almost certain to drop precipitously, and you may find yourself at the recieving end of someone else's nuclear arsenal. You have been warned![PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Global Warming[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Use of nuclear weapons will cause Global Warming to begin, turning previously fertile tiles into useless desert. Prolonged nuclear exchanges will transform the world into an uninhabitable wasteland.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]核弹[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]“核弹”，即“[LINK=UNIT_ICBM]战略导弹[\LINK]”（洲际弹道导弹），具有毁灭性的破坏力。这是文明IV中的终极武器，杀伤效果相当之强。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]制造核弹[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]要制造核武器，你需要以下条件:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]曼哈顿工程[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏中的文明完成[LINK=PROJECT_MANHATTAN_PROJECT]曼哈顿工程[\LINK]将启用核弹，而不必由你亲自完成；一旦某个文明完成曼哈顿工程，所有文明即可制造核弹（在满足其他前提的情况下）。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]火箭与核裂变科技[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你需要掌握[LINK=TECH_ROCKETRY]火箭[\LINK]与[LINK=TECH_FISSION]核裂变[\LINK]科技才能制造核弹。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]铀[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你需要拥有[LINK=BONUS_URANIUM]铀[\LINK]资源才能制造核弹。铀资源在发现[LINK=TECH_PHYSICS]物理学[\LINK]科技之后启用。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]制造核弹[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]核弹像其他单位一样在城市中制造。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]发射核弹[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]核弹具有无限的射程：能够打击任何[LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]已探明[\LINK]的区域。发射之后，核弹即命中目标并立即引爆。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]影响范围[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]核弹是具有“影响范围”的武器；核爆炸除了对目标方格造成破坏，也会对相邻的八个方格造成破坏。实际上，相邻方格与目标方格遭受的打击将同样巨大。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]破坏效果[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]建筑[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]核爆炸的影响范围如果包括城市所在方格，电脑将对每座建筑进行“死亡筛选”；如果某种建筑能经受筛选则将幸存。如果不能经受则将被摧毁（例外情况见下文“防空洞”）。但奇观不能被核弹摧毁![PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]单位[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]电脑将对每个单位进行“死亡筛选”；如果不能经受筛选将被摧毁。如果能经受则将幸存。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]区域设施[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]核爆炸的影响范围如果包括区域设施所在方格，该设施也将经受“死亡筛选”。（例外：核弹不能摧毁道路或铁路.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]辐射[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]核爆炸将在影响范围内造成“辐射”——放射性尘埃。辐射区域完全不能利用；也就是说，城市无法从辐射区获得食物、商业和工业产出，也不能利用当地的资源。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]清除辐射[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]一旦你获得[LINK=TECH_ECOLOGY]生态学[\LINK]科技，你的工人将可以“清除”（净化）辐射区域。清除辐射类似工人的其他行动；多个工人可同时清除同一区域以加快进度；某些[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]和[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]也可以加速工人清除辐射的速度。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]战略导弹防御系统与核弹[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=PROJECT_SDI]战略导弹防御系统[\LINK]工程有很大几率拦截来袭的核弹。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]防空洞与核弹[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]城市中的防空洞能使核爆炸造成的破坏减少75%%。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]外交惩罚[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]使用核弹有极大的外交惩罚。将造成与所有文明的关系急剧恶化，你也将成为其他文明的核弹所瞄准的目标。警惕这一点![PARAGRAPH:2][H2]全球变暖[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]使用核武器将引发全球变暖进程，使原先丰饶的土地变为荒漠。长期的核战争将使整个世界成为不适宜人类居住的荒凉星球。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_PRODUCTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Production[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]A [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City's[\LINK] basic "productivity" - that is, the speed at which it constructs buildings and units - is determined by the [LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]Terrain[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK] surrounding the city. Each terrain type and resource provides a certain amount of "production points" (a.k.a., "hammers" or also - to longtime Civilization fans - as "shields"). Hills and plains produce one production each turn, forests produce two, and grassland produces none. Various [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Improvements[\LINK] can increase a square's productivity. Mines, for instance, increase a hill's productivity to three per turn.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Changing Production[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Unlike previous Civilization games, production is saved separately for each item that a city chooses to build. If a city is building a [LINK=BUILDING_GRANARY]Granary[\LINK] and changes over to an [LINK=UNIT_ARCHER]Archer[\LINK] unit for defense, it must start production of the archer from the beginning; production does not "carry over" from the granary. After finishing the archer, the city could then go back to the granary and pick up where it left off before.[PARAGRAPH:2]Caution: If you wait too long to go back to a partially completed item, there will be a "decay" of production over time.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Hurrying Production[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]See [LINK=CONCEPT_HURRY_PRODUCTION]Hurry Production[\LINK] to learn how to speed up a city's production.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]生产[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]的基础“生产力”——就是指其完成建筑和单位的速度——由城市周围的[LINK=CONCEPT_TERRAIN]地形[\LINK]和[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]决定。每种地形和资源都可提供一定点数的“工业产能”（即“锤子”，或者对文明的老玩家来说——叫“盾牌”）。丘陵与平原每回合提供一个单位的产能，森林提供两个，草原则不提供产能。各种[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]区域设施[\LINK]可提升区块的产能。例如矿井，可使丘陵的产能提升为每回合三个单位。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]改变生产项目[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]与前代游戏不同，城市每个生产项目的产能是单独保存的。如果正在建造[LINK=BUILDING_GRANARY]粮仓[\LINK]的城市转而组建[LINK=UNIT_ARCHER]弓手[\LINK]用于防御，就必须从头开始弓手的组建；为粮仓积累的产能不能转而用于组建弓手。完成弓手的组建后，城市可以在原有进度基础上继续粮仓工程。[PARAGRAPH:2]注意：如果某项半截子工程时间拖延过久，其积累的产能可能“过期”。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]加速生产[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]有关如何加速城市生产的详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_HURRY_PRODUCTION]加速生产[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Promotions[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]It's well known that in war battle-tested veterans are more successful than green troops. They are better at staying alive, and better at seeing that the enemy doesn't stay alive. In Civilization IV, experienced troops earn "promotions" which give them special bonuses on offense, defense, healing, movement, and other martial-related skills.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Experience Points[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]Units[\LINK] gain promotions by acquiring "experience points" (or XPs) representing their training and practical battlefield experience. Only land and naval units get experience points; air units do not.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Training Experience Points[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Training XPs come from several sources. A land unit built in a city with a [LINK=BUILDING_BARRACKS]Barracks[\LINK] automatically receives 4 XPs. [LINK=BUILDING_DRYDOCK]Drydocks[\LINK] do the same for naval units. Various other [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Buildings[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK] provide training XPs too. The civic [LINK=CIVIC_VASSALAGE]Vassalage[\LINK] gives all new units 2 XPs, and the [LINK=CIVIC_THEOCRACY]Theocracy[\LINK] civic also grants 2 XPs for units built in cities with your state religion. Finally, certain civilization [LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]Leader Traits[\LINK] give bonuses also.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Combat Experience Points[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Units gain combat experience points by destroying an enemy unit in battle. It doesn't matter if the unit attacked or defended; as long as its enemy is destroyed, it gets an XP. Units DO NOT gain XPs for [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]Bombarding[\LINK] fortifications, nor do they get them if the enemy unit [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]Withdraws[\LINK] from combat (or if they themselves withdraw!).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Getting Promotions[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Promotions occur on a sliding scale of experience points. A unit gets its first promotion upon achieving 2 XPs. The second promotion requires 3 additional XPs (for a total of 5), the third 4 more XP (10 total), etc.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Promotion Choice[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Not all promotions are available to all units, and some promotions require that a unit have already gotten a specific previous promotion. When the unit is due for a promotion, the available promotions are displayed in the unit's "action box."[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Promotions List[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Look at the [LINK=PEDIA_MAIN_PROMOTION]Promotions List[\LINK] page to see all the promotions available in the game. Click on a promotion to discover which units can get it, its requirements, and its effects.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]晋升[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]众所周知，经历战火洗礼的老兵比刚入伍的新兵更擅长战斗。他们的生存能力更强，也能更有效地消灭敌人。在文明IV中，拥有经验的部队可通过“晋升”获得攻击，防御，治疗，机动等等方面能力的特殊奖励。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]经验点数[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]单位[\LINK]的晋升需要消耗代表其训练水平和战场经历的“经验点数”（XP）。只有陆地和水上单位可获得经验点数；空中单位没有经验点数。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]训练获得经验点数[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]通过训练可以获得经验点数。单位如果组建于有[LINK=BUILDING_BARRACKS]兵营[\LINK]的城市，将自动获得4点经验值。[LINK=BUILDING_DRYDOCK]干船坞[\LINK]则对水上单位发挥同样作用。各种其他[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]和[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]也可能提供经验点数。实行[LINK=CIVIC_VASSALAGE]分封制度[\LINK]内政法令可使所有新建单位获得2点经验值，而实行[LINK=CIVIC_THEOCRACY]神权政治[\LINK]内政法令可使信仰国教的城市组建的单位获得2点经验值。最后，有些文明的[LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]领袖特质[\LINK]也能提供经验值奖励加成。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]战斗获得经验点数[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]单位可以通过在战斗中消灭敌人获得经验点数。不论是作为进攻方还是防御方；只要敌人被消灭即可获得一点经验值。单位在[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]轰炸[\LINK]防御设施时不能获得经验值，如果敌方单位从战斗中[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]撤退[\LINK]（或已方撤退!）也不能获得经验值。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]获得晋升[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]晋升所需的经验点数各不相同。单位首次晋升需要2点经验值。第二次晋升需要另外3点经验值（共5点），第三次需要另外4点经验值（共10点），以此类推。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]晋升种类选择[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]单位不可能获得所有类型的晋升，某些晋升还需要其他晋升作为前提。当单位可以进行某类晋升时，可选晋升将显示在单位的“命令清单”中。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]晋升列表[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]请查看[LINK=CONCEPTS_PROMOTIONS]晋升列表[\LINK]页面了解游戏中的所有晋升类型。点击其中一项了解某种晋升所针对的单位类型，所需前提及作用效果。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_RELIGION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Religion[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Religion has always played a critical part in human history. Through religion, man has sought to make sense of the universe around him and to determine his place in it. Religion has inspired, enlightened and ennobled man; in its name men have erected beautiful buildings, written books of great wisdom, and made music of surpassing beauty. In its name men have also murdered and enslaved their fellows.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Religion in this Game[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]We know that people have extremely strong opinions about religions - in fact, many a war has arisen when these beliefs collide. We at Firaxis have no desire to offend anyone. However, given the importance that religions have had in human development, we didn't want to simply leave them out of the game altogether; instead we have tried to handle them in as respectful, fair and even-handed manner as possible. In fact, all religions in the game have the same effects, the only difference being their requirements.[PARAGRAPH:2]There are seven religions in Civilization IV (testing having determined that seven was the optimal number for gameplay). When determining which seven to include, we picked those religions that we thought would be most familiar to our audience. We do not mean to imply that these religions are more important, better or worse than any other religions.[PARAGRAPH:2]We offer no value judgments on religion; we mean no disrespect to anyone's beliefs. We're game designers, not theologians.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Founding a Religion[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If you are the first civilization to discover the associated technology, the religion is founded in one of your cities. It is extremely useful to have a city where a religion has been founded; it allows a prophet to create a "shrine" in that city (see below).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]State Religions[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When any cities in your civilization possess one or more religions, you may choose to assign one as the "state" religion. Having a state religion tends to make your cities possessing that religion happier and more productive; it also increases the effects of many religious buildings and religious civics.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Spreading Religions[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Religions spread randomly from city to city. Religions tend to spread from a city possessing the religion to nearby cities as well as to cities the possessing city has trade routes with. Some religious buildings (see below) increase the speed at which a religion will spread, and a civilization's religious civic (see below) can have a great effect upon the spread of religions, as well. [LINK=UNIT_BUDDHIST_MISSIONARY]Missionaries[\LINK] allow you to control the spread of religion; see the following section.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Missionaries[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Civilizations can construct special "missionary" units to spread the civilization's state religion. Each civilization may have only a limited number of missionary units in play at any one time, and each costs two gold per turn to maintain.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Building Missionaries[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2] Civilizations using the [LINK=CIVIC_ORGANIZED_RELIGION]Organized Religion[\LINK] civic can construct missionaries in any city with the state religion; if a civilization is not following Organized Religion, it can build missionaries only in cities with Monasteries.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Moving Missionaries[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Once constructed, missionaries can move about the map like any other unit. Your missionaries can freely enter your territory or neutral territory; they cannot enter another civilization's territory until you have an [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Open Borders[\LINK] agreement with that civ. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]How Missionaries Spread Religion[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]When the missionary is in the target city, click on the "spread religion" order in the missionary's unit box (see [LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]Units[\LINK]); if the attempt is successful the missionary's religion is now in the target city. Religions spread more easily into other cities within the missionary's civilization. Further, it is easier to spread a religion into a city with few or no religions already present; each resident religion decreases the odds of success. There is no limit to how many religions may be present in a single city; all seven religions can coexist in the same city. The missionary is consumed in the conversion attempt, successful or not.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Benefits of Religion[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Benefits[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]All cities that possess your state religion receive one extra happy face and produce one culture per turn. Spreading your state religion is thus a good way to expand cultural borders in the early stages of your civilization. The holy city for your state religion also receives an additional bonus of five culture per turn, allowing it to expand its borders very quickly.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Buildings[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Without a religion in a city, that city cannot construct religious buildings like Temples and Cathedrals (see below). Cities without religions also cannot create Priest [LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]Specialists[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Espionage[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If you control the holy city for a religion, you gain line-of-sight benefits in all foreign cities sharing your religion. This allows you to spy on what enemy cities are doing at no cost.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Shrine Income[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If you control the holy city for a religion and generate a Great Prophet, you can build the Shrine for that religion to generate income for every city in the world that possesses your religion (see below).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Religious Civics[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The religious [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] describe how religion affects your civilization. There are five religious civics in the game. You begin the game knowing only paganism; the other four become available when you learn their associated technologies.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Paganism:[\BOLD] No technology requirement. The basic religious civic. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Organized Religion:[\BOLD] Requires [LINK=TECH_MONOTHEISM]Monotheism[\LINK]. Increases production of buildings in cities with the state religion, and allows you to build missionaries without first constructing monasteries.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Theocracy:[\BOLD] Requires [LINK=TECH_THEOLOGY]Theology[\LINK]. Theocracy grants two additional experience points to units trained within cities with the state religion, and it stops the spread of non-state religions within the civilization.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Pacifism:[\BOLD] Requires [LINK=TECH_PHILOSOPHY]Philosophy[\LINK]. Greatly increases the [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great Person[\LINK] birth rate in cities with the state religion, and it increases the support cost of military units.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Free Religion:[\BOLD] Requires [LINK=TECH_LIBERALISM]Liberalism[\LINK]. A civilization with Free Religion has no state religion. Each city gets happiness for each non-state religion in the city; also, all cities get a 10%% boost in scientific [LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]Research[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Religious Buildings[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There are a number of religious buildings available to be constructed. Religious buildings are dedicated to specific religions and can only be built in cities which have that religion. A city with more than one religion can have religious buildings for each religion: for example, a city with Judaism and Confucianism could construct both a Jewish Temple and a Confucian Temple.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Temples[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The most primitive religious building. Temples boost a city's [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Culture[\LINK] and [LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]Happiness[\LINK]. They allow 1 population point to be turned into a priest [LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]Specialist[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Monasteries[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Monasteries increase a city's research by a small amount. More importantly, they allow the city to build missionaries to spread your religion.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Cathedrals[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Cathedrals drastically increase a city's culture. They increase happiness if their religion is the civilization's state religion. They allow two population points to be turned into priests. Note that "Cathedral" is a generic name for a religion's grander houses of worship - Jewish synagogues, Islamic mosques, Christian cathedrals, etc., all have the same effects. Your civilization can only build one cathedral for every three temples that your civilization possesses; for example, a civilization with seven temples could build two cathedrals. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Shrines[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Shrines can be built only in cities in which a religion has been founded. Shrines are constructed by [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great Prophets[\LINK]; a great prophet is the only unit that can build a shrine, and the prophet is consumed in the process. Shrines increase the spread of the religion, as well as the home city's culture. They increase the city's chance of generating prophets and allow the city to assign three population as priests. Most importantly, shrines generate one gold each turn for every city on the map that has the shrine's religion (thus explaining the importance of creating missionaries to spread the word). Each religion has a different name for its cathedral and shrine.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]宗教信仰[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]宗教信仰在人类历史上经常占据着重要的角色。通过宗教，人类寻求对宇宙的理解，确定自己存在的意义。宗教使人得到灵感和启迪，使人变得高贵和自尊；人们以宗教的名义修建宏伟的殿宇，撰写智慧的典籍，谱写美丽的乐章。人们也以宗教的名义屠杀和奴役着他们的兄弟姊妹。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]游戏中的宗教信仰[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]我们知道人们对于宗教信仰有非常强烈的观点和立场——事实上，信仰之间的冲突曾经导致了无数的战争。游戏的开发者无意冒犯任何人的信仰。但是，考虑到宗教信仰在人类文明发展中的重要作用，我们不能将这一重要元素排除在游戏之外；而且尽最大努力，以尊重，公正与中立的态度处理宗教元素。事实上，游戏中所有宗教的作用都是相同的，唯一不同的只是其创立的前提。[PARAGRAPH:2]在文明IV中有七种宗教信仰（经测试采用这个数量可以获得最佳的游戏性）。在具体选择时，我们采用了我们认为公众最为熟悉的几种宗教。我们并不认为这几种宗教比其他信仰更好或是更重要。[PARAGRAPH:2]我们并不对各种宗教进行价值判断；我们尊重任何人的任何信仰。我们是游戏设计师，不是神学家。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]创立宗教[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你率先发现与特定宗教相关联的科技，该宗教将在你的某一城市中创立。拥有一座宗教创始城市有非常多的好处；这将允许大预言家在该城市中建立一座“圣坛”（见下文）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]官方信仰[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你的城市中存在一种或几种宗教信仰，你可以选择其中一种作为“官方”信仰（国教）。设立官方信仰可使信仰该宗教的城市快乐度更高，生产能力更强；还可以提升宗教建筑和宗教制度类内政法令的作用。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]传播宗教信仰[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]宗教信仰会在城市间随机传播。宗教会传播到邻近的城市，或是有商路相连的城市。某些宗教建筑（见下文）可以提升相应宗教的传播速度，文明所实行的内政法令（见下文）也对宗教的传播具有重要作用。[LINK=UNIT_BUDDHIST_MISSIONARY]传教士[\LINK]使你可以主动进行传教；相关详情见下节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]传教士[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]一个文明可以组建专门的“传教士”单位以传播其官方信仰。每个文明在同一时刻保有的传教士数量有一定限制，每个传教士单位每回合的维持费为两个金币。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]训练传教士[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]实行[LINK=CIVIC_ORGANIZED_RELIGION]信仰控制[\LINK]内政法令的文明可以在任何信仰国教的城市训练传教士；对于不采用信仰控制政策的文明，则只能在建有修道院的城市训练传教士。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]移动传教士[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]一旦训练完成，传教士可以象其他单位一样在地图上移动。你的传教士可以在本国领土或中立领土中自由通行；但不能进入其他文明的领地，除非签有[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]开放边界[\LINK]条约。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]传教士如何传播宗教信仰[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]在传教士到达目标城市后，点击传教士单位命令清单中的“传播信仰”命令（见[LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]单位[\LINK]）；如果传播成功，则传教士的宗教将传入该城市。在本国城市传播信仰更容易取得成功。此外，在原来没有信仰的城市传播信仰也比较容易；每增加一种现存信仰，都会进一步降低传教的成功几率。一座城市存在宗教的数量没有限制；七种宗教可能在同一城市并存。传教士在执行任务后将消失，无论成功与否。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]宗教信仰的益处[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]对城市的益处[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]信仰国教的城市可额外增加一个单位的快乐值，并每回合产生一个单位的文化值。因此传播你的官方信仰是游戏早期扩展文化边界的好办法。官方信仰的圣城每回合还能产生五单位文化值，使其能够快速扩展文化边界。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]建筑[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]城市如不存在宗教，将无法建造宗教建筑，例如寺庙和大教堂（见下文）。不存在宗教的城市也不能供养神学家类的[LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]专业人员[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]间谍[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你拥有某一宗教的圣城，你的视野将扩展到所有信仰该宗教的外国城市。使你可以免费查探敌方城市的情况。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]圣坛收入[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你拥有某一宗教的圣城，并且产生了一位大预言家，你将可以建造该宗教的圣坛，使全世界所有信仰该宗教的城市都会为你带来收入（见下文）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]宗教制度类内政法令[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]宗教制度类的[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]可调整宗教对文明的影响。游戏中共有五种宗教制度。在游戏开始时只有原始信仰；其他宗教制度将在你掌握相应科技后启用。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]原始信仰:[\BOLD]无科技前提。基本的宗教制度。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]信仰控制:[\BOLD]需要[LINK=TECH_MONOTHEISM]一神论[\LINK]。提升信仰国教城市的建造建筑的能力，允许你训练传教士而无须建造修道院。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]神权政治:[\BOLD]需要[LINK=TECH_THEOLOGY]神学[\LINK]。实行神权政治法令，将使信仰国教的城市所组建的单位拥有两点初始经验，并禁止非官方信仰在本国的传播。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]和平主义:[\BOLD]需要[LINK=TECH_PHILOSOPHY]哲学[\LINK]。大大提升信仰国教城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]出现几率，并增加军事单位的维持费。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]信仰自由:[\BOLD]需要[LINK=TECH_LIBERALISM]自由主义[\LINK]。实行信仰自由的文明没有官方信仰。任何宗教都可提升城市的快乐度；并且所有城市额外获得10%%的[LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]科研[\LINK]加成。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]宗教建筑[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]可建造的宗教建筑有多种类型。不同宗教有相应的宗教建筑，城市必须信仰特定宗教才能建造相应宗教建筑。信仰多种宗教的城市可以建造多种宗教建筑：例如，同时信仰犹太教和儒学的城市即可同时建造犹太礼拜堂和儒学馆。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]寺庙[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]寺庙是最基本的宗教建筑。寺庙可促进城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化[\LINK]和[LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]快乐[\LINK]。允许1单位人口转化为神学家类[LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]专业人员[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]修道院[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]修道院可少量提升城市的科研能力。更重要的是使城市可以训练传教士，以传播你的信仰。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大教堂[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]大教堂可大大提升城市的文化等级。如所属宗教为官方信仰还将提升城市快乐度。并允许2单位人口转化为神学家。注意“大教堂”泛指任何宗教的大型活动场所——犹太教会堂，伊斯兰清真寺，基督教大教堂等等，其作用完全相同。建造一座大教堂的前提是已建有三座寺庙；例如，建有七座寺庙的文明将可建造两座大教堂。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]圣坛[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]圣坛只能建在创立宗教的城市。圣坛由[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]大预言家[\LINK]建造；大预言家是唯一能建造圣坛的单位，建造圣坛的代价是这位大预言家的消失。圣坛可提升相应宗教的传播速度，以及所在城市的文化等级。并能提升城市产生大预言家的几率，使城市可能供养三位神学家。更重要的是，圣坛能使全世界所有信仰相应宗教的城市为你的文明带来每座城市每回合一个金币的收入（因此训练传教士传播信仰是非常重要的）。每种宗教都有不同名称的大教堂和圣坛类建筑。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_RESEARCH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Research[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]To survive, your civilization must advance and grow technologically. Being backwards is suicide; advanced civilizations have huge advantages in expansion, growth, commerce, production, and, of course, in military units available to them. Your army may outnumber mine by ten to one, but if your army consists of archers and spearmen and mine of musketmen and macemen, you are going to get your butt seriously kicked. A small technological edge is powerful, while a large one is killer. (See [LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]Technology[\LINK] for more information on this important subject.)[PARAGRAPH:2]Each turn your civilization generates "research points" which go toward acquiring new technologies. The more research points generated, the faster your civilization will learn new technologies.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Generating Research Points[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The number of "research points" that you create each turn is determined by the amount of [LINK=CONCEPT_COMMERCE]Commerce[\LINK] the laborers in your cities generate. As your cities work the land around them, they earn food, production, and commerce. You use the "research button" to determine how much of that commerce you want to turn into research and how much you want in gold (see following). Only commerce generated by your cities can be turned into research: monies you earn from trading, pillaging and looting, merchant activities, and so forth are not available for this purpose.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]The Research Button[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The research button on the game's main screen displays the current percentage of your commerce you are dedicating to research. At game start it is set at 100%%; you can change this at any time. [PARAGRAPH:2]If your treasury is running low and your current research percentage would cost more commerce than you can spend, the game automatically lowers your research percentage to the highest percentage that you can afford. (You can manually adjust it even lower, of course.) Note that the game does not ever INCREASE your research percentage; any increases must be made manually by you.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Increasing Research Points[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]To get the maximum possible research points, first turn your research percentage up as far as it will go without bankrupting yourself. After that, there are a number of other things you can do. These include:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Construct Libraries and Other Buildings[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Buildings[\LINK] such as [LINK=BUILDING_LIBRARY]Libraries[\LINK] and Monasteries will increase a city's research.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Assign Scientist Specialists[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Change some of your city's populace into [LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]Scientist Specialists[\LINK]. [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK] such as the [LINK=BUILDING_GREAT_LIBRARY]Great Library[\LINK] allow you to change more of your populace into scientists.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Civics[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] like [LINK=CIVIC_FREE_RELIGION]Free Religion[\LINK] and [LINK=CIVIC_REPRESENTATION]Representation[\LINK] increase your civilization's research.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Increase Commerce[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Another way to speed up research is to increase the amount of commerce that your cities are generating. Building [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COTTAGE]Cottages[\LINK] with workers, settling more cities on the coast, and signing [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Open Borders[\LINK] agreements with other civilizations will all generate more commerce in your cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Increase Wealth[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Ironically, you can also increase the amount of research your civ is producing by generating more gold. Building [LINK=BUILDING_MARKETPLACE]Markets[\LINK] and [LINK=BUILDING_BANK]Banks[\LINK] will increase the amount of gold your civ is producing, which will usually allow you to increase the research button (see above) and thus generate more overall research! See the [LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]Wealth[\LINK] entry for more information on generating gold.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Expending Research Points[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]All research points are used to acquire [LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]Technology[\LINK]. See that subject for more information.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]科学研究[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]为了生存和发展，你的文明必须在科技方面保持不断进步。科技落后等于自杀；科技先进的文明将在所有方面体现出优势：拓展领土，增加人口，扩大贸易，促进生产，当然还有更强大的军事力量。质量低劣的军队面对装备先进的军队，即使拥有十比一的数量优势，也一样要被动挨打。拥有小幅技术优势即可体现威力，拥有大幅技术优势则将所向无敌。（关于科技的详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]科技[\LINK]一节.）[PARAGRAPH:2]你的文明每个回合将产生一些用以获取科技的“研究点数”。产生研究点数越多，获取新科技的速度越快。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]产生研究点数[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]每回合产生“研究点数”的数量受你的城市创造的[LINK=CONCEPT_COMMERCE]商业收入[\LINK]总量影响。城市周围有居民工作的区域将积累食物，工业和商业产出。你可使用“科研按钮”调整每回合商业收入用于科研和存入国库的数量之比（见下文）。只有城市所产生的商业收入才能用于科技研究：来自贸易事业和军事劫掠的金钱不在此列。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]科研按钮[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏主界面的科研按钮显示投入科技研究的商业收入的比率。在游戏开始时设为100%%；你可在任何时候改变比率。[PARAGRAPH:2]如果你的国库储备下降，商业收入不足以满足高比例科研经费，电脑会在尽可能高的前提下自动调整比率。（当然你也可以手动调节到更低水平.）注意电脑绝对不会自动调高科研经费比率；你必须手动调高。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]增加研究点数[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]要尽可能多地增加研究点数，首先应当在不至破产的前提下尽可能地调高科研经费比率。此外，还有其他一些办法。包括:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]建造图书馆等建筑[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]某些[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]例如[LINK=BUILDING_LIBRARY]图书馆[\LINK]和修道院可提升城市科研能力。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]供养科学家[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]将部分城市人口中国转化为科学家类型的[LINK=CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS]专业人员[\LINK]。某些[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]例如[LINK=BUILDING_GREAT_LIBRARY]大图书馆[\LINK]允许你在城市中安置更多的科学家。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]内政法令[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]某些[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]例如[LINK=CIVIC_FREE_RELIGION]信仰自由[\LINK]和[LINK=CIVIC_REPRESENTATION]代议制度[\LINK]可提升整个文明的科研能力。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]增加商业收入[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]加快科研的另一个办法就是增加商业收入总额。让工人修建[LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COTTAGE]农舍[\LINK]，在海滨建立城市，并与其他文明签订[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]开放边界[\LINK]条约将可带来更多商业收入。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]增加财富[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以通过赚取更多的金钱提升科研能力。建造[LINK=BUILDING_MARKETPLACE]市场[\LINK]和[LINK=BUILDING_BANK]银行[\LINK]将进一步增加金钱收入，使你能进一步调整科研按钮（见上文），然后产生更多的研究点数！有关获取金钱收入的详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]财富[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]消耗研究点数[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]消耗研究点数以获取[LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]科技[\LINK]。详情见相关小节。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_RESISTANCE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Resistance[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]After you capture a [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City[\LINK], it may be a while before its citizens recognize their good fortune in having gained such a wise and benevolent leader as yourself. In the meantime, they may "resist" your rule. Further, cities under great cultural pressure may go into resistance before revolting and "flipping" to another civilization's control (see [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Borders[\LINK]).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Resistance[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]No Production, Commerce or Food:[\BOLD] If a city is in resistance, its population refuses to work. Thus the city produces no food, production, or commerce for the duration of the resistance. This may lead to [LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]Starvation[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]No Cultural Radius:[\BOLD] The city has no [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Cultural Radius[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]No Defensive Bonus:[\BOLD] The city receives no defensive bonus for size or culture (see [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK]).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Duration of Resistance[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The duration of a city's resistance is based upon its similarity or dissimilarity to your civilization. If you recapture one of your own cities shortly after it was taken from you, you'll see little or no resistance. A foreign city that has been under a lot of cultural pressure from your civilization will tend to spend less time in resistance, as will a city that shares your civilization's religion. A big, old foreign city with a lot of culture and a different religion will tend to resist longer.[PARAGRAPH:2]You cannot do much to shorten the duration of resistance once it is in progress. However you can lessen the chances of the city returning to resistance by passing your state religion to that city and building temples and such, and by raising the city's culture and reducing any outside cultural pressure on that city. It is also a good idea to have one or two units garrisoning a city in resistance.[PARAGRAPH:2]A [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great Artist[\LINK] can instantly end resistance in a city by creating a Great Work in it - but be warned that this will consume the Artist.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]抵抗[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]当你夺取一座[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]，当地居民可能需要一段时间的体会，才能知道拥有你这样一位智慧贤明的统治者是多么的幸运。在此之前，他们可能会“抵抗”你的统治。此外，处于其他强势文化影响之下的城市也可能出现抵抗，暴乱甚至“叛逃”到其他文明（详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]国界[\LINK]）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]抵抗的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]没有工业，商业和食物产出:[\BOLD]处于抵抗状态的城市居民会拒绝工作。因此城市在此其间将没有食物，工业和商业产出。这可能会导致[LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]饥荒[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]没有文化影响范围:[\BOLD]城市将没有[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]文化影响范围[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]没有防御奖励加成:[\BOLD]城市将不能获得规模和文化等级带来的防御奖励（见[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]抵抗持续时间[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]城市的抵抗持续时间受双方文明相似程度影响。如果你在短期内收复一座原本就属于你的城市，可能完全没有抵抗活动。取得处于你方文化长期影响之下，或是与你信仰相同的异国城市，抵抗持续时间也会较短。规模庞大，历史久远，文化等级高，宗教差异大的异国城市的抵抗持续时间将会很长。[PARAGRAPH:2]减少抵抗持续时间的办法不多。你可以向占领的城市传播你的官方信仰，建造相应宗教建筑，提升城市本身的文化等级并减少外来文化的影响。在城市保留一个或两个防御单位也是个好主意。[PARAGRAPH:2]一位[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]大艺术家[\LINK]可以通过完成一件艺术杰作，立即结束城市的抵抗状态——但注意这将会使这位大艺术家消失。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_RESOURCES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Resources[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The world of Civilization IV contain various "natural resources" that have benefits for the civilizations which possess them. Some provide military benefits - the "horse" resource allows the creation of mounted units such as the [LINK=UNIT_CHARIOT]Chariot[\LINK] early on and [LINK=UNIT_CAVALRY]Cavalry[\LINK] in the Renaissance period. Some provide productivity benefits - marble decreases the labor required to construct the [LINK=BUILDING_PARTHENON]Parthenon[\LINK] wonder, for example. Other resources provide health and happiness to your cities, allowing them to grow to larger sizes and increase in power. A civilization that possesses a variety of resources will have a distinct advantage over one that possesses few or no resources, and resources are one of the most important factors to keep in mind when choosing city sites with settlers.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Discovering Resources[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Some resources - rice, gold, etc. - begin the game visible. You will be able to see these resources as soon as their space is visible (see [LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]Exploration[\LINK]). Other resources are hidden at the start of play: they are not uncovered until you have acquired specific [LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]Technologies[\LINK]. Copper is a good example of such a hidden resource; at game start no copper is visible anywhere on the map, but once you acquire the [LINK=TECH_BRONZE_WORKING]Bronze Working[\LINK] technology, copper is revealed.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Resource Locations[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Resources must be within your civilization's [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Cultural Borders[\LINK] in order to be connected to your [LINK=CONCEPT_CITY_NETWORK]City Network[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Working Resources[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]In addition to resources' special abilities, they also usually provide some kind of food, commerce, or production bonus to their space. For example, a wheat resource adds a significant amount of food to the tile on which it is located. If a resource space is within a city radius, that city's laborers can work that space like any other - and they will almost certainly want to, since resources are usually highly desirable tiles.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Resources and Improvements[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Resources require that "improvements" be made to their spaces before you can access their special bonuses (see [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Improvements[\LINK] for more details). Improvements are constructed by [LINK=UNIT_WORKER]Workers[\LINK] (except for water resources, which are improved by [LINK=UNIT_WORKBOAT]Work Boats[\LINK]). If an improvement is pillaged or otherwise destroyed, you lose the resource's benefits until the improvement is reconstructed.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Duplicate Resources[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]It is quite possible to have two or more of the same resource within your borders. Except for each space's production, commerce, and food value (see "Working Resources" above), you gain no additional benefit from multiple resources; a single resource is enough to take care of all of your civilization's needs. You may wish to hold onto the extras in case one is captured by an enemy, or you may want to trade the extras to other civilizations in exchange for their extra resources (see below).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Trading Resources[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You can trade any resource to other civilizations if that resource has been improved, and if it is connected by your [LINK=CONCEPT_CITY_NETWORK]City Network[\LINK] to your capital city (see [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomacy[\LINK] for more details on trading).[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]资源[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]文明IV的世界中存在各种能为拥有者带来利益的“自然资源”。某些具有军事价值——“马匹”资源使城市可以组建骑乘单位，例如早期的[LINK=UNIT_CHARIOT]战车[\LINK]和启蒙时代的[LINK=UNIT_CAVALRY]近代骑兵[\LINK]。某些资源带来产出奖励——例如大理石可以减少建造[LINK=BUILDING_PARTHENON]帕特农神庙[\LINK]奇观需要的工程量。还有的资源能为城市带来健康和快乐，使其能成长到更大的规模和更强的实力。拥有多种资源的文明相对拥有较少资源的文明，具有巨大的优势，资源也是城市选址最重要的考虑因素之一。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]发现资源[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]某些资源——稻米，黄金等等。在游戏开始时就是可见的。只要达到其所在区域即可发现资源（见[LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]探索[\LINK]）。其他资源在开始时不可见：直到你获得特定的[LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]科技[\LINK]才会在显示出来。铜就是此类资源的一个例子；在游戏开始时地图上看不到铜，但当你获得[LINK=TECH_BRONZE_WORKING]青铜器[\LINK]科技，铜即被启用。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]资源位置[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]资源必须位于本文明的[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]文化边界[\LINK]之内才能连入[LINK=CONCEPT_CITY_NETWORK]城市网络[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]获取资源[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]资源除了有特殊作用，通常还能为所在区域带来食物，商业或工业产出的奖励。例如，小麦资源能大量增加所在地的食物产出。如果资源位于城市范围之内，城市居民应该在资源所在地工作，获得更高的收益。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]资源与区域设施[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]要获取资源带来的特殊作用，需要修建相应的“区域设施”（详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]区域设施[\LINK]）。区域设施由[LINK=UNIT_WORKER]工人[\LINK]修建（水上设施则由[LINK=UNIT_WORKBOAT]工船[\LINK]）修建。如果设施遭劫掠或被摧毁，你将失去资源带来的收益，直到重建设施。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]重复资源[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你可能会拥有两个以上的同类资源。除了对区域的工业，商业和食物产出的奖励（见上文“获取资源”），重复资源并不会带来额外利益；一处资源即可满足整个文明的需要。但拥有额外资源可在一处资源被敌方占据时作为后备，也可以用来交换其他文明的额外资源（见下文）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]资源贸易[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以同其他文明开展资源贸易，前提是已建有相应区域设施并通过[LINK=CONCEPT_CITY_NETWORK]城市网络[\LINK]与你的首都相连（贸易的详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交[\LINK]一节）。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_REVOLUTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Revolution[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]A "revolution" occurs when you change your civilization's [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] or [LINK=CONCEPT_RELIGION]Religion[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of a Revolution[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]During a revolution your civilization descends into one or more turns of "anarchy." A civilization in anarchy produces no food, commerce, or production! Any progress towards completing buildings, units, or projects is stopped until the revolution is over.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Duration of a Revolution[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The duration of a revolt depends upon the number of civics that you change: one or two civics will usually result in one turn of anarchy, while three or more civics may cause two or more turns of anarchy. The civics screen tells you how many turns of anarchy you may look forward to after you choose which civics to change. If the length of time is too long, either make fewer changes or cancel them altogether until you can spare the time. Religions always have one turn of revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Immunity to Revolution[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Civilizations with [LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]Leaders[\LINK] possessing the "Spiritual" trait do not suffer the effects of revolution or anarchy at all.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Delay Period[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]After a revolution has taken place, there is a short period of delay before another revolution can be carried out. When the "Revolution" button appears once again on the civics screen, your citizens have recovered enough from the previous anarchy to carry out another revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]革命[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]“革命”会在你改变[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]或[LINK=CONCEPT_RELIGION]宗教信仰[\LINK]时发生。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]革命的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在革命发生期间，你的文明将进入至少一个回合的“无政府状态.”处于无政府状态的文明将没有任何食物，商业和工业产出！所有建筑，单位或大型工程项目都将暂停，直到革命结束才可恢复。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]革命持续时间[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]革命持续时间由你同时改变的内政法令数量决定：改变一项或两项内政法令通常会导致一个回合的无政府状态，改变三项以上内政法令可能导致两个回合以上的无政府状态。当你进行内政调整时，内政法令界面将提示具体可能导致几个回合的无政府状态。如果持续回合数过多，可以减少调整项目或暂时取消调整。改变官方信仰将导致一个回合的无政府状态。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]对革命免疫[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果文明的[LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]领袖[\LINK]拥有“虔信神灵”特质，则可免受革命的影响。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]延迟期[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在一场革命之后，在一段时期之内将不能再进行革命。直到内政法令界面中的“革命”按钮再次出现，你的文明才会从前一阶段的混乱状态影响中恢复过来，能够再次发动革命。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_SPACESHIP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Spaceship[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Constructing a spaceship and sending it on a successful journey to Alpha Centauri is one of the paths to victory. Alpha Centauri is the closest location of a potentially habitable world, so it has long been fantasized as the place most likely to contain other forms of intelligent life. Blasting into space with a ship capable of traveling to Alpha Centauri is a clear demonstration of the greatness of your civilization. Only an economical and scientific powerhouse could pull off such a feat.[PARAGRAPH:2]The spaceship components can only be built after discoverying most of the modern era technologies. In order to construct any of the spaceship components, you [BOLD]must[\BOLD] have first built the [LINK=PROJECT_APOLLO_PROGRAM]Apollo Program[\LINK]. Each component's production speed can be affected by several factors. Access to certain [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK] (most notably Aluminum) can provide production increases for certain components. A [LINK=BUILDING_LABORATORY]Laboratory[\LINK] in the city that is building the component always grants a 50%% increase in production speed. Finally, the [LINK=BUILDING_SPACE_ELEVATOR]Space Elevator[\LINK] wonder grants a 50%% increase in production on spaceship components [BOLD]for all cities[\BOLD].[PARAGRAPH:2]For more information about winning the game via the Spaceship, see the [LINK=CONCEPT_VICTORY]Victory[\LINK] Civilopedia entry.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]太空飞船[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]建造太空飞船并成功发射，开始飞往半人马座阿尔法星的远航是赢得胜利的方式之一。半人马座阿尔法星是距离我们最近的恒星，其中或许存在生存环境适宜的行星，因此许多幻想作品都相信那里居住着某种智慧生命。率先发射飞往半人马座阿尔法星的太空飞船，将确定无疑地彰显你的文明之伟大先进。只有经济最富庶，科技最昌明的强国才能做到这一点。[PARAGRAPH:2]建造太空飞船组件需要获得大部分信息时代科技。任何太空飞船组件的建造都[BOLD]必须[\BOLD]以完成[LINK=PROJECT_APOLLO_PROGRAM]阿波罗计划[\LINK]为前提。太空飞船组件的建造速度受以下几个因素的影响。拥有特定[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]（特别是铝）可加速某些太空飞船组件的建造。建有[LINK=BUILDING_LABORATORY]实验室[\LINK]的城市建造太空飞船组件的速度+50%%。最后，拥有[LINK=BUILDING_SPACE_ELEVATOR]天梯[\LINK]奇观可以使[BOLD]所有城市[\BOLD]的太空飞船组件建造速度+50%%。[PARAGRAPH:2]要了解通过发射太空飞船赢得游戏的详情，请查看文明百科中的[LINK=CONCEPT_VICTORY]胜利[\LINK]词条。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_SPECIALISTS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Specialists[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]When a [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City[\LINK] is first founded, all of its citizens are bound in the various requirements of day-to-day survival: hunting, fishing, tilling the land, and so forth. This may continue for some time, but eventually the city may grow large and prosperous enough that it can afford to dedicate some of its population to more rewarding pursuits. In Civilization IV, these more useful citizens are called "Specialists."[PARAGRAPH:2]There are six categories of specialists in Civilization IV: Engineer, Merchant, Scientist, Artist, Priest, and the default "Citizen" specialist. Each provides a city certain benefits.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Requirements for Employing Specialists[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]At the start of the game, you may only create one kind of specialist: the Citizen, who is the least useful of all of them. Each of the other specialist types requires certain [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Buildings[\LINK] or [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK] to be created. Further, each building or wonder will allow a limited number of specialists. For example, building a Temple allows you to create one (and only one) Priest in its city. But if you subsequently build a Cathedral there, you can create an additional two priests, for a total of three.[PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=CIVIC_CASTE_SYSTEM]Caste System[\LINK] civic allows you to create as many Merchant, Scientist, and Artist specialists in a city as you desire, regardless of whether or not you have the buildings that would normally be needed to create them. Be aware, however, that there is no way to get around the limitation on the number of Engineers and Priests that a city can support; you must have either the buildings or wonders necessary to create these specialists.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Turning City Population into Specialists[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When a city increases its population, it first seeks to employ that new population working the land around the city. (See [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK].) If any land spaces are yet unworked, the city puts the new civilian on the space it thinks will do the most good. A city can work up to  20 spaces - fewer if the city contains deserts or peaks in its [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City Radius[\LINK]. If you turn one of those working populations into a specialist, it no longer works the land. It still must eat, however, so the city's remaining working population must provide enough food for everybody. If not, the city will begin to starve. As a general rule, therefore, cities with more food will be able to create more specialists; cities that are food-poor will need all of their citizens to work the land just to prevent starvation.[PARAGRAPH:2]Once a city is working all available land, it automatically turns any additional population into specialists (keep in mind this usually will not take place until very late in the game!). It attempts to create the most useful specialist available; if no other slots are open, it creates a citizen specialist. You can also manually create specialists yourself by removing citizens from working the land (see below). When a city is about to grow past the level of [LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]Happiness[\LINK] that it can support, it is often a good idea to turn some of the population into specialists and halt growth rather than let the city increase in size and produce useless unhappy citizens.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Specialists and Great People[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]In addition to their other functions described below, specialists increase a city's generation of "Great People Points" by +3 each. Specialists also help determine what kind of great person the city will generate. See [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great People[\LINK] for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]How to Create a Specialist[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You can create a specialist on the city screen. The six types are visible on the right-hand edge of the screen. If a specialist type is grayed-out, you cannot build one. If a specialist is in full color, however, you can: click on the plus (+) sign next to the specialist you want
 to create. If you want to remove a specialist, click on the minus (-) sign. Creating a specialist removes one of your population points from working a tile in the City Radius.[PARAGRAPH:2]In order to manually select which tile to remove, first click on the tile that you want removed (the white circle around it should disappear). This creates a Citizen specialist. Then click on the plus (+) sign next to the specialist you want to employ, and the Citizen specialist will be replaced with the one you desire.[PARAGRAPH:2]Note that some [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK] automatically give you one or more specialists of a specific type; you can't remove or repurpose them at all. Some wonders and civics may also provide you with a free specialist in each city; in this case, you can choose which specialist to employ in each city, but cannot remove the specialist altogether.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Specialist Types[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Engineer[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Engineers increase a city's production by +2. They increase the city's great person generation rate by +3. They increase the chance that the city will generate a Great Engineer. [LINK=BUILDING_FORGE]Forges[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_FACTORY]Factories[\LINK], and similar industrial buildings are needed to create Engineers.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Merchant[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Merchants increase gold by +3. They increase the city's great person generation rate by +3. They increase the chance that the city will generate a Great Merchant. [LINK=BUILDING_MARKET]Markets[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_BANK]Banks[\LINK], and similar commercial buildings are needed to create Merchants.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Scientist[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Scientists increase a city's research rate by +3. They increase the city's great person generation rate by +3. They increase the chance that the city will generate a Great Scientist. [LINK=BUILDING_LIBRARY]Libraries[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_UNIVERSITY]Universities[\LINK], and similar research institutions are needed to create Scientists.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Artist[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Artists increase a city's research rate by +1, and its culture by +4. They increase the city's great person generation rate by +3. They increase the chance that the city will generate a Great Artist. [LINK=BUILDING_THEATRE]Theatres[\LINK] and other centers of the arts are needed to create Artists.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Priest[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Priests increase a city's commerce and production by +1 each. They increase the city's great person generation rate by +3. They increase the chance that the city will generate a Great Prophet. Temples, Cathedrals, and other religious buildings are needed to create Priests.[PARAGRAPH:2] [BOLD]Citizen[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Citizens increase a city's production by +1. They do not provide great person generation points, nor do they affect what kind of great person the city generates. Citizens require the construction of no buildings or wonders, and an unlimited number can always be employed. However, it is rarely worthwhile to create large numbers of Citizen specialists![PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Wonders and Civics[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Many wonders and civics can increase the power of specialists even further, with a variety of different effects.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Increased Great Person Points[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Several different wonders and civics increase the rate at which specialists create Great People. The [LINK=BUILDING_PARTHENON]Parthenon[\LINK] wonder increases the production of great person points by 50%% in all cities, and the [LINK=BUILDING_NATIONAL_EPIC]National Epic[\LINK] national wonder increases the rate by 100%% in the city in which it is built. The [LINK=CIVIC_PACIFISM]Pacifism[\LINK] civic also increases great person generation by 100%% in all cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Other Effects[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Other effects include increasing the output of the specialists themselves. For example, the [LINK=BUILDING_ANGKOR_WAT]Angkor Wat[\LINK] wonder adds +1 production to all Priest specialists, and the [LINK=BUILDING_SISTINE_CHAPEL]Sistine Chapel[\LINK] adds +2 culture to a
ll specialists. The [LINK=CIVIC_REPRESENTATION]Representation[\LINK] civic also adds +3 research to all specialists. Since all of these effects are cumulative, specialists can become very powerful if enough attention is paid to them.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]专业人员[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]当一座[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]初建时，所有的居民均需每日从事劳作以保证生存：捕猎，打渔，耕作等等。这种状况将持续一段时间，但城市会逐步发展得更大和更繁荣，并足够的能力供养一部分人口从事更有意义的活动。在文明IV中，这种作用更大的城市居民被称为“专业人员.”[PARAGRAPH:2]在游戏中有六种类型的专业人员：工程师，商业家，科学家，艺术家，神学家，以及默认的空闲“市民”。每种类型能为城市带来不同的利益。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]供养专业人员的前提[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在游戏开始时，你只能指定一种类型的专业人员：市民，市民的作用很小。其他类型的专业人员则需要建有特定的[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]或[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]。此外，每座建筑或奇观允许供养的专业人员数量也有一定限制。例如，建造寺庙使你能在该城市中供养一位（只能一位）神学家。但如果你再建造大教堂，你将可以再安置两位神学家，即总共三位。[PARAGRAPH:2]实行[LINK=CIVIC_CASTE_SYSTEM]等级社会[\LINK]内政法令使你可以供养任意数量的商业家，科学家和艺术家，而不论是否建有相应建筑。但是要注意，工程师和神学家的数量仍然会受到上述建筑或奇观条件的限制。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]将城市人口转为专业人员的作用[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当城市人口不断增长，新增居民将先占据城市范围内的空地。（见[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK].）如果存在空地，新增居民将在最适宜的空地上定居。一座城市范围最多包括20个方格——如果[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市范围[\LINK]内存在荒漠或山峰则可用方格将更少。如果你将其中一个方格中的居民转为专业人员，方格将变为可用空地。但专业人员也要消耗食物，城市的产出必须能满足全部人口的需要。否则，城市将发生饥荒。总而言之，城市食物产出越多，可供养的专业人员就越多；城市食物产出过少，则所有居民都必须在地块中劳作以避免挨饿。[PARAGRAPH:2]一旦城市的所有可用空地被占满，额外的人口将自动专为专业人员（注意通常只在游戏后期会出现此种情况!）。电脑将尽可能安排作用最大的专业人员；如果专业人员限制被占满，则将安置为市民。你也可以将居民移出所工作的地块，手动安置专业人员（见下文）。如果城市人口的增长即将超出[LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]快乐[\LINK]等级所支持的限度，则应该将部分人口转为专业人员减缓增长速度，而不是任其产生无用的不满的居民。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]专业人员和历史伟人[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]除了其他作用（见下文），每位专业人员还可使城市的“历史伟人点数”+3。专业人类的类型也会影响所产生的历史伟人类型。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]如何产生历史伟人[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以在城市界面中安置专业人员。六种类型显示在屏幕的右侧。如果某一类型呈灰色，则不可安置该类型人员。反之则可：点击相应类型人员右侧的加号（+）安置。如要移除一位专业人员，则点击减号（-）即可。增加专业人员则在城市方格工作的人口将相应减少。[PARAGRAPH:2]要手动选择要移除人口的方格，首先点击该方格（其周围的圆环将消失）。这将增加一个市民类型的专业人员。再点击某一类型人员右侧的加号（+），该市民将转化为该类型专业人员。[PARAGRAPH:2]注意某些[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]能够自动提供一位或多位特定类型的专业人员；在此情况下你将不能进行移除或调整。某些奇观和内政法令还可能为每座城市提供一位免费专业人员；在此情况下，你可以具体选择每座城市所供养的专业人员类型，但是不能将其移除。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]专业人员类型[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]工程师[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]工程师使城市工业产能+2。使城市历史伟人出现几率+3。使城市更可能产生大工程师。[LINK=BUILDING_FORGE]煅造场[\LINK]，[LINK=BUILDING_FACTORY]工厂[\LINK]，及类似工业建筑是供养工程师的前提。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]商业家[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]商业家使城市商业收入+3。使城市历史伟人出现几率+3。使城市更可能产生大商业家。[LINK=BUILDING_MARKET]市场[\LINK]，[LINK=BUILDING_BANK]银行[\LINK]，及类似商业建筑是供养商业家的前提。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]科学家[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]科学家使城市科研点数+3。使城市历史伟人出现几率+3。使城市更可能产生大科学家。[LINK=BUILDING_LIBRARY]实验室[\LINK]，[LINK=BUILDING_UNIVERSITY]大学[\LINK]，及类似科研机构是供养科学家的前提。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]艺术家[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]艺术家使城市科研点数+1，文化+4。使城市历史伟人出现几率+3。使城市更可能产生大艺术家。[LINK=BUILDING_THEATRE]剧场[\LINK]及其他艺术设施是供养艺术家的前提。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]神学家[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]神学家使城市商业收入与工业产出同时+1。使城市历史伟人出现几率+3。使城市更可能产生大预言家。寺庙，大教堂，及其他宗教建筑是供养神学前的前提。
[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]市民[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]市民使城市工业产能+1。但不增加历史伟人点数，也不影响城市产生历史伟人的类型。供养市民没有任何建筑前提，也没有数量限制。但是，安置大量市民型专业人员并没有多少价值![PARAGRAPH:2][H2]奇观与内政法令[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]许多奇观和内政法令可进一步提升专业人员的作用，具体影响各不相同。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]增加历史伟人点数[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]某些奇观与内政法令可提升专业人员产生历史伟人的几率。[LINK=BUILDING_PARTHENON]帕特农神庙[\LINK]奇观可使所有城市的历史伟人出现几率+50%%，而[LINK=BUILDING_NATIONAL_EPIC]民族史诗[\LINK]国家奇观可使所在城市历史伟人出现几率+100%%。[LINK=CIVIC_PACIFISM]和平主义[\LINK]内政法令也可使所有城市的历史伟人出现几率+100%%。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]其他作用[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]其他作用包括提升专业人员本身带来的产出。例如，[LINK=BUILDING_ANGKOR_WAT]吴哥窟[\LINK]奇观使所有神学家的产出作用+1，而[LINK=BUILDING_SISTINE_CHAPEL]西斯廷教堂[\LINK]使所有专业人员额外+2文化点数。[LINK=CIVIC_REPRESENTATION]代议制度[\LINK]内政法令使所有专业人员额外+3科研点数。所有这些作用均可累加，因此只要安排得法，专业人员将发挥巨大的效果。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_SPIES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Spies[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Spies are special "invisible" units which can sneak around the map and have a variety of special abilities. Spies also function defensively by increasing the odds of an enemy spy being exposed if it performs a mission in a nearby tiles.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Constructing Spies[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Spies may be built only in a city with the [LINK=BUILDING_SCOTLAND_YARD]Scotland Yard[\LINK] national wonder.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Invisible[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Spy units are invisible. They cannot be seen, attacked, or otherwise interacted with.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Movement[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Spies move like other units, except that they do not cause an automatic declaration of war when crossing foreign [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Borders[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Spy Missions[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Spies may perform a variety of missions, some of which are automatically fatal and others of which contain a chance of destruction. Spies can perform these missions anywhere on the map, including in territory belonging to allies or to civilizations you are at war with.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Exploration[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Being invisible, spies can move through neutral, friendly and enemy territory without risk.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Investigate City[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Upon entering a foreign city, a spy may look at it's City Screen and thus know important things, like what defenses the city contains, what it is currently building, and so forth.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Destroy Production[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]A spy performs this in a city. If successful, the spy survives and the city loses half of the production points towards whatever it is currently producing. For example, this can be quite devastating if the city is just a couple of turns from completing construction of a wonder. If the mission is unsuccessful, no production is lost and the spy is destroyed.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Sabotage Improvement[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]This is performed on any space containing an [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Improvement[\LINK]. If successful, the improvement is destroyed and the spy survives. If unsuccessful, the spy is destroyed and the improvement survives.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Steal Plans[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]This mission has a much higher chance of success in one of a civilization's "centers of government" - a city containing the [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE]Palace[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_GREAT_PALACE]Forbidden Palace[\LINK] or [LINK=BUILDING_VERSAILLES]Versailles[\LINK] wonder. If successful, the spy survives and you get to see everything that is visible to the foreign civilization. This includes everything in its territory or within sight of its units and borders. If unsuccessful, the spy dies and you don't get to see anything.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Determining Success or Failure of a Spy Mission[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The odds of success or failure of a spy's mission depend upon the number of units the other player has in the space the mission takes place. If a space is unoccupied, the chances of success are quite high. The chances of detection and failure increase with each unit in the target space. Further, nearby enemy spies significantly increase the chances of being caught.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Diplomatic Effects of Missions[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If a mission is successful, the target civilization will not know who performed the mission; thus that civilization's opinion of you will not change (see [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomacy[\LINK]). If the mission is a failure, the target civilization will know exactly who is responsible for the outrage and will adjust its opinion of you appropriately. It is quite possible for a failed spy mission to cause the victim civilization to declare war on your civilization![PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]间谍[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]间谍是特殊的“隐身”单位，可以四处潜行，具有许多特殊能力。间谍也可以作为防御性单位，用于发现敌方派来的间谍。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]训练间谍[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]间谍只能在建有[LINK=BUILDING_SCOTLAND_YARD]苏格兰场[\LINK]国家奇观的城市建造。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]隐身[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]间谍单位有隐身能力。他不能被普通单位所发现和攻击。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]移动[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]间谍的移动方式与其他单位类似，但是其在穿越别国[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]边界[\LINK]时不会引发战争。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]间谍的任务[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]间谍可以执行多种任务，有些必然发生作用，有些则有特定成功几率。间谍可在任何地方执行任务，包括在盟国和敌国的领土范围之内。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]探索[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]由于有隐身能力，间谍能够安全地通行于中立，友好和敌对方的领土。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]侦察城市[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]间谍进入别国城市时，可以查看城市界面了解重要信息，例如城市的防御设施，当前建造项目等等。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]破坏工程项目[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]间谍可在城市中执行此种任务。如果成功，间谍将存活下来，城市将失去当前建造项目所积累工业值的一半。如果此时城市只差几回合就能完成一座奇观，就会对其造成严重的打击。如果任务失败，则不会减少工业值，并将失去该间谍。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]破坏区域设施[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]间谍可在任何建有[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]区域设施[\LINK]的地方执行此种任务。如果成功，该设施将被摧毁，间谍继续存活。如果失败，失去间谍，保留设施。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]窃取计划[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]此种任务如在文明的“政治中心”——即建有[LINK=BUILDING_PALACE]宫殿[\LINK]，[LINK=BUILDING_GREAT_PALACE]紫禁城[\LINK]或[LINK=BUILDING_VERSAILLES]凡尔赛宫[\LINK]奇观的城市执行将有更高的成功率。如果成功，间谍将存活，你将可以查看该文明的一切信息。包括其全部领土及其单位视野所及的范围。如果失败，间谍消失，你什么也看不到。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]决定间谍任务成败的因素[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]间谍任务的成功几率与所在地的对方单位数量有关。如果当地无单位驻守，成功几率将很高。每增加一个驻守单位，失败几率就上升一点。此外，如果附近存在敌方间谍，任务失败的几率将大大提升。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]间谍活动对外交的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果间谍任务成功，对方文明将对此一无所知；因而不会影响其对你的态度（见[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交[\LINK]一节）。如果任务失败，对方文明将知晓是何人所为并相应调整对你的态度。一次失败的间谍行动很可能会导致对方文明向你宣战![PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Technology[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Judged strictly upon his physical capabilities, man is not a particularly well-designed animal. Other animals are faster and stronger, others have keener senses, and others are far better equipped for combat. None, however, is as good as man at "technology" - the ability to create practical applications based upon knowledge of his environment.[PARAGRAPH:2]Take the wheel, for example. Many creatures - mountain goats, for instance - are probably well aware that round rocks move more easily than do flat ones. But beyond figuring out that leaping onto round rocks is a good way to break their neck, goats have not otherwise exploited that knowledge. Man, on the other hand, figured out a way to use that knowledge to his great advantage: he created the technology of the wheel.[PARAGRAPH:2]There are over 80 technologies available in Civilization IV, each representing an important advance in mankind's ability to manipulate the environment.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Acquiring Technology[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Each civilization begins the game with knowledge of several primitive technologies. This list varies from civilization to civilization: one may know [LINK=TECH_THE_WHEEL]The Wheel[\LINK] and [LINK=TECH_AGRICULTURE]Agriculture[\LINK], while another may know [LINK=TECH_MYSTICISM]Mysticism[\LINK] and [LINK=TECH_FISHING]Fishing[\LINK]. Beyond the known technologies, there are a number of ways to acquire new ones:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Friendly Villages[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]As your units [LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]Explore[\LINK] the world, they may encounter tribal villages. These villages may attack your explorers, or they may give them maps, money, or new technology. You need to find them quickly, however; there are only a limited number of tribal villages on the map, and all civilizations want them.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Diplomacy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]As the game progresses, you will be able to acquire technologies from other civilizations through trade. See [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomacy[\LINK] for details.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Research[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]You can discover new technologies on your own, through [LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]Research[\LINK]. This is the most common way to acquire technologies. See that section for details.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Choosing Techs to Research[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When you have completed research and learned a new technology, the "choose a technology" menu appears and you must choose another technology to begin researching. At that time the game will provide a list of available technologies for you to choose from. Many techs have "prerequisite technologies" that you must know before you can learn the new technology - for instance, you need to know the [LINK=TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY]Animal Husbandry[\LINK] tech before you can study [LINK=TECH_HORSEBACK_RIDING]Horseback Riding[\LINK] and get the versatile [LINK=UNIT_HORSE_ARCHER]Horse Archer[\LINK] units.[PARAGRAPH:2]Some technologies may have multiple prerequisites to begin researching them; other technologies require one tech OR another tech to research. [LINK=TECH_MONOTHEISM]Monotheism[\LINK] is an example of the first group; it requires [LINK=TECH_POLYTHEISM]Polytheism[\LINK] AND [LINK=TECH_MASONRY]Masonry[\LINK]. [LINK=TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY]Animal Husbandry[\LINK] is an example of the second group; it requires [LINK=TECH_HUNTING]Hunting[\LINK] OR [LINK=TECH_AGRICULTURE]Agriculture[\LINK], but not both. A tech will appear on your list only when you have learned the necessary prerequisite technologies.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]The Tech Tree[\BOLD]: The extremely useful Technology Tree (F6) displays all of the technologies in the game and how they are interrelated. You can select which tech to research from the tree, or choose a research path by clicking on a tech that you want which is not currently available to be researched. The game will choose the shortest possible path to reach the tech you have selected.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Time to Research[\BOLD]: Each technology requires a certain number of "research points" to learn. The "choose a technology" screen lists the number of turns it will take to learn each technology - at your CURRENT research rate. See [LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]Research[\LINK] to learn how to increase your research rate and thus shorten the time it takes to learn new technologies.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Changing Research[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You are free to change what your civilization is researching at any point in time. You can do this by clicking on the research bar at the top of the main game screen, or by opening up the Tech Tree (see above) and selecting a different tech there. Unlike previous Civilization games, there is no penalty for changing research paths. You can research half of one technology, change to a second technology and finish it, then return to the first one and pick up right where you left off before.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Technology[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Technologies allow you to do cool stuff: build new units, wonders and buildings, change your civics, discover a new religion, trade different stuff with other civilizations, and so forth. Some techs give special bonuses to the civilization that first discovers them. Note that some techs render some [LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]Wonders[\LINK] obsolete.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]科技[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]如果根据身体力量进行评判，人类不能算是一种完善的动物。其他动物有的速度更快，有的力量更强，有的感觉更灵敏，还有的天生配备撕裂对手的武器。但是没有一种其他动物能象人类一样掌握“科学技术”——根据对周围环境的知识制造实用工具的能力。[PARAGRAPH:2]以轮子为例。许多动物——例如山羊——也许都了解圆形石头比方形石头更易移动。但山羊最多只明白跳到圆形石头上可能摔断脖子，但绝不可能设法利用这一知识。而人类却不同，他们发现这一知识能为自己带来好处：轮子科技就此诞生。[PARAGRAPH:2]文明IV中有超过80种的科技，每种科技都代表了人类改变周围环境能力的重要进步。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]获取科技[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]每个文明在游戏开始时都拥有几项初级科技。不同文明拥有不同的初始科技：有的已发现[LINK=TECH_THE_WHEEL]轮子[\LINK]和[LINK=TECH_AGRICULTURE]农业[\LINK]，有的可能掌握了[LINK=TECH_MYSTICISM]神秘学[\LINK]和[LINK=TECH_FISHING]渔业[\LINK]。要获得初始科技以外的新科技有多种方式:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]友好的村庄[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]在你的单位[LINK=CONCEPT_EXPLORATION]探索[\LINK]世界时，他们可能找到部落村庄。这些村庄可能与你为敌，也可能提供给你地图，金钱，或是新的科技。但你需要快一点找到他们；地图上的部落村庄数量有限，其他文明可能抢先一步。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]外交[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]随着游戏的进展，你将可能从通过交易从其他文明获得科技。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]科研[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以通过[LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]科研[\LINK]自力更生发现新科技。这是获取科技最常用的方式。详情见相关小节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]选择要研究的科技[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当你完成一项科技的研究后，将出现“选择一项科技”菜单供你挑选接下来要研究的科技。菜单将列出所有可研究研究的科技。许多科技都有在研究之前必须已经掌握的“前提科技”——例如，你需要先获得[LINK=TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY]动物驯养[\LINK]科技才能研究[LINK=TECH_HORSEBACK_RIDING]骑术[\LINK]，以启用灵活机动的[LINK=UNIT_HORSE_ARCHER]骑射手[\LINK]单位。[PARAGRAPH:2]有的科技可能有多个前提科技；还有的科技可能需要某两项科技的其中任何一项作为前提。例如[LINK=TECH_MONOTHEISM]一神论[\LINK]就同时需要[LINK=TECH_POLYTHEISM]多神论[\LINK]以及[LINK=TECH_MASONRY]石工术[\LINK]。而[LINK=TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY]动物驯养[\LINK]就是需要[LINK=TECH_HUNTING]捕猎[\LINK]或者[LINK=TECH_AGRICULTURE]农业[\LINK]，但不必两者兼有。只有满足研究前提的科技才会在科技研究的选择清单中显示。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]科技树[\BOLD]：科技树界面（F6）显示游戏中所有的科技及相互之间的关系。你可以在科技树中选择一项当前要研究的科技，或点击一项当前不可研究的科技来设置研究路线。电脑将选择一条通往所选科技的最短研究路线。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]研究时间[\BOLD]：完成每项科技研究都需要付出一定的“科研点数”。“选择一项科技”菜单会标示完成每项科技研究所需的回合数——基于当前的科研能力。有关如何提升科研能力，减少研究时间的方法详见[LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]科研[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]改变科研项目[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以在任何时候改变当前科研项目。你可以点击主界面顶部的科研栏，或打开科技树（见上文）选择另一项科技。但与前代游戏不同，改变科研项目并没有惩罚性规则。你可以在研究某项科技的半途转而研究另一项科技，在发现另一项科技之后转回前一项科技的研究而不损失原有进度。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]科技的作用[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]科技使你能够做许多事情：建造新的单位，奇观和建筑，改变内政法令，创立新宗教，与其他文明开展各种交易等等。有的科技还能给予率先发现者特殊奖励。但要注意，某些科技会使得某些[LINK=CONCEPT_WONDERS]奇观[\LINK]过时。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_TERRAIN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Terrain[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]In Civilization IV, the world is made up of land and water "squares." Each square is designated as a specific "terrain type": for example, desert, hills, plains, coast, ocean, etc. Each may contain additional "features": forest, jungle, oasis, and so forth. A river may run along the edge of the square as well. All of these elements help determine the usefulness of the square as a place to build a city, as well as how easy or difficult it is to move through the square. And, of course, terrain may have important effects on any combat taking place in a square. The charts below display all of the effects of terrain on the game.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Land and Sea[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]All squares are either land or water squares. Water units cannot enter land spaces (except for coastal cities), and land units cannot enter water squares (unless carried aboard [LINK=CONCEPT_TRANSPORT]Transport Vessels[\LINK]). Some air units can enter both types. (See [LINK=CONCEPT_AIR_UNITS]Air Units[\LINK] for details on air units.)[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Terrain Effects on Movement[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Some terrain is more difficult to move through than others. See [LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]Movement[\LINK] for details.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Combat Effects of Terrain[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When two units fight each other in open terrain, both fight at their standard [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]Combat Strength[\LINK]. Some terrain gives benefits to the defender - for example, most units get "defensive bonuses" when they are occupying hills or forests. Such bonuses serve to temporarily increase the defender's strength for that battle. For example, a spearman at full strength (with a strength of 4) who is attacked while in a forest, gets a 25%% defensive bonus; for that battle, his strength is increased to 5. However, if that spearman were to attack, he would get no bonus from the forest - defensive bonuses only go to the defender. See the [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]Combat[\LINK] entry for more information.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Terrain Productivity[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Cities draw sustenance from the squares they occupy, and from nearby surrounding squares. Each terrain-type and feature provides a certain amount of [LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]Food[\LINK], [LINK=CONCEPT_COMMERCE]Commerce[\LINK], and [LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]Production[\LINK] to cities; the higher these values, the better for the city. Note that [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK] will further increase a square's value, as will various worker [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Improvements[\LINK]. See [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK] for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Rivers[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Unlike other terrain features, rivers run alongside land squares, not in them. Rivers can affect all squares they run adjacent to. Rivers negate the movement benefit of roads until you acquire the [LINK=TECH_CONSTRUCTION]Construction[\LINK] technology. Rivers also reduce an attacker's combat strength when the target is on the other side of the river. Rivers improve the commerce value of adjacent squares as well.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]地形[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在文明IV中，整个世界是由陆地或水面“方格”构成的，每个方格均属于一个特定的“地形”：例如，荒漠，丘陵，平原，海滨，大洋等等。每种地形还可能有附加“特性”：森林，丛林，绿洲等等。方格的边缘还可能有河流经过。这些元素将影响该地块是否适于建造城市，以及在该方块上移动的容易程度。当然，地形也对其上所发生的战斗有一定的影响。下面的表格显示了游戏中所有地形的效果。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]陆地与海洋[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]所有方格或是陆地，或是水域。水上单位不能进入陆地（除了海滨城市），陆地单位也不能进入水面方格（除非由[LINK=CONCEPT_TRANSPORT]运输舰船[\LINK]运载）。某些空中单位在两种地形中均可通行。（详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_AIR_UNITS]空中单位[\LINK]一节.）[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]地形对移动的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]某些地形比其他地形更难通行。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]移动[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]地形对战斗的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]当两个单位进行战斗时，除了受其[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]战斗力[\LINK]影响。有些地形能为防御方提供奖励——例如，多数单位在占据丘陵或森林时可获得“防御奖励加成”。这种奖励能临时性了提升防御方的战斗力。例如，一个满员的矛兵单位（战斗力为4）如在森林中遭到攻击，将获得25%%的防御加成；即其实际战斗力将为5。但是，如果是矛兵主动进攻，则不能获得森林地形的奖励——防御加成只对防御方起作用。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]战斗[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]地形产出[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]城市的产出来自于其所占据的方格，以及附近的方格。每种地形和地形特性均可为城市提供一定数量的[LINK=CONCEPT_FOOD]食物[\LINK]，[LINK=CONCEPT_COMMERCE]商业[\LINK]，和[LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]工业[\LINK]；数值越高，城市的收益越大。注意各种[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]以及工人修建的[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]地形设施[\LINK]还可进一步提升某个方格的产出。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]河流[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]与其他地形特性不同，河流出现在陆地方格的边缘而不其在其内部。河流可对相邻的所有地块产生影响。河流会抵消道路对移动力的提升作用，除非已获得[LINK=TECH_CONSTRUCTION]建筑构造学[\LINK]科技。河流还能降低进攻方的战斗力（如果目标在河流对岸）。河流还能提升相邻方格的商业收入。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_TRADE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Trade[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]You can trade a number of useful things with other civilizations: [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK], [LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]Technologies[\LINK], [LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]Gold[\LINK], [LINK=CONCEPT_MAPS]Maps[\LINK], and even [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK]. You can only trade with civilizations that you have met, and you need certain technologies in order to trade certain items. See [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomacy[\LINK] for detailed information on trade.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]贸易[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以与其他文明开展贸易，交易各种有用的东西:[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]，[LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]科技[\LINK]，[LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]金钱[\LINK]，[LINK=CONCEPT_MAPS]地图[\LINK]，甚至[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]。你只能同与你有联系的文明进行贸易，交易某些对象还需要特定科技。关于外交贸易的详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_TRANSPORT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Transport[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]In the world, all land masses are not linked together. Islands and continents may be separated from each other by miles and miles of ocean. Needless to say, land units cannot walk on water: they need "naval transports" to carry them.[PARAGRAPH:2] [H2]Transport Types[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There are six naval transport units in the game. Some may carry only specific types of units, while others may not leave the coastline or waters inside their [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Cultural Borders[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Galley[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=UNIT_GALLEY]Galley[\LINK] is the earliest transport unit. It can carry up to two land units of any type. The galley must remain in coastal spaces or spaces within your cultural borders (or within the cultural borders of civilizations you have [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Open Borders[\LINK] agreements with).[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Caravel[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=UNIT_CARAVEL]Caravel[\LINK] may carry one [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great Person[\LINK], [LINK=UNIT_BUDDHIST_MISSIONARY]Missionary[\LINK], [LINK=UNIT_SCOUT]Scout[\LINK], [LINK=UNIT_EXPLORER]Explorer[\LINK], or [LINK=UNIT_SPY]Spy[\LINK]. The caravel is the first naval unit that can enter all ocean spaces. Unlike most units, Caravels do not trigger war when entering other civilizations' territories.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Galleon[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=UNIT_GALLEON]Galleon[\LINK] can carry three land units of any type. It can enter all ocean spaces.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Transport[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=CONCEPT_TRANSPORT]Transport[\LINK] can carry four land units of any type. It can enter all ocean spaces.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Submarine[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=UNIT_SUBMARINE]Submarine[\LINK] is invisible to most units. It can carry one [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great Person[\LINK], [LINK=UNIT_BUDDHIST_MISSIONARY]Missionary[\LINK], [LINK=UNIT_SCOUT]Scout[\LINK], [LINK=UNIT_EXPLORER]Explorer[\LINK], or [LINK=UNIT_SPY]Spy[\LINK]. Submarines can enter all ocean spaces. Subs do not trigger war when entering other civilizations' territories.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Aircraft Carrier[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=UNIT_CARRIER]Aircraft Carrier[\LINK] can carry three [LINK=UNIT_FIGHTER]Fighters[\LINK] and/or [LINK=UNIT_JET_FIGHTER]Jet Fighters[\LINK]. It can enter all water spaces.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Loading Land Units onto Transports[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If a unit is in a coastal city that is also occupied by a transport that can carry that unit, activate the unit and click on the "board transport" action button. If a transport is in a coastal space, direct the unit to move into the transport's space and it will load automatically. A unit will not board a transport if the transport is full or if it is not allowed aboard that type of vessel. Loading a unit onto a transport uses up any remaining movement points that unit may have had that turn.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Unloading Transports[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If a transport is in a city, click on the unit you want to unload and then click on the "exit transport" action button. If the transport is in a coastal square, you can order the transport to move onto a land square and all units aboard will exit onto that space. If you wish to unload just one of the transported units, activate the specific unit and order it to move to an adjacent land space. Unloading a unit uses up all of the unit's movement points for that turn.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Loading and Offloading Carriers[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]To load a fighter onto a carrier, activate the fighter and then right-click on the carrier. To offload a fighter from a carrier, activate the fighter and then right-click on a friendly city.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Sinking Transports[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Transports can fight like any other naval vessels. If a transport is sunk, all of the units it carries go down with the ship. Land units cannot fight when loaded aboard transports; fighters can, if given the appropriate mission (see [LINK=CONCEPT_AIR_UNITS]Air Units[\LINK] for details).[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Transporting Gunships[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_GUNSHIP]Gunships[\LINK] (combat helicopters) can be transported by galleys, galleons, and transports and are treated just like other land units. They CANNOT ride on carriers.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]运输[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在游戏的世界中，不是所有的陆地都彼此相连。岛屿和大陆之间由广阔的大洋分隔。显然，陆地单位不能在水上移动：需要“水上运输单位”运送他们。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]运输单位类型[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏中共有六种水上运输单位。有些只能运送特定类型的单位，有些不能离开海岸线或超出本国[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]文化边界[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]桨帆船[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_GALLEY]桨帆船[\LINK]是最早的运输单位。它可以运送两个任意类型的陆地单位。桨帆船必须在海滨区域或本国文化边界以内航行（也可进入别国文化边界，如果双方签有[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]开放边界[\LINK]条约）。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]轻帆船[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_CARAVEL]轻帆船[\LINK]可以运送一位[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]，[LINK=UNIT_BUDDHIST_MISSIONARY]传教士[\LINK]，[LINK=UNIT_SCOUT]侦察兵[\LINK]，[LINK=UNIT_EXPLORER]探险家[\LINK]，或[LINK=UNIT_SPY]间谍[\LINK]。轻帆船是第一种能进入大洋区域的水上单位。与其他单位不同，轻帆船进入别国领海不会引发战争。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大帆船[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_GALLEON]大帆船[\LINK]可以运送三个任意类型的陆地单位。它可以进入所有海域。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]运输舰[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=CONCEPT_TRANSPORT]运输舰[\LINK]可以运送四个任意类型的陆地单位。它可以进入所有海域。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]潜艇[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_SUBMARINE]潜艇[\LINK]对多数其他单位不可见。可以运送一位[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]，[LINK=UNIT_BUDDHIST_MISSIONARY]传教士[\LINK]，[LINK=UNIT_SCOUT]侦察兵[\LINK]，[LINK=UNIT_EXPLORER]探险家[\LINK]，或[LINK=UNIT_SPY]间谍[\LINK]。潜艇可进入所有海域。潜艇进入别国领海不会引发战争。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]航空母舰[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_CARRIER]航空母舰[\LINK]可以装载三个[LINK=UNIT_FIGHTER]战斗机[\LINK]或[LINK=UNIT_JET_FIGHTER]喷气式战斗机[\LINK]单位。它可以进入所有海域。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]装载陆地单位到运输单位[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果一个陆地单位和一个运输单位在同一个海滨城市中，则可激活陆地单位并点击“装载”命令按钮。如果一个运输单位位于海滨区域，可将陆地单位移至运输单位所在区域即可自动装载。如果运输单位已满或类型不符将不能装载。装载命令将消耗陆地单位本回合的全部移动力。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]卸载运输单位[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果运输单位位于城市，点击运输单位并点击“卸载”命令按钮。如果运输单位位于海滨区域，可命令运输单位移向陆地区域，其所装载的单位将自动登陆。如果你只希望其中一个单位登陆，可激活该单位并将其移至相邻陆地。卸载命令将消耗陆地单位本回合的全部移动力。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]装载和卸载航空母舰[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]要装载战斗机到航空母舰，激活战斗机并右击航空母舰即可。要从航空母舰卸载战斗机，激活战斗机并右击本方城市即可。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]击沉运输单位[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]水上运输单位可象其他水上单位一样进行战斗。如果运输单位被击沉，其中装载的单位也将一同沉没。陆地单位在运输单位中不能进行战斗；战斗机则可执行战斗任务（详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_AIR_UNITS]空中单位[\LINK]一节）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]运送武装直升机[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_GUNSHIP]武装直升机[\LINK]（“空中炮艇”）可以和其他陆地单位一样由帆桨船，大帆船或运输舰运送。但不能装载到航空母舰。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_TREASURY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Treasury[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Your treasury shows how much wealth your civilization possesses. This must be a positive number or zero, or else your civilization will start selling off units and buildings to pay the costs. See [LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]Wealth[\LINK] for information on money and its many uses in the game.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]国库[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]你的国库储备指当前所拥有的金钱财富数额。这应该是正值或零，否则你的文明将解散单位变卖建筑以弥补亏空。金钱的概念及其作用的详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_WEALTH]财富[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_UNITED_NATIONS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]United Nations[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The United Nations is an important great wonder that can be built at the end of the game after a civilization discovers the [LINK=TECH_MASS_MEDIA]Mass Media[\LINK] technology. The construction of the United Nations opens up the possibility of a [LINK=CONCEPT_VICTORY]Diplomatic Victory[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Voting[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Once the United Nations has been built anywhere in the world, votes will begin being held every few turns. Every civilization that is still alive participates in these votes, regardless of how strong or weak they may be. The number of votes that a civilization receives is determined by population; the larger the population of a civilization, the more votes that its leader casts in United Nations elections.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Types of Votes[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Secretary General Elections[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The first United Nations vote will always be to determine which leader will be selected as Secretary General (see below for more information on the powers granted to the Secretary General). The civilization that builds the United Nations will always be one of the two candidates to stand for Secretary General; the other candidate for Secretary General will be the leader whose civilization has the highest population (or second-highest if that is the civilization who builds the United Nations). When voting for the Secretary General, each civilization will choose one of the two candidates to cast their votes in favor of, or can choose to abstain altogether. If one of the two candidates receives a majority of the total votes (including the civilizations who abstain), that candidate becomes the Secretary General. If there is no majority, the election is inconclusive and there will be another election for Secretary General again a few turns later. Nothing else may be accomplished until the United Nations selects a Secretary General.[PARAGRAPH:2]When a Secretary General has been chosen, he or she can choose from a list of the following resolutions to put to a vote. After three such resolutions have been voted upon, there is a new election for Secretary General, and the process repeats. Unlike the simple majority vote to determine the Secretary General, all of the following resolutions require 60 percent or greater of the total votes to be adopted.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Single Currency[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Adopting a Single Currency for the entire globe will naturally increase trade and commerce. Every city in the world receives an extra trade route.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Free Trade[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Adopting the Free Trade resolution removes all barriers to trade everywhere in the world. Trade routes function as though all civs have Open Borders with one another regardless of what their diplomatic situation may be.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]No Nukes[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Adopting this resolution causes an end to the proliferation of nuclear weapons. No civilizations anywhere in the world can construct nuclear weapons (although existing nukes do not disappear).[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Universal Suffrage[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Adopting this resolution forces all civilizations to change to the civic [LINK=CIVIC_UNIVERSAL_SUFFRAGE]Universal Suffrage[\LINK], regardless of whether or not they possess the technology to do so normally.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Free Speech[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Adopting this resolution forces all civilizations to change to the civic [LINK=CIVIC_FREE_SPEECH]Free Speech[\LINK], regardless of whether or not they possess the technology to do so normally.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Emancipation[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Adopting this resolution forces all civilizations to change to the civic [LINK=CIVIC_EMANCIPATION]Emancipation[\LINK], regardless of whether or not they possess the technology to do so normally.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Environmentalism[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Adopting this resolution forces all civilizations to change to the civic [LINK=CIVIC_ENVIRONMENTALISM]Environmentalism[\LINK], regardless of whether or not they possess the technology to do so normally.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Free Religion[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Adopting this resolution forces all civilizations to change to the civic [LINK=CIVIC_FREE_RELIGION]Free Religion[\LINK], regardless of whether or not they possess the technology to do so normally.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Diplomatic Victory[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The Secretary General may also put him or herself up for a Diplomatic Victory. With enough votes from the other civilizations of the world, he or she can win the game through becoming the undisputed leader of the United Nations. Who said nice guys finish last?[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]联合国[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]联合国是游戏后期重要的大奇观，获得[LINK=TECH_MASS_MEDIA]大众传媒[\LINK]科技后将可建造。建成联合国将启用[LINK=CONCEPT_VICTORY]外交胜利[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]投票[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]一旦任何一个文明建成联合国，每隔数个回合将进行联合国投票。所有仍然存在的文明都有投票权，不论其力量强弱。一个文明所拥有的选票数由其人口决定；人口越多，文明领袖在联合国中的投票权越多。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]投票类型[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]选举秘书长[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]联合国进行的第一次投票决定哪位文明领袖担任联合国秘书长（有关秘书长职权的详情见下文）。建成联合国的文明是两位秘书长候选人之一；另一位则是人口最多的文明的领袖（建立联合国的文明除外）。在选举秘书长时，每个文明可以选择支持某位候选人，也可投弃权票。如果某位候选人得票达到多数（总票数包括弃权票），即可当选秘书长。如果无人达到多数，则选举无效，将在数回合后重新选举秘书长。联合国必须选出秘书长后才能进行其他活动。[PARAGRAPH:2]秘书长经选举产生后，将可选择一项决议案提交表决。完成三项决议案的表决之后，将重新开始秘书长的选举，如此周而复始。当选秘书长只须简单多数，通过决议案则需要支持票占总票数的60%%以上。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]单一货币[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]全球实行单一货币，这能大大促进贸易和商业发展。全世界每座城市额外增加一条商路。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]自由贸易[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]全球实行自由贸易，移除所有贸易壁垒。对商路的增加效果相当于所有文明均相互签署开放边界条约。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]禁止核武器[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]通过此项决议将禁止核武器扩散。所有文明均不得制造核武器（但现有核武器不会消失）。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]普选制度[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]通过此项决议将使所有文明实行[LINK=CIVIC_UNIVERSAL_SUFFRAGE]普选制度[\LINK]，不论其是否拥有相应科技。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]言论自由[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]通过此项决议将使所有文明实行[LINK=CIVIC_FREE_SPEECH]言论自由[\LINK]，不论其是否拥有相应科技。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]人身自由[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]通过此项决议将使所有文明实行[LINK=CIVIC_EMANCIPATION]人身自由[\LINK]，不论其是否拥有相应科技。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]绿色经济[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]通过此项决议将使所有文明实行[LINK=CIVIC_ENVIRONMENTALISM]绿色经济[\LINK]，不论其是否拥有相应科技。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]信仰自由[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]通过此项决议将使所有文明实行[LINK=CIVIC_FREE_RELIGION]信仰自由[\LINK]，不论其是否拥有相应科技。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]外交胜利[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]秘书长可以发起全球领袖选举以触发外交胜利。如果获得足够票数，即可成为无可争议的世界领袖并赢得游戏。谁说好人没好报?[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_UNITS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Units[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]In Civilization IV, the term "unit" refers to anything that can move around the map. There are a number of different types of units in play - military units, work units, missionaries and great people - with military units forming the bulk of them.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Unit Statistics[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]All units have two basic statistics (or "stats"): movement speed and combat strength.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Movement Speed[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]A unit's movement speed determines how quickly the unit can move around the map. Movement speeds generally range from 1 to 8. Some units have movement speeds of 0, which indicates that these units have special rules governing their movement. See the section on [LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]Movement[\LINK] for details.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Combat Strength[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]A unit's combat strength determines how tough the unit is when fighting an enemy unit. Combat strengths range from 1 to 40, and this base strength can be affected by many modifiers (see [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]Combat[\LINK]). Some units have combat strengths of 0, which indicates that the unit cannot fight or has special rules governing combat. See the section on [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]Combat[\LINK] for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Acquiring Units[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You can obtain units in a number of ways:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Game Start[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]You have two or more units at the start of a game. At least one of these units is a settler; the remainder are workers or military units.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Tribal Villages[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]You may gain a new unit when one of your units enters a tribal village. (Or you may gain gold, technology, or experience - or the village may be hostile and generate barbarians to attack your unit.)[PARAGRAPH:2] [BOLD]Capturing Units[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_WORKER]Workers[\LINK] and [LINK=UNIT_SETTLER]Settlers[\LINK] are automatically captured when attacked by a military unit, or when they are in a city that is captured. (Note that settler units turn into workers when captured.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Constructing Units in Cities[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]You construct most of your units in [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK]. See below.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Generating Units in Cities[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Your cities generate [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great People[\LINK] units automatically. See that section for more details.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Gifts from other Civilizations[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Very rarely, a civilization may give you a unit.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Constructing Units in Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]As discussed above, most of your units come from your cities. Cities also construct buildings (plus other specialized items). They can only construct one item at a time - balancing the need for units against the need for buildings is crucial to your success in the game. Following is some information about constructing units; more can be found in the [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]Cities[\LINK] entry.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Choosing Units to Construct[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]When a city is ready to begin constructing a new unit or building, the city construction menu appears. This lists everything that you can construct in that city, as well as the time required for construction. Click on the unit/building you wish to build and the city will begin construction immediately. If you wish to change what a city is constructing, go to the city screen and click on the new item you wish to build.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Unit Availability[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Not all units are available for construction at the start of the game. Many units have [LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]Technological[\LINK] requirements, and some units require that you have access to one or more [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK]; for example, you cannot build a [LINK=UNIT_SWORDSMAN]Swordsman[\LINK] until you have researched [LINK=TECH_IRON_WORKING]Iron Working[\LINK] and have access to [LINK=BONUS_IRON]Iron[\LINK]. Also, a few units have [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Building[\LINK] and/or [LINK=CONCEPT_RELIGION]Religious[\LINK] prerequisites.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Construction Time[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]A unit's construction time is based upon the city's [LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]Production[\LINK]. The greater the amount of production a city has, the faster it can train new units.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Unit Support Costs[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The number of free units you will be able to have is affected by the Difficulty Level you are playing. Once you have surpassed the number of free units you are awarded, you will be charged per unit over your free unit total. Each unit costs one gold per turn to maintain. Certain [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] modify the number number of free units that are available to you.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Unit Away Costs[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Units that are not within your civilizations borders cost additional money to maintain and supply. Invading an enemy civilization will cause a serious strain on your budget.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Selecting Units[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A circle around a unit's indicates that the unit is "selected" and waiting for your orders. The computer auto-selects each unit waiting for orders in turn; if the unit already has orders the computer will not select that unit. You can also click on any of your units to select them manually.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Unit Orders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]When a unit is selected, you can order it to move (see [LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]Movement[\LINK]), or to attack (see [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]Combat[\LINK]). The unit might have other options available to it: these are displayed in the unit's "order box" at the middle-bottom of the screen. To give a unit an order, click on the appropriate icon in the order box (many orders have keyboard shortcuts, as well).[PARAGRAPH:2]There are a wide variety of orders available in Civilization IV. The specific orders available vary from unit to unit and may also vary depending upon the unit's location, health status, experience, and so forth. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Other Orders:[\BOLD] [LINK=UNIT_BOMBER]Bombers[\LINK] may have bombing orders; [LINK=UNIT_FIGHTER]Fighters[\LINK] may have recon orders; [LINK=UNIT_GALLEON]Galleons[\LINK] may have transport orders; and so forth. Check on a [LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]Unit's[\LINK] Civilopedia entry to find out what a unit can do.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Selecting Multiple Units[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You can select two or more units and give them both orders simultaneously. All of the units must be in the same space on the map. To do so, click on one unit, then shift-click on the other(s). All units will be selected.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Moving Multiple Units[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If two or more units are selected and you give them orders to move, they will do so in a group, at the speed of the SLOWEST unit. (Note: it is often smart to move a settler and a military unit simultaneously to make sure that the settler doesn't get destroyed by the first animal or barbarian it runs into.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Multiple Unit Combat[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If you have the stack attack option enabled and you order two or more military units to attack an enemy unit, the most powerful unit against the defender will attack that unit. If that unit's attack is unsuccessful, the attack won't continue automatically; if you want to attack with another unit, you'll have to give that unit new orders. However, if you hold down the ALT key when ordering an attack with multiple units selected, the units will perform a stack attack with combat resolving immediately.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Multiple Unit Improvements[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If you have two or more workers selected, you can order them both to work on improvements. The workers' combined efforts will speed up construction considerably.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Promotions[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]A combat unit gets "experience points" for winning battles. Enough experience points will earn that unit [LINK=CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS]promotions[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Unit Types[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Each unit belongs to a different "group"; for example, [LINK=UNIT_MUSKETMAN]Muskets[\LINK] are Gunpowder units and [LINK=UNIT_KNIGHT]Knights[\LINK] are considered Mounted units. Many of the promotions and natural unit abilities are based upon these unit types. For example, [LINK=UNIT_SPEARMAN]Spearmen[\LINK] naturally get a huge boost when fighting Mounted units, and the [LINK=PROMOTION_SHOCK]Shock[\LINK] promotion grants a unit +25%% against Melee units. Consult the entries on [LINK=PEDIA_MAIN_PROMOTION]Promotions[\LINK] and on each individual unit for more information.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]单位[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]在文明IV中，“单位”指任何可以在地图上移动的对象。游戏中有多种类型的单位——军事单位，工人单位，传教士以及历史伟人——其中军事单位的种类占据了其中的大部分。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]单位数据[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]所有单位拥有两个基本信息数据（或叫“数值”）：移动速度和战斗能力。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]移动速度[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]单位的移动速度决定单位在地图上移动的快慢。移动速度通常在1到8之间。有的单位移动速度为0，表明此类单位有特殊的移动规则。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]移动[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]战斗能力[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]单位的战斗能力决定单位与敌人作战时的表现。战斗能力通常在1到40之间，这个基础值可受许多修正因素的影响（见[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]战斗[\LINK]）。有的单位战斗能力为0，表明此类单位无法用于作战，或有特殊的作战规则。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]战斗[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]获得单位[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]要获得单位有多种方式:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]游戏初始[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏初始时你会拥有两个或更多的单位。其中至少会有一个移民单位；其余的可能是工人或军事单位。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]部落村庄[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]当你的单位进入一个部落村庄时，可能获得一个新单位。（也可能获得金钱，科技或经验值——也可能该村庄决意与你为敌，派出蛮族单位向你进攻.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]俘获单位[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][LINK=UNIT_WORKER]工人[\LINK]和[LINK=UNIT_SETTLER]移民[\LINK]在遭受军事单位攻击或是所在城市被占领，将被俘获。（注意移民被俘获后将转化为工人.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]在城市中组建单位[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你的大多数单位均在[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]中组建。见下文。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]在城市中产生单位[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你的城市可以自动产生[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]单位。详细见相关小节。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]其他文明的赠礼[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]有时，某个文明可能向你赠送单位。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]在城市中组建单位[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如上所述，你的大多数单位均在城市中组建。城市还能建造建筑（以及其他特殊项目）。一座城市同时只能进行一个项目——平衡处理单位项目和建筑项目之间的关系将是游戏胜利的关键。以下是组建单位的相关信息；更多信息见[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市[\LINK]词条。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]选择所组建的单位[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]当城市准备开始一个新的建造项目时，将显示城市建造菜单。列出该城市可以建造的所有项目，以及完成每个项目所需的时间。点击其中一个单位/建筑，将立即开始建造。如果你希望改变城市的当前建造项目，可进入城市界面，点击希望建造的新项目。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]可选单位[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏开始时可建造的单位非常有限。许多单位都有相应的[LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]科技[\LINK]前提，有些单位还需要拥有一种或更多种[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]；例如，要想组建[LINK=UNIT_SWORDSMAN]剑士[\LINK]你需要获得[LINK=TECH_IRON_WORKING]铁器[\LINK]科技并拥有[LINK=BONUS_IRON]铁[\LINK]资源。而且，有的单位还有[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]和/或[LINK=CONCEPT_RELIGION]宗教[\LINK]前提。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]建造时间[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]单位的建造时间基于城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_PRODUCTION]生产能力[\LINK]。城市拥有的工业产能越高，组建新单位的速度越快。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]单位维持费用[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以拥有的免维持费用的单位数量受游戏难度的影响。一旦超过免维持费单位数量上限，超过数量的单位就需要支付维持费用。某些[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]可改变免维持费单位数量上限。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]远征单位费用[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]处在本文明边界范围之外的单位需要额外支付补给费用。入侵敌国将造成大量的金钱耗费。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]选择单位[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]单位周围的圆环表示该单位被“选定”并等待你的命令。电脑会按顺序自动选择各个单位等待命令；如单位正在执行命令则电脑不会自动选择该单位。你也可以点击某个单位以进行手动选择。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]单位命令[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]单位被选定后，你可以命令其移动（见[LINK=CONCEPT_MOVEMENT]移动[\LINK]），或攻击（见[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]战斗[\LINK]）。单位可能还有其他可选命令：这些命令将显示在屏幕下方中间的单位“命令清单”之中。要向单位下达命令，可点击命令清单中的相应命令（许多命令也有相应快捷键）。[PARAGRAPH:2]文明IV中有各种不同的单位命令。具体可选命令因单位种类不同而不同，还可能因单位的位置，实力状态，经验等等而不同。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]其他命令:[\BOLD][LINK=UNIT_BOMBER]轰炸机[\LINK]具有轰炸命令；[LINK=UNIT_FIGHTER]战斗机[\LINK]具有侦察命令；[LINK=UNIT_GALLEON]大帆船[\LINK]拥有运输命令等等。相关详情见文明百科的[LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]单位[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]选择多个单位[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以选择两个以上的单位同时下达命令。所有单位必须位于同一区域。具体方法是，先点击一个单位，再按住Shift键点击其他单位。即可选定所有单位。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]移动多个单位[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果向两个以上被选定单位下达移动命令，他们将作为一个群组进行移动，速度以最慢的单位为准。（注意：同时移动一个移民和一个军事单位是聪明的做法，可确保移民不受野兽或蛮族的攻击.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]多个单位的作战[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果在启用了堆叠攻击选项的情况下向两个以上被选定单位下达攻击命令，对敌方攻击力最强的单位将首先进攻。如果该单位的攻击失败，将自动停止后续攻击；如果你希望其他单位继续攻击，必须重新下达命令。但是，如果你按住ALT键向多个单位下达攻击命令，所有单位将进行连续攻击，并立即判断最终战斗结果。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]多个单位修建设施[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你选定两个以上的工人，可以命令其一起修建设施。多个工人共同修建设施将更快地完成项目。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]晋升[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]作战单位赢得战斗后将获得“经验点数”。经验点数可使单位获得[LINK=CONCEPT_PROMOTIONS]晋升[\LINK]。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]单位类型[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]每个单位都有所属的“类型群组”；例如，[LINK=UNIT_MUSKETMAN]火枪手[\LINK]属于火器单位[LINK=UNIT_KNIGHT]骑士[\LINK]属于骑乘单位。单位的晋升类型和特殊能力受所属类型的影响。例如，[LINK=UNIT_SPEARMAN]矛兵[\LINK]天生对骑乘单位具有极大的战斗力加成，而[LINK=PROMOTION_SHOCK]冲击能力[\LINK]晋升将使单位增加+25%%对肉搏单位的战斗力加成。具体详情见[LINK=PEDIA_MAIN_PROMOTION]晋升[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_VICTORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Victory [\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]There are multiple paths to victory in Civilization IV. You can win by achieving political, cultural or technological dominance, and of course, by the ever-popular "crushing everyone else into dust beneath the wheels of your chariot" method. These various methods are described below:[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Victory[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]You win. Everybody else loses. Game over (but see below). If your victory was spectacular enough, your exploits might be recorded on the Civilization IV Hall of Fame screen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Continuing a Game After Victory:[\BOLD] You can continue playing after winning the game, but any further accomplishments will not be recorded on the Hall of Fame screen. It is also impossible to win another victory type after victory or defeat has initially taken place.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Defeat[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If you are wiped off the map or if one of your opponents achieves one of the victories listed below, you lose. The game is over. All of the other leaders will mock you. It's time to start a new game and try again.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Victory Conditions[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Following is a list of the ways you can achieve victory in Civilization IV. For more details, press F8 to go to the "Victory Conditions" screen. There you will see a list of the roads to victory available in the present game and how close you are to achieving each of them. (Note that if a specific type of victory is not listed on the Victory Conditions screen, it means that this particular victory was excluded during game setup.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Time Victory[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The game ends at a specific turn, usually 2050 AD. The civilization with the highest score at the end of that turn wins.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Conquest Victory[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The game ends when one civilization eliminates all rivals. A civilization is eliminated when its last city is captured or destroyed - even if it still has units in play.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Domination Victory[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The game ends when one civilization controls 75%% of the world population AND 75%% of the world's land area.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Cultural Victory[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The game ends when a civilization has three cities with "Legendary Culture" (50,000 culture points per city with Normal game speed). See [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Culture[\LINK] for a description of culture and how cities get it.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Space Race[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The game ends when you construct all of the components for your space ship, launch it and successfully reach Alpha Centauri. You can keep track of the space race with rival civs by monitoring the F8 Victory Conditions screen. This screen lists all of the components needed to build the spaceship and how many you have completed so far.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Diplomatic Victory[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]The game ends when the [LINK=CONCEPT_UNITED_NATIONS]United Nations[\LINK] is built and a leader wins an election for world leader.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]胜利[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]文明IV中要赢得胜利有多种方式。你可以通过取得政治，文化或科技方面的支配地位而获胜，当然，也可以通过广受玩家欢迎的“用战车把所有对手都辗至渣”而获胜。各种胜利方式说明如下:[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]胜利的结果[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]结果就是你赢了。其他人输了。游戏结束了（例外情况见下文）。如果你赢得足够精彩，你的成就将列入文明IV的名人殿堂。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]胜利之后继续游戏:[\BOLD]你在胜利之后仍可继续游戏，但此后的成绩不会记入名人殿堂。也不可能在此之后达到另一种胜利方式。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]失败[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你被从地球上抹去，或是你的对手达到了某一项胜利方式，结果就是你输了。游戏结束了。所有其他领袖会嘲笑你。你应该新建游戏再试一次。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]胜利条件[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]以下是文明IV中所有胜利方式清单。具体详情可按F8键查看“胜利条件”界面。其中将显示当前游戏可用的胜利方式及进展程度。（注意如果某种胜利方式未在胜利条件界面中显示，说明此种胜利方式在游戏设置中被排除.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]时间胜利[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏在达到特定回合时结束，通常为公元2050年。在回合结束时积分最高的文明获胜。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]征服胜利[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏在某个文明消灭所有对手时结束。文明的灭亡是指其所有城市被占领或摧毁——即使仍有单位存在。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]支配胜利[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏在某个文明控制世界人口的75%%以及世界陆地面积的75%%时结束。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]文化胜利[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏在某个文明有三座城市的文化达到“辉煌永恒”级别时结束（正常游戏速度下每座城市应达到50,000文化点数）。有关文化的详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]太空胜利[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏在某个文明建成所有太空飞船组件并成功发射前往半人马座阿尔法星时结束。你可以按F8进入胜利条件界面，了解对手的太空飞船建设进度。胜利条件界面将显示所有需要建造的组件及当前完成情况。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]外交胜利[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]游戏在[LINK=CONCEPT_UNITED_NATIONS]联合国[\LINK]建成后某个文明赢得选举成为世界领袖时结束。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_WAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]War[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]War happens to everybody. Sooner or later even the most peace-loving leader is going to find himself fighting one of his neighbors - perhaps because all of the neutral lands have been taken, perhaps because his opponent controls resources he covets, or perhaps merely because he looked at him funny. You do not need to conquer the world to [LINK=CONCEPT_VICTORY]Win[\LINK] a game of Civilization IV, but you do need to be able to defend yourself against other civilizations until you do win.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]How Wars Begin[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There are a number of ways that a civilization may initiate war against another:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Declare War[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]You can declare war on another civilization while conducting [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomacy[\LINK] with that civilization's leader.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Attack a Unit[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]When your unit enters a space containing a foreign unit, the program will ask if you want to attack that unit or enter peacefully. If you choose the former option, your unit and the other unit will battle, and your civs will be at war. If you choose the latter option, your unit will enter the other unit's square peacefully, and no war will ensue.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Enter Another Civilization's Territory without Signing Open Borders[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]When you direct a unit to enter another civilization's territory, the program will remind you that doing so will cause war with the other civilization. If you tell the unit to go ahead, the unit moves and you're at war.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Exceptions:[\BOLD] There are a couple of exceptions to this rule. If you have an [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Open Borders[\LINK] agreement with the civilization, then no war ensues. [LINK=UNIT_CARAVEL]Caravels[\LINK] and some "invisible" [LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]Units[\LINK] do not cause war when entering another civilization's territory.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Have a Defensive Pact with a Civilization that is Attacked[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If you have a [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Defensive Pact[\LINK] with another civilization and that civilization is attacked, you are automatically at war with the attacker. (Note that if your ally declares war on another civilization, your defensive alliance is revoked; you are not automatically at war with your ex-ally's new foe.)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Have a Permanent Alliance with a Civilization that is Attacked or Attacks another Civilization[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If you have a [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Permanent Alliance[\LINK] with another civilization, you are automatically at war with any civilization at war with your partner, no matter who started it.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of War[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Units Expelled from Enemy Territory[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If you had any visible units in your new enemy's territory when war was declared, all such units are expelled to your territory or neutral territory. The same happens to any of your enemy's units within your borders. (Note: This stops the shabby trick of making an Open Borders agreement with somebody, moving a lot of troops next to that civilization's capital, and then declaring war and assaulting the target city... Shame on you for even thinking of it!)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Trade Agreements[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If you have any trade agreements with your new enemy, all such agreements are now void. If your enemy's territory sits aside a trade network with a third civilization, that trade network is cut and you can no longer trade resources with the third civilization until a path is opened.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Movement Through Enemy Territory Slowed[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]If you have an Open Borders agreement with a civilization, your units can use that civilization's roads. If you are at war with another civilization, however, you cannot use the roads in that civilization's borders.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]War Weariness[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Your cities may become afflicted with [LINK=CONCEPT_WAR_WEARINESS]War Weariness[\LINK], which causes their population to become unhappy.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Combat[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]Combat will occur any time that one of your units tries to enter an enemy unit's square, and vice versa. See [LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]Combat[\LINK] for details.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Achieving Peace[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]War ends when one civilization loses all of its cities and is thus out of the game (see [LINK=CONCEPT_VICTORY]Victory[\LINK]). Short of total destruction, wars may be ended [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomatically[\LINK] when both sides agree to a Cease Fire or Peace Treaty.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]战争[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]战争会临到任何国家头上。甚至最爱好和平的领袖也迟早会和邻国交战——也许因为所有土地已划分完毕，也许因为对方控制了他所垂涎的资源，或者只是因为对方的看人的眼神太讨厌。在文明IV中你不一定要通过征服世界赢得[LINK=CONCEPT_VICTORY]胜利[\LINK]，但在赢得胜利之前，你必须有能够保护自己不受其他文明的攻击。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]战争的开始[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]文明之间的战争可能有多种触发方式:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]宣战[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你可以在进行[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交[\LINK]时向其他文明领袖宣战。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]攻击对方单位[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]当你的单位进入别国单位占据的区域，程序将询问你是要攻击该单位还是和平进入。如果你选择前者，双方单位将发生战斗，战争就此开始。如果你选择后者，你的单位可进入该区域而不引发战争。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]未签订开放边界条约而进入别国领土[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]当你命令一个单位进入其他文明的领土，程序将提醒你这样做将导致与该国的战争。如果你坚持命令单位前进，战争即爆发。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]例外:[\BOLD]上述情况存在例外。如果你与对方文明签有[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]开放边界[\LINK]条约，则不会引发战争。[LINK=UNIT_CARAVEL]轻帆船[\LINK]以及某些“隐形”[LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]单位[\LINK]在进入别国领土时不会引发战争。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]与遭受攻击的文明签有共同防御条约[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你与某个文明签有[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]共同防御[\LINK]条约，当该国遭受攻击时，你将与攻击方进入战争状态。（注意如果是你的盟友主动对其他文明宣战，共同防御条约即告失效；你将不会加入这场战争.）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]签有永久性同盟条约的文明遭受攻击或攻击其他文明[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你与其他文明签有[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]永久性同盟[\LINK]条约，你将自动与任何同盟友交战的国家进入战争状态，不论哪一方主动开战。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]战争的影响[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]单位被驱出敌方领土[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你在开战时有任何非隐形单位在敌方领土之内，这些单位将自动回到本国领土或中立区域。敌方在你境内的单位亦然。（注意：这将防止利用开放边界条约调集大军进入其他文明的领土，然后不宣而战夺取其首都的做法……这种做法是很可耻的!）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]贸易协议[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你原来与新的敌人签订有贸易协议，此类协议将自动失效。如果你与第三方的贸易网络需要通过敌方的领土，该贸易线路也将中断。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]在敌方领土的移动速度[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你与其他文明签有开放边界条约，你的单位将可利用该国的道路。如果你与该国开战，你将无法利用该国境内的道路。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]厌战情绪[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你的城市可能出现[LINK=CONCEPT_WAR_WEARINESS]厌战情绪[\LINK]，造成城市居民的不满。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]战斗[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2]你的单位试图进入敌方单位所在区域，或敌方单位试图进入你的单位所在区域都将引发战斗。详情见[LINK=CONCEPT_COMBAT]战斗[\LINK]一节。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]实现和平[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果一方文明因失去所有城市而被消失，战争即结束（见[LINK=CONCEPT_VICTORY]胜利[\LINK]）。除此之外，战争也可能通过[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交方式[\LINK]结束，如果双方同意签订停火协议或和平协议。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_WAR_WEARINESS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]War Weariness[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]If you are engaged in a protracted [LINK=CONCEPT_WAR]War[\LINK], then "war weariness" may begin to make your citizens unhappy. The section on [LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]Happiness[\LINK] discusses in depth the effects of unhappiness and how to deal with it, but here are some special rules about war weariness.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Captured Cities[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If you have captured a city from another civilization, the captured city is much more susceptible to war weariness while you're fighting that civilization. This effect fades over time as you fully assimilate the city into your culture.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Fighting War Weariness[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]There are a number of ways to limit the effects of war weariness. The most obvious way is to make peace; that stops the unhappiness immediately. If that is not feasible, then you can build [LINK=BUILDING_JAIL]Jails[\LINK] to reduce war weariness or adopt the [LINK=CIVIC_POLICE_STATE]Police State[\LINK] civic to completely eliminate war weariness. You can also devote a greater percentage of your civilization's commerce to the [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Culture Button[\LINK] (enabled with the [LINK=TECH_DRAMA]Drama[\LINK] technology) to help increase the happiness of your citizens.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]厌战情绪[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你卷入一场长期的[LINK=CONCEPT_WAR]战争[\LINK]，则“厌战情绪”可能导致你的市民不满。在[LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]快乐[\LINK]一节详细说明了不满的影响和解决方法，但关于厌战情绪还有一些特别的规定。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]被占领城市[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你从其他文明手中占领了一座城市，被占领城市将因你与其原属文明进行的战争而表现出极度的厌战情绪。这种影响会随时间的流逝和文明的同化而逐渐消失。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]消除厌战情绪[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]要消除厌战情绪的影响有多种方法。最直接的方法就是实现和平；这将立即消除厌战情绪。如果无法做到，则可以建造[LINK=BUILDING_JAIL]监狱[\LINK]以降低厌战情绪，或实施[LINK=CIVIC_POLICE_STATE]强化监控[\LINK]内政法令以完全消除厌战情绪。你还可以将更大比例的金钱分配到[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化支出[\LINK]（需要[LINK=TECH_DRAMA]戏剧[\LINK]科技）以提升市民的快乐度。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_WEALTH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Wealth[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Time and again, history shows us the importance of managing wealth properly. In the 16th century, Spain had access to the nearly limitless gold and silver of Central and South America, yet so much of this wealth was lost through corruption and mismanagement that Spain was unable to finance the ships and soldiers to protect her American possessions, leaving them vulnerable to attack by enemy nations and pirates. At the end of the First World War, Germany was bankrupt and shorn of her overseas colonies; yet in twenty years she acquired enough wealth to build and support the mightiest military machine yet seen in the world.[PARAGRAPH:2]Wealth is an extremely important part of Civilization IV; manage your wealth properly and your civilization will flourish and thrive; squander it and your civilization will languish.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2] Current Wealth[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The "wealth counter" on the main screen displays your current wealth. This is usually a positive number or zero (if it is not, your civilization is in serious trouble!). The number adjacent to the wealth counter shows how much wealth your civilization is currently gaining (or losing) each turn.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Commerce and Wealth[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The amount of wealth that your cities are producing is determined by what percentage of your commerce is going into [LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]Research[\LINK] (and, later on, [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Culture[\LINK]). The percentage of your commerce that is turned into wealth is whatever is not being spent on research and culture. For example, if you are spending 70%% on science and 10%% on culture, the remaining 20%% of your commerce is going towards generating wealth.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Acquiring Wealth[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Wealth:[\BOLD] Each of your cities generates commerce from working the spaces within its [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]City Radius,[\LINK] and certain [LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]Resources[\LINK] such as gold, silver, and incense are particularly valuable. Constructing [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Improvements[\LINK] such as cottages and mines can dramatically increase the commerce of your cities - which will translate into more wealth.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Tribal Villages:[\BOLD] When one of your units enters a "tribal village," the villagers might give you gold as tribute.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Capturing Cities and Plundering Improvements:[\BOLD] You may gain an influx of gold when you capture an enemy or barbarian city. You may get a (far smaller) portion of gold when your units [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Pillage[\LINK] enemy/barbarian improvements.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Merchants:[\BOLD] If your cities generate a [LINK=UNIT_MERCHANT]Great Merchant[\LINK], you can send him on a Trade Mission to a foreign city. This will generate an enormous amount of gold that gets placed in your civilization's treasury.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Diplomacy:[\BOLD] You can acquire wealth through [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomacy[\LINK] through the buying and selling of technologies and the trading of resources. [PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Expending Wealth[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]City Maintenance:[\BOLD] It costs a certain amount each turn to maintain your cities. This cost increases as the size and number of your cities increase. A city's distance from the [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE]Palace[\LINK] also affects its maintenance cost.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Civic Upkeep:[\BOLD] Most [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] have upkeep costs associated with them that cost a certain amount of gold each turn. Some civics are much more expensive than others, so keep this in mind when selecting civics.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Inflation:[\BOLD] As a game of Civilization IV progresses, your empire will slowly become more expensive to maintain due to the economic process known as Inflation. This will cost your civilization a certain amount of gold each turn in addition to all other costs. You cannot fight Inflation, other than by generating more wealth to counteract its effects.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Technological Research:[\BOLD] You spend money each turn to finance your civilization's [LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]Technological Research[\LINK]; at some point, it will almost certainly be necessary to scale back research to prevent your civilization from going bankrupt.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Unit Support:[\BOLD] Depending upon your current civics, you may be required to pay "support costs" for each [LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]Unit[\LINK] you have in play.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Unit Upgrades:[\BOLD] After you have built a unit, future [LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]Technological Advances[\LINK] may allow you to upgrade that unit (say, from an archer to a crossbowman). You must pay for such upgrades.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hurrying Construction: [\BOLD]The [LINK=CIVIC_UNIVERSAL_SUFFRAGE]Universal Suffrage[\LINK] civic allows you to spend gold to "hurry" a city's construction of units or buildings.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Diplomacy:[\BOLD] You can expend wealth to grease the wheels of [LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]Diplomacy[\LINK] in many different ways. Enemy civilizations will usually agree to do what you want - if the price is right.[PARAGRAPH:2]You can see a display of all of your civilization's current expenditures by opening up the Financial Advisor screen with the F3 key.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Civics and Wealth[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Your civilization's [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] greatly affect the rate at which you acquire/expend wealth. For example, some civics reward you for peaceful trading, while others cut down the cost of maintaining a huge army.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Running Out of Money[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If your civilization cannot afford to pay its current expenses, your cities will go on "strike;" they will cease production of units and buildings until your finances are in better shape. Further, you may lose units and buildings that you cannot afford to pay support for. When your cities go on strike, it is extremely important to get expenses in line with income as soon as possible.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Early Wealth Mismanagement[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]It is quite possible to get yourself into serious financial difficulties in the early game. This usually occurs because you have built too many cities or units without first constructing the buildings and improvements necessary for your existing cities to support the costs of this expansion. The result is that your expenses greatly outstrip your income and your treasury goes away fast. There are a number of possible steps you can take to get out of this fiscal mess:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Tribal Villages:[\BOLD] If there are any tribal villages about, send a unit to them; they may give you wealth as tribute. (This is a stop-gap solution at best!)[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Lower Your Research Budget:[\BOLD] Decrease the amount you are spending each turn on [LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]Technological Research[\LINK] using the button in the top-left corner of the screen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Build Improvements:[\BOLD] Build [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COTTAGE]Cottages[\LINK] and other [LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]Improvements[\LINK] that exploit money-making resources within your [LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]Borders[\LINK]: mines for gold and silver, camps for fur and ivory, and so forth. Build roads to connect your cities to these resources.[PARAGRAPH:2] [BOLD]Construct Buildings:[\BOLD] Build [LINK=BUILDING_COURTHOUSE]Courthouses[\LINK] to reduce your city maintenance costs and [LINK=BUILDING_MARKET]Markets[\LINK] to increase your income. If you aren't able to construct those buildings yet, direct your [LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]Research[\LINK] towards the techs which will allow their construction. Failing to construct these buildings soon enough is a problem that nearly every newcomer to Civilization IV encounters![PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Build Wealth:[\BOLD] If your tech level allows, you can assign your cities to build Wealth rather than new units or buildings.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Emphasize Wealth:[\BOLD] Set your cities to [LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]"Emphasize Wealth"[\LINK] when working the land around them. Be aware, however, that the city governor may not make the same choices that you would.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Adjust Civics:[\BOLD] Check the [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] screen to see if you can reduce your "civic upkeep" by switching to less expensive civics.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Destroy Units:[\BOLD] Delete extra military units. Destroy settlers rather then creating more cities that you cannot support.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Diplomacy:[\BOLD] Depending upon your present technology level, you may be able to get gold from your neighbors - through trade OR coercion.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Capture Enemy Cities:[\BOLD] You usually get some significant cash from capturing enemy cities or pillaging improvements.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Abandon Cities:[\BOLD] If nothing else works, you can abandon money-losing cities. You can give them to other civilizations via diplomacy, or you can simply remove all military units from a city and hope that a barbarian captures it. (If things are THIS bad, however, you might also want to consider the "Start a New Game" ploy.)[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]财富[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]历史的经验一再证明了良好的财政管理对国家的重要性。在16世纪，西班牙从中美和南美地区获得了几乎无法计数的金银，但如此巨额的财富却因贪污腐败和管理不善而大量流失，以至于西班牙政府无钱维持足够的舰船和军队以保护其在美洲的领地，成为一块敌国和海盗肆意掠夺的肥肉。在第一次世界大战结束时，德国已完全破产并被迫放弃所有海外殖民地；但仅仅过了二十年时间，便再次积累起充足的财富，能够组建并维持人类历史上最强大的战争机器。[PARAGRAPH:2]财富在文明IV中也极为重要；正确理财可使你的文明繁荣兴旺；浪费财富则会使你的文明走向衰败。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]现有财富[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]主界面中的“财富计数器”显示了你现有的财富。现有财富通常为正数或零（如果为负数，将非常糟糕!）。现有财富后的数值显示你的文明在每回合增加（或减少）的金钱数量。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]商业收入与财富[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]你的城市所创造的财富由你的商业收入投入[LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]科研[\LINK]（以及稍后的[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化[\LINK]）的比例所决定。所有商业收入扣除投入科研和文化事业的部分即转化为财富。例如，如果你将商业收入的70%%投入科技，10%%投入文化，则剩余的20%%将转为现金财富。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]获取财富[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市财富:[\BOLD]你的城市通过安排市民在[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]城市范围[\LINK]区域内工作来创造商业收入。某些[LINK=CONCEPT_RESOURCES]资源[\LINK]例如黄金，白银，和薰香具有极高的商业价值。修建[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]区域设施[\LINK]例如农舍与矿井可以大大提升城市的商业收入——从而带来更多的财富。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]部落村庄:[\BOLD]当你的单位进入“部落村庄,”村民可能向你提供金钱赠礼。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]占领城市及劫掠设施:[\BOLD]在你占领敌国或蛮族城市时可能获得一笔金钱。在你的单位[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]劫掠[\LINK]敌国或蛮族区域设施时也可能获得（较少量的）金钱。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]大商业家:[\BOLD]如果你的城市产生了一位[LINK=UNIT_MERCHANT]大商业家[\LINK]，你可以将他派往外国城市开展贸易事业。这将为你的国库带来一大笔金钱。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]外交:[\BOLD]你可以通过[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交[\LINK]交换科技和资源以获取财富。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]消耗财富[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]城市维护费:[\BOLD]你的城市在每回合都需要消耗维护费。维护费总额将随城市规模和数量的增加而上升。城市与[LINK=BUILDING_PALACE]宫殿[\LINK]的距离也会影响维护费的高低。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]内政经费:[\BOLD]大多数[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]的实施也需要每回合支出相应费用。有些内政法令的经费水平很高，在选择内政法令时需加以注意。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]通货膨胀:[\BOLD]随着游戏的进行，维持文明发展所需的费用将随着通货膨胀这一经济现象而不断提升。通货膨胀会使你在每回合的正常支出以外还需消耗一笔金钱。你无法遏制通货膨胀，只能依靠创造更多的财富来抵销其影响。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]科技研究:[\BOLD]你需要每回合支出一笔经费用于[LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]科技研究[\LINK]；在必要的情况下，你需要削减科研经费，以避免财政破产。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]单位维持费:[\BOLD]根据你当前所实施的内政法令，你可能需要为你的[LINK=CONCEPT_UNITS]单位[\LINK]支付维持费。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]单位升级:[\BOLD]在你组建单位之后，获得新的[LINK=CONCEPT_TECHNOLOGY]科技进展[\LINK]可能允许你升级原有单位（例如将弓手升级为弩手）。升级单位通常也需要支出金钱。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]加速建造:[\BOLD]实行[LINK=CIVIC_UNIVERSAL_SUFFRAGE]普选制度[\LINK]内政法令可允许你支付金钱以“加速”城市单位或建筑工程的进度。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]外交:[\BOLD]你可以使用金钱作为[LINK=CONCEPT_DIPLOMACY]外交[\LINK]手段。敌对的文明也可能满足你的要求——只要出得起价钱。[PARAGRAPH:2]你可以按F3键打开财政顾问界面，查看当前的财政状况。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]内政法令与财富[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]文明所实行的[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]对财富的获取和消耗有重大影响。例如，有的内政法令可增进国际贸易收入，有的则可以降低维持大量军队的花费。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]财富耗尽[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你的文明现有财富无法满足支出需要，你的城市将会“罢工;”停止单位和建筑工程，直到财政状况获得改善。此外，无力支付维持费还可能导致单位解散和建筑被毁。如果你的城市发生罢工，需要尽快设法改善财政状况。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]早期财政困难[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]在游戏早期你可能陷入严重的财政困难。这通常是由于你建造了过多的城市或单位，而没有建设能为扩张提供财政支持的建筑与设施。因支出远大于收入而耗尽现金储备。解决此类问题有多种方法:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]部落村庄:[\BOLD]如果发现部落村庄，可派遣单位前往查探；村民可能向你提供金钱赠礼。（这至少能缓解燃眉之息!）[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]减少科研支出:[\BOLD]点击屏幕左上角的按钮减少每回合投入[LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]科技研究[\LINK]的经费比例。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]修建设施:[\BOLD]修建[LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COTTAGE]农舍[\LINK]及其他[LINK=CONCEPT_IMPROVEMENTS]区域设施[\LINK]获取[LINK=CONCEPT_BORDERS]国界[\LINK]以内的有价值资源：修建矿井获取黄金和白银，修建猎场获取毛皮和象牙等等。修建道路将这些资源连接到城市。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]建造建筑:[\BOLD]建造[LINK=BUILDING_COURTHOUSE]法庭[\LINK]减少城市的维护费，建造[LINK=BUILDING_MARKET]市场[\LINK]增加收入。如果还不能建造此类建筑，则尽快[LINK=CONCEPT_RESEARCH]研究[\LINK]相应的科技。文明IV的新手的问题就是往往不能及时建造此类建筑![PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]生产财富:[\BOLD]如果获得相应科技，你可以命令城市将工业产能转为财富而不是建造单位和建筑。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]专注财富:[\BOLD]令城市周边设施的修建[LINK=CONCEPT_CITIES]“专注于财富”[\LINK]。但是要注意，电脑市长的具体选择可能与你的希望不符。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]调整内政法令:[\BOLD]打开[LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]内政法令[\LINK]界面查看是否可能通过选择低经费水平的内政制度以减少“内政经费”。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]解散单位:[\BOLD]解散多余的军事单位。解散已组建的移民单位，而不是继续建立无法维持的城市。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]外交:[\BOLD]根据当前科技水平，你可能从邻国获得金钱——通过交易或是敲诈。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]占领敌方城市:[\BOLD]你可以通过占领敌方城市或劫掠区域设施获得大量金钱。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]废弃城市:[\BOLD]如果其他办法没有效果，你可以废弃无用的城市。你可以通过外交将其赠送给其他文明，或撤出守城的军事单位，任由蛮族将其占领。（当然如果情况已无可挽回，你还可以考虑“开始新游戏”。）[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_WONDERS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Wonders[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Wonders are the spectacular buildings, inventions, and concepts that have stood the test of time and changed the world forever. The Pyramids, Notre Dame Cathedral, the Statue of Liberty and Hollywood are all examples of wonders. Wonders require much time and energy from your cities, but once completed, they provide your civilization with many benefits.[PARAGRAPH:2]There are two basic types of wonders: great wonders and national wonders.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Great Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] Great wonders are unique; only one of each can be constructed during a game. For example, the Great Lighthouse is a great wonder; whoever completes it first is the only one who may possess its benefits. Great Wonders tend to be quite powerful indeed, but also extremely time-consuming to build.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]National Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] National wonders may be built once by each civilization in the game. That is, each civilization can have the Wall Street national wonder (though no civilization can have two of them). Each city may only build two national wonders, so be sure to plan ahead where you wish to put them. [PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Constructing Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2] Wonders are constructed in cities, like any other [LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]Building[\LINK]. If you can build a wonder, it will appear in your city build menu; just click on the wonder to get started. Note that only one city in your civilization can be building a single wonder at a time.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Losing the Construction Race:[\BOLD] If another civilization completes a great wonder while you are in the process of building it, your construction ceases, and a certain amount of your production efforts are converted into gold. This does not occur with national wonders, since each civilization can build its own copy of those.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Wonders and Resources:[\BOLD] Certain resources will allow cities to produce wonders of both types at double the usual speed. For example, a civilization that has Stone connected to its [LINK=CONCEPT_CITY_NETWORK]City Network[\LINK] can build the Pyramids at a much faster rate.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Civilization Traits:[\BOLD] [LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]Leaders[\LINK] who possess the Industrious trait build all wonders at twice the usual rate.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Wonders have a broad range of effects. Some increase productivity; others increase income from trade. Some improve research, others make your workers build improvements faster. All wonders improve their home city's [LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]Cultural Output[\LINK] as well as the speed at which the city generates [LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]Great People[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Capturing Wonders[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]If you capture a city with a great wonder, you gain possession of that wonder. If you capture a city with a national wonder, the national wonder is destroyed. If a city is destroyed, all wonders in that city are destroyed along with it. Great wonders can never be rebuilt once they are destroyed.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Wonder Obsolescence[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Some wonders can become obsolete over time. This obsolescence is caused by any civilization in the game learning a specific technology. When that occurs, the wonder's special effects vanish, but it still continues to produce culture. For example, the Great Lighthouse wonder provides a trade benefit to all coastal cities, as well as +8 culture to the city where it is constructed. The Great Lighthouse is rendered obsolete once any civilization gains the [LINK=TECH_STEAM_POWER]Steam Power[\LINK] technology, at which point the owner loses the Lighthouse's trade benefit but retains its +8 cultural output.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>[H1]奇观[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]奇观指那些历经时间考验，深刻影响世界历史的伟大建筑，发明创造或思想观念等。例如大金字塔，圣母院，自由女神像和好莱坞等等。建设奇观需要城市付出大量时间和精力，但如果能够完成，将为你的文明带来许多利益。[PARAGRAPH:2]奇观分为两类：世界奇观（大奇观）和国家奇观（小奇观）。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]世界奇观[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]大奇观是独一无二的；整个游戏中只能建造一个。例如，大灯塔即属于大奇观；最先完成大奇观的文明将独享其利益。大奇观的作用非常大，但其建造也需要付出非常多的时间。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]国家奇观[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]国家奇观每个文明均可在游戏中建造一个。例如，每个文明都可以拥有自己的华尔街（但不能拥有两个）。每个城市只能建造两座国家奇观，因此需要事先做好规划。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]建造奇观[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]奇观在城市中建造，和其他[LINK=CONCEPT_BUILDINGS]建筑[\LINK]一样。如果你可能建造某座奇观，它将出现在城市的建造菜单中；只需点击该奇观即开始建造。注意你的文明在同一时间只能有一座城市建造某一特定奇观。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]在建造竞争中失败:[\BOLD]如果其他文明先于你完成一座大奇观，你的建造进程将中断，已经积累的产能将转换为一定数量的金钱。但国家级奇观则不存在此种文明间竞争的问题。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]奇观和资源:[\BOLD]某些资源可使奇观建造速度加倍。例如，一个文明的[LINK=CONCEPT_CITY_NETWORK]城市网络[\LINK]中如果有花岗石，则可以更快速地建造大金字塔。[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]文明特质:[\BOLD][LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]文明领袖[\LINK]如果拥有勤奋刻苦的特质，则奇观建造速度加倍。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]奇观的作用[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]奇观拥有各种不同的作用。有些增加生产力；有些增加贸易收入。有些提升科研能力，还有的能使你的工人更有效率。所有奇观均能增加所在城市的[LINK=CONCEPT_CULTURE]文化产出[\LINK]以及城市产生[LINK=CONCEPT_GREAT_PEOPLE]历史伟人[\LINK]的几率。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]夺取奇观[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]如果你夺取了拥有大奇观的城市，也就拥有了该座大奇观。如果你夺取了拥有国家奇观的城市，该国家奇观会被摧毁。如果城市被摧毁，其中所有的奇观也会随之毁灭。大奇观被摧毁后无法再次重建。[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]奇观的过时[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]有些奇观会随时间的流逝而失去作用。任何发明特定科技将使某些奇观过时。在这种情况下，奇观的特殊作用将消失，但是仍能继续积累文化值。例如，大灯塔能为所有海滨城市带来商业收入，并使所在城市文化产出+8。大灯塔的将在任何文明获得[LINK=TECH_STEAM_POWER]蒸汽机[\LINK]科技之后过时，该奇观将不再带来商业收入，但城市每回合文化产出则继续+8。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
