<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- freesand -->
<!-- Civic and Religion Infos -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DESPOTISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Despotism is a form of government characterized by a ruler who wields absolute power over his people. Despite the word's negative connotations, a leader doesn't necessarily have to be a corrupt, evil megalomaniac to be a despot; it is possible to be a benevolent despot, though history records few cases of such. [PARAGRAPH:2]The strength of this form of government is that the ruler can easily implement his decisions; he does not need to compromise, cajole, or bribe anyone to get the job done. The weakness of this form of government is that the ruler can implement bad decisions just as easily as good ones; with no checks and balances, how can he be stopped? Also, there is a lot of truth in the old saying, "Power corrupts; absolute power corrupts absolutely." And though as said before, despots don't need to be corrupt, evil megalomaniacs, many of them end up that way.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>专制制度的特点是统治者对其臣民拥有绝对的权力。虽然该词有负面的含义，但专制的领袖并不一定就是腐化堕落，邪恶残暴的人。专制领袖也可能是宽厚仁慈的，但这在历史上极为少有。[PARAGRAPH:2]这种政府体制的优势在于统治者能方便地贯彻其决策，他不需要与他人进行协调，妥协或是贿赂。这种政府体制的弱点在于统治者也同样能方便地贯彻错误的决策，不必接受任何约束和制衡，怎么会不危险呢？正如古人所说：“权力导致腐败；绝对的权力导致绝对的腐败。”虽然说专制领袖并不一定腐化和残暴，但他们最终往往会变得如此。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_HEREDITARY_RULE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Hereditary Rule is a form of government wherein the rulership is passed down from one member of the family to the next. This kind of succession is most often associated with monarchical rulers, but it occasionally appears in despotisms or even purportedly communist regimes - North Korea, for example. There is often a religious justification for hereditary rule; kings are said to rule by "divine right" or "the mandate of Heaven." [PARAGRAPH:2]The strength of hereditary rule is that there is usually a clear line of succession, and thus perhaps less squabbling for power when the current monarch dies. (There are plenty of exceptions to this rule throughout history, of course.) Further, there may be a certain amount of familial pressure on the ruler to not mess things up too badly for the next generation. However, hereditary rule suffers the same kind of weaknesses as do all unelected rulers; the leader is not answerable to the people, and it can be extremely difficult to get rid of a bad one.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>世袭制度的特点是政权在一个家族的成员间传承。这种继承方式往往与君主制联系在一起，但有时也被专制政权甚至共产政权所采用——北朝鲜就是一个例子。世袭制度还往往从宗教信仰当中寻求其合理性：君主们的权力经常号称来自“神授”或“天命”。[PARAGRAPH:2]世袭制度的优势在于后任者的继承顺序通常较为明确，使得现任君主去世后较少暴发权力争夺。（当然历史上的例外情况也不少。）而且，君权会受到来自家族内部的制约，使统治者的劣行不至于危及子孙的利益。但是，世袭方式和其他非选举方式具有同样的弱点：统治者无须响应人民的呼声，因而要想罢免一位坏的统治者是很困难的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_REPRESENTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In a representative government the population elects a number of "representatives" to run the government on their behalf. The representatives serve for a limited time and then must stand for reelection. These representatives form a group (council, parliament, senate, etc.) that determines and implements government policy. In some cases the government may have a monarch at its head, while in other cases there may be a separately elected ruler (as in the United States), or the representatives themselves may elect one or more of their members to be the executive power. [PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>代议制度的政府是由民众选举一批“代表人”负责统治。代表人的任期有限，到期必须重新选举。这些代表人会组成一个机构（委员会、国会、参议院等。）来决定和实施各项政策。有时这样的政府也可能以一位君主作为首脑，但多数首脑都是通过单独选举产生的（例如美国），也可能由代表人集体选举一人或数人掌握最高统治权。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_POLICE_STATE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Under a police state the government maintains strict control over its populace by means of a police force (and often a "secret" police force). Civil liberties are denied and those who voice opinions contrary to the government are subject to punishments ranging from imprisonment to death. [PARAGRAPH:2]The strength of police states lies in their ability to control the population in bad times, forcing them to do what's necessary no matter what their personal opinions of the matter may be. It has been argued, for example, that Stalin's Soviet Union would not have survived the German assault in World War II if he didn't have the entire power of the state under his dictatorial control. The weakness of the police state comes from its tendency to crush individual initiative and inventiveness. Police states are often subject to excesses of paranoia; they see everyone as against them and constantly implement more repressive policies to remain in power.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>强化监控政体的特点是政府通过警察的力量（且往往是“秘密警察”）对人民大众实施严格的控制。政治自由被完全禁止，任何人发表对政府不满的言论都可能受到监禁甚至死刑的惩罚。[PARAGRAPH:2]强化监控政体的优势是能够在不利的社会环境下保持对民众的控制，可以强制人们从事符合国家利益的活动而不必考虑个人利益。例如有许多人认为，如果斯大林不采取强化监控政体保证对权力的绝对掌控，第二次世界大战中苏联将不可能击败德国的入侵。强化监控政体的弱点在于它会扼杀个人的主动性和创造性。强化监控的政权往往走向极端和偏执；统治集团总是感觉遭到所有人的反对，因而不断强化警察力量以维持权力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_UNIVERSAL_SUFFRAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Universal suffrage means extending the vote to everyone, regardless of race, creed, or gender. Note however that even the most universal suffrage is usually less than totally universal; in the United States, for example, one must be 18 years of age to vote, and being convicted of certain criminal offenses results in permanent loss of suffrage. [PARAGRAPH:2]The positive side of universal suffrage is that everyone is allowed an equal say in electing those who will run the country. The negative side is that this includes everyone, regardless of intelligence, honesty, or any other characteristic. As someone once said, "I reject any form of government in which the opinion of the village idiot is given the same weight as the opinion of Aristotle." </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>普选制度指将选举权扩大到每一个人，不论其种族、信仰或性别。但是要注意，即使是最全面的普选往往也不能覆盖所有人群，例如在美国，18岁以上的人才有选举权，犯下某些罪行的人会终生失去选举权。[PARAGRAPH:2]普选制度的积极意义是每个人都有选择国家管理者的平等话语权。其消极的一面也在于每个人都有平等话语权，不论其智力程度，诚信程度和其他方面的品行如何。正如有人所说的：“我反对将村野白痴和亚里士多德的意见平等看待的任何政府。”</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BARBARISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Barbarism is the most primitive legal system. Under barbarism, the strong take what they want from the weak: their money, possessions, even spouses and children. Disputes are settled by combat; might is right. [PARAGRAPH:2]There is little positive to say about barbarism, except perhaps that it cuts way back on red tape. It does not support a legal class that can complicate and obfuscate the law to ensure job security.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>原始法律是最古老的法律体系。在野蛮时代，强者可以任意侵吞弱者的财物，土地，甚至配偶和子女。任何争端均通过打斗来解决，力量就是正义。[PARAGRAPH:2]野蛮法律没有多少积极意义，不过也许这种方式省去了各种繁文缛节，不需要社会供养一批靠研究复杂法律条文吃饭的专职人员。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_VASSALAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Vassalage is a feudal term referring to a person who enters a contract with his or her lord, agreeing to serve and protect the lord in return for monetary rewards or ownership or sovereignty over a parcel of land. The contract is often of both political and religious significance binding both parties by the rules of man and of God. [PARAGRAPH:2]Vassalage is often tribal in nature. One tribe conquers another, and rather than killing the conquered tribe or taking over its direct management, the conquering ruler makes the conquered his vassal: the lower ruler continues to maintain control over his people and territory, while paying tribute to his or her lord in the form of money, goods, soldiers or slaves. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>分封制度指封建社会下臣属与其领主以订立契约的方式规定相互间权利和义务的体制，臣属宣誓保卫领主，以换取钱财奖赏或获得封地统治权。这种契约往往具有政治和宗教方面的双重约束。[PARAGRAPH:2]分封制度源于部族统治制度。当一个部族征服另一个部族时，征服方的统治者不是屠尽被征服者或实施直接统治，而是将其收为臣属，作为管理其部族人口与领地的下级统治者，为此臣属需要向其领主交纳金钱、物资、士兵或奴隶作为贡礼。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_BUREAUCRACY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Bureaucracy is a form of government in which a professional class manages the day to day operations of the government. They collect the taxes. They build the roads. They turn the ruler's wishes into actuality. The Chinese mandarins are an early example of a bureaucracy; the motor vehicle agency of your local government is a later example. [PARAGRAPH:2]Bureaucracies provide a certain amount of stability and competence to a government, ensuring that the government will continue to operate efficiently even if the old ruler is thrown out and a new and totally inexperienced ruler takes his or her place. Over time, though, a bureaucracy may become "entrenched" - growing in size and inefficiency to the point where it is extremely difficult for a leader to accomplish anything - good or ill.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>官僚制度是由专业的官员阶层负责政府日常管理的制度。包括征收赋税、修建道路、贯彻统治者的决策等。中国最早实行这样的官僚制度。你所在地方政府的机动车管理所也是官僚机构的一个实例。[PARAGRAPH:2]官僚制度使政府的机能维持稳定和完善，即便在旧统治者去世，毫无经验的新统治者继任时也能保证政府有序运转。但随着时间的流逝，官僚机构可能变得日益“僵化”——规模不断扩大，而效益却不断降低，以至统治者无法做成任何事——不论是好事还是坏事。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_NATIONHOOD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A "nation" is a group of people sharing some kind of common identity. Nations may be united by language, custom, history, or religion (or any combination of them). [PARAGRAPH:2]Sharing languages, customs, histories and so forth provides strength to a nation - the sense of identity and commonality reduces internal strife, civil and religious wars, and so forth. Unfortunately, citizens with different languages, customs, and backgrounds may be looked upon with suspicion, distrust, and contempt, promoting unhappiness and unrest from the minority and limiting their ability to fully contribute to the society.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>“国民”或“民族”是指具有一系列相同社会文化特征的人群。一个民族可能通过语言、风俗、历史、宗教或多项综合因素而结合在一起。[PARAGRAPH:2]共同的语言、风俗、历史等使一个民族保持其力量——相互之间的认同感会减少内部的纠纷或战争。但不幸的是，同一国家的各民族间如果存在语言、风俗和历史背景的差异，可能又会相互猜疑、蔑视和敌对，导致少数民族的不满和骚动，造成社会的不稳定因素。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FREE_SPEECH_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The term "free speech" describes a legal system in which a person cannot be stopped from saying anything he or she wants, as long as the speech doesn't cause immediate harm to those around him or her - even in the freest society, it is still illegal to shout "Fire!" in a crowded movie theatre. [PARAGRAPH:2]The benefits of free speech are many. The citizens may debate their government's policies and actions fully, without fear of punishment. A free press allows the citizens great access to news and information, allowing them to more accurately judge the events taking place in the world around them. Tyrants and despots rightly fear free speech more than almost anything else. On the other hand, free speech may be hate speech; it may be lies. Such speech must be allowed: once a government is allowed to determine which speech is to be allowed and which is to be suppressed, the temptation to abuse that power is overwhelming, and speech isn't free any more.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>“言论自由”指在不会对他人造成损害的情况下，允许个人发表任何言论的法律体系——当然即使在言论最自由的社会中，在坐满观众的电影院中大喊“着火了！”也是违法的行为。[PARAGRAPH:2]言论自由有许多好处。公民可以充分讨论政府的政策和行为，而不用担心因此遭受惩罚。言论自由的媒体则可全面地提供各种新闻和信息，使人们可以更准确的判断周遭所发生的事件。暴君和独裁者们最害怕的东西就是言论自由。在另一方面，自由的言论也可能是传播仇恨或是虚假的言论。但这样的言论也不应该禁止：一旦可以由政府来决定是否允许或禁止某种言论，这样的权力就极有可能被滥用，言论自由便不复存在了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TRIBALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Tribalism is a form of organization which emphasizes the tribe as the sole unit of importance. Individuals have no rights; each man, woman and child exists only to support the tribe.  Tribalism is a fairly useful form of government for a small group of people who exist on the edge of catastrophe. In a tribe everyone knows everybody else; who is strong and who is weak, who is intelligent and who is not, who is skilled and who is unskilled. [PARAGRAPH:2]Leadership in the tribe is usually determined by merit, according to the tribe's needs: if the tribe is hungry, the best hunter becomes the leader. If the tribe is surrounded by enemies, the best warrior is chosen. And so forth. A tribe must quickly learn how to pick successful leaders; otherwise it will perish. [PARAGRAPH:2]Tribalism tends to break down when the tribe becomes overly large. People no longer know everyone in their tribe. Groups (or factions) appear, and everyone no longer share the same objectives. The tribe must find a more sophisticated system of government or fracture into smaller squabbling units.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>部落分工是一种强调部落重要性的劳动组织形式。个人没有多少权力，每个男人，女人和孩子的存在都必须符合部落的利益。部落制是处于险恶生存环境之中的远古人类的最佳选择。在部落中，人人都彼此了解：谁强悍、谁懦弱、谁聪明、谁愚蠢、谁灵巧、谁无能。[PARAGRAPH:2]部落的领导权的选择以符合部落的利益为标准：如果食物不足，最好的猎手就是部落领袖。如果被面对敌人，则选择最强的勇士。以此类推。部落必须学会如何推选好的领袖，否则就无法生存下去。[PARAGRAPH:2]随着人口的增加，部落逐渐解体。同一部落的人们不再相互了解。相对独立的集团开始出现了，不同集团具有不同的目标。部落制必须转为更复杂的制度，否则就将面临分裂。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SLAVERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Slavery is a system whereby some people are judged far inferior to others and are treated as objects or possessions, with no more rights than those afforded to chairs or cattle. Slavery has existed as long as human history, from the earliest primitive times to the enlightened days of Greece and Rome and right up until today. Sometimes convicted criminals were made into slaves. Sometimes captured enemies of the state were enslaved. Sometimes people of a specific race or coloration were enslaved. In some civilizations a person could purchase their freedom or were allotted it after being enslaved for a specific period of time. [PARAGRAPH:2]The advantage of slavery is that it allows people to be forced to do jobs that they would otherwise refuse to do without adequate compensation. Cheap labor results in concentration of wealth and thus the creation of great buildings and temples or the maintenance of large professional armies. Aside from its basic moral repugnance, the disadvantages of slavery are numerous: it corrupts both slave and master, it badly underutilizes the intelligence and creativity of the subject people, and it almost inevitably leads to revolts and internal strife. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>奴隶制度是将一部分“劣等人”视为物品或财产的制度，奴隶拥有的权利并不比一头牛或一把椅子更多。奴隶制在人类文明产生之后即已出现，从原始时代，到古希腊和罗马，甚至在今天仍然存在。奴隶的来源有时是被定罪的犯人。有时是敌国的战俘。有时一个部族会全体沦为奴隶。在有的文明中，奴隶可以用钱赎得自由，或经过规定的时间后脱离奴隶身份。[PARAGRAPH:2]奴隶制的优势是统治者可以强迫奴隶做自由人不愿做的工作而无须增加报酬。廉价的劳动力能创造大量财富，使宏伟的宫殿和神庙得以建成，庞大的职业军队得以维持。除了在道德上的不合理性，奴隶制还存在许多负面作用：它使奴隶和奴隶主阶级都趋于堕落，压制了人民大众的智慧和创造力，几乎不可避免地会造成暴动内乱。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SERFDOM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Serfdom is a more "enlightened" form of slavery in that the power of the master is not absolute and the serfs are accorded a certain number of rights. The specific rights and obligations of masters and serfs vary significantly over time and from place to place. In some societies, the master had the right to control every aspect of a serf's life except that he couldn't kill the serf without just cause; in others, the serfs had the rights to marry and to inherit wealth and to a certain amount of self-government, but they could not leave the land without their lord's permission. [PARAGRAPH:2]The basic premise of serfdom is that one group of people are superior to another, and that they have the political and god-given right to control the other group's destiny. Thus serfdom only makes sense if one agrees with the group currently in power about who is superior to whom. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>农奴制度是一种较为“文明的”奴隶制度，农奴主对农奴的权力受到一定限制，农奴拥有少量的权利。对于农奴制度权利义务的具体规定在不同时代不同国家有所不同。在某些地方，农奴主有权控制农奴的一切，但没有正当的理由不得杀死农奴；在其他地方，农奴有权结婚和继承财产，且有一定的人身自由，但未经农奴主的允许不得离开所居住的土地。[PARAGRAPH:2]农奴制的基本理念仍是人天生存在优劣之分，上等人掌握神授的权力，可以控制下等人的命运。在拥有无上政治权力的人群看来，农奴制就是合理的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CASTE_SYSTEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The caste system is one where one's parentage determines one's place in society. If your parents are street-cleaners, then so are you. If your parents are merchants, that's what you are. If your parents are nobility, then you are as well. Your status is determined at birth, and there's nothing you can do to better it. One may advance within one's caste, but that's as far as it goes. Marriages between castes are taboo. [PARAGRAPH:2]There is little advantage to the caste system, except to the people whose parents are on the top of the heap. Merit and initiative are useless: if the most intelligent and wise person in the culture happens to be born a street-cleaner, then he'll be an intelligent and wise street-cleaner. He'll never have a chance to become a priest, philosopher, or leader.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>等级社会制度以人的出身决定其社会地位。如果你的父母是清洁工，你就是清洁工。如果你的父母是商人，你就是商人。如果你的父母是贵族，你就是贵族。你的社会地位在出生时即已决定，而且无法改变。一个人可能在本等级内发展，但仅此而已。不同等级间也禁止通婚。[PARAGRAPH:2]等级社会没有多少好处，除非是对于父母属于较高等级的人来说。个人才能和主动性没有任何用处：假如等级社会国家中最有智慧的人恰好出生在清洁工的家庭，那他只好当一个最有智慧的清洁工。他绝不可能有机会成为一位神学家，哲学家或是领导人。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_EMANCIPATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Emancipation refers to the abolition of slavery, serfdom, and caste system. Members of the society are on an equal footing: you may be rich and I poor, but if I'm smarter or more cunning than you, I can end up as your boss or even your ruler. Merit and experience and initiative are fully rewarded; each member of a nation can reach his or her potential, to the benefit of all. [PARAGRAPH:2]The previous paragraph describes a somewhat utopian society. In reality, one's situation at birth will have an effect upon one's progress in society. If your parents are rich, you are likely to be healthier, better educated and better connected than a person whose parents are poor. But at least it isn't illegal for the poor person to succeed: his innate qualities can overcome the disadvantages of his parentage. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>人身自由指完全废除奴隶制，农奴制和等级社会等。所有的社会成员一律处于平等地位：也许你是富人，我是穷人，但只要我比你更聪明机变，最终我可能成为你的老板甚至你的统治者。每一个人的才学、经验与主动性可以获得充分的回报；每一个人都可以充分发挥其潜能，在利人的同时也能利已。[PARAGRAPH:2]前一段所描述的其实是一种理想状况。在现实中，人的出身仍对其在社会中的发展具有重要影响。如果你的父母很富有，通常你就能比穷人家的孩子更健康地成长，获得更好的教育，建立更好的社会关系。但至少穷人争取成功的努力不违反法律：他可以通过个人能力弥补出身造成的不利因素。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DECENTRALIZATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Decentralization describes an economy in which the central government doesn't attempt to manage every aspect of a nation's production. The government doesn't set quotas, doesn't determine exactly what the nation's farms, factories, theatres and schools will output. Each farmer determines what his or her farm will produce; each factory owner decides what to build, whether to modernize or not, and so forth. [PARAGRAPH:2]This kind of a totally freewheeling economy may seriously increase a nation's productivity. However, it may also lead to disaster - if all of the farmers decide to produce cotton then the nation's people will be very hungry - well-dressed, perhaps, but still very hungry. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>分散经济指中央政府不集中管理整个国家各行各业的生产活动。政府不编制经济预案，不规定各地的农场、工厂、剧场和学校所要完成的指标。每位农场主自行决定产出什么；每位工厂主自行决定制造什么，是否要进行设备改造等。[PARAGRAPH:2]这种完全自主的经济制度可能提升全国的生产力。但是也可能造成灾难——如果所有农场主都决定产出棉花，国家就可能发生饥荒——也许衣着光鲜，但是饿得要死。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MERCANTILISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Mercantilism refers to government policy that strictly manages the nation's production. The government determines which farmers produce which crops, decides who will be allowed to sew pants and who will have a monopoly on shirts, and so on. The nation may ban all foreign imports. [PARAGRAPH:2]The advantages of mercantilism are that it ensures that a nation's wealth remains within the nation itself, and that its people are not put out of business by cheap foreign imports. On the other hand, the success or the failure of the entire economy is in the hands of just a few men or even one, and if they make foolish or unlucky decisions, the nation as a whole suffers. Further, the ban on foreign imports limits the nation's exposure to new products and new ideas. And if someone has a monopoly on an item, there is little pressure for that person to improve the item or make it cheaper.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>重商主义指政府严格管制国家的生产活动。政府决定每位农场主种植什么庄稼，决定谁负责卖裤子，谁拥有衬衫的专营权等。国家可能禁止所有从外国进口的产品。[PARAGRAPH:2]重商主义的好处是能确保国家的财富不外流，使民族产业不会因廉价外来产品的进口而遭受排挤。但在另一方面，整个经济系统的成败完全掌握在少数人甚至是一个人的手中，如果掌权者作出错误的决策，整个国家就会遭殃。此外，禁止进口也使国家不能获取新产品和新技术。而如果某种产品由少数人专营，这些垄断者就不会积极改进产品或降低成本。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FREE_MARKET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A free market system is similar to a decentralized system, in that the government doesn't try to impose price controls, quotas or other artificial limits on production. The market - what people want and what they are willing to pay for it - determines production. Unlike in decentralization the state maintains some controls over the system, attempting to ensure that the markets remain truly free and is not distorted by monopolies or corruption. [PARAGRAPH:2]A state may have some free markets while maintaining more control over others that it considers critical to the state's survival; in modern times these usually include the production and dispersion of energy and the production of weapons.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>自由市场与分散经济有些类似，政府不试图通过价格和配额等手段控制生产活动。而由市场供求——人们的需求决定其原意支付的价格——来决定生产。与分散经济不同的是，国家对经济系统保持一定程度的控制，以使市场保持自由竞争，不至产生垄断和腐败现象。[PARAGRAPH:2]一个国家可能实行自由市场制度，同时保持对关乎国计民生的重要产业的控制；现代国家往往会将能源工业和军火工业置于严格控制之下。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_STATE_PROPERTY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The state property civic describes an economy in which the citizens have no private property: everything belongs to the State. The State owns the factories, the farms, the universities, the grocery stores and virtually everything else. A citizen may own his or her clothing, furniture, and vehicle, but everything else he has is given to him by the State, and may be taken away any time the State sees fit. [PARAGRAPH:2]In a utopian society there would be no need for private property. Each person would contribute his or her best to the State; in return the State would distribute its largess according to each citizen's needs. Unfortunately, state property is quite a bit less fair when applied in real life. The State determines what each person gets, but often those decisions are based upon the citizen's political orthodoxy, family connections, or ability to pay bribes. The citizens feel that they are not rewarded for the quality of their efforts, and thus they see no point in achieving excellence. Innovation is pointless if one doesn't personally benefit from the innovation.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>国营经济体制下的公民没有私人产业：一切属于国家。国家拥有工厂，农场，大学，店铺以及其他一切。普通居民可能拥有自己的衣物，家具和汽车，但其他重要物资都是由国家分配的，也随时可能被国家收回。[PARAGRAPH:2]在理想社会中，私人产业确实是不必要的。每个人都努力为国家作出贡献；国家则根据个人需要进行财富的分配。不幸的是，现实世界中的国营经济并没有这么公平。国家决定每个人可获得的财富，但这样的决定往往要基于个人的政治态度，家庭关系，甚至贿赂官员的能力。人民常常感到他们的工作没有得到应有的回报，干好干坏一个样。如果个人不能获得利益，就不会努力进行创新。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_ENVIRONMENTALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Environmentalism is the civic which describes a society in which every effort is made to remain in balance with nature. Emphasis is placed upon renewable resources and energy, and every possible item is recycled. This of course describes the ideal; no modern society on earth of any size can as yet achieve perfect harmony with the world around it. [PARAGRAPH:2]There are many benefits to environmentalism, not the least of which is that it would ensure that mankind will not suffocate under the weight of its own greed and pollution. The population of a fully "green" society would live longer and healthier lives, secure in the knowledge that their children and grandchildren would enjoy the same beautiful world that they did. [PARAGRAPH:2]Unfortunately, such changes will come slowly, if at all. Rich and powerful nations are extremely reluctant to cut back on the resources they consume, and loathe to implement the kind of political and market reforms that such an economy would require. Meanwhile the poorer countries wish to attain all of the power and wealth currently enjoyed by the rich: to them a smokestack is a symbol of progress, not of the ongoing destruction of the earth. Radical change will have to wait for the time when the magnitude and imminence of disaster is visible to everyone.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>绿色经济以保持自然生态的平衡为基本目标，注重资源与能源的再生，尽可能循环利用各种物品——这当然是一种理想情况，尚未有任何现代社会达到这种与自然和谐相处的状态。[PARAGRAPH:2]实施绿色经济具有许多好处，可使人类不再因自己的贪婪和污染而遭受损害。生活在完全“绿色”社会里的人们将更加健康长寿，将来他们的子孙也将享受同样美好的生活。[PARAGRAPH:2]不幸的是，这种发展趋势即使正在推进，也是极其缓慢的。富有的强国特别不愿意减少资源的消耗量，不愿意实施符合绿色经济要求的政治与经济改革。同时穷国则希望达到富国现有的发达程度，对他们来说，烟囱是发展的标志，而不是对自然的损害。也许只有等到所有人都面临灾难，这种状况才会真正发生改变。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PAGANISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Paganism" describes religions that believe in the holiness of all things around them - rocks, trees, animals, clouds and so forth - rather than in specific concepts or beings. Pagans believe in multitudes of gods, that the gods are all around them, causing the sunset, the rising of bread, and the success of the hunt. [PARAGRAPH:2]A pagan seeks to remain in harmony with the natural world around him or her. The pagan doesn't look to appease a distant deity or hierarchy of deities who control his or her destiny. To a pagan, the gods are all around him or her, in plain sight every day. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>“原始信仰”是古老的万物有灵论——崇拜岩石、树木、动物，云雾等——而不是一种确定的信仰概念。原始信仰供奉多种神灵，认为神灵无处不在，控制着日出日落、作物的生长以及捕猎的成败。[PARAGRAPH:2]原始人希望保持与自然的和谐相处。他们认为无须取悦某个遥不可及的神灵。对原始人来说，每时每刻，神灵就在他们身边。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_ORGANIZED_RELIGION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An organized religion is one in which there is a central authority which interprets or determines theology, which decides which ceremonies are to be performed at which times, and which appoints priests or holy men to keep worshipers on the correct path. The central authority may be a rigid and powerful hierarchy with great religious and secular power, or it may be a group of elders who meet periodically to discuss matters of importance to their members. [PARAGRAPH:2]An organized religion can be a mighty thing, more powerful than kings or despots. Its followers may provide it with great wealth, and may construct mighty edifices in their gods' honor. Usually, however, organized religions are less powerful than that and must live in uneasy harmony with the local secular governments. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>信仰控制是由一个集中的权威负责解释和传播信仰，决定何时进行何种宗教仪式，任命神职人员使信徒保持正确的行为方式。这种集中的权威可以是一个强有力的等级体系，拥有各种宗教和世俗权力，或者可能是一群定期集会，讨论并决定宗教事务的长者。[PARAGRAPH:2]实行信仰控制的宗教机构可能比君主更强大。宗教的信徒可能赋予其大量财富，为其建造宏伟的神殿。但是通常来说，宗教机构往往需要与世俗政府保持和谐相处才能维持其权利。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_THEOCRACY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A theocracy is a form of government where priests or holy men are in charge of the government. The government is run to benefit the people, but, more importantly, in accord with the wishes of the almighty, as interpreted by the holy men and priests. According to the theory, it is the will of God that such men be in charge of running things, and political dissent is sinful and wrong-headed, if not outright heresy. [PARAGRAPH:2]In the modern world, theocracies tend to be backward-looking, seeking to return their country to some usually mythical past state of grace and away from the evil and corrupt modern world. Diplomacy tends to be extremely difficult for such countries, since countries who act against their interests are doing so at the urging of the devil, rather than because the other countries have their own points of view and objectives. How can a holy leader compromise with an imp of Satan?</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>神权政治是由神职人员管理政府机构的一种体制。政府除了服务于大众，还要服务于神的意志，而神的意志则是由神职人员负责解读的。根据神权政治的理论，神职人员管理政权是出于神的意志，反对他们就是对信仰的犯罪，甚至是魔鬼的异端。[PARAGRAPH:2]在现代，神权政治的国家往往趋于保守，向往使国家回归过去的荣耀，远离邪恶堕落的现代文明。与这种国家开展外交是非常困难的，因为实施不同的政策将被该国视作屈服于魔鬼的意志，而不是出于政治观点和目标的差异。一位神圣的宗教领袖怎么可能与魔鬼的代理人妥协呢?</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PACIFISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Pacifism is the religious belief that all conflict is against the will of God. Man must not fight against his fellow man. If a person slaps your face, simply turn the other cheek. Basically, what happens to a person in this world really doesn't matter much at all: if a bully takes your stuff or kills you and you don't fight back, you will gain your reward in heaven (or in your next incarnation). The bully may enjoy his ill-gotten gains for a few paltry years in this world, but he will suffer tenfold in the next. [PARAGRAPH:2]Pacifism seems to enjoy popularity among people or nations who have little power of their own, people who cannot physically resist their oppressors with any hope of success. Once such people gain power and gain some measure of control over their destinies, however, they often discard their pacifism for more militant beliefs.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>和平主义认为一切宗教冲突都不符合神的意志。人人都是兄弟姊妹，不应相互争斗。如果别人打你的左脸，应该把右脸也转过去让他打。基本上，在这个世界上发生的一切都无关紧要：如果暴徒抢走你的财物或夺去你的生命而你不加抵抗，你将在天堂（或是在来世）得到回报。暴徒在有生之年可以享受其掠夺的成果，但在来世将遭受到十倍的痛苦。[PARAGRAPH:2]和平主义的观念往往在力量弱小的人群和国家中普遍存在，因为他们没有希望真正推翻强者的压迫。而一旦人们拥有了实力并能够掌握自身的命运，往往便会抛弃和平主义的理念。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FREE_RELIGION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Free religion refers to a society in which no single religion is dominant, in which people are free to worship or not worship as they please. There is no state religion; the government is totally secular. [PARAGRAPH:2]Such states allow all to express their religious beliefs. This encourages immigration by people whose religions are suppressed elsewhere, and the general society benefits from the multitude of experiences and beliefs of its members. However, such freedom and tolerance of religions may weaken a nation's people's beliefs in any religion, which could cause the people to become morally lax and decadent. Further, members of the more militant and expansionist religions may seek to destroy the competition, causing a good deal of stress and conflict within a country. A good deal of maturity is required on the part of a government and its people to successfully sustain free religion.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>信仰自由指任何信仰都不处于社会支配地位，人人都有信仰某一宗教或不信仰宗教的权利。不存在一种官方信仰，政府完全是世俗性质的。[PARAGRAPH:2]信仰自由的国家允许任何人表达自己的宗教观念，这吸引了大批在祖国遭受宗教迫害的人群流入，高素质的外来移民能使整个社会获得好处。但是，信仰自由和宽容政策也可能使国民对任何宗教都失去热情，容易造成人们的道德堕落倾向。此外，某些强势宗教的信徒可能采取手段破坏信仰自由，造成国家内部的紧张和冲突。政府需要足够的耐心和技巧以维持信仰自由的政策。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_JUDAISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Born perhaps 4000 years ago, Judaism is one of the oldest religious traditions practiced today, the first known religion to embrace monotheism and one of the most influential in history. Born in the "cradle of religions," the Middle East, Judaism provided the foundations for Christianity and Islam, two other "Abrahamic" religions. [PARAGRAPH:2]Judaism is the religion of the Jews, originally a Semitic tribe that lived in an area of the Middle East roughly centered on the ancient city of Jerusalem. Over time their central beliefs were written down in the Bible (Old Testament), which contains the history of the Jews, as well as the words of prophets and kings. Most importantly, the Bible teaches the children of Israel how to live according to God's wishes. [PARAGRAPH:2]These are the central beliefs of Judaism. There is only one God and you must not worship any other gods before Him. God is all powerful, all knowing, and eternal. Each man prays to God directly, without the need for an intermediary. People can atone for sins through words and deeds. God has chosen the Jewish people to be in a covenant with Him, and some day God will send a Messiah to bring all of the chosen people back to Israel and usher in an era of peace and prosperity to the Earth. [PARAGRAPH:2]Judaism is a remarkably strong and resilient faith. Throughout history the Jews have been oppressed and enslaved by a series of conquerors. They have been taken from their homeland and scattered across Europe, Africa and Asia. They have been the targets of a program of unbelievably brutal genocide. But throughout it all, the Jews have remained faithful to their religion and their God. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>犹太教大约在4000年前诞生，作为流传至今最古老的宗教之一和已知最早的一神教，是历史上最具影响力的一种宗教信仰。犹太教诞生于有宗教摇篮之称的中东地区，是另外两个“亚伯拉罕”的宗教——基督教与伊斯兰教的本源。[PARAGRAPH:2]犹太教是闪族部落的一个分支——犹太人的信仰，他们生活的地区以古城耶路撒冷为中心。经过长期的演进，他们的信仰被写成圣经（旧约），其中包含了犹太人的历史，以及先知与国王们的言行。最重要的是，圣经教导着以色列的孩子们如何按照上帝的旨意生活。[PARAGRAPH:2]犹太教有几个要义：世间只有一位真神耶和华，此外不能崇拜别的神。神是掌握权柄的、全知全能的、永生的。所有人直接向神祷告，不需任何代言人。人们通过话语与行动来赎罪。神选择了犹太人来与他立约，而有朝一日神会派一位救世主（“弥赛亚”）带领神的选民回到以色列，开创和平与繁荣的盛世。[PARAGRAPH:2]犹太教是一个非常坚强，极具弹性的信仰。在历史长河中犹太人饱受许许多多的征服者压迫与奴役。他们被人从家园赶走辗转途径欧洲，非洲和亚洲。他们难以置信的成为一系列残忍暴力种族屠杀的目标。但是即使遭受如此种种，犹太人还是坚守他们的信仰和他们的神。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_CHRISTIANITY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Christianity is the world's largest religion. It is the dominant religion in Europe, North, Central and South America, and has made significant inroads in all other parts of the world. Christianity is based upon the teachings of Jesus Christ, whom Christians believe to have been the "son of God made flesh," brought to the world to teach men the way of salvation. Jesus lived from approximately 6 BC to 30 AD. [PARAGRAPH:2]Jesus' life and teachings are recorded in the New Testament. Born of the Virgin Mary, a Jew, the Christ lived and taught in and around present-day Palestine and Israel. According to the New Testament, he performed many miracles during his lifetime, and he taught men how to cleanse themselves from sin and thus achieve eternal happiness after death. Jesus was betrayed and crucified, but he rose from death after three days and ascended into heaven. [PARAGRAPH:2]After Christ's death, Christianity spread throughout the eastern Mediterranean. The Romans tried unsuccessfully to suppress it, but eventually they adopted Christianity as the state religion. With the might of Rome behind it, Christianity spread rapidly through the known world. When the Roman Empire fell, Christianity broke into two branches. Since then it has continued to fragment, with a number of the branches quite hostile to others. Today, the major Christian branches include Roman Catholicism, Protestantism, Orthodox Christianity, and Mormonism.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>基督教是世界第一大宗教。它在欧洲与整个美洲占统治地位，在其他地区也拥有巨大影响力。基督教信仰是基于耶稣的教导，基督徒相信耶稣是神的儿子，来到世上教导人们救赎之道。耶稣大约生活在公元前6年到公元后30年。[PARAGRAPH:2]耶稣的言行事迹记录在新约圣经中。耶稣是犹太处女玛丽亚所生，他在今巴勒斯坦与以色列地区生活与教导众人。根据新约记载，他一生中显示了许多奇迹，他教导门徒如何从原罪里洁净自身，以在死后获得永恒的幸福。后来耶稣被出卖并被钉死在十字架上，但他三天后复活并升入天堂。[PARAGRAPH:2]耶稣死后，基督教传遍了整个东地中海地区。罗马帝国曾经竭力镇压它，但是劳而无功，最终基督教却成为了罗马的国教。此后基督教以罗马帝国的威名为后盾迅速传遍西方世界。罗马帝国衰亡后，基督教分裂为两派。后来又分裂为更多的教派，有的教派之间甚至水火不容。今天，主流基督教派别包括天主教、新教、东正教和摩门教等。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_ISLAM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Islam" means "the submission to God." It is the world's second largest religion. Most adherents can be found in the Middle East, Asia and Africa, but Islam has a strong presence in Europe as well. Muslims - followers of Islam - believe that there is only one God ("Allah" in Arabic), and that over the years he has revealed his desires to a number of great prophets: Adam, Abraham, Moses, Jesus, and Muhammad. The last and greatest of prophets, Muhammad has written down God's direct words in the Koran, which is the only true guide to a holy life. [PARAGRAPH:2]Muhammad was born in the city of Mecca (which is now part of Saudi Arabia). He lived from 570 to 632. He began life as a merchant, but during his 40th year he experienced a series of visions from God, who commanded him to memorize the verses that would later make up the Koran. Muhammad revealed his visions to others and he gained followers. He and his followers were reviled and attacked by those who did not believe, but they were following the path that God had set for them and emerged triumphant, eventually unifying all of Arabia under one rule. After Muhammad's death, his words spread throughout the Middle East and far beyond. [PARAGRAPH:2]Since Muhammad, Islam has broken into a number of branches, the three most prominent being the Sunni, Shi'ite and Kharijite. These schools disagree on the correct succession of authority after Muhammad's death - a matter of great religious and political importance to Islam. [PARAGRAPH:2]All Muslims believe in the "Five Pillars of Islam," which state that one must do the following to achieve salvation: acknowledge that there is no god but God, and Muhammad is his Prophet; pray daily to God at the five established times; give a portion of one's wealth to the poor; fast from dawn to dusk during the month of Ramadan; and make a pilgrimage to Mecca during the holy month of Dhul Hijjah.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>伊斯兰教或称“回教”，“伊斯兰”的意思是“对主谦卑”。作为世界第二大宗教，它在中东，亚洲和非洲拥有大量信徒，在欧洲也有很强的影响力。穆斯林——即伊斯兰教信徒——相信只有一位真主（阿拉伯语称为“安拉”），他不断地向古代先知显示他的期待：亚当、亚伯拉罕、摩西、耶稣，而穆罕默德是最后也是最重要的一位先知。穆罕默德在可兰经中写下了神的教导，这是唯一真正的圣命指导书。[PARAGRAPH:2]穆罕默德出生于麦加（今属沙特阿拉伯）。他生活在公元570至632年间。原是一个商人，但在40岁时梦到真主的谕示，真主令他记下许多诗文（即后来的可兰经）。穆罕默德向世人宣示他的梦境并获得了众多信徒。起初穆罕默德及其追随者不断遭受辱骂甚至攻击，但他们仍紧随真主为他们铺设与指引的道路，最终获得了胜利，所有的阿拉伯人全都统一在安拉的名下。穆罕默德死后，他的教导传遍了整个中东乃至更远的地区。[PARAGRAPH:2]穆罕默德之后，伊斯兰教分裂为多个派别，其中最主要的三个是逊尼派、什叶派和哈里哲派。在穆罕默德死后，这些教派无法就由谁担任伊斯兰教最高精神领袖达成一致——这对伊斯兰世界有着重要的宗教与政治意义。[PARAGRAPH:2]伊斯兰教信仰的基本原则即“念，礼，课，斋，朝”五功：认主独一（信奉安拉是唯一的真主，穆罕默德是最后一位先知），按时礼拜（每日五次），交纳天课（向穷人施舍财物），谨守斋戒（在斋月的白天禁食）和朝觐圣地（一生至少一次在朝圣月前往麦加）。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_HINDUISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Hinduism is considered to be the oldest religion still in practice. Its roots can be traced back to the Rig-Veda, a collection of over 1000 religious hymns written about 3500 years ago in Sanskrit. Today Hinduism has approximately one billion followers, most concentrated in the Indian subcontinent. [PARAGRAPH:2]Hinduism believes that man needs to strive for self-realization in order to once again become part of the Ultimate Reality, which is God. All things are God - each man suffers only because he has forgotten that. Until he remembers, his soul remains in bondage, and he must suffer the eternal cycle of death and rebirth into this world. [PARAGRAPH:2]Perhaps the most interesting part of Hindu thought is that there is no one true path to self-realization. Any kind of spiritual practice followed with faith and love will lead one to this enlightenment. Hindus have a rich pantheon of deities, all of whom are but a different aspect of the one God. Many contemporary Hindus believe in a Holy Trinity, consisting of Brahma the Creator, Vishnu the Preserver, and Shiva the Destroyer - all are equal, all are faces of the One. Other Hindus have different interpretations, some citing one god as God and others as subordinates. [PARAGRAPH:2]Despite these differences, there is little conflict between the various schools of thought. For, as Krishna, avatar of Vishnu, said, "Whatever deity or form a devotee worships, I make his faith steady." </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>印度教或称“兴都教”、“婆罗门教”，直到今天，人们仍然认为印度教是最古老的一种宗教。它的根源可以追溯到《梨俱吠陀》，此书汇集了大约3500年前的1000余首梵文宗教赞美诗。现在印度教大约有十亿信徒，主要集中于印度次大陆。[PARAGRAPH:2]印度教相信人们必须不断修行来完成自我实现，以期成为最高实现——也就是神——的一部分。神无处不在，如果有人忘记这点他就会一直遭受苦难，他的灵魂将永被束缚，并在这个世界中永受生死轮回。[PARAGRAPH:2]也许印度教思想中最有趣的部分，是并不存在一条通往自我实现的真正道路。任何遵从信念与爱的精神训练可以给人启迪。印度教有众多神祗，每位神各司其职。现在很多印度教徒信仰三位一体的大神：造物主梵天、保护神毗湿努、破坏者湿婆——三者平等，是一体的三个侧面。其他信徒有不同的见解，他们认为只有一个最高的神，其他的神都处于下级。[PARAGRAPH:2]除去这些差别，不同的思想学派之间还有些矛盾。比如，毗湿努的化身克利须那说：“无论崇拜哪个神，我使他的信仰坚定。”</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_BUDDHISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Buddhism is one of the world's major religions, with more that 350 million followers. Buddhism originated in India and has since spread throughout the subcontinent and into central and southeast Asia. [PARAGRAPH:2]Buddhism follows the teachings of Siddhartha Gautama, the Buddha. Gautama lived from 620 to 540 BC. The Buddha ("enlightened one") sought to teach his followers to search for "Dharma," the truth. By doing so, they too would become enlightened and thus achieve "Nirvana," the perfect peace that would free one's soul from the unending cycle of death and rebirth that all men suffer. [PARAGRAPH:2]Three major schools of Buddhism survive today. Vajrayana believes that people can "speed up" enlightenment through "tantric" techniques such as yoga, mantras (chants), and various other rituals. Theravada and Mahayana are sutric schools that believe that one achieves enlightenment primarily through study of the Budda's teachings.</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>佛教是世界上的主要宗教之一，拥有超过三亿五千万信徒。佛教起源于印度，之后逐渐传播到整个南亚次大陆以及中亚和东南亚。[PARAGRAPH:2]佛教遵从悉达多·乔达摩——也就是佛陀——的教诲。乔达摩生活于公元前620年至540年。佛陀（“大彻大悟之人”）希望教导他的信徒去寻找“德性”，也就是生活的真谛。如果做到这些，他们就会大彻大悟，达到“涅磐”的境界，灵魂会从无尽的生死轮回中解脱出来，进入完全的超脱状态。[PARAGRAPH:2]佛教流传至今有三种主要门派。金刚乘佛教相信人们可以通过瑜伽、曼特拉（瑜伽颂歌）以及其它多种仪式等“密派方术”使人们更快达到大彻大悟的境界。大乘佛教和小乘佛教则是更注重于研究经文的教派，他们相信不断学习佛陀的教诲是使人大彻大悟的唯一途径。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_CONFUCIANISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Confucianism is an East Asian religion based upon the teachings of Confucius. Confucius (known in Chinese as Kong Fu Zi) lived between 552 and 479 BC. Confucius lived in China during an especially turbulent period, when the country lacked central leadership and various small states fought constantly for dominance. As much a philosopher and political theorist as a religious leader, Confucius sought to teach others the correct behavior for man in society. His philosophy emphasized personal and governmental morality and strong family loyalty. He believed that each man had a place in society, and that each should behave righteously and correctly according to that place. This included the ruler, who needed to be devoted to the people rather than to personal aggrandizement. [PARAGRAPH:2]Confucianism grew in influence for the two centuries following Confucius' death, until it was rigidly suppressed during the Qin Dynasty, whose leaders saw it as a threat to their power. The Qin systematically destroyed the Confucian temples and burned all the Confucian books, including most of Confucius' writings. Virtually everything was lost, except for a cache of important books hidden in the walls of a believer's home. When these were discovered, the few remaining believers were able to rebuild and spread their religion. Eventually Confucianism became the state religion of China. It remained so until the Communists came into power in the 20th Century. [PARAGRAPH:2]Today, Confucianism is enjoying something of a revival, and many Chinese students (and students from around the world) study the great philosopher and his teachings. However, in modern times Confucianism is mostly studied as a philosophy rather than a religion (though it should be pointed out that there is no clear distinction between the two in Eastern thought).</English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>儒学是依据孔子的教诲而建立的一种信仰，在东亚影响广泛。孔子生活于前552至前479年。当时的中国正处王室黯弱、诸侯纷争的乱世。除了作为儒学信仰的至尊领袖，孔子还是一位哲学家和政治理论家，他教导人们在社会中的行为准则。他的哲学思想着重于个人与政府行为的道德规范，强调家庭和秩序的重要性。他认为每个人在社会中都有相应的地位，他们的行为应该符合他所处的地位。这也包括统治者，他必须致力于提升民众的福祉，而非强化个人的权势。[PARAGRAPH:2]孔子去世后的两个世纪里，儒学的影响力不断增强，但在秦朝建立后又遭到严厉的镇压，秦始皇认为儒学思想威胁到了自己的统治。政府下令拆毁孔庙，焚毁所有儒学典籍，包括孔子大量的著作。当时几乎所有典籍都被销毁，但也有一部分被儒生们藏在自己家的墙壁里。当这些典籍重见天日，儒学思想才得以重建并再度获得广泛传播。最终儒学成为中国的官方信仰，直到20世纪时共产党取得政权后才失去其崇高地位。[PARAGRAPH:2]在今天，儒学再次复苏，有无数中国以及全球各地的学生在学习这位伟大哲学家的思想和他的教诲。不过在现代，儒学更多的被视为一种哲学而并非宗教（不过有一点必须指出，在东方人的思想中，这两者的界限并不明确）。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_RELIGION_TAOISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>When discussing "Taoism," one must be careful to distinguish between the philosophy of Tao and the religion of Tao. The philosophy of Tao came first. According to tradition, the philosopher Lao-Tsu lived in the 4th Century BC. He wrote the "Tao Te Ching," which can be roughly translated as "The Book of the Way and its Virtue." [PARAGRAPH:2]The Tao Te Ching is written in verse. It is extremely subtle and difficult to understand. Many scholars have spent years trying to interpret it. The book can be (very primitively and probably inaccurately) summarized as follows. The "Tao" is what exists before everything else. It is formless, and from it all things are formed. Man must aspire to simplicity; only by discarding the useless trappings of culture and civilization can man return to his original state of emptiness - Tao - when all is possible. According to Lao-Tsu, "the sage has no heart of his own" - no intentions, no preconceptions, and no agenda. [PARAGRAPH:2]The religion of Taoism is based upon worship of Lao-Tsu as a deity. According to Taoist religious tradition, in 142 AD Lao-Tsu appeared to Zhang Daoling, a hermit, and told him that the world was coming to an end, and those who followed Lao-Tsu would go on to another, better life. Further, Lao-Tsu's followers would have access to the celestial powers that control the fate of mankind. Zhang preached Lao-Tsu's words and gained many converts.[PARAGRAPH:2]Over time, Taoism split into a number of schools. Some believed that they could change the world through talismans, alchemy, and magical spells. Some sought to achieve immortality through a Buddhist-like enlightenment. A variety of gods from Chinese folklore and Buddhist tradition were incorporated into the religion.[PARAGRAPH:2]Taoism spread widely throughout China, and it was the official state religion for a thousand years, until the end of the Qing Dynasty in 1911. The Communists virtually eradicated the religion in China during the Cultural Revolution (1960-76), when many of the temples were destroyed and the monks and priests sent to "reeducation" camps. In the 1980s China restored some religious tolerance, and Taoist temples are slowly being rebuilt and repaired. [PARAGRAPH:2]It is believed that many Chinese still practice Taoism in some form, despite the government's restrictions. Taoism is also practiced by some 31 million people outside of China, the largest group being in Taiwan. Its influence can be felt world-wide in the practices of acupuncture, herbalism, feng shui, and martial arts. </English>
<L1 /><L2 /><L3 /><L4 />
		<Chinese>在讨论“道”这一名词的时候，必须小心区分作为哲学流派的道家和作为宗教信仰的道教。首先出现的是道家哲学。据记载，哲学家老子生活的年代是公元前四世纪。他的著作就是“道德经”——这一书名的含义大致可以理解为“关于道及其美德的阐述”。[PARAGRAPH:2]道德经是以韵文的形式写成的。用词极其玄妙，非常难懂。无数学者花费了无数的时间尝试解释其中所包含的意义。这部著作的含义可以（极其粗浅和简略地）解释如下：“道”先于天地而生。道无形无象，但创生了宇宙万物。人应当追求无为；只有弃绝所谓的仁义礼智，人类才能回归原本自然，无知无欲的状态，像“道”对待万物那样的无为而治。根据老子的观点，“圣人处无为之事，行不言之教”——不强加意图，不强作判断，不强行干涉。[PARAGRAPH:2]作为一种宗教信仰的道教则将老子奉为神明。根据道教传说，在公元142年，老子降临在一位隐士张道陵的面前，告诉他世界即将面临末日，只有信奉老子的人才能脱离尘世，得道成仙，拥有呼风唤雨，掌控命运的能力。张道陵于是开始宣扬老子的教导，并获得了大批追随者。[PARAGRAPH:2]随着时间的推移，教道中分出了诸多流派。有的流派相信能通过神符，丹药或是咒语控制万物。有的流派则试图通过类似佛教信徒的修行方式求得永生。大量来自中国神话和佛教传说的神灵也逐渐被引入道教的信仰体系。[PARAGRAPH:2]道教在中国各地均相当普及，并被作为官方信仰达上千年之久，直到1911年清朝的灭亡。在文化大革命期间（1966-1976），中国共产党政权实际上完全禁绝了任何宗教信仰，许多道教观宇被拆毁，大批道士被送往“劳改营”。到20世纪80年代，中国政府基本恢复了信仰宽容政策，各地的道观才得以重建和修缮。[PARAGRAPH:2]据认为，虽然政府采取了各种限制措施，但目前在中国仍有许多人信奉着各种流派的道教。道教信徒在中国大陆之外约有3100万人，主要分布于台湾地区。来自于道教的针灸、风水和武术文化已经传遍了整个世界。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
