<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Civ4GameText>
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HIGH_WARLORD_1</Tag>
		<English>An esteemed warlord who operates from the castle in %s2_city has offered to set up a special military academy at his own expense.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位军事首领提议由他出资创办一所军事学院。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_2</Tag>
		<English>Alright, try limited tests, but only on non-essential citizens.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>针对少部分人群进行有限度的临床试验。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SOLO_FLIGHT_1</Tag>
		<English>This grand achievement has won admiration from people across the globe!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这一英雄壮举赢得了全世界人民的赞誉！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MAN_NAMED_JED_2</Tag>
		<English>This substance must be studied to see how we might make use of it.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们要好好研究一下这种液体，看看能用它来做些什么。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_TRADING_COMPANY_CONQUERORS</Tag>
		<English>With the establishment of our own Trading Company, our country's merchants are approaching you to take action to further assert their position in the South Asian markets.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>随着我们贸易公司的建立，我们国家的商人正根据你的意图采取行动，以便进一步巩固在南亚市场的地位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WEDDING_FEUD_1</Tag>
		<English>Send well wishes and a token wedding gift, trying not to further anger our neighbors.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>送上美好的祝福和象征性的礼物，尝试不再激怒邻国。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANTIMONARCHISTS_2</Tag>
		<English>It's a valid point, our clerics need more influence.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>有点道理，神职人员应该获得更大的权力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BLESSED_SEA_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>Receive a Great Prophet.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>赠送一位大预言家。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_RURAL_FARMERS_1</Tag>
		<English>A grocer in %s2_city has struck a deal with rural farmers who live outside the normal range of business of any major city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位杂货商与远郊区的农民签订了一份收购协议。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SPORTS_LEAGUE_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective cities have built enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Arenas[COLOR_REVERT] to complete the National Sports League quest, strengthening their social fabric and their national identity.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective通过建造足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]竞技场[COLOR_REVERT]胜利完成了“国家体育联合会”任务，增强社会凝聚力和民族认同感。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ICE_SCULPTURE_1</Tag>
		<English>We are glad to see that the local culture is thriving.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们很高兴看到当地文化的繁荣。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_NOBLE_KNIGHTS_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective people have trained the largest force of lancers. Advisors across the known world tremble at the thought of facing rows of lances powered by the thundering hooves of a full battle charge.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective建立了一支强大的骑士部队。各国统治者一想到他们将要面对隆隆的铁蹄、密集的长枪巨大的冲击力都会感到颤栗不已。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HALBERD_1</Tag>
		<English>Our weapon masters have devised a halberd design that remains fully effective versus mounted units but will boost effectiveness versus foot soldiers.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的武器工匠设计了一种新式长戟，这种新武器不但保持了对骑兵的优势，还增强了对抗步兵的能力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HOLY_MOUNTAIN_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Your people are inspired by the way in which you have honored your faith.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国人民因你光大了我们的信仰而备受鼓舞。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BLACK_PEARLS_1</Tag>
		<English>Locals have figured out a way to obtain a higher yield of black pearls. They are guarding their secret with great care.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>当地居民找到了大规模养殖黑珍珠的方法，他们小心保守着这个秘密。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BOWYER_1</Tag>
		<English>A master bowyer has crafted a bow design that works particularly well with our native wood.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位制弓大师改进了弓弩设计，使我们可以用便宜的本国木材大量生产良弓。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BEST_DEFENSE_DONE_HELP_2</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Receive [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]%D1[COLOR_REVERT] attitude from all leaders</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]所有领袖的外交态度[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]%D1[COLOR_REVERT]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FEDERAL_RESERVE_1</Tag>
		<English>Let the free market make use of these techniques.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在市场经济中运用这些新调控手段。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FARM_PLOWS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective plow sales are booming.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective出产的犁在市场上大量销售。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROKEN_DAM_3</Tag>
		<English>Repair the dam and provide compensation to the affected families.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>立即修复大堤并向灾民发放救济金。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HORTICULTURE_3</Tag>
		<English>Certain rare insects found near %s2_city, when harvested and ground into a paste by a reclusive tribe, can be ingested to reduce fever.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s2_city附近发现了一种稀有昆虫，当地部落居民将其碾成糊状服用以治疗热病。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_INTERSTATE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective Empire has begun construction of a modern national highway network that shall be the envy of the world.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective开始兴建令全世界羡慕的现代化国家公路网。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SUBWAY</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective metropolis of %s2_city has constructed a mass transit marvel: an underground railroad network. They are calling it the Subway.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city这座现代化大都市完成了宏伟地下轨道公共交通网络，人们称之为“地铁”。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_THE_GOTHS</Tag>
		<English>A massive barbarian uprising is occurring. The Goths have gathered an army and their axemen seek to plunder civilizations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>蛮族开始大举入侵！哥特人集结了庞大的军队，用他们手中的利斧掠夺各个文明国度的财富。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SECRET_KNOWLEDGE_2</Tag>
		<English>Preserve these works as a cultural treasure.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>秘密保存这一文化宝库。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FOREST_FIRE_3</Tag>
		<English>Tragedy has struck near %s2_city as a village fire spread to the forest, scarring the land for miles.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>悲剧降临了%s2_city，一场小火灾蔓延到了附近的森林，大片绿地化为焦土。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FASHION_1</Tag>
		<English>Silk dresses have become the latest fashion, sweeping the nation thanks to radio advertising.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在媒体广告的大力宣传下，丝绸服装已成为社会各阶层的流行时尚。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_INSPIRED_MISSION</Tag>
		<English>Inspired %s3_religion_adjective missionaries from the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city have greatly expanded the influence of their religion!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>来自%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city的%s4_religion_adjective传教士迅速拓展了他们宗教的影响力！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HORSE_WHISPERING_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>Our horses are trained to be more productive on the farm.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>经过我们训练的马匹能够更快地繁育。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_OTHER_5</Tag>
		<English>Our %s1_civ_adjective religious brothers have gifted us with [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ivory[COLOR_REVERT] to aid us in our war effort!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>同我们一样信奉%s1_civ_adjective的兄弟之邦提供了[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]象牙[COLOR_REVERT]资源以资助我们的战争！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HIYOSILVER</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective miners have struck it rich with the discovery of new veins of Silver ore.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的探矿者因找到了一处银矿而大发横财。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MOTHER_LODE_1</Tag>
		<English>Cash in on our success!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让我们享受胜利果实吧！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BARBARIAN_UPRISING</Tag>
		<English>We are likely to take the worst of the barbarian horde's fury.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们正面临蛮族部落的大举入侵。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPORTS_LEAGUE_1</Tag>
		<English>National Sports League[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your cultural advisors to build enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Arenas[COLOR_REVERT] to support viable sports leagues.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“国家体育联合会”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]你的文化顾问提议建造足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]竞技场[COLOR_REVERT]以举办各种体育赛事。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MINING_ACCIDENT_1</Tag>
		<English>A minor earthquake near %s2_city has caused the collapse of a nearby mine. Trapped miners have perished by the hundreds.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city附近发生了一场地震，造成附近矿井坍塌，有数以百计的矿工遇难。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_AIRLINER_CRASH_2</Tag>
		<English>Stall them for time while your own team learns what it can first.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>阻挠对方救援队的行动，让我们的人先进行调查。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SECURITY_TAX</Tag>
		<English>The well-protected %s1_civ_adjective citizens endure paying a Security Tax to help maintain their city walls and guards.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>获得良好保护的%s1_civ_adjective居民被迫额外交纳“安全税”，用于维护城墙及供养守卫。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SALTPETER_1</Tag>
		<English>Our ability to manufacture large amounts of gunpowder should prove lucrative.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>规模化的火药生产有利于国家。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SECRET_KNOWLEDGE_1</Tag>
		<English>A cache of ancient writings has been discovered hidden away in a cubby hole in a monastery in %s2_city!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s2_city修道院地下的隐秘洞穴里发现了一批古籍。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WHALEOFATHING_1</Tag>
		<English>Sailors have spotted a new population of whales.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的水手在海上发现大量鲸鱼。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEROIC_GESTURE_WORLD_2</Tag>
		<English>A heroic gesture of mercy by the %s3_civ_adjective forces toward the %s1_civ_adjective wounded has brought an unexpected opportunity for peace. The two sides are at least pausing to consider the possibility.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s3_civ_adjective军队对俘获的%s1_civ_adjective伤兵的善意举动带来了意外的和平机会，双方已准备进行停火谈判。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HIGH_WARLORD_1</Tag>
		<English>We have no need of his services. Ask him instead to donate his money to the state.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们不需要军事学院，让他直接把钱捐给国家。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CHILLY_FLIGHT_1</Tag>
		<English>A pilot from %s2_city has become the first to fly solo over the North Pole and return safely.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>来自%s2_city的一位飞行员首次独自飞越北极并安全返回。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPICY_1</Tag>
		<English>That sounds like welcome news for our economy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这对我们的经济来说是个好消息。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PRAIRIE_DOGS_1</Tag>
		<English>Tamers have figured out how to domesticate the abundant supply of prairie dogs on the open range. They are now selling these as pets.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>草原居民大量驯养土拨鼠，并作为宠物销售。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WEDDING_FEUD_2</Tag>
		<English>Two prominent families are feuding over their children, who eloped together against everybody else's wishes. %s1_civ_adjective leaders are particularly upset that the marriage was held in our %s4_religion_adjective tradition.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>两个有名望的家族为他们的孩子而发生争执，他们的孩子违背了家长的意愿一起私奔了。%s1_civ_adjective的领袖还因我们坚持按%s4_religion_adjective传统举行婚礼而感到不满。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HORSE_WHISPERING_1</Tag>
		<English>Horse Whispering[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your elite trainers to build enough stables for them to transcend the traditional limits of animal husbandry.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“马语者”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]资深驯马师请你完成一项任务：建造足够数量的马厩，以便他们尝试超越传统理念的新型驯马方法。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MODERNOLYMPICS</Tag>
		<English>The modern %s2_city Games have begun, with the full richness of the ancient athletic traditions brought back for all the world to enjoy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city开始举办现代运动会，继承并发扬了古代运动会的传统，令全世界再次感受到体育运动的无限魅力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPY_DISCOVERED</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_civ_adjective spy is operating on a high level in our government! What should we do?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一名%s1_civ_adjective间谍渗入了我国政府高层！我们该如何处理？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SETBACK_1</Tag>
		<English>Progress sometimes comes more slowly than we would wish.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>进度有时要比我们想象的慢。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANCIENTOLYMPICS_1</Tag>
		<English>These Games are honorable, but overall their importance to our civilization is minor.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真是一场盛大的赛事，但是未免有些劳民伤财。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PRAIRIE_DOGS_1</Tag>
		<English>Prairie dogs? This is making us money? That's good, I suppose.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>土拨鼠也能卖钱？我想这是件好事。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SOUR_CRUDE</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective merchants are offering discounts on barrels of their sour crude oil, which is filled with impurities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective商人开始倾销劣质原油。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GUNS_BUTTER_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Leverage our military advantage to collect harsh taxes from our feudal lords and their counties.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用我们的军事优势对下属封国课以重税。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GOLD_RUSH_1</Tag>
		<English>A gold rush has begun at the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city. Fortune seekers from across the world travel there in hopes of getting rich quickly.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city附近发现黄金，世界各地的淘金者蜂拥而至，梦想着一夜暴富。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TOO_CLOSE_TO_CALL_2</Tag>
		<English>Refuse to submit to constitutional rule of law, citing wishful reinterpretations of the constitution or arguments based on passion and principle. Arrive at the desired outcome without heed to the actual constitution.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>反对机械片面地解读法律，改以符合情理的方式重新解读宪法条文，达成令各方都能接受的结果。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_THE_GOTHS_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]A dangerous number of barbarian [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Axeman[COLOR_REVERT] units have spawned near our border.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]大量蛮族[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]斧兵[COLOR_REVERT]出现在我国边境地区。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SALTPETER_DISCOVERED</Tag>
		<English>Saltpeter Discovered.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>发现硝石.</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TORNADO_2</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective infrastructure was wiped out by a deadly thunderstorm and the violent twisters it spawned.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的基础设施遭到雷暴和飓风的严重破坏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HEALING_PLANT</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective herbalists have discovered a plant that might result in better illness treatment.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的草药医生发现了一种极具治疗效果的药用植物。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HOSTILE_TAKEOVER_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective people have completed the quest of Corporate Expansion. %s6_corporation profits expected to skyrocket.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective完成了“恶意接管”任务，正如预期的那样，%s6_corporation的收益像宇宙火箭般迅速窜升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FAUX_PAS_1</Tag>
		<English>Our ambassador to the %s1_civ_adjective Empire has committed a faux pas!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国驻%s1_civ_adjective大使发生失礼行为！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRUFFLES_1</Tag>
		<English>Truffles! How delicious. Our people eat richly, do they not?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>块菌！太美味了。我们的人民难道会不喜欢美食吗？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SMOKELESS_POWDER_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective weaponsmiths have invented smokeless powder, giving their musketeers a significant advantage.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的武器工匠发明了无烟火药，使火枪手的战斗力获得提升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_BEAST</Tag>
		<English>A great beast has been discovered near one of our hunting camps.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>某地的猎场附近出现一只巨兽。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WATERS_OF_LIFE_1</Tag>
		<English>Folklore claims that the Waters of Life may be drawn from a certain oasis. Rumors are spreading that these waters can heal the sick and injured.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据传某个绿洲存在一眼能够治病疗伤的“生命之泉”。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_PROTEST_3</Tag>
		<English>We need a positive publicity campaign for our military, right now!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们必须加强对我国军事力量的正面宣传！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MARATHON_1</Tag>
		<English>This heroic deed has inspired our entire army!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这件英雄壮举鼓舞了我们全军将士！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PATRON_OF_KNOWLEDGE_2</Tag>
		<English>A wealthy family from %s2_city has discovered a cache of lost and rare writings in one of their vaults. They have opted to give these materials to the library.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位%s2_city当地的富豪在密室中找到一批珍贵的手稿，决定将其捐赠给公共图书馆。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_EARTHDAY_1</Tag>
		<English>Our government announces the first annual Earth Day to raise awareness of all environmental issues among the populace.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的政府宣布开展一年一度的“地球日”活动，提升公众对环境问题的关注度。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BABY_BOOM_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective soldiers and their wives are celebrating the end of war by creating a baby boom.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>退伍的%s1_civ_adjective战士和他们的妻子努力生养儿女以庆祝战争结束，由此导致了一场婴儿潮。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_1</Tag>
		<English>Although our brothers are in need, it is best not to get involved at this time.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>虽然我们的兄弟确实需要帮助，但是此时介入并不明智。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GUNS_BUTTER_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective people have trained the largest force of arquebus units. Advisors across the known world are panicking at the thought of their nation being ground under the thundering clatter and deadly terror of an endless hail of bullets.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective建立了全世界最强大的火器部队。各国统治者一想到他们将要面对的战火硝烟和枪林弹雨都会感到恐惧不已。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_5</Tag>
		<English>Our experiments have been a success! Our cities now enjoy better healing herbs!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国医生的临床试验获得了成功！所有国民都将受益于这种新药！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HIYOSILVER_2</Tag>
		<English>Commit our government to harvesting this new resource immediately.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让政府立即组织开采这处新资源。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NEW_DYNASTY_2</Tag>
		<English>Let the nobles fight amongst themselves. The strongest or cleverest will emerge as the new monarch.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>任由贵族们互相争斗，让最强者脱颖而出成为新的君主。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_GOLD_RUSH_2</Tag>
		<English>Prospectors have successfully mined newly discovered veins of gold near %s2_city. The news has produced a gold rush.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city附近新发现了一处金矿，引发了一场淘金热。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DUSTBOWL_1</Tag>
		<English>We need that food. Do whatever it takes to figure out how to mitigate the erosion of the soil and end the dust storms.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们需要保证粮食供应，采取一切必要手段解决水土流失问题。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MINING_ACCIDENT_3</Tag>
		<English>Tragedy has struck near %s2_city as poisonous gases filled a mine and struck down most of the miners who were inside.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city附近的矿井发生了一场悲剧：地下喷出的致命毒瓦斯导致井下矿工几乎全部遇难。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ANCIENTOLYMPICS</Tag>
		<English>The %s2_city Games have become a unifying event for all those who are able to participate.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s2_city举办了一场盛大的综合运动会，大批选手同场竞技，无数观众欢聚一堂。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BARDS_TALE_1</Tag>
		<English>A heartrending ballad written by an artist in %s2_city is inspiring cultural pride amongst the %s1_civ_adjective people.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位艺术家创作的一首感人的民谣唤起了%s1_civ_adjective人的文化自豪感。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FOREST_FIRE_3</Tag>
		<English>We are too pressed to spare any aid.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们很忙，无法提供救助。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_MEDIATOR_2</Tag>
		<English>Peace would benefit both sides. Give our blessing to this mediator, and may his words prove sharper than their hatreds.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>和平对双方都有利，祝福这位调停者，希望他的言辞能战胜仇恨。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MASTER_BLACKSMITH_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>The master's best student will be granted control over his forge when he retires, launching a tradition of metalcasting excellence in that city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位最优秀的学徒将在煅造大师退休后接管他的煅造场，继续发扬光大当地冶金业的优良传统。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INSPIRED_MISSION_2</Tag>
		<English>We can afford a small donation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们可以提供少量资助。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CARELESS_APPRENTICE_3</Tag>
		<English>Unknown arsonists have torched the Forge in %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>不明身份的纵火犯烧毁了%s2_city的煅造场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MARATHON</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_civ_adjective soldier has run a great distance to warn of invasion, inspiring defenders all across their lands.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一名%s1_civ_adjective战士奔跑了漫长的距离带回敌人入侵的警讯，鼓舞了国人的抗战意志。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SLAVE_REVOLT_AGAIN_2</Tag>
		<English>The slave revolt in %s2_city continues unabated. The economy there is at a standstill.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的农民起义有增无减。经济处于停滞状态。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_TSUNAMI_1</Tag>
		<English>A wall of water more than fifteen meters high has struck without warning at %s2_city. The tsunami has caused unprecedented destruction!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在没有任何先兆的情况下，高达15米的“水墙”袭击了%s2_city，这次海啸造成了空前的破坏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_ASKCOLONIALCITY_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1 Trading Company</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1贸易公司</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FARM_BANDITS_AGAIN</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective Empire continues to suffer a loss of food production due to banditry.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的粮食生产由于匪患而遭受严重损失。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_RUNNING_BULLS_2</Tag>
		<English>We should make this a national holiday!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该使其成为全国性节日！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_OTHER_6</Tag>
		<English>Our %s1_civ_adjective religious brothers have gifted us with [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Oil[COLOR_REVERT] to aid us in our war effort!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>同我们一样信奉%s1_civ_adjective的兄弟之邦提供了[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]石油[COLOR_REVERT]资源以资助我们的战争！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRUSADE_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>The Holy City needs more protection. Recruit and train capable units from among the faithful.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>圣城需要更好的保护，应该从虔诚的信徒当中征召和训练一批精锐的战士。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_WHALEOFATHING</Tag>
		<English>A new source of Whales has been located off the %s1_civ_adjective coast.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s1_civ_adjective的领海发现了大量鲸鱼。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_RURAL_FARMERS_1</Tag>
		<English>This arrangement brings more food to the city? Excellent.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这份协议能使城市获得更充足的食物供应？太好了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BEST_DEFENSE_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Leverage our defensive advantage in to political capital.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用所获优势提升我们的政治威望。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPORTS_LEAGUE_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Use the leagues to make your people happy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用体育联赛使人民更加快乐。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAMINE_OTHER_2</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective people in %s2_city have sent half their stored food to your city of %s4_city to fend off starvation caused by a poor local harvest. This humanitarian relief may represent a positive turning point in your relations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city的居民拿出一半粮食储备救助我国遭遇严重饥荒的%s4_city居民。这次无私的人道主义行动也许是两国关系走向全面友好的转折点。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SECURITY_TAX_1</Tag>
		<English>Our citizenry, fully protected by city walls, have accepted the burden of a Security Tax to help maintain their protection.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>由于获得新建城墙的良好保护，我们的市民同意额外交纳“安全税”以维护防御系统的运作。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REFORMATION_EMBRACE</Tag>
		<English>State religion and most of your cities will change to Protestantism. Catholicism can remain in larger cities. Seizing control of Church assets in Catholic cities is expected to bring %d1 gold to your treasury. If you have founded Protestantism, a shrine will be built in its holy city. Catholic civilizations may declare war on you to stop the Reformation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你的官方信仰及大多数城市的宗教将变为新教。天主教也会在一些大城市中得以保留。没收天主教的教会资产将为你的国库带来%d1金币的收益。如果是你创立了新教，神殿将会在圣城中建立。天主教国家将可能会向你宣战来阻止宗教改革。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCC_COLONIZE</Tag>
		<English>Will offer %d1 gold to our colonists to settle %s2.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>为我们的殖民者提供%d1金币用来殖民%s2。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HORSESHOE</Tag>
		<English>A master smith has developed improved horseshoes, boosting the chance for %s1_civ_adjective mounted units to strike and then escape.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位煅造大师改进了马掌设计，使%s1_civ_adjective骑兵能够更有效地发动奔袭并迅速转移。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SALTPETER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_COMMERCE] in %d1 additional [NUM1:plot:plots]</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%d1个区域[ICON_BULLET]+1[ICON_COMMERCE]。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PARROTS_1</Tag>
		<English>Tamers have figured out how to farm the abundant supply of parrots within one of our tropical forest regions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>热带森林地区的居民大量饲养鹦鹉。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CARELESS_APPRENTICE_1</Tag>
		<English>A careless apprentice started a fire at the Forge in %s2_city, during which the facility was destroyed.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一个粗心的学徒点燃了%s2_city的煅造场，所有设备都被烧毁了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BANANA_SPLIT</Tag>
		<English>Invention of the banana split by a %s1_civ_adjective businessman has led to booming ice cream sales for their vendors.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective商家发明了“香蕉船”冰淇淋，使得冰激凌销售量大幅增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CIV_GAME_3</Tag>
		<English>Computer games? They have no place in our society! Sell the franchise to foreign buyers!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>电脑游戏？我们的社会不需要这种电子海洛因！把版权卖给外国人吧！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HURRICANE_1</Tag>
		<English>Buildings have been destroyed.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一些建筑被毁</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MASTER_SMITH_1</Tag>
		<English>%s2_city has produced a grand master blacksmith who has overseen the expansion and upgrade of the Forge to increase its efficiency.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s2_city，一位煅造大师改进了熔炉设计，提高了生产效率。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPY_DISCOVERED_3</Tag>
		<English>That is an act of war! Clearly, our people and military contractors will rise to the occasion!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这是战争行径！显然我们的人民——还有我们的军火商应该作出最强烈的反应！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FARM_BANDITS_2</Tag>
		<English>Criminal activity has disrupted food production in a farming region outside %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city周边盗匪肆虐，扰乱了粮食生产。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HORSESHOE_1</Tag>
		<English>We will utilize the improved shoes for all of our mounted units.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们将在骑兵部队中推广新型马掌。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TOXCATL</Tag>
		<English>During the Toxcatl feast, the young man who is Tezcatlipoca's likeness has escaped from the teokalli in %s2_city before he could be sacrificed!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>托克斯卡特尔祭礼上，一名被特兹凯里波卡神选定的年轻人在被献祭之前挣脱锁链逃出了%s2_city！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_OTHER_3</Tag>
		<English>Our %s1_civ_adjective religious brothers have gifted us with [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Iron[COLOR_REVERT] to aid us in our war effort!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>同我们一样信奉%s1_civ_adjective的兄弟之邦提供了[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]铁[COLOR_REVERT]资源以资助我们的战争！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WARSHIPS_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must train %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]War Galley[COLOR_REVERT] [NUM1:unit:units].[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if your civilization has built [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s2_building[COLOR_REVERT].[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you arrive at the Middle Ages without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须训练%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]三层桨战船[COLOR_REVERT]单位。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你的文明建造了[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s2_building[COLOR_REVERT]，将可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者当你进入中古时代仍未达成目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROKEN_DAM_2</Tag>
		<English>Repair the dam from our emergency funds.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>动用应急基金立即修复大堤。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_TOO_CLOSE_TO_CALL_1</Tag>
		<English>Election results are so close, they fall within the margin of error typically written off to system inadequacies such as lost or mismarked ballots, hanging chads, or counting errors. With no indisputable way to decipher the true vote count, the election's outcome has been placed in the hands of the courts.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>大选的票数是如此接近，以至于诸如丢失选票、错涂选票、作废选票、统计错误等情况可能对结果造成直接影响。在存在巨大争议的情况下，只能由宪法法院来作出最终裁定。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_OLYMPICS</Tag>
		<English>All records of ancient games have been forever lost.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>古代运动会的相关记载永远失传了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SPICY</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_civ_adjective chef has identified a new and valuable type of spice.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位%s1_civ_adjective的厨师发现了一种珍贵的新香料。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LOOTERS_OTHER_1</Tag>
		<English>Civil unrest near %s4_city has led to riots and looting.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s4_city附近发生骚乱和抢掠事件。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SLAVE_REVOLT_2</Tag>
		<English>Restore order first, then investigate and redress some of the slaves' grievances.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>先恢复秩序，然后调查农民的不满并进行矫正。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SUBWAY_1</Tag>
		<English>The glorious city of %s2_city has added an underground railroad network to its mass transit system, greatly boosting commercial traffic.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>现代化的%s2_city又新增了一种公共交通设施——地铁，极大地促进了城市经济发展。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAMINE_3</Tag>
		<English>Send all of the food stores! Spare no expense to aid our friends!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>拿出全部的粮食储备，不计代价地帮助我们的朋友！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GUNS_BUTTER_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>Enjoy our Golden Age of Gunpowder.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让我们进入“火枪的黄金时代”！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MODERNOLYMPICS_1</Tag>
		<English>In the spirit of international cooperation, the city of %s2_city has decided to revive its ancient tradition of the Games, forming this in to a world event.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>本着国际协作精神，%s2_city决定复兴古代运动会的传统，将现代运动会办成一场世界性的体育盛事。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_VOLCANO_1</Tag>
		<English>A volcanic eruption near %s2_city has devastated the countryside. Fortunately, the %s1_civ_adjective city itself was spared.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>火山喷发对%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city周边地区造成严重破坏，城市本身则幸运地逃过此劫。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HAPPY_HUNTING_1</Tag>
		<English>Moose herds near %s2_city have grown particularly large. Our hunters have harvested a cache of surplus food.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city附近的驯鹿快速繁衍，当地的猎人收获颇丰。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PARTISANS_2</Tag>
		<English>Although we will lose up to half their number to exhaustion, desertion and willful refusal to leave the area, we must convince these units to retreat. Have them march to our capital city, where they will reform into units.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>尽管漫长征途和思乡情绪可能导致大量减员，但我们必须说服他们撤离，并前往首都接受正规化训练。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_PROTEST_2</Tag>
		<English>What? Find those who spread such nonsense and prosecute them!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>什么？将那些散布谬论的人绳之以法！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LOOTERS_1</Tag>
		<English>Their problems are none of our affairs. Tell our operatives to stand down.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>他们的问题与我们无关，让我们的特工继续潜伏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PATRON_OF_KNOWLEDGE_1</Tag>
		<English>Disperse the writing to our researchers so that we may obtain some immediate benefit.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>立即将手稿交给学者进行研究。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HERESY_2</Tag>
		<English>Tolerate the heresy, yet reward the faithful with reduced taxes for a while, to send a message.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>容忍异端，但对坚持正确信仰的人实行减税，以表达我们的态度。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_NOBLE_KNIGHTS_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have trained a large enough force of [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Lancer[COLOR_REVERT] units. Please choose your reward.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经训练了足够数量的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]骑士[COLOR_REVERT]单位。请选择你的奖励。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FREEDOMCONCERT_1</Tag>
		<English>Donate the money raised to the local temples.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>将筹集的善款捐献给当地寺庙。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ESTEEMED_PLAYWRIGHT_1</Tag>
		<English>The theatre patronage will enhance city revenue.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>剧场赞助商可以增加城市收入。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HARBORMASTER_1</Tag>
		<English>The Harbormaster[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your merchant marine industry to build enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Wharfs[COLOR_REVERT] for them to become the undisputed trading kings of the sea. You will also need to build a fleet of [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Caravels[COLOR_REVERT] to help carry cargo across deep water.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“港口主管”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]海上贸易商人请你完成一项任务：建造足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]港口[COLOR_REVERT]使他们能够主导全世界的海上贸易。你还需要建立一支[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]轻帆船[COLOR_REVERT]舰队以提升跨越大洋运送货物的能力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HAPPY_HUNTING</Tag>
		<English>Surplus game harvested by hunters near the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city has fueled a minor population boom.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city附近的猎人捕获大量野味，增加了食物供给。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CORPORATE_EXPANSION_1</Tag>
		<English>Corporate Expansion[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your corporate leaders to expand the reach of their corporation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“商业扩张”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]我国一家公司请求国家支持拓展他们快速拓展业务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ELITE_SWORDS_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must train %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Swordsman[COLOR_REVERT] [NUM1:unit:units]. A source of Iron will be required.[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if your civilization is operating the [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Monarchy[COLOR_REVERT] civic.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you arrive at the Middle Ages without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须训练%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]剑士[COLOR_REVERT]单位，这需要拥有铁资源。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你的文明实行[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]世袭制度[COLOR_REVERT]法令，将可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者当你进入中古时代仍未达成目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CLASSIC_LITERATURE_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must build %d1 [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Libraries[COLOR_REVERT] in your various cities.[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if you control the [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Great Library[COLOR_REVERT] if and when this quest is successfully completed.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you reach the Renaissance Era without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须在本国城市建造%d1座[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]图书馆[COLOR_REVERT]。[PARAGRAPH:1]此外，如果你的文明拥有[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]大图书馆[COLOR_REVERT]将可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者当你进入启蒙时代仍未达成目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FAMINE_3</Tag>
		<English>Tragedy has struck just beyond your border, as the %s1_civ_adjective Empire struggles to feed all its hungry people in %s6_city. Many will die without enough to eat. Should the citizens of %s2_city move to assist them?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>悲剧在我们的边境发生，虽然%s1_civ_adjective政府尽力赈济%s6_city的饥民，但仍有许多人面临死亡威胁。%s2_city的居民应该努力提供救助吗？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DISSIDENT_PRIEST_3</Tag>
		<English>Diversity is good. Allow these beliefs to spread and be recorded, though convincing our people that it's nothing to fear won't be easy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>应该允许百花齐放，允许不同思想自由传播，虽然我们的人民一时还难以改变固有的观念。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INSPIRED_MISSION_1</Tag>
		<English>We are unable to assist at this time.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们现在无法提供资助。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PESTILENCE_3</Tag>
		<English>Massive colonies of termites have overrun and destroyed some of our agriculture near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city附近白蚁泛滥成灾，一些农田被毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FOREST_FIRE_1</Tag>
		<English>A forest fire sparked by lightning has raged across the land near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>闪电引发的森林大火在%s2_city附近肆虐。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HAMBURGER_JOINT</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective entrepreneurs have invented the fast food hamburger joint. Thanks to radio advertising, this phenomenon is spreading rapidly.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的企业家发明了快餐连锁经营模式，通过媒体广告的大力宣传，这种新型商业模式迅速发展。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_IMPEACHMENT_2</Tag>
		<English>That's an overreaction. The President has gotten the message that his administration needs to improve.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>不必反应过度，既然总统已经认识到了错误。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MOTOR_OIL_1</Tag>
		<English>Our chemists have developed an improved motor oil that lasts longer and lubricates engines better.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的化学家改进了润滑油的提炼方法，能够大大提升发动机性能。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NEWS_IMPACT_CRATER_1</Tag>
		<English>Discovery of naturally occurring glass globules has been ignored by %s1_civ_adjective leadership and will pass in to the dustbin of history.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective境内某处发现了大量天然玻璃球，但并未引起国家领导人的重视。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CITY_RUINS_INDUSTRIAL_1</Tag>
		<English>An archaeological expedition to city ruins near %s2_city has uncovered lost treasures, texts and artifacts.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一支探险队在%s2_city附近的废墟中发现了一批珍宝、古籍和艺术品。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BETTER_COAL_2</Tag>
		<English>I suppose we can make our Drydocks a more healthy place to work and slightly more productive, then.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在所有干船坞推广这项新技术，在减少工业污染的同时增加产能。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HURRICANE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city took a direct hit from a powerful hurricane.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city遭遇特大飓风的直接袭击。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CORPORATE_EXPANSION_1</Tag>
		<English>The Chief Executive Officer of %s11_corporation seeks government incentives to better enable his company to expand.[PARAGRAPH:1]If we can assist in spreading his corporation to new cities, profits will skyrocket.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s11_corporation的首席执行官请求国家给予优惠政策，鼓励他们快速拓展业务。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果我们能资助该公司将业务拓展到更多城市，其收益将像宇宙火箭般迅速窜升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JAIL_1</Tag>
		<English>So what? No one is going to escape anyway.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>开什么玩笑？犯人不可能越狱。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HOLY_MOUNTAIN_1</Tag>
		<English>The Holy Mountain[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your religious leaders to locate, settle near and seize control over the Holy Mountain.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“圣山”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]宗教领袖要求你去寻找圣山，在附近建立定居点以取得对圣山的控制权。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TOWER_SHIELD_1</Tag>
		<English>Issue shields to our troops as supplies permit.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在军队中大量装备塔盾。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_ANTELOPE_1</Tag>
		<English>With removal by man of natural predators, the antelope population has grown large enough to serve as a sustained food source.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>人类活动使食肉动物数量大减，导致羚羊种群迅速繁育，可以用作新的食物资源。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FUGITIVE</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective authorities are rumored to have captured a fugitive fleeing from %s4_civ_adjective justice. No confirmation is available.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据传，%s1_civ_adjective当局逮捕了一名遭%s4_civ_adjective政府通缉的逃犯。此事尚未得到确认。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_INSPIRED_MISSION_1</Tag>
		<English>Inspired %s4_religion_adjective missionaries have spread their influence out of %s2_city. They now seek an audience with you, requesting your assistance in funding additional missions to the %s1_civ_adjective Empire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>热忱的%s4_religion_adjective传教士努力将他们的信仰传播到%s2_city以外的地方。他们请求你的接见，希望您资助他在全%s1_civ_adjective的传教活动。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CYCLONE_1</Tag>
		<English>A powerful cyclone originating in the southern hemisphere has made landfall at %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>产生于南半球的特大飓风在%s2_city登陆。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FORTY_THIEVES_1</Tag>
		<English>The legend of Forty Thieves is luring treasure hunters and adventure seekers to %s2_civ_adjective lands.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>四十大盗的传说吸引了大批追求财富和刺激的冒险者涌入%s2_civ_adjective。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_OVERWHELM_1</Tag>
		<English>The Overwhelm Doctrine[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your military leaders to construct a fully functional aircraft carrier battle fleet.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“绝对优势”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]你的海军将领请求建立一个强大的航空母舰战斗群。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PATRON_OF_KNOWLEDGE_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund the expansion of the Library to include a new wing housing all of these precious writings.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>扩建当地图书馆以存放这批手稿。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HINDENBERG_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund a drive to regulate air traffic, improve safety and ensure the viability of commercial air travel.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>投资加强空中交通管理，保证商业航空旅行的安全。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_AIRLINER_CRASH_OTHER_1</Tag>
		<English>One of your passenger airliners has crashed in %s1_civ_adjective territory. They have allowed unrestricted access to your recovery teams, building trust between your two nations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一架我国客机%s1_civ_adjective境内坠毁。对方允许我们的救援队自由前往现场，以在两国间建立互信。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FUGITIVE_1</Tag>
		<English>Extradite the offender back to his homeland.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>将这名罪犯引渡回国。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ICE_SCULPTURE</Tag>
		<English>A new art form involving the carving of large blocks of ice has been created in the icy tundra near the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一种新的艺术形式――冰雕在%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city的冰天雪地中诞生。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_LONG_RANGE_FIGHTERS_1</Tag>
		<English>Our engineers have developed an advanced fighter design that is lighter and carries slightly more fuel, extending its operational range.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的工程师们研制出了一种先进的战斗机，新机型的重量更轻、载油量更多，作战范围因而大大提升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SOUR_CRUDE_1</Tag>
		<English>Most of the crude oil being pumped from one of our sites is thick with sulfur and other impurities. We are stuck with a source of sour crude!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>从某个油井中开采出来的原油含有大量硫磺，这种劣质原油已积压了数百万桶。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HAPPY_HUNTING_3</Tag>
		<English>Deer proliferate through the forest near %s2_city, allowing our hunters to store up extra meat.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city附近的森林中野鹿数量激增，当地的猎人收获颇丰。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_LEFT_AT_ALTAR_1</Tag>
		<English>A politically arranged marriage between one of our noblemen and a woman from a noble %s1_civ_adjective family has collapsed into feuding as the groom backed out of the wedding on the wedding day.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位我国贵族和一位%s1_civ_adjective世家女的政治联姻演最终变成了激烈的国际冲突――因为新郎在结婚当日取消了婚礼。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CHAMPION</Tag>
		<English>A champion unit has emerged from the war games conducted by the %s1_civ_adjective military. This unit is rumored to be the strongest and toughest amongst all their forces.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一支作战部队在%s1_civ_adjective参谋部组织的兵棋推演中大获全胜，成为公认的王牌精锐。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_HOLY_MOUNTAIN</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of The Holy Mountain.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“圣山”任务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HAPPY_HUNTING_2</Tag>
		<English>The people of %s2_city celebrate as the latest caribou hunting season has brought a rich harvest.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>由于在狩猎季节中收获颇丰，%s2_city居民举城欢庆。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BARDS_TALE_2</Tag>
		<English>A songwriter from %s2_city has gained local and national recognition, strengthening %s1_civ_adjective culture.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位艺术家创作的歌曲广受欢迎，加强了%s1_civ_adjective的文化影响力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ESTEEMED_PLAYWRIGHT_2</Tag>
		<English>We could double the cultural value of the theatre by officially sanctioning this artist's works.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>给予这位艺术家的作品官方保护，剧场可以积累双倍的文化点数。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_ESTEEMED_PLAYWRIGHT_1</Tag>
		<English>A prolific playwright from %s2_city has written a long series of exceptionally popular plays. His home theatre has gained renown.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位杰出剧作家创作的一系列剧本广受欢迎，当地剧场因此名声大振。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CLASSIC_LITERATURE</Tag>
		<English>Our eldest scholars have collaborated on an effort to collect, record, and preserve all of our oral traditions and unwritten literature.[PARAGRAPH:1]They require storage space for pottery, stone tablets and other artifacts, as well as special repositories within our cities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>许多著名学者正致力于搜集、记录和保存在民间口头流传的历史与文学作品。[PARAGRAPH:1]他们要求在我们的城市中建立专门用于贮藏陶器、石板等古代文物的场所。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_ELITE_SWORDS_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have trained a large enough force of [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Swordsman[COLOR_REVERT] units. Please choose your reward.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经拥有了一支强大的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]剑士[COLOR_REVERT]部队。请选择你的奖励。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_JOYOUS_WEDDING_3</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_civ_adjective industrial heiress has received a marriage proposal from one of our prominent business tycoons. Their %s4_religion_adjective wedding will occur this year.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国一位显赫的商业大亨已向一家%s1_civ_adjective公司的女继承人求婚。他们遵照%s4_religion_adjective传统的婚礼将在今年举行。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PRAIRIE_DOGS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective merchants are now selling domesticated prairie dogs as exotic pets.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective商人开始批量销售作为宠物的土拨鼠。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_LEFT_AT_ALTAR</Tag>
		<English>A collapsed politically arranged wedding and a jilted bride are at the center of new tensions between the %s4_civ_adjective and %s1_civ_adjective Empires.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位显贵的女儿在一场失败的政治联姻中被抛弃，导致%s4_civ_adjective和%s1_civ_adjective之间关系极度紧张。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_BEAST_2</Tag>
		<English>Looks like it could feed many people. Organize a hunting party!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>它的肉够许多人吃的，马上组织狩猎队！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CHARISMATIC_1</Tag>
		<English>Advise him to focus on his relationship with the armed forces.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>建议他加强对军队的控制。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HOSTILE_TAKEOVER_1</Tag>
		<English>The Chief Executive Officer of %s11_corporation covets getting out from under the thumb of foreign suppliers of raw materials.[PARAGRAPH:1]If we can obtain control over all resource types his corporation needs for industrial use, their profits will skyrocket.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s11_corporation的首席执行官渴望摆脱受制于外国原材料供应商的状况。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果我们能控制该公司需要的所有资源，其收益将像宇宙火箭般迅速窜升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_AIRLINER_CRASH</Tag>
		<English>A %s4_civ_adjective passenger aircraft has crashed within %s1_civ_adjective territory. Neither side has provided any details of the incident.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一架%s4_civ_adjective客机在%s1_civ_adjective境内坠毁。事件双方均未就此事透露任何细节。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PREACHING_RESEARCHER_2</Tag>
		<English>See if the scientist would be willing to continue the scientific work at the Monastery, given some additional funding.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>提供资助让这位学者在修道院里继续他的科学研究。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ROGUE_STATION_2</Tag>
		<English>Round up the broadcasters, that should send a message.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>派遣警察包围这家电台，如果他们知趣得话应该会放老实点。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_EARTHDAY_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund an international awareness effort in addition to our local efforts.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>拨出专款提升国际社会对环境问题的关注度。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BLESSED_SEA_1</Tag>
		<English>Our spiritual leaders are urging us to seek the blessings of the sea![PARAGRAPH:1]The wise masters have divined the way regarding our relationship with the sea. They urge us to embrace the sea, to broaden our influence over it and spread our traditions to new lands.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宗教领袖催促我们寻找海洋的祝福！[PARAGRAPH:1]睿智的导师指出我们应如何与神圣的海洋友好相处。他们要求我们拥抱海洋，加强我们的海上力量，将我们的贸易拓展到新的陆地。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MINING_ACCIDENT_3</Tag>
		<English>We are too pressed to spare any aid for the city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们太忙了，无法提供额外救助。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PARTISANS_OTHER_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective citizens from the city we just razed are taking to the surrounding countryside to form Partisan resistance units!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective人民在被毁城市周围的乡村进行游击战，以抗击入侵者。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HYMNS_AND_SCULPTURES</Tag>
		<English>Inspired by religious music and sculpture in %s2_city, a new Great Artist has emerged in the %s1_civ_adjective Empire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s2_city宗教音乐和雕塑作品的熏陶下，一位年轻的大艺术家在%s1_civ_adjective崭露头角。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_4</Tag>
		<English>Send large herds of war-trained Horses to our brothers.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>向我们的兄弟提供大量马匹。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WAR_CHARIOTS_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Leverage our military advantage into a drive to spread our faith.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用强大的军事优势传播我们的信仰。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_SPORTS_LEAGUE</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of The National Sports League.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“国家体育联合会”任务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HARBORMASTER</Tag>
		<English>Our harbormasters request government aid in expanding our overseas trading empire.[PARAGRAPH:1]We will need to build enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Wharfs[COLOR_REVERT] in our cities and construct enough ocean worthy ships.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的港口主管请求政府资助扩张海外贸易。[PARAGRAPH:1]我们需要建造足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]港口[COLOR_REVERT]和远洋船舶。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MIRACLE_1</Tag>
		<English>A miracle is believed to have occurred at the city wall in %s2_city. Pilgrims are flocking from all over to visit the new holy site.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据报在%s2_city发生了奇迹，大批朝圣者从各地涌向这个新的圣地。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SPOILED_GRAIN_1</Tag>
		<English>Vermin have gotten in to the granary in %s2_city. All the food stored there is spoiled.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的粮仓发生虫害，粮食储备严重受损。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WARSHIPS_1</Tag>
		<English>Our naval commanders wish to prepare for war.[PARAGRAPH:1]If we train enough [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]War Galley units[COLOR_REVERT], we could dominate the seas!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的海军将领希望为战争做好准备。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果我们训练了足够数量的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]三层桨战船[COLOR_REVERT]单位，我们就能随心所欲地支配海洋！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FUGITIVE_3</Tag>
		<English>Release the prisoner. This is none of our affairs.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>将其释放。此事与我们无关。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_THE_HUNS_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]A dangerous number of barbarian [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Horse Archer[COLOR_REVERT] units have spawned near our border.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]大量蛮族[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]骑射手[COLOR_REVERT]出现在我国边境地区。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROKEN_DAM_1</Tag>
		<English>That is very unfortunate, but we can not help. Tell the local authorities they'll have to handle the situation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真是不幸的消息，但是我们帮不上忙。让当地官员自行处理。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FAVORITE_SON_1</Tag>
		<English>A gladiator from %s2_city has survived many battles in the arena. He is attracting a lot of fans.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位英勇的角斗士在%s2_city赢得了无数场生死角斗的胜利，吸引了大批热情的角斗迷。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_REACTOR_LEAK_2</Tag>
		<English>Leaks like these are dangerous. We must invest in modernizing our reactors to keep them safe for the future.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>像这样的泄漏是危险的。我们必须投资使我们的反应堆现代化，以保证它们在未来的安全。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_NOBLE_KNIGHTS_1</Tag>
		<English>Our civilization cries out for nobility to lead our people forward into a brighter future.[PARAGRAPH:1]If we train enough [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Lancers[COLOR_REVERT], we should be able to find our way forward, through times peaceful or warlike.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们需要一个强大的贵族阶层引领人民进入更加光明的未来。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果我们训练了足够数量的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]骑士[COLOR_REVERT]单位，那么无论是在平安祥和还是在战火纷飞的年代，我们都能够稳步前进。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WEDDING_FEUD_3</Tag>
		<English>An industrial heiress from the %s1_civ_adjective Empire has received a marriage proposal from one of our prominent business tycoons. The marriage is going forward, but the families on both sides are feuding over which religion should preside over the ceremony. The couple has decided on a %s4_religion_adjective wedding to the great annoyance of the bride's family.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective一家企业的女继承人收到我国一位商业大亨的求婚并欣然同意。但双方家族为应按何种宗教传统举行婚礼而各执己见。这对新人决定按%s4_religion_adjective传统举行婚礼以平息新娘家族的不满。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_TIN_1</Tag>
		<English>A rich source of Tin has been discovered in the hills!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在山区发现贮量丰富的锡矿！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANTELOPE_1</Tag>
		<English>That sounds like welcome news for our economy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这个消息有利于我们的经济发展。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HAMBURGER_JOINT_1</Tag>
		<English>Can we have fries with that? Thanks!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>来份炸薯条好吗？谢谢！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WEDDING_FEUD_2</Tag>
		<English>Send hearty congratulations and a generous wedding gift.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>送上衷心的祝福和大方得体的礼物。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_AIRLINER_CRASH_1</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_civ_adjective passenger flight has crashed in our territory near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一架%s1_civ_adjective客机在我国%s2_city附近坠毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MASTER_SMITH_1</Tag>
		<English>We applaud the accomplishments of our revered grand master blacksmith.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>表彰煅造大师的杰出成就。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BLIZZARD_2</Tag>
		<English>A blizzard has dumped disastrous quantities of snow upon a %s1_civ_adjective region near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>猛烈的暴风雪袭击了%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BLACK_PEARLS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective merchants are now selling black pearls in larger quantities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective商人开始批量销售黑珍珠。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CITY_RUINS_1</Tag>
		<English>Send commendations to the leaders of the exploring party.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>嘉奖探险队的领袖。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_ELITE_SWORDS</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of the Elite Swordsmen!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“精锐剑士”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HINDENBERG_1</Tag>
		<English>Outlaw the use of hydrogen in lighter-than-air vehicles.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>立法禁止空气浮力飞行器使用氢气填充。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRISIS_IN_THE_SENATE_3</Tag>
		<English>Rely on judicial authority to enforce the letter of the constitution.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>提交司法裁决，确立现行宪法的绝对权威。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GOLD_RUSH_2</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective Empire is enjoying a population increase at %s2_city thanks to a gold rush bringing in prospectors and hopefuls.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>由于怀揣发财梦的淘金者大量涌入，%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city的人口迅速增加。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MONSOON</Tag>
		<English>Monsoon flooding, more severe than usual for %s2_city, has visited disaster upon the %s1_civ_adjective people there.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>百年一遇的洪水给%s2_city居民带来了巨大灾难。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GIRLS_BEST_FRIEND</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective diamond ring sales are booming.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的钻戒销售量大幅增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GOLD_RUSH_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund efforts to motivate more of the gold seekers to settle down when the rush ends.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>最初的热潮消退之后，许多淘金者决定在此定居，长期发展。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_VOLCANO_1</Tag>
		<English>Send what aid we can to the survivors. Be thankful that the city itself was not struck.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>尽力救助幸存者，幸好城市未被完全摧毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_HOSTILE_TAKEOVER</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of the Hostile Takeover!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“恶意接管”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PESTILENCE_1</Tag>
		<English>A plague of locusts have swarmed over a Pasture near %s2_city, destroying all the livestock there.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>蝗灾席卷%s2_city附近的牧场，导致大批牲畜饿死。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_CRUSADE</Tag>
		<English>Your Crusade has ended. The quest has failed.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>对异教徒的征讨无果告终，你没能完成“圣战”任务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_MEDIATOR_1</Tag>
		<English>We do not want peace! Let the war continue.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们不需要和平！让战争继续。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JOYOUS_WEDDING_OTHER_2</Tag>
		<English>A %s5_religion_adjective wedding between one of our citizens and one from the %s1_civ_adjective Empire has drawn a blessing from them with generous wedding gifts. Our people are pleased by this gesture.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>通过一场%s5_religion_adjective传统婚礼，一位我国显贵和一位%s1_civ_adjective人结为夫妇。有人送上丰厚的礼物以表达对他们的祝福。我们的人民对此表示满意。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HERESY_1</Tag>
		<English>A heretical spiritual movement has started in %s2_city and is gaining strength among some sections of our populace.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一个发源于%s2_city的异端信仰开始在我国部分地区散播！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SALTPETER_1</Tag>
		<English>Our bat herds in the hills near %s2_city, legendary in quantity, are now providing us surplus sources of saltpeter for use in gunpowder.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city附近山洞中生活着数量庞大的蝙蝠，我们可以从山洞中大量采集硝石制造火药。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CORPORATE_EXPANSION_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have completed the quest of Corporate Expansion and enabled %s11_corporation to turn extra profit.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经完成了“商业扩张”任务，使%s11_corporation能够创造更多的利润。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HORSE_WHISPERING_DONE_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Receive %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Horse Archers[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]获得%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]骑射手[COLOR_REVERT]单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BLESSED_SEA_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must establish or capture cities on %d1 total landmasses of any size, from one-plot islands to massive continents. All landmasses where you have at least one city are counted. Note that additional cities on the same island or continent do not help in this quest. The goal is to establish your presence on a number of different landmasses and thereby prove your mastery over the waters.[PARAGRAPH:1] You will fail this quest if you change state religions, cease to have a state religion or reach [COLOR_TECH_TEXT]Industrialism[COLOR_REVERT] without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须在%d1块陆地上建立或占领城市，陆地的大小没有限制，只有一格的小岛或是广阔的大洲都可以。只要你在一块陆地上拥有至少一个城市，这片陆地就会被计算在内。请注意，在同一个海岛或大陆上建立多个城市无助于完成本任务。任务目标是将你的势力扩张到尽可能多的独立陆地上，并由此展现你对海洋的统治能力。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你改变了国教、不再设立国教或已获得了[COLOR_TECH_TEXT]产业主义[COLOR_REVERT]时目标仍未达成，任务即宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TOXCATL</Tag>
		<English>The man who is Tezcatlipoca's likeness has escaped during this year's Toxcatl feast in the %s1_civ_adjective Empire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s1_civ_adjective举行的托克斯卡特尔祭礼上，一名特兹凯里波卡神选定的年轻人挣脱锁链逃走了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TEA</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective citizens who are socially advanced have adopted imported %s4_civ_adjective tea as their beverage of choice.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective上流社会饮用自%s4_civ_adjective进口的茶饮料已蔚然成风。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PREACHING_RESEARCHER</Tag>
		<English>A well-known scientist from %s2_city has become a preacher at the local Christian Monastery.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位著名学者决定到当地修道院的担任宣教师。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SETBACK_2</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective discoveries have turned out to be false! This dead end result has slowed their current research project.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的一项新发现被证明是错误的！研究被迫进度放缓。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPY_DISCOVERED_2</Tag>
		<English>Every man has his price. His knowledge could make him a very valuable asset.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>国家利益至上。他所掌握的情报也可以成为我们的财富。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SLAVE_REVOLT</Tag>
		<English>A slave revolt has taken place in the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city发生农民起义！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BEST_DEFENSE_1</Tag>
		<English>The Best Defense[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your armed forces to build enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Castles[COLOR_REVERT] for them to ward off invasion effectively.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“顶级防御”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]军队将领请你完成一项任务：建造足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]城堡[COLOR_REVERT]以有效地防御敌人入侵。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HURRICANE_2</Tag>
		<English>Citizens have been killed.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>许多市民死亡</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ANGEL_OF_MERCY</Tag>
		<English>The hospital in %s2_city is gaining favor among the pious because it is believed to be blessed by a spirit angel.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的市立医院受到大批信徒的尊崇，他们相信在那里能得到天使的保佑。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HOLY_MOUNTAIN_REVEALED_1</Tag>
		<English>Look at the Holy Mountain.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让我们一起仰望这座神圣的山峰。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HIYOSILVER_1</Tag>
		<English>That sounds like welcome news for our economy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这个消息有利于我们的经济发展。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_IMPACT_CRATER_2</Tag>
		<English>Commit our government to unlocking the secrets of this mystery.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>组织专家学者开展深入研究。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_THE_HUNS</Tag>
		<English>A massive barbarian uprising is occurring. Attila the Hun leads his forces in a crusade against the very concept of civilization.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>蛮族开始大举入侵！匈人首领阿提拉发动了旨在毁灭文明世界的大规模征伐。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_APPLESEED</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_civ_adjective folk hero has caused the creation of a new forest of apple trees.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在一位%s1_civ_adjective民间植树英雄的带领下，人们创造了一处繁茂的苹果树林。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FRIENDLY_LOCALS_1</Tag>
		<English>Friendly locals have granted sanctuary to a wounded %s1_civ_adjective unit.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一名受伤的%s1_civ_adjective战士获得了友善的当地居民的救助。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GOLDEN_BUDDHA_3</Tag>
		<English>The blacksmith is a true talent, we should encourage him to make more of these statues.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真是艺术天才，我们应该鼓励他制作更多的雕像。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HAPPY_HUNTING_1</Tag>
		<English>Send congratulations to the citizens.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>向当地的居民发去祝贺。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_THE_VEDIC_ARYANS_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]A dangerous number of barbarian [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Archer[COLOR_REVERT] units have spawned near our border.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]大量蛮族[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]弓手[COLOR_REVERT]出现在我国边境地区。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WEDDING_FEUD_2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1[ICON_HAPPY] in all cities with %F3_religion for %d2 [NUM2:turn:turns]</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]所有信仰%F3_religion的城市%D1[ICON_HAPPY]，持续%d2回合</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_INDEPENDENTFILMS_1</Tag>
		<English>A community of independent film producers based in %s2_city has managed to secure a slice of the Hit Movies market.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city集中了多家独立电影公司，在世界电影市场上占有极大份额。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SALTPETER</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective merchants are now selling gunpowder in larger quantities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective商人开始批量销售火药。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PARTISANS</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective people from the city of %s5_city have seen their homes burned! They are rising up against the wicked %s4_civ_adjective invaders, forming Partisan units to join the resistance as militia fighters!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s5_city的人民目睹家园被烧毁！他们组织起一支游击队来帮助我们对抗邪恶的%s4_civ_adjective侵略者。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_AT_THE_SWORD_1</Tag>
		<English>Decorate our glorious heroes of the sword!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>为我们光荣的战争英雄授勋！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HARBORMASTER_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The seaworthy %s1_civ_adjective people have completed the quest of The Harbormaster!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>擅长航海的%s1_civ_adjective人胜利完成了“港口主管”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WININGMONKS_1</Tag>
		<English>That sounds like welcome news for our economy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这个消息有利于我们的经济发展。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_REACTOR_LEAK_1_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Medium risk of a nuclear meltdown.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Radiation leaks may continue.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]核熔毁的中等风险。[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]辐射泄漏可能继续。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FARM_BANDITS_AGAIN_2</Tag>
		<English>Criminals are still preying on our farmers. A more stringent response may be necessary in %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的农民仍然遭受盗匪侵害，或许有必要在%s2_city周边采取更严厉的措施。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HORSESHOE_1</Tag>
		<English>A brilliant smith has developed significant innovation in the design of horseshoes.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位煅造大师改进了马掌设计。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PATRON_OF_KNOWLEDGE_1</Tag>
		<English>A patron of knowledge from the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city has donated a cache of rare writings to the local Library.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city，一位收藏家向当地图书馆捐赠了一批珍贵的手稿。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MONSOON_1</Tag>
		<English>Although %s2_city is used to some flooding during monsoon season, a rare and powerful monsoon has brought devastatingly strong floods this year.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>尽管%s2_city人已经习惯了河流的季节性泛滥，然而这场洪水威力空前，造成了严重的破坏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREED_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Recruit and train units that take advantage of our new resources.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用新获得的资源征召和训练部队。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BLACK_PEARLS_1</Tag>
		<English>Let them keep the secret. We are happy enough to tax their higher profits.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让他们继续保守秘密吧，我们可以从销售利润中收取税金。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DISSIDENT_PRIEST_1</Tag>
		<English>That is disgusting and preposterous. The heresy must be dealt with in the name of Amun-Re, even if the locals won't support it.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这是在哗众取宠。异端分子必须以真神的名义加以铲除，即使当地人反对这样做。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPOILED_GRAIN_2</Tag>
		<English>Pay to have the lost grain replaced.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>立即出资补充粮食储备。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HOSTILE_TAKEOVER_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Cha-ching! Show me the money!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>太棒了！让我数数有多少钱。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRUSADE_1</Tag>
		<English>Crusade[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your religious leaders to capture and occupy the Holy City.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“圣战”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]我国早高精神领袖要求使用武力夺取圣城。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TIN</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective Empire has become the world's leading producer of tin.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective成为世界产锡大国。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SMOKELESS_POWDER_1</Tag>
		<English>Convert our musketeers to the new gunpowder.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让我们的火枪手换用无烟火药。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_STAINED_GLASS_1</Tag>
		<English>A large order of stained glass has been shipped to %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city地方政府大量购入彩色玻璃。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CONTROVERSIAL_PHILOSOPHER</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_civ_adjective philosopher has stirred up controversy among the religious population.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位%s1_civ_adjective哲学家提出的新学说在虔诚的教徒中引发了激烈的争议。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WATERS_OF_LIFE_1</Tag>
		<English>This will attract more traffic to the oasis? That sounds good.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这会吸引更多人到那个绿洲吧？听起来很不错。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ESTEEMED_PLAYWRIGHT</Tag>
		<English>A renowned playwright from %s2_city is attracting patrons and fans from far and wide.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位著名剧作家创作的优秀作品吸引了来自各地的赞助商和观众。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_GREAT_MEDIATOR_1</Tag>
		<English>A great mediator has emerged, offering to arbitrate the dispute between %s1_civ_adjective leadership and our nation. This could be a chance for peace.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位中立国领袖主动提出充当调停者，对%s1_civ_adjective与我国之间的争端进行仲裁，这可能是一个和平的机会。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CYCLONE</Tag>
		<English>A massive cyclone has made landfall at the %s1_civ city of %s2_city, causing widespread wind and storm surge damage.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>特大飓风在%s1_civ的%s2_city登陆，狂风和海浪造成了巨大的破坏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BREAKTHROUGH_1</Tag>
		<English>Our researchers have made a technological breakthrough, rapidly advancing their progress.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的科学家在技术上取得突破，使得当前研究进度加快。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_AIRLINER_CRASH_OTHER_2</Tag>
		<English>One of your passenger airliners has crashed in %s1_civ_adjective territory. They seemed to be unsure how to react at first, but finally allowed your recovery teams access to the crash site.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一架我国客机在%s1_civ_adjective境内坠毁。经过一番交涉，对方最终同意我们的救援队前往现场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_THOROUGHBRED_1</Tag>
		<English>A new breed of race horse is generating a lot of revenue from our stables.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一个新赛马品种的成功繁育为我们的马厩带来了一笔额外利润。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CORPORATE_EXPANSION_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective people have completed the quest of Corporate Expansion. %s6_corporation profits expected to skyrocket.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective完成了“商业扩张”任务，正如预期的那样，%s6_corporation的收益像宇宙火箭般迅速窜升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CITY_RUINS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective explorers have discovered valuable information buried in ruins near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective探险队在%s2_city附近发现了埋藏在废墟中的重要资料。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ELITE_SWORDS_1</Tag>
		<English>Elite Swordsmen[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your military leaders to train a sizable force of [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Swordsmen[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“精锐剑士”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]你的军事将领请求训练足够数量的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]剑士[COLOR_REVERT]单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BOILERS_1</Tag>
		<English>A new design of steel boiler is in demand, because it can raise manufacturing productivity.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一种新型锅炉在各地广受欢迎，因为它显著提升了生产效率。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ANCIENT_TEXTS_1</Tag>
		<English>In the sands of a %s2_civ_adjective desert, archaeologists have unearthed a cache of ancient texts.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>考古学家在%s2_civ_adjective境内的沙漠中发掘出一批古籍。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LOOTERS_OTHER_4</Tag>
		<English>We have identified %s1_civ_adjective agents who are systematically and actively aggravating the situation in %s4_city!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们发现有%s1_civ_adjective的间谍在暗中参与%s4_city骚乱！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JADE_1</Tag>
		<English>We can sell the precious jade for additional profit.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该批量销售玉器换取财富。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TEA_1</Tag>
		<English>The taxes from these sales should boost our coffers nicely, as well as boosting our relations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>茶叶贸易增进了两国关系，从中征收的销售税也充实了我们的国库。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CLASSIC_LITERATURE_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Our library with the largest repository of classic literature receives a research bonus.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们保存着经典文学宝库的图书馆带来了额外的科研奖励。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BLIZZARD_1</Tag>
		<English>Severe winter weather is plaguing the %s1_civ_adjective people near their city of %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city遭遇百年一遇的严冬。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_NEW_DYNASTY</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective hereditary dynasty has died out. A new faction has claimed the throne and is off to a roaringly successful start.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective原来的世袭王室已经绝嗣，一个新的派系夺取了统治权并着手稳定局势。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_COMET_FRAGMENT_1</Tag>
		<English>What if something even bigger is out there, on a collision course with our world? If so, we must find it. We must get into space!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>是否还有其他更巨大的天体可能撞击地球？必须提前发现及早准备，我们必须登上太空！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CONTROVERSIAL_PHILOSOPHER_2</Tag>
		<English>He's a senile old fool. Let him teach if he wants to.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>他只是个老糊涂虫，不必理会那些胡言乱语。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FREEDOMCONCERT_HELP_2</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Spread each of the religions present to a new city</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]将现有的信仰传播到一座新城市。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HOSTILE_TAKEOVER_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must settle near uncontrolled resources or attack rival civilizations and take over their resources.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will need to obtain new sources of %d1 [NUM1:resource type:different resource types] (%s2_list_of_resources).[PARAGRAPH:1]You must also retain control over all needed resource types already owned.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization who is also seeking to obtain control over needed resources for one of its corporations should happen to complete this task ahead of you.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须在无主资源所在地建立定居点，或者夺取别国领土以接管其资源。[PARAGRAPH:1]你需要夺取%d1种资源（%s2_list_of_resources）。[PARAGRAPH:1]您还必须保持对已有相关资源的控制权。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明的公司率先达成控制全部相关资源的目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FARM_PLOWS_1</Tag>
		<English>A new plow design has become popular. Our Forges have filled orders for the new plows from farmers across our lands.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一种新型的犁在市场上大受欢迎，各地农场主的订单雪片般飞往我们的煅造场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_METAL_DECKS_1</Tag>
		<English>Make it so.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>就这么办。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRUSADE_DONE_HELP_3</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Spread [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s1_religion[COLOR_REVERT] to up to %d2 new [NUM2:city:cities].</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]传播[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s1_religion[COLOR_REVERT]到%d2座新的城市。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INFO_FUGITIVE_5</Tag>
		<English>Word of our interrogation of the fugitive has leaked to %s3_civ_adjective authorities, angering them.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s3_civ_adjective政府已获知对我们逃亡者的进行秘密审问，这势必引发外交纠纷。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MASTER_BLACKSMITH_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Use our advantage to discover a new source of [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Copper[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用所获优势发现一处[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]铜[COLOR_REVERT]资源。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CORPORATE_EXPANSION_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must spread [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s1_corporation[COLOR_REVERT] to %d2 new cities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须在%d2座新城市设立[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s1_corporation[COLOR_REVERT]的分支机构。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CLUNKER_COAL_1</Tag>
		<English>Clunker coal? What a mess. Less valuable per ton, but it still burns, right? Just deal with it.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>劣质煤炭？真是糟糕，但应该还烧得着吧？允许继续销售。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_WAR_CHARIOTS_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective people have trained the largest force of Chariot units. Advisors across the known world are panicking at the thought of their nation being ground under the thundering hooves and churning wheels of these mighty war machines.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective建立了一支强大的战车部队。各国统治者都被这些战争机器的铁蹄和车轮巨大的轰鸣声吓得心慌意乱！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HAMBURGER_JOINT_1</Tag>
		<English>A new type of rapid-service restaurant selling primarily hamburgers was launched recently. Thanks to successful radio advertising, the chain is now expanding across the nation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一种以销售汉堡为主的新型自助式连锁快餐店在市场上出现，通过媒体广告的大力宣传，这种新型商业模式迅速发展。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_WININGMONKS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective monks who have grown their vinyards over the years are now producing Wines in significant quantities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的僧侣们努力经营葡萄园，出产了大批美酒。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_GREED_1</Tag>
		<English>Our generals covet a source of [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s9_resource[COLOR_REVERT] that lies within %s1_civ_adjective borders. Without it, we cannot properly train and equip our troops!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的将军垂涎于%s1_civ_adjective境内的[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s9_resource[COLOR_REVERT]资源。由于缺乏这种资源，我们无法更有效地训练和装备部队！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PESTILENCE_2</Tag>
		<English>Fire ant armies of massive proportion have laid waste to grazing lands near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>大群火蚁横扫%s2_city附近地区。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TORNADO_1</Tag>
		<English>Do what we can to aid the survivors.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>尽力救助灾民。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BARDS_TALE_1</Tag>
		<English>A songwriter from %s2_city has composed a heartrending ballad, which is growing in popularity amongst the people there.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位艺术家因创作了一首感人的民谣而广受赞誉。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INDUSTRIAL_FIRE_1</Tag>
		<English>Emphasize improved safety so that this particular type of accident should never happen again.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>加强安全措施，避免类似事故再次发生。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MARBLE_STATUES</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective officials in %s2_city have lavishly decorated their public buildings with finely carved marble statues.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city地方官员决定使用精美的大理石雕像装饰各大公共建筑。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_GREED</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the Quest of Greed!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没有完成“贪婪的欲望”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_AXE_HAFT_1</Tag>
		<English>Our craftsmen have devised a technique for improving the balance of our axes.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国的工匠改进了斧柄设计，使其威力大大提升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRUSADE_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization captures %s1_city first, if you change your state religion, or if your war ends for any reason prior to your success.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先占领%s1_city，或者你改变了官方信仰，或者在达成目标之前结束战争，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JOYOUS_WEDDING_1</Tag>
		<English>Send well wishes and a token wedding gift.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>送去美好的祝福和一份象征性的礼物。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FRIENDLY_LOCALS_1</Tag>
		<English>A small tribe of friendly locals have granted sanctuary to our beleaguered %s3_unit.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一个友善的当地部落为遭到围攻的我方%s3_unit单位提供了帮助。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HOLY_MOUNTAIN_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must extend your cultural influence and control over the Peak plot that is the Holy Mountain. You may achieve this by divine providence by settling near any Peaks you find. Eventually you may find the right one.[PARAGRAPH:1]Or you may seek further guidance from studying the holy scriptures. If you build %d3 religious buildings (Temples and Monasteries), your religious leaders will solve the puzzle and identify the correct location of the Holy Mountain, which you must then still go and settle near to complete the quest. A %s2_building allows for more coordinated worship and is worth as much as four Temples for the purposes of this quest.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if you change state religions, cease to have a state religion, or reach [COLOR_TECH_TEXT]Industrialism[COLOR_REVERT] without having met the conditions. You will also fail this quest if any other civilization takes control of the Holy Mountain before you do.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这个任务，你必须扩张你的文化影响并控制圣山主峰所在的地区。你可以在你见到的每个山峰附近建立定居点，这样你就一定能找到真正的圣山。[PARAGRAPH:1]你也可以靠深入研究经文来得到更多启示。如果你建成%d3座宗教建筑（神庙和修道院），你的宗教领袖就能最终确定圣山的位置；在确定的位置建立定居点即可任务。一座%s2_building可以容纳更多信徒开展宗教活动，因此其价值等同于四座神庙。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你更换了国教、取消了国教或者在获得[COLOR_TECH_TEXT]产业主义[COLOR_REVERT]后仍然没有达成以上条件，任务就将失败。如果其他文明比你先控制了圣山，任务也将失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WEDDING_FEUD_OTHER_2</Tag>
		<English>A %s5_religion_adjective wedding between one of our citizens and one from the %s1_civ_adjective Empire has drawn our rivals' blessing with generous wedding gifts. Our people are outraged by this insult to our faith.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位我国显贵同一位%s1_civ_adjective人按%s5_religion_adjective传统举行了婚礼，对方国家为此送来祝福和丰厚的礼物。但他们对我们信仰的侮辱还是引发了国民的公愤。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HIGH_WARLORD_2</Tag>
		<English>Excellent! Have him train Pikeman units for us.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>太好了！让他为我们训练一批长枪兵。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FOREST_FIRE_2</Tag>
		<English>Criminals have set fire to the forest near %s2_city in a failed bid to aid their escape from justice.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一群罪犯在%s2_city附近的森林里纵火，妄想乘乱逃脱法网。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CRUSADE_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! Your Crusade to secure the sacred lands of %s2_city has wrested control of the city away from the %s1:2_civ_adjective! Please choose a reward from among the benefits that may accrue from the joy your people feel in this successful Crusade.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你的军队从%s1:2_civ_adjective异教徒手中夺取了圣城%s2_city！这场胜利使人民感到欢欣鼓舞，请在赢得圣战可带来的奖励中选择一项。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HORTICULTURE_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund efforts to increase production without endangering the natural resources that produce them.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>为此项目投入资金，在增加产量同时确保这一自然物种的延续。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREED_DONE_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Receive %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s2_unit[COLOR_REVERT] [NUM1:unit:units].</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]获得%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s2_unit[COLOR_REVERT]单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PARTISANS_1</Tag>
		<English>Our city of %s6_city has been destroyed by the rampaging %s1_civ_adjective army. Some of our citizens are forming partisan resistance!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的城市%s6_city已经被残暴的%s1_civ_adjective军队夷为平地，一些幸存的市民组织起一支游击队！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WASHED_OUT_2</Tag>
		<English>Dispatch emergency crews to repair the damage, without heed to cost.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>立即派遣抢修队，不惜代价地迅速修复。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HINDENBERG_1</Tag>
		<English>Reckless merchants used hydrogen instead of helium to fill their dirigibles and one has caught fire and crashed in a spectacularly fatal accident.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>唯利是图的商人使用氢气而非氦气作为填充气体，导致一艘飞艇起火爆炸并坠毁，造成重大人员伤亡。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HOLY_RITUAL_1</Tag>
		<English>The high priest of the temple in %s2_city has placed a large order for our domestically produced incense for use in holy rituals.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的高级祭司准备大量订购薰香用于举办祭仪。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BLIZZARD_2</Tag>
		<English>Massive snowfall has buried a region of our territory near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>深深的积雪几乎将%s2_city完全掩没。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAMINE_2</Tag>
		<English>Open the city granaries and send half the stores to our troubled neighbors.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>打开我们的粮仓，给陷入困境的邻居提供一半的粮食储备。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TRADING_COMPANY_CONQUERORS</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective Trading Company considers to take further actions to enforce its South Asian market position.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective正采取行动，以巩固其在南亚市场的地位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_REINFORCED_HULL_1</Tag>
		<English>Rumors abound that %s1_civ_adjective shipmasters are doing extensive refitting work on their war galley fleet.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据报%s1_civ_adjective正对其三层桨战船进行技术改装。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_TORNADO_3</Tag>
		<English>A perfect storm spawned numerous F5 Class tornadoes, carving a path of destruction across our lands, smashing our %s8_improvement.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>强烈的飓风横扫了我们的国土，摧毁了我们的%s8_improvement。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INFO_FUGITIVE_4</Tag>
		<English>Our gesture of goodwill toward the %s1_civ_adjective Empire has angered %s6_player.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们对%s1_civ_adjective的善意姿态激怒了%s6_player。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SLAVE_REVOLT_3</Tag>
		<English>We are too busy to be bothered. Leave the matter to the local authorities. (Revolt may continue)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们太忙了，把这件事交给地方当局吧。（起义可能仍将继续下去）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_APPLESEED_1</Tag>
		<English>How many trees were planted? That's amazing!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>种植了多少棵树？真是太棒了！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_IMPEACHMENT_1</Tag>
		<English>Then the impeachment should proceed, if that's the people's will.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>启动弹劾程序，既然这是人民的意愿。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HERESY</Tag>
		<English>The thoroughly religious %s1_civ_adjective state is dealing with an outbreak of heresy in some segments of its population.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一种异端信仰开始在%s1_civ_adjective的部分地区流行，对正统信仰的统治地位造成冲击。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRADING_COMPANY_CONQUERORS_2</Tag>
		<English>Draft an army to establish control.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>计划建立一支军队。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WAR_CHARIOTS_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have trained a large enough force of [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Chariot[COLOR_REVERT] units. Please choose your reward.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经拥有了一支强大的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]战车[COLOR_REVERT]部队。请选择你的奖励。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BETTER_COAL</Tag>
		<English>Our scientists have developed better ways of processing coal fuel. Our economy stands ready to benefit from this development.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的科学家发明了更先进的煤炭深加工技术，我们的经济发展将因此受益。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANCIENT_TEXTS_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund an effort to preserve these artifacts in museums, accessible only to the most careful scholars.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>将古籍存放在博物馆中，开放给少数学者进行研究。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SLAVE_REVOLT_1</Tag>
		<English>A slave revolt has taken place in %s2_city!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city发生奴隶暴动！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GOLD_RUSH_1</Tag>
		<English>When the boom passes, many of the immigrants will settle down.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>最初的热潮逐渐消退，许多新移民决定在此定居。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MASTER_BLACKSMITH_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have met the goals of your master blacksmith and built enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Forges[COLOR_REVERT] for each for his students to have his own to operate. Please choose a reward from among the benefits your new metalworking empire is able to provide to you.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经为煅造大师和他的学徒建造了足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]煅造场[COLOR_REVERT]，请在“冶金王国”可带来的奖励中选择一项。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HERESY_3</Tag>
		<English>Ignore the heresy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>无视异端。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CIGARETTE_SMOKER</Tag>
		<English>Fire has destroyed the Theatre in %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的剧场被大火烧毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_3</Tag>
		<English>Health is the bedrock to world domination! Run full scale tests on all but the youngest and weakest among us.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>国民健康是国家强盛的基石！针对大部分人群进行临床试验。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HORSE_WHISPERING_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must build %d1 [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Stables[COLOR_REVERT] in your various cities.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you reach the Renaissance Era without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须在本国城市兴建%d1座[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]马厩[COLOR_REVERT]。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者当你进入启蒙时代仍未达成目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_RIFLED_CANNON_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective Cannon units can now shoot farther and more accurately thanks to improved barrel design.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的工程师改进了炮管设计，大大提升了加农炮的射程和精度。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NOBLE_KNIGHTS_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>With such a large force of Lancers working together, additional training for these units can be achieved.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该加强对这支强大骑士部队的训练。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BLESSED_SEA_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have met the goals of your religious masters and spread your civilization across the waters. You have completed the quest of The Blessed Sea.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你达成了宗教领袖的要求，将文明扩张到了大洋的彼岸。你已完成了“受祝福的海洋”任务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BERMUDA_TRIANGLE</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective ships and planes have disappeared without a trace in the Bermuda Triangle!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的飞机和轮船连续在“百慕大三角”海域神秘失踪。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_EXPERIENCED_CAPTAIN</Tag>
		<English>A retiring %s1_civ_adjective naval captain has pledged his expertise to assist the Drydock located in %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective海军的一位退休舰长请求到%s2_city的干船坞工作，继续发挥他的才干。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CHAMPION_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Our %s1_unit will gain the [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s2_promotion[COLOR_REVERT] promotion</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]我们的%s1_unit获得[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s2_promotion[COLOR_REVERT]晋升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRUSADE_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>Spread the word of our success and of the blessings of our faith as far and wide as possible.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>大力宣扬圣战的辉煌功绩，向四方传播我们的信仰。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_OVERWHELM_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective people have constructed what is by far the most deadly fleet of warships in the history of warfare. Their aircraft carrier battle group could crush anything that gets in its way.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective建立了有史以来最强大的现代化海军，他们的航空母舰战斗群能够轻易摧毁任何敌人。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HOLY_RITUAL</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective sales of incense are booming.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的薰香销售量大幅增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JOYOUS_WEDDING_OTHER_3</Tag>
		<English>A %s5_religion_adjective wedding between one of our citizens and one from the %s1_civ_adjective Empire has been honored by a national holiday, including outlandish wedding gifts and donations to our religious institutions. Our people are thrilled by this gesture.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>通过一场%s5_religion_adjective传统婚礼，一位我国显贵和一位%s1_civ_adjective人结为夫妇。我们的领袖下令举国欢庆，两位新人获赠了许多珍奇的礼物，还有人为此向我们的宗教机构捐款。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HORTICULTURE_1</Tag>
		<English>Herbalists have discovered rare and precious plants that grow in abundance only in a certain region near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>草药医生发现一种稀有的药用植物在%s2_city附近大量生长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_OTHER_2</Tag>
		<English>Our %s1_civ_adjective religious brothers have gifted us with [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Copper[COLOR_REVERT] to aid us in our war effort!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>同我们一样信奉%s1_civ_adjective的兄弟之邦提供了[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]铜[COLOR_REVERT]资源以资助我们的战争！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INFLUENZA_HIT_CITY</Tag>
		<English>The Influenza virus has struck %s1_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_city暴发流感。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MAN_NAMED_JED_1</Tag>
		<English>While hunting, our %s3_unit has discovered a rich supply of a black oil that burns rather hot.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的%s3_unit在野外狩猎时偶然发现了一种能够炙烈燃烧的黑油。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FUGITIVE_2</Tag>
		<English>An assassin wanted for slaying a %s1_civ_adjective official has been caught fleeing through our land.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一名因暗杀%s1_civ_adjective官员而遭该国政府通缉的刺客在我国境内被抓获。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CLASSIC_LITERATURE_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]The Great Library[COLOR_REVERT] receives additional scholars to help boost research.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]大图书馆[COLOR_REVERT]带来了额外的科研奖励。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GUNS_BUTTER_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must train %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT] Arquebusier[COLOR_REVERT] units.[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if your civilization is operating in the [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Vassalage[COLOR_REVERT] civic.[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if your civilization controls [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s2_building[COLOR_REVERT].[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you discover [COLOR_TECH_TEXT]Replaceable Parts[COLOR_REVERT] without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须训练%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]火枪手[COLOR_REVERT]单位。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你的文明实行[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]分封制度[COLOR_REVERT]，将可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你的文明拥有[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s2_building[COLOR_REVERT]，也可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者你在达成目标前获得了训练更先进火器单位的技术（[COLOR_TECH_TEXT]膛线[COLOR_REVERT]或[COLOR_TECH_TEXT]铁路[COLOR_REVERT]），你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_MELTDOWN</Tag>
		<English>The worst has occurred! One of our reactors has suffered a nuclear meltdown!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>最糟糕的事情发生了！我们的一个反应堆发生了核熔毁！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PARROTS_1</Tag>
		<English>Parrots make fine pets. We should promote them as one of our trade goods.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>鹦鹉可以作为宠物，我们应该进行批量销售。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GOLDEN_BUDDHA_1</Tag>
		<English>That's not his job. Sell the statue and remind the blacksmith what his responsibilities are.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真是不务正业，卖掉金佛像并敦促他专注于本职工作。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRADING_COMPANY_CONQUERORS_3</Tag>
		<English>This is none of our concern.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这与我们无关。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPORTS_LEAGUE_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>Organize  large-scale periodic sporting events in the name of Zeus.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>以众神之王宙斯的名义定期举办大型综合运动会。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_RURAL_FARMERS_2</Tag>
		<English>The Grocer in the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city is becoming renowned for its superior selection, quality and quantity of foodstuffs.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city的杂货店以其质量优异、货物充足、品种多样而享誉四方。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HIGH_WARLORD_3</Tag>
		<English>Superb! Have all our military recruits in that city undergo a training regimen at the new academy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>太棒了！在那里征召的所有部队都应到军事学院进行训练。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_OVERWHELM_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>Leverage our military advantage to persuade the world to ban nuclear weapons.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用我们的军事优势对别国施加影响，推动世界无核化进程。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_DUSTBOWL_CONT</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective farmers continue to suffer loss of their land due to ongoing dust storms sweeping across the plains.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>由于沙漠化进程的加剧，%s1_civ_adjective的农民推动了大片耕地。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WEDDING_FEUD_OTHER_3</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_religion_adjective wedding between one of our citizens and one from %s2_civ has been honored by a national holiday by our rivals, including outlandish wedding gifts and donations to their religious institutions. This insult against our religious traditions has outraged our populace. Should we declare a holy war upon the unbelievers?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位我国显贵同一位%s2_civ人按%s1_religion_adjective传统举行了婚礼，对方下令举国欢庆并送来珍奇的礼物，还向他们的宗教机构捐献大笔金钱。他们对我们信仰的侮辱引起了国民的公愤，我们应该向这些异教徒发动圣战吗？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SECRET_KNOWLEDGE_1</Tag>
		<English>Hand the material over to our researchers.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>将这批古籍交给我们的研究人员。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MEDIATOR_WORLD_2</Tag>
		<English>A great mediator has attempted to broker peace between the %s1_civ_adjective and %s3_adjective Empires!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位中立国领袖提出调停%s1_civ_adjective与%s3_adjective之间的争端，恢复和平！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_LABORATORY</Tag>
		<English>A scientific breakthrough at the laboratory in %s2_city is credited in part to the free flow of ideas and information nurtured by the %s1_civ_adjective government.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s1_civ_adjective政府的大力资助下，%s2_city的实验室获得了一项重大科研突破。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FOREST_FIRE</Tag>
		<English>Fire has raged through a forest near the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjectiv的%s2_city附近发生森林大火。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_REACTOR_LEAK_1</Tag>
		<English>Our reactors are safe. Contain the leaks, but there is no need for further action.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的反应堆是安全的。控制泄漏，但无需采取进一步措施。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_ANCIENTOLYMPICS_1</Tag>
		<English>In honor of our gods, the city of %s2_city has organized and hosted a grand series of Games. Athletes from all over the nation travel there to compete.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>为了彰显众神的荣耀，%s2_city举办了一场盛大的综合运动会，全国各地的选手们踊跃参赛。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LITERACY_1</Tag>
		<English>Continue to promote reading and writing. Knowledge is power!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>继续推进文化教育事业，知识就是力量！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRUSADE_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Harness the fervor of the believers to construct a Holy Shrine to honor the sacred sites where our faith was born.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>将狂热的信徒们组织起来，在我们神圣信仰的诞生地建造一座圣坛。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_ANGEL_OF_MERCY_1</Tag>
		<English>Rumors that a spirit angel of mercy is watching over the patients in the hospital in %s2_city are leading many devout believers to seek treatment there.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据传%s2_city的市立医院有天使保佑，大批信徒涌向那里接受治疗。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MASTER_BLACKSMITH_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must build a total of %d1 [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Forges[COLOR_REVERT] in your various cities. This may include Forges already completed.[PARAGRAPH:1]The master smith is a religious man. An additional reward option will be available if your civilization has a state religion if and when the quest is completed successfully.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, if you lose control over %s2_city and the master smith, or if you reach the Renaissance Era without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须在本国城市建造%d1座[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]煅造场[COLOR_REVERT]（已建成的包括在内）。[PARAGRAPH:1]这位煅造大师非常虔信宗教。如果你的文明设立了官方信仰，则在完成任务时可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者当你失去了煅造大师所定居的城市%s2_city，或者当你进入进入启蒙时代仍未达成目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_NUCLEAR_REACTOR_LEAK</Tag>
		<English>Radiation leaks have been discovered in the reactor of the Nuclear Plant in the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在 %s1_civ_adjective 城市 %s2_city 的核电站反应堆中发现了辐射泄漏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_INTERSTATE_1</Tag>
		<English>Our engineers have conceived a national highway system of divided highways free of all traffic stops, built in straight lines on smooth grades.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的工程师完成了多车道、全封闭、全立交的现代化国家公路网设计。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRADING_COMPANY_CONQUERORS_1</Tag>
		<English>Fund the establishment of contracted harbors out of our treasury.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>从我们的国库中出资建设承包港口。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SOLO_FLIGHT_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Receive [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]%D1[COLOR_REVERT] attitude from all leaders</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]所有领袖对你的态度[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]%D1[COLOR_REVERT]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANGEL_OF_MERCY_1</Tag>
		<English>The extra patients will enhance city revenue.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>大批求医者将增加城市收入。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MASTER_BLACKSMITH_1</Tag>
		<English>The Master Blacksmith[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by the master blacksmith to build enough new [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Forges[COLOR_REVERT] to provide acceptable working environments for all the students to whom he intends to pass on his trade secrets.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“煅造大师”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]一位煅造大师请你完成一项任务：建造足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]煅造场[COLOR_REVERT]以便为他的众多学徒提供良好的训练和工作环境。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INFLUENZA_HELP_2</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]The virus spreads to some nearby cities and reduces their population by %d1</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]疫情传播导致周围城市人口减少%d1级。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HARBORMASTER_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>Our ship captains gain extra experience, enabling them to better navigate.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>为我们的船长积累更多的经验，提升海军整体素质。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ROGUE_STATION_1</Tag>
		<English>Send a blackops group to destroy the radio tower, we can blame it on an industrial accident.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>派遣特工破坏他们的广播塔，并将原因归结为一次工业事故。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HORSE_WHISPERING</Tag>
		<English>Our horse trainers believe that it would be possible to gain a much deeper bond with and understanding of our riding animals.[PARAGRAPH:1]They require a larger and more coordinated network of [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Stables[COLOR_REVERT] to pursue this goal.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的驯马师相信骑手与马匹之间可以进一步增进相互了解，建立牢固的感情纽带。[PARAGRAPH:1]为实现这一目标，他们要求在各个城市兴建设施完善的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]马厩[COLOR_REVERT]。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_TEA_1</Tag>
		<English>Imported %s1_civ_adjective tea has become all the rage amongst our social elite.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>自%s1_civ_adjective进口的茶饮料已成为我国社会精英阶层热烈追捧的时尚饮品。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LOOTERS_OTHER_3</Tag>
		<English>Massive civil unrest near %s4_city has led to riots and looting. Both inside and outside the city, some of our improvements have been destroyed by looters.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s4_city附近发生骚乱和抢掠事件。许多建筑和设施遭到破坏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DUSTBOWL_2</Tag>
		<English>We cannot afford to spend gold on this problem. Leave the matter to the local authorities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们无法继续在此领域投入资金，让当地官员自行处理。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_DEPRESSION_1</Tag>
		<English>There is really not much we can do about this, is there?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>对此我们无能为力，不是吗？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SPICY_1</Tag>
		<English>An innovative chef has discovered a new type of spice, which grows only in a forest near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位厨师发现了一种新香料，这种香料仅出产于%s2_city附近的森林。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WEDDING_FEUD_OTHER_1</Tag>
		<English>A %s5_religion_adjective wedding between one of our citizens and one from the %s1_civ_adjective Empire has angered our people. Our rivals have granted no special gifts or attention, though, so our people are merely grumbling and fuming.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位我国显贵和一位%s1_civ_adjective人按%s5_religion_adjective传统举行的婚礼激起了我国人民的愤怒。不过对方国家并未采取挑衅行动，相信我们的人民也不会有更过激的反应。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CIV_GAME</Tag>
		<English>Our game designers have developed a new addictive game of Civilization. How shall we proceed?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国的游戏设计师开发了一款令人上瘾的全新电脑游戏——《文明》，对此我们应作何反应？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CIGARETTE_SMOKER_1</Tag>
		<English>A careless cigarette smoker started a fire at the Theatre in %s2_city, during which the building was destroyed and numerous patrons died.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位粗心的烟民在%s2_city的剧场引发了一场火灾，剧场被烧毁，许多观众被烧死。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CRAB_CAKES</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective crab cake sales are booming.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的蟹肉饼销售量大幅增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HYMNS_AND_SCULPTURES_2</Tag>
		<English>The art and sculpture decorating the %s5_building in %s2_city has nurtured the imagination and talents of a new Great Artist!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的%s5_building中的壁画和雕塑激发了一位年轻的大艺术家的想象力和创造力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BLIZZARD_1</Tag>
		<English>The rescue and recovery efforts are best handled by the locals.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>组织当地居民进行清理。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LOOTERS_4</Tag>
		<English>Our agents have been exposed!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的间谍被发现了！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANTIMONARCHISTS_1</Tag>
		<English>Our King is the State!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>国王即国家！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BABY_BOOM_1</Tag>
		<English>Our people are thriving in peace time.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国进入欣欣向荣的和平时代。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT</Tag>
		<English>Our herbalists have discovered a new plant that holds great promise for health treatments. However, tests on human subjects are required to find the right mixture.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国草药医生发现了一种新的药用植物，对多种疾病具有极佳的疗效。但确定最佳配方还需要进行大量临床试验。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_GUNS_BUTTER_1</Tag>
		<English>Our generals request that we focus on making guns. These are the weapons of the future![PARAGRAPH:1]If we train enough [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Arquebusier[COLOR_REVERT] units, we should be able to command any battlefield.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的军事将领要求大量生产火枪，这是属于未来世界的武器！[PARAGRAPH:1]如果我们训练了足够数量的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]火枪手[COLOR_REVERT]单位，我们就能支配任何战场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_DISSIDENT_PRIEST</Tag>
		<English>A priest from %s2_city is doubting the supreme power of Amun-Re.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位祭司质疑传统神灵的至尊地位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TORNADO_1</Tag>
		<English>Vicious tornadoes carved a path of destruction through the %s1_civ_adjective Empire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>强烈的飓风横扫%s1_civ_adjective，沿途留下一片废墟。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CHILLY_FLIGHT_1</Tag>
		<English>Set up a monument at the airport to produce tourism.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在当地机场建造一座纪念碑以吸引游客。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_CORPORATE_EXPANSION</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of the Corporate Expansion!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“商业扩张”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DEFECTING_AGENT_2</Tag>
		<English>Unacceptable. An "accident" should happen to the traitor!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>绝不能宽恕叛国行为，给他安排一场意外“事故”。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HORTICULTURE_2</Tag>
		<English>A medicinal tea cultivated by locals has been found to be effective with treating illnesses. This tea grows only in a specific region near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>生长于%s2_city附近一种茶树被发现极具治疗功效，成为当地独有的特产。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CRUSADE_DONE</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective armies have completed their Crusade, wresting control of the Holy City of %s2_city away from the %s4_civ_adjective people!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的军队发动了一场圣战，从%s4_civ_adjective异教徒手中夺取了圣城%s2_city。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HIGH_WARLORD</Tag>
		<English>A warlord from %s2_city has made a generous contribution to his community.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位军事首领以实际行动慷慨地回报家乡父老！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_LOOTERS_2</Tag>
		<English>There are riots taking place near the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s6_city. Our agents stand ready to add fuel to these fires, to stir up additional trouble.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的%s6_city附近发生骚乱。我们派往该处的间谍提议火上浇油，制造更大的麻烦。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FUEL_ADDITIVES_1</Tag>
		<English>The mass transit system in %s2_city has implemented a city-wide program of using fuel additives to reduce pollution and improve on maintenance costs and fuel efficiency.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的公交系统开始推广使用新型燃油添加剂，以减少污染、节约成本并提升燃油效率。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MONEY_CHANGERS_2</Tag>
		<English>Money changers have flocked to the Market in the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city, attracting all manner of customers in need of changing one nation's currency for another's.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city的市场中聚集了大批货币兑换商，为各国顾客提供货币兑换业务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_JOYOUS_WEDDING</Tag>
		<English>A joyous marriage in the %s3_religion_adjective tradition has forged new bonds between %s1_civ_adjective and %s4_civ_adjective peoples, who both adore the new couple and are pleased with the behavior of the inlaws from the other nation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一场遵照%s3_religion_adjective传统进行的婚姻在%s1_civ_adjective和%s4_civ_adjective人民之间建立了新的纽带，双方都很欣赏这对新人，乐于接纳来自外国的亲家。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CLASSIC_LITERATURE_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Discover and decipher lost knowledge from within some of the literature.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>通过研究经典文学宝库寻找并破解失传的远古科技。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREED_1</Tag>
		<English>Greed[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your military leaders to seize control of that resource.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“贪婪的欲望”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]你的军事领袖要求夺取一处资源的控制权。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PATRON_OF_KNOWLEDGE_1</Tag>
		<English>Upon his passing, a patron of knowledge from %s2_city has willed his extensive collection of writings to the library.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>根据一位热爱学术的收藏家立下的遗嘱，当地图书馆获赠一批珍贵的手稿。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FORTY_THIEVES_1</Tag>
		<English>The legend of Forty Thieves has attracted treasure hunters and tourists to the area, boosting local commerce.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>四十大盗的传说吸引了大批追求财富和刺激的冒险者，促进了地方经济的繁荣。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_3</Tag>
		<English>Provide Iron so that they may craft strong weaponry.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>向他们提供铁用于加强军备。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_INDUSTRIAL_FIRE_1</Tag>
		<English>A fire at the Factory in %s2_city, which was started by a worker's mistake, has gutted the building.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一座工厂被工人操作失误引起的大火烧毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCC_CONQUEST</Tag>
		<English>Will draft armies to attack %s1 to conquer their cities of %s2.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>迅速征召军队攻打%s1的城市%s2。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_EARTHDAY</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective Empire has announced the first annual Earth Day, crusading for the cause of Environmentalism.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective宣布开展一年一度的“地球日”活动，大力宣传环境保护。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MOTOR_OIL_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund upgrades to our army's vehicle fleet to make use of the new formula.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在军队中推广使用新型润滑油。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FUGITIVE_2</Tag>
		<English>Secretly interrogate the prisoner, hoping to learn sensitive information.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>秘密审问，以便获取敏感情报。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LOOTERS_3</Tag>
		<English>Unleash our agents. Allow them to capitalize on any opportunities for mischief-making that they can find.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让特工采取行动，允许他们乘机煽风点火。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MONEY_CHANGERS_1</Tag>
		<English>The Market in %s2_city has become renowned as a worldwide center of dealings in global currency. This is bolstering %s1_civ_adjective profits.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的市场成为闻名世界的贸易中心，促进了%s1_civ_adjective的经济繁荣。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_BEAST_3</Tag>
		<English>Hunt it? Are you mad? The beast is a manifestation of a divine spirit!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>猎杀它？你疯了吗？那只巨兽是神灵的化身！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TOWER_SHIELD_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective Melee units are now deployed with new, larger shields, improving their defense versus Archery units.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的肉搏部队开始装备巨型塔盾，提升了对弓箭的防御能力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TOO_CLOSE_TO_CALL</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective election results were so close, the courts had to rule on the vote-counting procedures to arrive at an outcome.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective大选的票数是如此接近，宪法法院不得不下令重新计票以获得准确结果。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SECRET_KNOWLEDGE</Tag>
		<English>A cache of ancient texts has been discovered hidden away in a %s1_civ_adjective monastery.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s1_civ_adjective的一座修道院里发现了一批古籍。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GUNS_BUTTER_1</Tag>
		<English>Guns Not Butter[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your military leaders to train a sizable force of arquebus units.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“要火枪不要黄油”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]你的军事将领请求训练足够数量的火枪手单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_STRONGER_FITTINGS_1</Tag>
		<English>Weaponsmiths have improved the strength and durability of fittings used to make crossbows. This allows for stronger tension and improved power.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>武器工匠改进了弩机设计，使弩的射程和威力大大提升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_INFLUENZA</Tag>
		<English>A deadly influenza epidemic has broken out amongst %s1_civ_adjective people, originating in the city of %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city暴发了一场严重的流感，许多%s1_civ_adjective人因此丧生。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_AT_THE_SWORD</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective soldiers have rallied behind their heroes of the sword.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的勇士们聚集在战争英雄的麾下。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ROGUE_STATION_3</Tag>
		<English>Wait for the station to get more listeners, then round them up along with the broadcasters and send them all to do labour at our factories.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>不动声色地暗中监视，等时机成熟时再将鼓动者和追随者一网打尽，全部送进工厂做苦力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FOREST_FIRE_2</Tag>
		<English>Send emissaries to assist the bereaved.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>派遣专员救助灾民。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WASHED_OUT_1</Tag>
		<English>We will have to send workers to repair them at a later time.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们稍后将派工人进行修复。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PESTILENCE_5</Tag>
		<English>Fire ant armies of massive proportion have laid waste a region of plantations lands near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>大群火蚁横扫%s2_city附近地区。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_TORNADO_1</Tag>
		<English>The heavens opened up and down came the fist of retribution. Terrible twisting rages of air wiped away our %s8_improvement.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>上天向我们显示了怒火，强烈的飓风摧毁了我们的%s8_improvement。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TSUNAMI_1</Tag>
		<English>The city now lies in ruins. All life has been lost, all property obliterated.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>城市变成了废墟，市民几乎全部死亡，建筑几乎全部被毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAMINE_OTHER_3</Tag>
		<English>The generous %s1_civ_adjective people in %s2_city have sent all of their food stores to your city of %s4_city to prevent famine caused by a poor local harvest. This humanitarian effort has brought your two peoples much closer together!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city的居民拿出了全部粮食储备救助我国遭遇严重饥荒的%s4_city居民。这次无私人道主义行动大幅拉近了两国人民的关系。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPOILED_GRAIN_1</Tag>
		<English>That sounds like bad news, but what can we do? Nothing.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真是个坏消息，但我们能有什么办法？什么办法也没有。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_OTHER_4</Tag>
		<English>Our %s1_civ_adjective religious brothers have gifted us with [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Horses[COLOR_REVERT] to aid us in our war effort!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>同我们一样信奉%s1_civ_adjective的兄弟之邦提供了[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]马匹[COLOR_REVERT]资源以资助我们的战争！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_BEAST_1</Tag>
		<English>Let it breed and give offspring. Hunt sparingly.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>限制狩猎，让它自由地繁育幼兽。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JOYOUS_WEDDING_2</Tag>
		<English>Send hearty congratulations and a generous wedding gift.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>送去衷心的祝愿和一份丰厚的礼物。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SETBACK_1</Tag>
		<English>Our researchers have experienced a setback in their efforts.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的科学家遭遇重大挫折，研究进度放缓。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEROIC_GESTURE_2</Tag>
		<English>Perhaps this is a sign that enough blood has been shed. Send our emissaries to see if they are ready to discuss peace.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>也许血确实流得够多了，派出使节尝试与对方和谈。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HORTICULTURE</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective horticulturists have harnessed rare local resources to produce remedies.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的园艺师采集当地特有植物制成一种珍贵的药物。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FAMINE_1</Tag>
		<English>A dreadful harvest for our %s1_civ_adjective neighbors in the city of %s6_city just across the border has left its people starving. We may have a chance to gain favor with them if we provide humanitarian assistance from %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>靠近我国边境的%s1_civ_adjective的%s6_city粮食严重歉收，人民陷入饥荒。如果%s2_city能够提供一批人道主义援助，他们将非常感激。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPORTS_LEAGUE_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Leverage these sports leagues in to a cultural tradition.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>使体育联赛成为一项新的文化传统。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DEFECTING_AGENT</Tag>
		<English>One of our high-ranking intelligence agents has defected to the %s1_civ_adjective empire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国的一名高级特工叛变投靠了%s1_civ_adjective的情报部门。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CIV_GAME</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective game designers have developed a new game of Civilization.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的游戏设计师开发了一款全新电脑游戏――《文明》。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NOBLE_KNIGHTS_1</Tag>
		<English>Noble Knights[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by the mandate of your people to train a sizable force of [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Lancer[COLOR_REVERT] units.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“贵族骑士”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]我们的精英阶层要求训练足够数量的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]骑士[COLOR_REVERT]单位.</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GOLDEN_BUDDHA_2</Tag>
		<English>Impressive. This should make the Forge a cultural attraction.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真是精美绝伦，应该让更多人参观这座充满文化气息的煅造场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HORSE_WHISPERING_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Use our advantage to immediately train [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Horse Archers[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用所获优势立即训练[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]骑射手[COLOR_REVERT]。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_AIRLINER_CRASH_OTHER_3</Tag>
		<English>One of your passenger airliners has crashed in %s1_civ_adjective territory. They are denying all access and have claimed the wreckage as their own. This outrage has angered your people and driven a diplomatic wedge between your two nations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一架我国客机在%s1_civ_adjective境内坠毁。对方禁止我们的救援队入境并将飞机残骸据为己有。这种行为激起了我国人民的愤怒，两国外交关系陷入僵局。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FUGITIVE_1</Tag>
		<English>A fugitive from justice, wanted for crimes in the %s1_civ_adjective Empire, has been discovered hiding out in our territory.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一名遭%s1_civ_adjective政府通缉的逃犯被发现正隐藏于我国境内。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HYMNS_AND_SCULPTURES_1</Tag>
		<English>The music played in your %s5_building in %s2_city has inspired a young person, who has grown into a Great Artist!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位年轻人受到%s2_city的%s5_building中演奏的音乐熏陶，逐渐成长为杰出的大艺术家。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BOWYER</Tag>
		<English>A master bowyer has developed techniques that improve the strength of all %s1_civ_adjective war bows.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位制弓大师改进了弓弩制造技术，使%s1_civ_adjective部队装备的弓弩更加强劲。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_WARSHIPS</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of the Warships!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“无敌舰队”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_LITERACY</Tag>
		<English>The learned %s1_civ_adjective people enjoy a virtually universal literacy rate.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的文化教育事业迅速推进，几乎完全消除了文盲。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCC_ACQUIRE</Tag>
		<English>Will offer %d1 gold to %s2 for their cities of %s3. Their refusal will lead to war.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>为了殖民%s3向%s2提供%d1金币。若他们拒绝则立刻开战。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_ELECTRIC_COMPANY_1</Tag>
		<English>The workers for our electric companies are so happy and well motivated, they repair damaged lines quickly no matter the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国电力部门的员工爱岗敬业、技术精熟，努力克服各种不利因素的影响，及时地修复发生故障的线路。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_IMMIGRANTS</Tag>
		<English>Inspired by books telling stories about the culture of %s2_city, immigrants are flowing to the city!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city悠久的历史和文化吸引了大量外来人口！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_NUCLEAR_REACTOR_LEAK_AGAIN</Tag>
		<English>The radioactive leaks in Nuclear Plant in the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city are still not contained.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>核电站的放射性泄漏仍没有得到控制。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TSUNAMI_2</Tag>
		<English>The city has suffered massive loss of life and property. Recovery will take decades.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>人员和财产损失严重，需要数十年才能恢复。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PARROTS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective merchants are now selling caged parrots as exotic pets.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective商人开始批量销售作为宠物的鹦鹉。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MINING_ACCIDENT_1</Tag>
		<English>Organize a rebuilding effort, with emphasis on improved mining safety.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>组织重建矿井，加强安全管理。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BEST_DEFENSE_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The sturdy %s1_civ_adjective people have completed The Best Defense quest!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>坚强的%s1_civ_adjective人民胜利完成了“顶级防御”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_IMPACT_CRATER_1</Tag>
		<English>Why is this important? Do not bother me with petty details.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这算什么重要消息？我可没时间管鸡毛蒜皮的小事。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_PROTEST</Tag>
		<English>Our people are protesting against our nuclear arsenal. They fear that we would use nukes with disastrous consequences.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国民众举行大规模抗议活动，反对加强核军备。他们担心使用核武器会造成灾难性的后果。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_JOYOUS_WEDDING_1</Tag>
		<English>Two prominent families, one from our people and one from the %s1_civ_adjective people, have forged an alliance through an arranged %s4_religion_adjective marriage.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>两个显赫的家族，一个来自我国，另一个来自%s1_civ_adjective，通过一场%s4_religion_adjective传统婚礼结成了亲家。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BANANA_SPLIT_1</Tag>
		<English>One of our ice cream parlors has invented the banana split.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国的一位小商贩发明了“香蕉船”冰淇淋。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FIRING_PINS_1</Tag>
		<English>Supply our Grenadiers with the improved explosives.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让我们的掷弹兵换用新式手榴弹。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CONTROVERSIAL_PHILOSOPHER</Tag>
		<English>A philosopher from %s2_city is stirring up controversy among our population. Our people are highly distrustful of his teachings.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位来自%s2_city的哲学家提出的新学说引发了激烈的争议，许多民众认为他的言论与传统教义相悖。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DISSIDENT_PRIEST_2</Tag>
		<English>We can ignore that nutter, our people will get over it.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>完全不加理会，我们的人民很快就会忘记这件事。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_REACTOR_LEAK_2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Low risk of a nuclear meltdown.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Radiation leaks may continue.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]核熔毁的低风险。[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]辐射泄漏可能继续。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DISSIDENT_PRIEST</Tag>
		<English>A dissident priest from %s2_city is doubting the supreme power of Amun-Re in an unprecedented outbreak of heresy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位激进的祭司强烈质疑传统神灵的至尊地位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_MASTER_BLACKSMITH</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of The Master Blacksmith.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“煅造大师”任务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_APPLESEED_1</Tag>
		<English>A passionate young man has undertaken a crusade to plant as many new apple trees as he can.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位热情的年轻人年复一年地种下无数棵苹果树。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TOXCATL_2</Tag>
		<English>Make every effort to recapture him!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>尽一切努力把他抓回来！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CRISIS_IN_THE_SENATE_1</Tag>
		<English>The eldest senator of the leading opposition party has been disgraced by scandal. The entire senate has been thrown into chaos.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>来自最大反对党的一名资深议员遭遇政治丑闻的困扰，导致整个参议院陷入混乱。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAMINE_1</Tag>
		<English>We are unable to assist at this time. Send our condolensces to their leaders.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>现在我们爱莫能助，只能向对方领袖致以真切的慰问。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SECURITY_TAX_1</Tag>
		<English>Collect the taxes!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>开征“安全税”！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_INDEPENDENTFILMS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective filmmakers from %s2_city have managed to wrest control over a slice of the Hit Movies market.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city的多家电影公司拍摄了多部卖座大片。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FUEL_ADDITIVES</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective mass transit system in %s2_city has begun to use advanced fuel additives to reduce pollution, cut costs, and improve vehicle performance.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city的公交系统开始推广使用新型燃油添加剂，以减少污染、节约成本并提升车辆性能。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CLASSIC_LITERATURE_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have met the goals of your scholars and built for them enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Libraries[COLOR_REVERT] to store their newly recorded works. Please choose a reward from among the benefits your new treasure trove of written literature are able to provide to you.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经为学者们建造了足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]图书馆[COLOR_REVERT]以保存新近搜集整理的经典著作。请在经典文学宝库可带来的奖励中选择一项。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MASTER_BLACKSMITH_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The skilled %s1_civ_adjective metalworkers have completed the quest of The Master Blacksmith!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的冶金业者胜利完成了“煅造大师”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PATRON_OF_KNOWLEDGE_2</Tag>
		<English>The Library in the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city has received an influx of precious writings thanks to the generosity of a wealthy family.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city，当地图书馆从一位收藏家那里获赠一批珍贵的手稿。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WARSHIPS_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>With such a large fleet of warships, additional training for the crews can be achieved.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该加强对这支强大海军的训练。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HALBERD_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective Pikemen have begun using a new type of halberd, boosting their strength versus foot soldiers.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的长枪兵开始使用新式长戟，增强了对抗步兵的能力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_STRONGER_FITTINGS_1</Tag>
		<English>Commission the new fittings for all of our crossbow units.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让我们的弩手换装新式劲弩。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BEST_DEFENSE_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must build %d1 [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Castles[COLOR_REVERT] in your cities.[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if your civilization controls the Great Wall.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you discover [COLOR_TECH_TEXT]Urban Planning[COLOR_REVERT] without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须在本国城市建造%d1座[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]城堡[COLOR_REVERT]。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你的文明拥有长城将可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者当你发现[COLOR_TECH_TEXT]膛线[COLOR_REVERT]、[COLOR_TECH_TEXT]铁路[COLOR_REVERT]或[COLOR_TECH_TEXT]经济学[COLOR_REVERT]时仍未达成目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_TRUFFLES_1</Tag>
		<English>A rich source of truffles has been discovered in a series of caves. The locals have begun to farm them.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在当地的洞穴中发现了美味的块菌，人们开始大量养殖。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SEA_TURTLES_1</Tag>
		<English>Turtles! What will they think of next?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>海龟！那里还有什么好吃的东西？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BEST_DEFENSE</Tag>
		<English>Our generals request government aid in expanding our fortifications.[PARAGRAPH:1]We will need to build enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Castles[COLOR_REVERT] to satisfy their views on mounting a proper defense for our nation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的将军请求政府加强城防建设。[PARAGRAPH:1]我们需要建造足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]城堡[COLOR_REVERT]以保护国家安全。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BABY_BOOM_2</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective population is growing rapidly as a post-war baby boom sweeps through their settlements.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>受战后婴儿潮的影响，%s1_civ_adjective的人口正迅速增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BLESSED_SEA_1</Tag>
		<English>The Blessed Sea[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your religious leaders to found cities on new landmasses. If you can build enough cities on new landmasses you will please the masters, who will offer you a choice of rewards.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“受祝福的海洋”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]宗教领袖交给你一个任务：在新的大陆上建立城市。如果你在新大陆上建立了足够的城市，宗教领袖将给予你一种奖励。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BABY_BOOM_1</Tag>
		<English>Our soldiers, returning from war, have dedicated themselves to peace and to raising families. Our civilization is experiencing a baby boom!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的士兵从战场返回家园，为和平与家庭努力奉献他们的力量。我们的文明进入了生育高峰期！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MOTHER_LODE_1</Tag>
		<English>Our gold miners near %s2_city have struck the mother lode! We are rich, rich, rich!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的矿工在%s2_city附近的金矿中找到了主矿脉，我们发财了！发财了！发财了！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CITY_RUINS_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund additional exploratory efforts.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>资助他们继续探险。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BLIZZARD_1</Tag>
		<English>A blizzard has dumped several meters of snow on a region near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s2_city地区，强冷空气带来深达数米的积雪。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NOBLE_KNIGHTS_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Enlist our noble Lancers into a drive to spread our faith.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用高贵骑士的声名大力传播我们的信仰。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANCIENT_TEXTS_1</Tag>
		<English>Disperse the texts to various researchers and specialists, to see what we might learn.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>将古籍开放给所有专家学者进行研究。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_IMMIGRANTS_1</Tag>
		<English>We are pleased at their new choice of residence.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>很高兴他们找到了梦想中的新家园。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_JOYOUS_WEDDING_2</Tag>
		<English>One of our prominent young noble ladies has fallen in love with a %s1_civ_adjective nobleman and they are to be wed in the %s4_religion_adjective tradition.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国一位家世显赫的年轻贵族小姐爱上了一位%s1_civ_adjective贵族，他们将按%s4_religion_adjective传统举行婚礼。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_AIRLINER_CRASH_3</Tag>
		<English>Deny access. Claim the wreckage and let your engineers pore over it.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>禁止别国救援队进入现场。让我们的人对飞机残骸进行全面调查。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PREACHING_RESEARCHER</Tag>
		<English>A scientist from %s2_city has undergone baptism and become a preacher at the city's Christian Monastery.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位著名学者决定接受洗礼，到当地修道院担任宣教师。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAVORITE_SON_1</Tag>
		<English>No one survives forever. Cash in on the phenomenon before he meets the inevitable end.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>没人能永远好运，利用他当下的声名及时获取利益。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INTERSTATE_1</Tag>
		<English>Construction will begin as soon as plans are finalized.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>完善设计后立即开工建造。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BEST_DEFENSE_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have met the goals of your military planners and built enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Castles[COLOR_REVERT] to serve as fortresses against invaders. Please choose a reward from among the benefits your defense is able to provide to you.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经建造了足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]城堡[COLOR_REVERT]以有效地防御敌人入侵。请在顶级防御体系可带来的奖励中选择一项。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BROKEN_DAM</Tag>
		<English>The dam in %s2_city has broken, flooding the city's suburbs and killing people.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的大堤发生垮塌，大部分郊区被淹没，人员伤亡严重。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DUSTBOWL_2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Significant chance the dustbowl will continue</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]沙漠化很有可能继续下去。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SOUR_CRUDE_1</Tag>
		<English>Sour crude? What a mess. Less valuable per barrel, but it still burns, right? Just deal with it.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>劣质原油？真是糟糕，但应该还烧得着吧？允许继续销售。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INSPIRED_MISSION_3</Tag>
		<English>We are pleased to provide any assistance they may require!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们可以尽力满足他们。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_GOLD_RUSH_1</Tag>
		<English>Small amounts of gold panned from streams have sparked a gold rush to the area by immigrants looking to strike it rich.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>由于在当地的河滩上发现少量金沙，世界各地的淘金者蜂拥而至，梦想着一夜暴富。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FIRING_PINS_1</Tag>
		<English>A master smith has devised a firing pin for our grenades, ending the need to use fuses.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位武器大师为我们的手榴弹设计了一种撞针式引信，淘汰了原来使用的导火线。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FORTY_THIEVES_1</Tag>
		<English>Excellent.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>棒极了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREED_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must invade %s1_civ and gain control of the %s2_resource resource.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization captures the target city first, if the city is destroyed, or if %d3 turns pass without achieving the objective.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]为了完成这项任务，你需要入侵%s1_civ并取得对%s2_resource资源的控制权。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先占领该城，或者该城被摧毁，或者经过%d3回合仍然未达成目标，任务即宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TSUNAMI</Tag>
		<English>A tsunami more than fifteen meters high has rolled over the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city. The destruction is unprecedented in world history.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>高达15米的海啸袭击了%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city，造成史上罕有的巨大破坏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HALBERD_1</Tag>
		<English>Issue the new weapons to all of our heavy spearmen.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让我们的长枪兵换装新式武器。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HINDENBERG</Tag>
		<English>A hydrogen-filled %s1_civ_adjective airship has exploded and crashed. Their government is scrambling to prevent a reoccurrence.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一艘%s1_civ_adjective的氢气飞艇意外爆炸并坠毁，该国政府已展开调查，努力避免此类事故再次发生。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PERSONAL_COMPUTERS_1</Tag>
		<English>Personal computers manufactured in %s2_city are in high demand among homes and small businesses.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city出产的个人电脑广受家庭用户和小型公司的欢迎。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_NOBLE_KNIGHTS</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of "Noble Knights!"</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“贵族骑士”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BOWYER_1</Tag>
		<English>We will include the new design principles in all of our bowmaking.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们将全面推广改进的弓弩设计。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HORSE_WHISPERING_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have met the goals of your horse trainers and built for them enough facilities to empower their plans. Please choose a reward from among the benefits your horse trainers are able to provide to you.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经建成了足够数量的马厩，请在驯马师可带来的奖励中选择一项。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_IMPEACHMENT</Tag>
		<English>The Congress wants to impeach the President. The population supports this motion.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>国会希望弹劾总统，这一动议获得了民众的支持。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_THE_VANDALS_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]A dangerous number of barbarian [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Swordsman[COLOR_REVERT] units have spawned near our border.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]大量蛮族[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]剑士[COLOR_REVERT]出现在我国边境地区。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SLAVE_REVOLT_AGAIN_1</Tag>
		<English>The local authorities in %s2_city have so far been unable to put down the slave revolt.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>到目前为止地方当局仍无法平息%s2_city的农民起义。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_METAL_DECKS_1</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective Empire has halted production of aircraft carriers with wooden decks. Their decks are now made of steel.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的航空母舰停止采用木制甲板，改用钢制甲板。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_LONG_RANGE_FIGHTERS_1</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective Empire has developed a long range Fighter plane.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective研制出了一种新型远程战斗机。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FEDERAL_RESERVE_1</Tag>
		<English>Our economists have devised a system of regulating interest rates to help normalize economic growth.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的经济学家研究出了一套完善的利率管理制度，能够确保经济的平稳增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MOTOR_OIL_1</Tag>
		<English>Authorize the selling of the improved motor oil on the open market.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>授权新型润滑油在市场销售。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAUX_PAS_OTHER_1</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective ambassador has committed a faux pas. This insulting gaffe has adversely affected our relations with his country.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective大使发生失礼行为，对我国与该国的关系产生了负面影响。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MIRACLE</Tag>
		<English>A miracle performed at the city wall in %s2_city is attracting %s3_religion_adjective pilgrims from far and wide.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据报在%s2_city发生了奇迹，吸引了来自天南海北的%s3_religion_adjective朝圣者。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANTELOPE_2</Tag>
		<English>Commit our government to harvesting this new resource immediately.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让政府统一组织捕猎活动。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_WASHED_OUT</Tag>
		<English>Floods have washed out some of the routes near the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective发生洪灾，%s2_city附近的道路被冲毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_ASKCOLONIALCITY_MESSAGE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1 Trading Company asks for the control of %s3 and offers %d2 gold. Refusal will lead to war. Shall we accept their offer?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1贸易公司向您索要%s3的控制权以及%d2金币。 拒绝将会导致战争。我们是否同意他们的要求？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANTIMONARCHISTS</Tag>
		<English>Anti-monarchists are claiming that the King has too much power and that religious leaders need to have some, too.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一些宗教人士发动示威抗议君主专制，他们认为宗教领袖应该拥有更大的权力。 </Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BANANA_SPLIT_1</Tag>
		<English>Mmm, ice cream. The customers must be going bananas over that!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>嗯，香蕉加冰淇淋，顾客一定会喜欢的！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CARELESS_APPRENTICE_2</Tag>
		<English>Brush fires sparked by dry conditions near %s2_city spread to the trade district. The Forge was burned down.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city附近干燥的气候引发的火灾扩散到了商业区，煅造场被彻底烧毁了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_REINFORCED_HULL_1</Tag>
		<English>Our shipmasters have devised a way to reinforce the hulls of our war galleys. This will help with both ramming and being rammed.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的船舶工程师找到了加固三层桨战船船身的新方法，使其在撞击敌舰和遭敌撞击时都更具优势。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NEW_DYNASTY_3</Tag>
		<English>Follow the guidance of spiritual leadership in identifying who enjoys divine favor, then support that claimant.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让宗教领袖决定谁是神所眷顾的新任君主。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TIN_1</Tag>
		<English>Excellent news. Among other things, this will boost our production of bronze.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>好消息，锡是生产青铜的重要原料。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BREAKTHROUGH_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective researchers are rumored to have made a technological breakthrough, rapidly advancing their progress.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据报%s1_civ_adjective科学家在技术上取得突破，使其研究进度快速增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_WATERS_OF_LIFE_1</Tag>
		<English>The Waters of Life, drawn from a certain oasis in %s2_civ_adjective lands, are rumored to be able to cure the sick and heal the injured.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据传%s2_civ_adjective境内的某个绿洲存在一眼能够治病疗伤的“生命之泉”。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_1</Tag>
		<English>Forget these tests. Anything worth knowing has already been discovered, so why risk needless death?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>不必进行临床试验了，我们的医学知识已经够丰富了，何必让宝贵的生命冒无谓的风险？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FARM_BANDITS_3</Tag>
		<English>We are too busy to be bothered. Leave the matter to the local authorities. (Banditry may continue)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们没时间管这烦心事，让当地官员自行处理吧。（匪患可能会继续）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_RUNNING_BULLS</Tag>
		<English>"Running With the Bulls", an annual ritual practiced by the people of %s2_city, is gaining worldwide renown.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city每年一度的“奔牛节”盛典已闻名全世界。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CARELESS_APPRENTICE</Tag>
		<English>A fire has destroyed the Forge in the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一场大火烧毁了%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city的煅造厂。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GOLDEN_BUDDHA</Tag>
		<English>A blacksmith working in the Forge of %s2_city has made a beautiful golden statue of Buddha.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city煅造场的一位工匠制作了一尊美丽的金佛像。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_1</Tag>
		<English>Our brothers in the true %s4_religion_adjective faith who dwell in the %s1_civ_adjective Empire are at war. They lack for vital strategic resources that we have in abundance. This is our chance to come to their aid!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>与我们一样信奉%s4_religion_adjective的%s1_civ_adjective兄弟正处于战争状态。而我们拥有他们所缺乏的重要战略资源，这是我们提供帮助的机会！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HORSE_WHISPERING_DONE</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective stable masters and horse trainers have completed the quest of Horse Whispering!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的驯马师在政府大力支持下胜利完成了“马语者”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PREACHING_RESEARCHER_1</Tag>
		<English>Send the scientist our well wishes.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>向这位学者致以美好的祝愿。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROKEN_DAM</Tag>
		<English>The dam in %s2_city has broken. The city's suburbs are flooded and deaths have been reported.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的大堤发生垮塌。洪水冲入郊区，造成许多人员伤亡。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_WAR_CHARIOTS</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of the War Chariots!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“战车部队”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SETBACK_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective researchers are rumored to have suffered a major setback, slowing their progress.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据报%s1_civ_adjective科学家遭遇重大挫折，使得研究进度放缓。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_LOOTERS</Tag>
		<English>The %s4_civ_adjective city of %s5_city is suffering civil unrest. Riots and looting have broken out.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s4_civ_adjective的%s5_city周边的局势已经失控，骚乱和劫掠事件层出不穷。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRISIS_IN_THE_SENATE_1</Tag>
		<English>Let the senators fight amongst themselves. When both sides are weakened, step in and assert presidential authority.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>任由参议员们互相争斗，等双方都精疲力竭再乘机强化总统的权力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FUEL_ADDITIVES_1</Tag>
		<English>Reduced costs, lower pollution and improved revenues are always welcome news.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>能够节约成本、减少污染并增加收入肯定是好事情。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TEXT_TRADING_COMPANY_CONQUERORS_1</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective Trading Company has established control over South Asian harbors.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective已经控制了南亚的港口。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HOSTILE_TAKEOVER_1</Tag>
		<English>Hostile Takeover[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your corporate leaders to obtain (by any means necessary) our own source of all resource types they need to conduct their operations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“恶意接管”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]我国一家公司请求国家采取行动（通过任何必要的手段）控制其需要的所有资源。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LOOTERS_OTHER_2</Tag>
		<English>Civil unrest near %s4_city has led to riots and looting. Multiple improvements have been destroyed!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s4_city附近发生骚乱和抢掠事件。大量设施遭到破坏！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REFORMATION_COUNTER</Tag>
		<English>Your state religion remains Catholic. Protestantism will only spread to some of your larger cities. You will declare war on all civilizations that decided to convert to Protestantism.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你的官方信仰仍为天主教。新教只会传播至你的一些较大的城市。你将会向所有皈依新教的国家宣战。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_ANCIENT_TEXTS_1</Tag>
		<English>Archaeologists have unearthed a cache of scrolls and stone tablets buried in the desert sands.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>考古学家找到了一批埋藏在沙漠中的卷轴和石板古籍。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SMOKELESS_POWDER_1</Tag>
		<English>The invention of smokeless powder has improved the effectiveness of our muskets on the battlefield.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>无烟火药的发明使我们的火枪手能够更好的发挥战斗力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_THOROUGHBRED</Tag>
		<English>Thoroughbred race horses raised by %s1_civ_adjective breeders have generated extra revenue for their treasury.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective繁育的纯种赛马在世界市场上广受欢迎。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BLESSED_SEA_DONE</Tag>
		<English>%s4_religion_adjective leaders have bestowed grand rewards upon the %s1_civ_adjective people for completing the Quest of the Blessed Sea!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“受祝福的海洋”任务完成了，%s4_religion_adjective的精神领袖为此赐予%s1_civ_adjective人民巨大的奖赏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ANTELOPE</Tag>
		<English>Antelope are thriving in %s1_civ_adjective territory well enough to serve as a new resource.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective境内的羚羊迅速繁育，可以用作新的食物资源。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BLIZZARD_2</Tag>
		<English>Organize and send assistance to help them dig out and to preserve threatened facilities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>派遣救援人员帮助灾民并修复设施。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_DEPRESSION_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]All nations in the world suffer the loss of %d1%% their national treasury.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]所有国家的国库储备均减少%d1%%。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_LABORATORY_1</Tag>
		<English>A scientific breakthrough has occurred at the Laboratory in %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的实验室获得了一项重大科研突破。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WAR_CHARIOTS_1</Tag>
		<English>War Chariots[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your military leaders to train a sizable force of [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Chariots[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“战车部队”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]你的军事将领请求训练足够数量的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]战车[COLOR_REVERT]单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRISIS_IN_THE_SENATE_2</Tag>
		<English>Support the ruling party in impeaching numerous members of the scandalized party, destroying all effective opposition to the ruling party.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>弹劾深陷丑闻的其他党派议员，确立执政党的优势地位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NOBLE_KNIGHTS_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must train %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Lancer[COLOR_REVERT] units.[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if your civilization is operating in the [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Clergy[COLOR_REVERT] civic.[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if your civilization controls [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s2_building[COLOR_REVERT].[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you discover [COLOR_TECH_TEXT]Combined Arms[COLOR_REVERT] without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须训练%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]骑士[COLOR_REVERT]单位。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你的文明实行[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]信仰控制[COLOR_REVERT]法令，将可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你的文明拥有[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s2_building[COLOR_REVERT]，也可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者你在达成目标前获得了训练更先进火器单位的技术（[COLOR_TECH_TEXT]军事制度[COLOR_REVERT]、[COLOR_TECH_TEXT]膛线[COLOR_REVERT]或[COLOR_TECH_TEXT]铁路[COLOR_REVERT]），你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_PROTEST_1_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Lose all nuclear weapons.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]失去全部核武器。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CLUNKER_COAL</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective merchants are offering discounts on tons of their clunker coal, which is filled with impurities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective商人开始倾销劣质煤炭。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TEXT_TRADING_COMPANY_CONQUERORS_2</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective government supports its Trading Company to achieve military control over its South Asian trade routes!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective政府支持它的贸易公司，以实现对南亚贸易路线的军事控制！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TOXCATL_1</Tag>
		<English>This is horrible news. May the heavens be merciful...</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真是可怕的消息，也许是众神在怜悯他……</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BERMUDA_TRIANGLE_1</Tag>
		<English>Our investigations have turned up no worthwhile results? This is most peculiar.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>调查人员没有获得任何有价值的结果？这真是太奇怪了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JAIL_2</Tag>
		<English>Boost jail security and organize a campaign to convince the citizens that they're safe.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>加强监狱的安全措施，并通过媒体进行宣传以使市民们放心。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HORTICULTURE_1</Tag>
		<English>We should establish internal trade with the locals for these rare commodities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该与这个部落开展贸易以获取这种珍奇的商品。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SLAVE_REVOLT_3</Tag>
		<English>Production at %s2_city has been halted temporarily by rebellious slaves.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>由于叛乱的农民，%s2_city的生产已经处于停滞状态！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FAUX_PAS</Tag>
		<English>A faux pas commited by the %s1_civ_adjective ambassador has caused quite a stir in the %s4_civ_adjective Capital.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective大使的失礼行为在%s4_civ_adjective国内引发强烈不满。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_TORNADO_2</Tag>
		<English>An extremely violent weather system filled with powerful tornadoes wrecked our %s8_improvement.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>强烈的飓风摧毁了我们的%s8_improvement。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MONEY_CHANGERS_1</Tag>
		<English>The Market in %s2_city has attracted a number of prominent money changers and is becoming renowned for its dealings involving foreign currency.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的市场聚集了许多资本雄厚的货币兑换商，使那里成为著名的外汇交易中心。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GREED_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective army, in a purely greedy bid for strategic resources, have attacked the %s4:2_civ_adjective and seized control of resources they lacked within their own borders.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的军队出于对战略资源的贪婪，攻击了%s4:2_civ_adjective，并且缴获了自己国境内没有的资源。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_OVERWHELM_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must build %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s2_unit[COLOR_REVERT], %d3 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s4_unit[COLOR_REVERT], %d5 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s6_unit[COLOR_REVERT], and %d7 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s8_unit[COLOR_REVERT] units. A source of [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Oil[COLOR_REVERT] will be required to fuel the planes.[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if your civilization was the one to build [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s9_building[COLOR_REVERT].[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you discover [COLOR_TECH_TEXT]Satellites[COLOR_REVERT] or [COLOR_TECH_TEXT]Superconductors[COLOR_REVERT] without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须建造%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s2_unit[COLOR_REVERT]单位，%d3个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s4_unit[COLOR_REVERT]单位，%d5个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s6_unit[COLOR_REVERT]单位和%d7个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s8_unit[COLOR_REVERT]单位。为给舰载战机补充燃料，必须保证[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]石油[COLOR_REVERT]资源的供应。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你的文明建造了[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s9_building[COLOR_REVERT]，将可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CORPORATE_EXPANSION_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Cha-ching! Show me the money!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>太棒了！让我数数有多少钱。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_OVERWHELM</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of the "Overwhelm Doctrine!"</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“绝对优势”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_INFLUENZA_1</Tag>
		<English>An influenza epidemic has struck hard at the people of %s2_city. Most have fallen ill and many are dying.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city暴发了一场严重的流感，许多人患病死亡。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_OTHER_7</Tag>
		<English>Our %s1_civ_adjective religious brothers have gifted us with [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Uranium[COLOR_REVERT] to aid us in our war effort!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>同我们一样信奉%s1_civ_adjective的兄弟之邦提供了[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]铀[COLOR_REVERT]资源以资助我们的战争！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_REFORMATION</Tag>
		<English>The Reformation has reached the %s1_civ_adjective civilization.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宗教改革的浪潮已经衍生到了%s1_civ_adjective。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ROGUE_STATION</Tag>
		<English>A rogue radio station in the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city is broadcasting propaganda against the ruling party.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city的一家电台发起宣传攻势，鼓动民众反对执政党。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FREEDOMCONCERT_2</Tag>
		<English>Use the money to fund a public service ad campaign for religious freedom and tolerance.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>用筹集的善款建立公益基金，大力宣传信仰自由。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_REFORMATION</Tag>
		<English>The introduction of academic traditions has unleashed a wave of new doctrines. Reformers all over the Catholic world are challenging the authority of the Pope over Christian theology. How shall we react?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>印刷术的发明引发了一场革新教义的浪潮。天主教世界的改革者们正在向教皇的权威发起挑战。我们该如何面对这场风波？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WAR_CHARIOTS_1</Tag>
		<English>Our military commanders wish to prepare for war.[PARAGRAPH:1]If we train enough [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Chariot[COLOR_REVERT] units, we should be able to rout our enemies on the field of battle!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的军事将领希望为战争做好准备。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果我们训练了足够数量的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]战车[COLOR_REVERT]单位，我们就能随心所欲地消灭任何敌人！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WARSHIPS_1</Tag>
		<English>Warships[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by your naval commanders to build a sizable force of [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]War Galleys[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“无敌舰队”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]你的海军将领请求训练足够数量的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]三层桨战船[COLOR_REVERT]单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_GIRLS_BEST_FRIEND_1</Tag>
		<English>Jewelers have successfully launched a tradition of the diamond ring as the gift of choice for wedding proposals.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在珠宝公司的大力宣传下，选择钻戒作为求婚礼物已蔚然成风。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ELITE_SWORDS_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>With such a large force of Swordsmen working together, additional training for these units can be achieved.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该加强对这支强大剑士部队的训练。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WININGMONKS_2</Tag>
		<English>Commit our government to harvesting this new resource immediately.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让政府接手管理这处新资源。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HARBORMASTER_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must construct %d1 [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Wharfs[COLOR_REVERT] in your various coastal cities. You will also have to build %d2 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Caravels[COLOR_REVERT].[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you reach the Industrial Era without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须在沿海城市兴建%d1座[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]港口[COLOR_REVERT]，还要建造%d2个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]轻帆船[COLOR_REVERT]单位。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者当你进入工业时代仍未达成目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CARELESS_APPRENTICE_3</Tag>
		<English>We are too pressed to spare any attention to a small fire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们很忙，没有精力去管一次小小的火灾。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REINFORCED_HULL_1</Tag>
		<English>Our existing ships can also be refitted? Begin immediately.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>现有的战船都可以改装吗？立即着手改装。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FARM_BANDITS</Tag>
		<English>Bandits are wreaking havoc in %s1_civ_adjective farmlands.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>盗匪在%s1_civ_adjective的乡村肆虐。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HARBORMASTER_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have met the goals of your merchant marine and built for them enough ships and docks to empower their plans. Please choose a reward from among the benefits your new trading empire is able to provide to you.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经为拓展海上贸易建造了足够数量的港口和船舶。请在海上贸易可带来的奖励中选择一项。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_2</Tag>
		<English>Offer to send them a large supply of Copper for weapon making.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>向他们提供铜用于制造武器。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_TRUFFLES</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective people are bragging about their truffles, claiming they are the most delicious in the world.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective人声称该国出产的块菌是世界上最美味的食物。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BEST_DEFENSE_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>Now that we are safe, focus on learning what others are planning.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>既然我们已经能够确保自身安全，那就专注于刺探别国的机密吧。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_JADE_1</Tag>
		<English>A rich source of jade has been found amongst the veins of iron at one of our mines.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>工人在一处铁矿脉中发现丰富的玉石原料。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MASTER_BLACKSMITH</Tag>
		<English>The master blacksmith in %s2_city has offered to take on and train multiple apprentices if the government will build new forges for them to operate once their training has been completed.[PARAGRAPH:1]We will need to build enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Forges[COLOR_REVERT] in our cities to accommodate the master's new students.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位煅造大师希望政府建造更多的煅造场，以便为他招收的众多学徒提供良好的训练和工作环境。[PARAGRAPH:1]我们需要建造足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]煅造场[COLOR_REVERT]以接纳大师的新学徒们。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ELECTRIC_COMPANY</Tag>
		<English>Motivated by freedom and quality of life in the %s1_civ_adjective Empire, the power company workers restore electricity outages rapidly, making the citizens there even happier.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>为了满足生活品质日益增长的需求，%s1_civ_adjective电力部门的员工努力扩大能源生产，赢得了市民的赞誉。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANGEL_OF_MERCY_2</Tag>
		<English>We could sanction the hospital as a state holy site. This may please the local populace.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>大力宣传这家神圣的医院，当地居民将因此受益。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_MEDIATOR_OTHER_3</Tag>
		<English>A great mediator has offered to arbitrate our grievance with the %s1_civ_adjective Empire. This opens the door to a possible peace treaty. Do you wish to end the war?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位中立国领袖主动提出调停我们与%s1_civ_adjective之间的争端，这开启了通往和平的大门，您希望结束战争吗？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ROGUE_STATION</Tag>
		<English>A rogue radio station in %s2_city is broadcasting propaganda against our ruling party in an amazing display of impudence.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一家非官方电台发起大规模宣传攻势，鼓动民众反对执政党。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_OVERWHELM_DONE_HELP_3</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]No nuclear weapons.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]禁止核武器。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HERESY_1</Tag>
		<English>Suppress the heresy! Then launch a drive to remind our people that we already adhere to the one true faith.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>镇压异端！让人民了解我们必须尊奉真正的信仰。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FARM_BANDITS_2</Tag>
		<English>Dispatch some of our troops to hunt down these bandits.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>派遣一些部队去围剿这帮强盗。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MOTHER_LODE</Tag>
		<English>Gold miners near the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city have struck the mother lode.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective矿工在%s2_city附近的金矿中找到了主矿脉。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INDUSTRIAL_FIRE_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund an emergency rebuilding effort.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>紧急拨款组织重建。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SLAVE_REVOLT_1</Tag>
		<English>Crack down on the rebels. Put down the revolt. Re-establish order.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>重创叛军。镇压起义。恢复秩序。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HIYOSILVER_1</Tag>
		<English>Prospectors have discovered rich new veins of Silver ore.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>探矿者找到了一处储量丰富的银矿。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BOILERS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective factories are benefitting from a new boiler design, providing a short term rise in their tax revenue.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一种新型锅炉的普及提升了%s1_civ_adjective工业能力，国家税收因而迅速增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SLAVE_REVOLT_WARNING</Tag>
		<English>The slaves of %s2_city are on the verge of revolt!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的奴隶无法继续忍受残酷的压迫！整个社会面临严重危机。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HORSE_WHISPERING_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Use our existing horses as more effective scouts.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>使用现有马匹加强我们的侦察部队。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MODERNOLYMPICS_1</Tag>
		<English>The Games will be a grand spectacle, with athletes from all nations invited to attend!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这届运动会将成为空前的体育盛事，向所有国家的选手发出邀请！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NEWS_IMPACT_CRATER_2</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective geologists have discovered a rich source of [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Uranium[COLOR_REVERT] at what turned out to be a very large and ancient impact crater.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的地质学家在一处巨大的远古陨石撞击坑中发现了储量丰富的[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]铀[COLOR_REVERT]资源。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MIRACLE_2</Tag>
		<English>We should hire and train some of the pilgrims as missionaries.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该在朝圣者中征召和训练一批传教士。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MINING_ACCIDENT</Tag>
		<English>A tragic mining accident near the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city has claimed the lives of hundreds of their miners.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city附近发生一场矿难，造成数以百计的矿工遇难。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INDEPENDENTFILMS_1</Tag>
		<English>That sounds like welcome news for our economy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这个消息有利于我们的经济发展。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LEFT_AT_ALTAR_1</Tag>
		<English>Send condolences to both families and urge them to seek a peaceful resolution to their grievances.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>向双方家族表示遗憾并促请他们用和平的方式化解的怨气。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GUNS_BUTTER_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>With such a large force of arquebusiers working together, additional training for these units can be achieved.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该加强对这支强大火枪手部队的训练。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MARBLE_STATUES_1</Tag>
		<English>Local officials in %s2_city have ordered a large number of marble statues to adorn their public buildings and their forum.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city地方官员订购了许多大理石雕像，用于装饰各大公共建筑和市政广场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LOOTERS_3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Between %d1 and %d2 buildings destroyed in %s3_city</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]%s3_city中的%d1至%d2座建筑被摧毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CLASSIC_LITERATURE_1</Tag>
		<English>Classic Literature[PARAGRAPH:1]You are tasked by our scholars to build enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Libraries[COLOR_REVERT] to hold the newly recorded texts of our ancient stories and oral traditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“经典文学”任务[PARAGRAPH:1]我国的学者请你完成一项任务：建造足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]图书馆[COLOR_REVERT]以保存新近搜集整理的古老文献。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPY_DISCOVERED_1</Tag>
		<English>Be discreet. Offer the to release the spy to their government, but question him first.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>保持谨慎态度。允许将其释放回国，但要先进行审讯。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_COMET_FRAGMENT_1</Tag>
		<English>A comet fragment has crashed to earth in a remote tundra region, obliterating an entire forest and speeding the earth's rotation by two seconds.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一块彗星碎片撞击地球，坠落在寒冷的冻土地带，大片森林被摧毁，还导致地球自转周期加快了2秒钟。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CLASSIC_LITERATURE_DONE_HELP_2</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Receive a random Technology from among Ancient Era techs not yet discovered.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]随机获得一项未被发现的远古时代科技。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MINING_ACCIDENT_2</Tag>
		<English>Send emissaries to assist the bereaved.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>派专人安抚死难者家属。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCC_NO_CITIES</Tag>
		<English>There are no cities that your armies could conquer.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>没有城市可供你的军队征服。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BETTER_COAL_1</Tag>
		<English>Put it to use at our Coal-fueled power plants. Production is power!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在所有使用煤炭的发电站推广这项新技术，产能就是力量！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CHARISMATIC</Tag>
		<English>A charismatic %s1_civ_adjective dictator has risen to control the Party. This strong man is reshaping the government to suit his plans.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位魅力超群的独裁者掌握了%s1_civ_adjective的最高权力，并通过铁腕手段改组政府以实现他的个人野心。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WININGMONKS_1</Tag>
		<English>Monks from the Monastery in %s2_city have grown their private vinyards large enough for them to become nationally significant.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city修道院的僧侣们努力经营葡萄园，那里出产的美酒享誉全国。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FRIENDLY_LOCALS_1</Tag>
		<English>This assistance should help our unit recover its strength.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>当地部落可帮助我们的单位恢复力量。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SEA_TURTLES</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective people are now harvesting sea turtles on an annual basis.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective人开始大量捕捉海龟。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FARM_BANDITS_AGAIN_1</Tag>
		<English>The local authorities of %s2_city are still struggling to control the bandit activity plaguing our farmers.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city地方政府无力阻止横行乡里的强盗。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_THE_PHILISTINES</Tag>
		<English>A massive barbarian uprising is occurring. The Philistines have gathered an army of spearmen and are on the march.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>蛮族开始大举入侵！非利士人集结了庞大的军队，用他们手中的长矛掠夺各个文明国度的财富。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CHARISMATIC_2</Tag>
		<English>Advise him to focus on domestic harmony and stamping out sources of opposition.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>建议他专注于社会和谐，平息一切反对声浪。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FRIENDLY_LOCALS_2</Tag>
		<English>A wounded %s1_civ_adjective unit has received assistance from a small faction who resists the rule of their enemy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>对敌人的压迫心怀不满的当地居民救助了一名受伤的%s1_civ_adjective战士。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SPORTS_LEAGUE_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have met the goals of your sports entrepreneurs and built enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Arenas[COLOR_REVERT] to support viable leagues. Please choose a reward from among the benefits your new national pastimes can provide to you.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经建造了足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]竞技场[COLOR_REVERT]以举办各种城际体育赛事，请在丰富的体育文化可带来的奖励中选择一项。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_RIFLED_CANNON_1</Tag>
		<English>Do we want stronger cannon? Is that a trick question?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们是否需要更强大的加农炮？这个还用问吗？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WAR_CHARIOTS_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>With such a large force of chariots working together, additional training for these units can be achieved.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该加强对这支强大战车部队的训练。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PESTILENCE</Tag>
		<English>Pestilence has struck %s1_civ_adjective agricultural lands.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>瘟疫侵袭%s1_civ_adjective的乡村地区。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ICE_SCULPTURE_2</Tag>
		<English>This is an endeavor worth pursuing. Fund an effort to master this new art form and incorporate it in to the local culture.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>冰雕艺术具有美好的前景，资助这种新兴艺术的创作，发展地方特色文化。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PERSONAL_COMPUTERS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective personal computers, manufactured in %s2_city, are selling in record numbers.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city出产的个人电脑销量大幅增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PARTISANS_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>Receive %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s2_unit[COLOR_REVERT] [NUM1:unit:units] near the ruins of the city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在城市的废墟周围获得%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s2_unit[COLOR_REVERT]单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CIV_GAME_1</Tag>
		<English>Send congratulations to the developers. Our people should enjoy this game.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>向游戏设计师表示祝贺，所有人都应该来体验这款游戏带来的无穷乐趣。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPORTS_LEAGUE_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must build %d1 [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Arenas[COLOR_REVERT] in your cities.[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if you control [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s2_building[COLOR_REVERT] if and when this quest is successfully completed.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you reach the Modern Era without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须在本国城市建造%d1座[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]竞技场[COLOR_REVERT]。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果在达成目标时你的文明已拥有[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s2_building[COLOR_REVERT]，将可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者当你进入信息时代时仍未达成目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CARELESS_APPRENTICE_2</Tag>
		<English>Investigate the cause of the fire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>调查火灾起因。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_THE_VEDIC_ARYANS</Tag>
		<English>A massive barbarian uprising is occurring. The Vedic Aryans seek to plunder the riches of civilization.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>蛮族开始大举入侵！吠陀雅利安人集结了庞大的军队，四出掠夺各个文明国度的财富。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JOYOUS_WEDDING_3</Tag>
		<English>Announce a national celebration, send an outlandish wedding gift and donate generously to religious organizations in the name of the newlyweds.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宣布举国欢庆，送上一份珍奇的礼物，并以这对新人的名义向宗教机构慷慨捐赠。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HARBORMASTER_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Our trade empire should be leveraged in to producing lots of wealth.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用我们的海上贸易霸主地位创造更多的财富。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CHILLY_FLIGHT</Tag>
		<English>A pilot from %s2_city has inspired pride amongst the %s1_civ_adjective people by becoming the first to fly solo over the North Pole.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>来自%s2_city的一位飞行员首次独自飞越北极，这一英雄壮举激发了%s1_civ_adjective人的民族自豪感。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MINING_ACCIDENT_2</Tag>
		<English>A massive explosion has destroyed one of our mines. The cause is unknown, but hundreds are dead.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国的一处矿井毁于不明原因的大爆炸，数百名矿工遇难。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PESTILENCE_1</Tag>
		<English>That's horrible.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>那太可怕了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FASHION</Tag>
		<English>Silk dresses manufactured in %s1_civ_adjective factories have become an extremely popular fashion choice across the region, due in part to radio advertising.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>通过媒体广告的大力宣传，%s1_civ_adjective出产的丝绸服装已成为社会各阶层的流行时尚。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SLAVE_REVOLT_2</Tag>
		<English>The slaves in %s2_city have rebelled against their keepers. The city is in chaos.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的农民反抗其领主。城市正处于混乱之中！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_6</Tag>
		<English>Their vehicles require diesel. Tanks cannot roll without fuel!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>他们需要柴油，坦克没有燃料就无法行动！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_EXPERIENCED_CAPTAIN_2</Tag>
		<English>We should fund an effort to translate his experience into a format that can be passed on to future generations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该拨出专款，让他主持编写海军教材。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FEDERAL_RESERVE_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund a national Federal Reserve Bank to carry out the new policy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>建立联邦储备银行以推行新经济政策。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CONTROVERSIAL_PHILOSOPHER_3</Tag>
		<English>That's one exceptional mind! Sponsor an Academy for him to teach!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真是一位天才思想家！拨款资助他创办一所学院！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TSUNAMI_2_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Up to %d1 buildings destroyed in %s2_city</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]%s2_city共有%d1座建筑物被毁</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HARBORMASTER_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Use our advantage to boost the seamanship of our current and future Naval units</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用所获优势提升现有和未来海军单位的技术水平。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_REACTOR_LEAK_3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Nuclear Plants will become obsolete.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]核电站将被淘汰。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WEDDING_FEUD_1</Tag>
		<English>A politically arranged marriage between one of our noble families and another %s1_civ_adjective family has collapsed over feuding about whether to hold the marriage in their tradition or to make it a %s4_religion_adjective wedding. Tensions are escalating.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国一个贵族世家和另一个%s1_civ_adjective家族之间的一场政治联姻因是否应按%s4_religion_adjective传统进行婚礼而争论不休，紧张局势逐步加剧。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GREAT_BEAST</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective hunters have discovered a great beast lurking near one of their camps.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective某地的猎场附近出现一只巨兽。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SOLO_FLIGHT_1</Tag>
		<English>A daring pilot has successfully flown around the globe in a single person airplane.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位勇敢的飞行员驾驶一架小型单座飞机，胜利完成了首次单人环球飞行。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PARTISANS_HELP_2</Tag>
		<English>Receive %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s2_unit[COLOR_REVERT] [NUM1:unit:units] in our capital city of %s3_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在我们的首都%s3_city获得%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s2_unit[COLOR_REVERT]单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SPY_DISCOVERED</Tag>
		<English>A %s4_civ_adjective infiltrator has been dicovered in the %s1_civ_adjective government.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective政府内部发现了一名潜伏的%s4_civ_adjective间谍。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_EXPERIENCED_CAPTAIN_1</Tag>
		<English>The reputation boost should enhance revenues.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这将提升城市声望并增加收入。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MAN_NAMED_JED_1</Tag>
		<English>We have no time for such nonsense. Order them to continue scouting.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们没时间理会这些鸡毛蒜皮的事情，命令他们继续打猎。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_BLESSED_SEA</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of The Blessed Sea.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“受祝福的海洋”任务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_GUNS_BUTTER_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have trained a large enough force of arquebus units. Please choose your reward.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经训练了足够数量的火枪手。请选择你的奖励。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BEST_DEFENSE_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Use our advantage to help better train our forces.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用所获优势更好地训练我们的军队。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_GREAT_DEPRESSION_1</Tag>
		<English>Corporate fraud within our own [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s11_corporation[COLOR_REVERT] has collapsed the company's stock price, taking the rest of the market down with it and triggering a global economic depression.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s11_corporation[COLOR_REVERT]被揭发存在商业欺诈行为，其股价暴跌，进而导致证券市场疲软，引发全球经济萧条。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CLUNKER_COAL_1</Tag>
		<English>Most of the coal being mined from one of our sites is thick with rock, shale, and other impurities. We are stuck with a source of clunker coal!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>从某个矿井中开采出来的煤炭混有大量泥沙，这种劣质煤炭已经堆积成山！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FEDERAL_RESERVE</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective economists have developed advanced economic theory pertaining to inflation costs.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的经济学家提出了一种有关控制通货膨胀的新理论</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LABORATORY_1</Tag>
		<English>This should speed our current research.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这显然会加快我们目前的科研速度。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CHAMPION_1</Tag>
		<English>Decorate our champions! We shall celebrate their achievement.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>嘉奖冠军部队！祝贺他们取得优异成绩。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_6</Tag>
		<English>Our experiments have been a resounding success! We now posess much better treatments!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国医生的临床试验获得了巨大成功！我们拥有了疗效更好的新药！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FAMINE_2</Tag>
		<English>Famine has struck the city of %s6_city. Our people in %s2_city have enough food on hand to assist their %s1_civ_adjective neighbors. We stand ready to provide aid and comfort.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s6_city发生了严重饥荒。我国的%s2_city的居民有足够的粮食储备来为他们的%s1_civ_adjective邻居提供援助。我们已做好了提供救援的准备。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HURRICANE_1</Tag>
		<English>A powerful hurricane has made a direct hit on %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>特大飓风袭击了%s2_city。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REFORMATION_2</Tag>
		<English>Tolerate the new sects.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>默许新的教义。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BROTHERS_IN_NEED</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective leaders have met with their %s4_civ_adjective %s3_religion_adjective brothers to discuss the possibility of sending them strategic resources to aid in their war effort.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective领袖已与同样信仰%s3_religion_adjective的%s4_civ_adjective领袖会面，讨论是否需要向对方提供战争援助。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_OVERWHELM_1</Tag>
		<English>Our brightest admiral has proposed an amphibious assault strategy designed to capture port cities with lightning strikes.[PARAGRAPH:1]If we construct a large enough aircraft carrier battle fleet, we can bring any coastal city to its knees, making it much easier to attack amphibiously. We need a force large enough to disable all defenses with heavy shore bombardment and soften the defenders by bombing from the air. Then our troops may land on the same day the battle begins and thrust inland against a foe who will be in total disarray.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的海军将领设想了一种通过快速突袭夺取敌方重要港口城市的新型两栖攻击策略。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果我们建立一个强大的航空母舰战斗群，我们就能欲心所欲地控制任何沿海城市。我们需要足够的海空战力，先利用舰炮和飞机进行地毯式的轰炸摧毁敌军防御设施，再发动大规模两栖登陆并迅速深入敌国内陆地区，使其彻底丧失抵抗能力。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PARTISANS_OTHER_2</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective citizens from the city we just razed are fleeing toward their capital and are expected to form Partisan resistance units there!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们摧毁的%s1_civ_adjective的市民向他们的首都撤退，并将组织起新的抵抗军！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_DEFECTING_AGENT_1</Tag>
		<English>That's regrettable. We'll need to review our security procedures.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真是遗憾，我们的安全体系需要进行全面检查。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NEW_DYNASTY_1</Tag>
		<English>Throw support behind the leading general to become the new monarch via coup d'&#233;tat.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>暗中支持一位军事将领发动政变夺取统治权。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CITY_RUINS_ANCIENT_1</Tag>
		<English>Scouts exploring ruins near %s2_city have discovered a cache of knowledge.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>侦察兵在%s2_city附近的废墟中发现了一批秘密资料。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_HORSE_WHISPERING</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of Horse Whispering</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“马语者”任务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CRUSADE</Tag>
		<English>Our war against the %s1:2_civ_adjective continues. Our spiritual leaders cry out for us to wage a crusade to wrest control of %s6_city away from them.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们与%s1:2_civ_adjective的战争仍在继续，最高精神领袖号召发动圣战，从敌人手中夺取圣城%s6_city。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FRIENDLY_LOCALS_3</Tag>
		<English>A pious tribe who believe in mercy have extended religious protection to a wounded unit of %s1_civ_adjective origin.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>虔诚信教、慈悲为怀的当地居民救助了一名受伤的%s1_civ_adjective战士。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_HARBORMASTER</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of the Harbormaster</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“港口主管”任务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_BEST_DEFENSE</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of The Best Defense</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“顶级防御”任务。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WASHED_OUT_1</Tag>
		<English>Floods have washed out the routes near %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>洪水冲毁了%s2_city附近的道路。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MASTER_BLACKSMITH_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Our metalworking empire should be leveraged into producing stronger weaponry.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用我们的冶金王国地位改善武器装备。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HYMNS_AND_SCULPTURES_1</Tag>
		<English>Please grant an audience to this promising new artist so that we may decide how best to make use of their talents.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>会见这位极具潜质的艺术家，我们要最充分地运用其天赋。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_METAL_DECKS_1</Tag>
		<English>Our shipmasters have concluded that switching to steel decks on our carriers instead of wooden decks would be to our advantage.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的船舶工程师决定将航空母舰原本使用的木制甲板改为钢制甲板，以提升其性能。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FARM_BANDITS_1</Tag>
		<English>We need that food. Do whatever it takes to deal with those bandits.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>确保粮食供给，尽一切手段对付盗匪。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CIGARETTE_SMOKER_2</Tag>
		<English>An accident on stage at the Theatre in %s2_city started a fire that burned down the building. Most of the audience escaped alive, thank goodness.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一场意外火灾烧毁了%s2_city的剧场，不过大部分观众都幸运逃生。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_AXE_HAFT_1</Tag>
		<English>Convert our axemen to the new axe handles immediately.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让我们的斧兵换装新式战斧。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_THE_VANDALS</Tag>
		<English>A massive barbarian uprising is occurring. The Vandals strike out against civilization, seeking to claim its prizes with their swords.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>蛮族开始大举入侵！汪达尔人四出袭扰各个文明国度，用他们手中的刀剑掠取财物。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SLAVE_REVOLT_WARNING</Tag>
		<English>Sir, our slaves are on the verge of revolting! As long as our society continues to use slaves, there is a possibility of them revolting!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>阁下，我国的奴隶无法继续忍受残酷的压迫！如果我们继续实行奴隶制度，有发生大规模奴隶暴动的危险！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEALING_PLANT_4</Tag>
		<English>In their attempts to find the right mixture of herbs, our healers caused fatalities throughout the empire!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国医生为了寻找正确的草药配方进行了大规模临床试验，结果酿成了一场可怕的灾难！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPICY_2</Tag>
		<English>Commit our government to harvesting this new resource immediately.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>让当地政府大量收购这种新香料。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JOYOUS_WEDDING_OTHER_1</Tag>
		<English>A %s5_religion_adjective wedding between one of our citizens and one from the %s1_civ_adjective Empire has drawn no protest from them, and in fact little interest at all. Some family members of the newlyweds are griping but the incident appears to have passed without much bitterness.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>通过一场%s5_religion_adjective传统婚礼，一位我国显贵和一位%s1_civ_adjective人结为夫妇。他们的行为没有遭到反对，但也没得到关注。尽管两位新人的亲属对此颇有微词，但一切毕竟还算是比较顺利。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FREEDOMCONCERT_1</Tag>
		<English>Musical artists from across our nation have gathered in %s2_city to raise money and awareness for the cause of religious freedom.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>全国各地的音乐家齐聚%s2_city，参加为推进信仰自由而举办的慈善募捐晚会。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SALES_TAXES</Tag>
		<English>The taxes from these sales should nicely boost our coffers.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>征收商业税充实国库。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_GREED_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! Your Greed is unmatched! You have managed to wrest control of the coveted %s1_civ_adjective [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s9_resource[COLOR_REVERT] resource! Your generals are already expanding their military planning.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你贪婪的欲望得到了满足！你夺取了%s1_civ_adjective的[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]%s9_resource[COLOR_REVERT]资源！你的将军们已经开始研究扩军方案！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MIRACLE_1</Tag>
		<English>The tourism will enhance city revenue.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>旅游业的兴盛增加了城市收入。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REFORMATION_TOLERATE</Tag>
		<English>Protestantism can spread to your cities and even replace Catholicism.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>新教会传播至你的城市，甚至取代天主教。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SPOILED_GRAIN</Tag>
		<English>Vermin got in to the granary in %s2_city. All the food stored there was ruined.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的粮仓发生虫害，失去了全部粮食储备。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GREAT_DEPRESSION</Tag>
		<English>Corporate fraud within %s6_corporation, headquartered in the %s1_civ_adjective Empire, has collapsed the company's stock price, taking the rest of the market down with it and triggering a global economic depression.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>总部设在%s1_civ_adjective境内的%s6_corporation近日被揭露存在商业欺诈行为，其股价暴跌，进而导致证券市场疲软，引发全球经济萧条。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BARDS_TALE_1</Tag>
		<English>We are glad to see that the local culture is thriving.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们很高兴看到当地文化的繁荣。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HOLY_MOUNTAIN_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have located the Holy Mountain and extended your cultural influence over the sacred site!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经找到了圣山并将本国文化扩展到了这片圣地！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INFLUENZA_2</Tag>
		<English>If only we had knowledge of Medicine!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该加强医学研究！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WHALEOFATHING_1</Tag>
		<English>That sounds like welcome news for our economy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这个消息有利于我们的经济发展。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_WEDDING_FEUD</Tag>
		<English>Nobles from a %s4_civ_adjective family are angry with their new %s1_civ_adjective inlaws for holding a %s3_religion_adjective wedding against their wishes. This event has drawn great interest within these nations as feuding has broken out over the dispute.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一个%s4_civ_adjective的贵族世家对他们的%s1_civ_adjective亲家表示非常愤怒，因为按%s3_religion_adjective传统举行的婚礼违背了他们的意愿。这件事引起了极大的关注，一场争端因此而引发。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_DUSTBOWL_1</Tag>
		<English>Excessive tilling of the soil on the open plains has caused massive wind erosion and created a dustbowl effect, complete with dust storms.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>人们在平原地区的过度开垦造成严重的沙尘暴，导致土地日渐贫瘠。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_7</Tag>
		<English>Anything for our brothers in need. There is no limit to our support.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>他们有任何需要，我们都可以无限供应！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_PROTEST_1</Tag>
		<English>The people's wishes are our top priority. We will disband our nuclear weapons.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>人民的意志是国家的最高准则，让我们全面销毁核武器。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_VOLCANO_2</Tag>
		<English>The earth has spewed forth lava and ash from a previously dormant volcano near the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city附近，一座休眠火山突然猛烈喷发。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_EARTHDAY_1</Tag>
		<English>Enshrine the day as a national holiday.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>将地球日定为国家假日。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_DUSTBOWL_CONT_1</Tag>
		<English>The dustbowl effect continues. Another of our Farms has been wiped out by soil loss and by farmers abandoning their steads.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>随着沙漠化进程的加剧，昔日肥沃的农田变成了荒地。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INTERSTATE_EFFECT</Tag>
		<English>All Roads on flatland will be replaced by Highways.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>平地上的所有道路都将被公路取代。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CRISIS_IN_THE_SENATE</Tag>
		<English>Scandal has thrown the %s1_civ_adjective senate in to chaos. A constitutional crisis has emerged. Yet this also opens the door to political reforms.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective参议院深陷政治丑闻的泥潭，导致了一场宪法危机，政治革新之门由此开启。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CHARISMATIC_1</Tag>
		<English>A stronger, more charismatic dictator has seized control of the Party and the nation!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位强悍而魅力超群的独裁者掌握了党和国家的最高权力！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_WARSHIPS_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have built the world's largest combat navy. Please choose your reward.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经拥有了全世界最强大的海军。请选择你的奖励。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_PESTILENCE_4</Tag>
		<English>A plague of locusts have swarmed over a Plantation near %s2_city, destroying all the crops there.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>蝗灾席卷在%s2_city附近的种植园，导致大量经济作物被毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ELITE_SWORDS_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective people have trained the largest force of Swordsman units. Advisors across the known world are wondering if their civilizations will survive long enough to see what lies beyond the sword.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective建立了一支强大的剑士部队，各国统治者都在担心自己的文明恐怕无法存活到“刀剑之上”的时代。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SUBWAY_1</Tag>
		<English>This is a model for the entire world to follow! Great work.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真全世界的楷模！干得好。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PASTURE_BUILT_1</Tag>
		<English>Send them our thanks.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>向他们致以真诚的感谢。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_JADE</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective merchants are now selling jade carvings in small quantities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective商人开始销售用玉石雕刻的艺术品</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PARTISANS_1</Tag>
		<English>Send word to the new partisan units to continue the fight near their destroyed homes.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>给游击队们带去口信，告诉他们继续在被毁的城市周围抗击敌人。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HOLY_MOUNTAIN_REVEALED_1</Tag>
		<English>You have built enough religious buildings for your religious leaders to solve the puzzle and identify the correct location of the Holy Mountain. Settle near that location to complete the quest!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你已经建成足够数量的宗教建筑，你的宗教领袖将能并最终确定圣山的位置了。在那附近建立城市以完成这个任务吧！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BETTER_COAL</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective scientists have developed better ways of processing coal fuel.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的科学家发明了更先进的煤炭深加工技术。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_PASTURE_BUILT</Tag>
		<English>Industrious villagers near our city of %s2_city have built a Pasture.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s2_city附近，勤劳的当地村民新建了一个大牧场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FAVORITE_SON</Tag>
		<English>A %s1_civ_adjective gladiator from %s2_city has become a local hero and an inspiration.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位%s1_civ_adjective角斗士以其英勇无畏的气概赢得了%s2_city居民的赞赏和尊敬。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HOLY_MOUNTAIN_1</Tag>
		<English>Our religious leaders believe our people can earn the blessings of the deity if we can reclaim the Holy Mountain![PARAGRAPH:1]They have studied the scriptures with an eye toward locating the holy mountain. They have so far not found it anywhere within our lands and believe that it must lie elsewhere. More study will be needed if we are to identify the sacred location.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宗教领袖相信：如果将遥远的圣山纳入我国版图，人民将会得到神灵的眷顾！[PARAGRAPH:1]宗教领袖对提及圣山位置的经文进行了研究。他们未能在我国境内找到圣山，它应该位于世界的其他地方。如果我们想要找到那个地方，就需要对经文进行更多的研究。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INFLUENZA_1</Tag>
		<English>Spend whatever is necessary to quarrantine the city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>采取一切必要措施控制疫情。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANCIENTOLYMPICS_HELP_2</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Receive a %D1 diplomatic boost with all your close neighbors</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]与邻国的外交关系%D1</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BROTHERS_IN_NEED_5</Tag>
		<English>War Elephants are what they need. Send in the jumbos!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>他们需要战象，我们送一批过去！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HOLY_RITUAL_1</Tag>
		<English>Fill the order!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>批准订购！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_TOWER_SHIELD_1</Tag>
		<English>Invention of the tower shield has provided our foot soldiers with some protection against archers.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>塔盾的发明使我们的步兵能够有效地防御弓箭。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_IMPEACHMENT</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective President is facing impeachment.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的总统面临弹劾。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REFORMATION_1</Tag>
		<English>Embrace the Reformation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>皈依新教。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HOSTILE_TAKEOVER_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have completed the quest of Hostile Takeover and enabled %s11_corporation to turn extra profit.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经完成了“恶意接管”任务，使%s11_corporation能够创造更多的利润。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_BERMUDA_TRIANGLE_1</Tag>
		<English>On a sunny day, with no storms in sight, one of our vessels has been lost at sea. Not only is the cause unknown, but there is no trace whatsoever of the ship or its crew or cargo. Several smaller vessels and some airplanes in the same general region also have vanished without a trace. Rumors are flying concerning this mystery. This region has been dubbed by the press as the Bermuda Triangle, named after a small island nearby.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一艘轮船在风平浪静的晴朗天气神秘地消失于海面。人们找不到船只、人员和货物的任何踪迹。也曾有其它较小的船只和飞机在此海域神秘失踪。围绕这一神秘现象的谣言不胫而走、愈传愈盛，该海域也因附近的一座岛屿被媒体称为“百慕大三角”。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CONTROVERSIAL_PHILOSOPHER_1</Tag>
		<English>We won't tolerate such heresy. Send him into exile!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们不能容忍异端邪说，立即将他驱逐出境！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BLESSED_SEA_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Receive a Temple improvement in all cities with five population or more, where your State Religion is present.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在人口规模5级以上且信奉国教的城市赠送神庙。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_RIFLED_CANNON_1</Tag>
		<English>Our knowledge of rifled barrels has been successfully applied to new cannon designs.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的新型加农炮成功应用了线膛炮管技术。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_UNIT_AT_THE_SWORD</Tag>
		<English>Heroes of the Sword</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>战争英雄</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CIGARETTE_SMOKER_3</Tag>
		<English>We are too pressed to spare any attention to a fire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们太忙了，没空理会这场小火灾。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CRAB_CAKES_1</Tag>
		<English>Crab cakes prepared in our cities have become enormously popular across the region.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们城市生产的蟹肉饼在各地广受欢迎。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_LITERACY_1</Tag>
		<English>Our citizenry enjoys virtually universal literacy. This achievement is bound to pay off in unexpected ways.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们已经成功普及了基础教育，这一成就将带来长远而深刻的社会影响。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TOO_CLOSE_TO_CALL_1</Tag>
		<English>Let the court case take its course, even if the judges seem to split their vote along a purely partisan basis. Follow the constitution to its letter, even though the outcome appears to come down to which party in the dispute had more supporters on the bench.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>进入司法程序，即便法官都难以保证中间立场。遵守宪法条文，即便选举结果仅能代表法官的意志。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRUSADE_DONE_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Add %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s2_unit[COLOR_REVERT] [NUM1:defender:defenders] to %s3_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]%s2_unit[COLOR_REVERT]单位加入%s3_city的防御。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FREEDOMCONCERT</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective Empire has donated funds raised at a charity event to the cause of religious freedom.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective举办了一场旨在推进信仰自由的慈善募捐活动。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BLESSED_SEA_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Establish your religion in a number of your cities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>将你的宗教信仰传播到多座本国城市。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_IMPACT_CRATER_1</Tag>
		<English>Researchers have discovered a large incidence of naturally formed glass globules in an area around a wide circular valley.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>科学家在一处巨大的环形山谷中发现了大量天然玻璃球。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAUX_PAS_1</Tag>
		<English>This gaffe has adversely affected our relations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这一过失对双边关系产生了负面影响。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAVORITE_SON_2</Tag>
		<English>Arrange for him to be matched against easy opponents and see that his legend increases.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>给他安排好打的对手，确保他的传奇永远延续。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_CLASSIC_LITERATURE_DONE</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ scholars have successfully recorded all of their oral traditions and stories in to a new compendium of literature, thereby completing the quest of Classic Literature!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ学者对本民族的口头传说故事进行了全面的记录和整理，从而胜利完成了“经典文学”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_AIRLINER_CRASH_1</Tag>
		<English>Allow their recovery teams unfettered access to the crash site.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>允许他们的救援队自由前往现场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_INDEPENDENTFILMS_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1%F2 in %s3_city</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]%s3_city%D1%F2</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CARELESS_APPRENTICE_1</Tag>
		<English>Organize a rebuilding effort.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>立即组织重建。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_LEFT_AT_ALTAR_2</Tag>
		<English>Two prominent families, one from our people and one from the %s1_civ_adjective Empire, are feuding over their children. A groom, from our family, jilted his would-be bride by walking his cold feet right on out of the temple, insulting and outraging his would-be inlaws.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>两个显赫的贵族世家，一个来自我国，另一个来自%s1_civ_adjective，正为他们的孩子而发生激烈冲突。由于新郎在教堂中突然抛弃新娘独自逃走，严重激怒了对方家族。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SLAVE_REVOLT_AGAIN</Tag>
		<English>The slaves in %s2_city are still in revolt. Local authorities are bumbling the crackdown.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的农民仍在暴动。地方当局已经无法控制形势！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_SPY_DISCOVERED_3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Receive %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT][NUM1:Tank:Tanks][COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]获得%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]坦克[COLOR_REVERT]单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_AT_THE_SWORD_1</Tag>
		<English>Soldiers from our victorious %s3_unit have rallied behind their combat heroes! Their strength and resolve have firmed! Their proficiency has increased!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>战无不胜的%s3_unit部队的战士们聚集在战争英雄麾下！他们的力量和勇气在燃烧！他们的战争经验大大提升！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_GREAT_BEAST_3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]%D1[ICON_HAPPY] in all cities with %F3_religion for %d2 [NUM2:turn:turns].</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]所有信仰%F3_religion的城市%D1[ICON_HAPPY]，持续%d2回合。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_MARATHON_1</Tag>
		<English>A brave and hardy soldier has run over twenty-six miles on foot to warn of the invasion!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一名勇敢而坚强的战士徒步奔跑了26英里，带回敌人入侵的警讯！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CIV_GAME_2</Tag>
		<English>This game seems to have great educational potential. Suggest that it be used in our educational system.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这款游戏的内容非常有教育意义，建议在我们的教育系统中推广应用！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEROIC_GESTURE_OTHER_3</Tag>
		<English>A heroic gesture of mercy by your forces in regard to %s1_civ_adjective wounded has opened the door to a possible peace treaty. Do you wish to end the war?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你的军队对俘获的%s1_civ_adjective伤兵的崇高善意开启了通向和平的大门，你希望结束战争吗？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_COMET_FRAGMENT</Tag>
		<English>A comet fragment has struck the earth in a remote tundra region, obliterating a whole forest. %s1_civ_adjective scientists are scrambling like mad to learn more about potential threats posed to our planet by other rogue heavenly bodies: comets, asteroids, meteors, and whatever else may be lurking out there.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一块彗星碎片撞击地球，坠落在寒冷的冻土地带，大片森林被摧毁。%s1_civ_adjective的科学家们正在紧张地研究各种对对地球构成潜在威胁的天体，包括彗星、小行星及流星。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FARM_BANDITS_3</Tag>
		<English>We may need to take action against thieves in %s2_city who are preying upon our farmers.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们要对在%s2_city猖狂肆虐的盗匪采取行动。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_ELITE_SWORDS_1</Tag>
		<English>Our military commanders wish to prepare for war.[PARAGRAPH:1]If we train enough [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Swordsman[COLOR_REVERT] units, we should be able to rout our enemies on the field of battle!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的军事将领希望为战争做好准备。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果我们训练了足够数量的[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]剑士[COLOR_REVERT]单位，我们就能随心所欲地消灭任何敌人！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MOTOR_OIL</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective chemists have developed an advanced refinement process for motor oil.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的化学家改进了润滑油的提炼方法。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SPORTS_LEAGUE</Tag>
		<English>Our cultural advisors believe that our nation could benefit from city-based sports franchises if we built enough [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Arenas[COLOR_REVERT] to support national sports leagues.[PARAGRAPH:1]Each major city would require its own facility in which its teams could play.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的文化顾问认为：应该建造足够数量的[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]竞技场[COLOR_REVERT]供国家体育联合会举办城际体育赛事。[PARAGRAPH:1]每座主要城市都应该拥有自己的大型体育设施以便实行主客场赛制。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_NUCLEAR_REACTOR_LEAK_1</Tag>
		<English>Radiation leaks have been discovered in the reactor of the Nuclear Plant in %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s2_city的核电站反应堆中发现了辐射泄漏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WEDDING_FEUD_3</Tag>
		<English>Announce a national celebration, send an outlandish wedding gift and donate generously to our religious organizations in the name of the newlyweds. This is likely going to trigger war!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宣布举国欢庆，送上最珍奇的礼物并以新人的名义向我们的宗教机构慷慨解囊。但这可能会引发战争！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_NUCLEAR_PROTEST</Tag>
		<English>News reports indicate massive %s1_civ_adjective protests over the country's nuclear weapons stockpile.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据报%s1_civ_adjective的民众举行大规模抗议活动，反对本国政府加强核军备。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_GUNS_BUTTER</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of "Guns not Butter!"</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“要火枪不要黄油”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_GOLDEN_BUDDHA</Tag>
		<English>A blacksmith from %s2_city has made a beautiful golden Buddha statue at his Forge.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的一位工匠制作了一尊美丽的金佛像。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_NEW_DYNASTY_1</Tag>
		<English>The old dynasty has died out! No more hereditary heirs remain to claim the throne!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>古老的王朝宣告灭亡！没有留下合法继承者！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_HEROIC_GESTURE_1</Tag>
		<English>No good deed shall go unpunished. Send our recovered soldiers back into battle the moment they are ready.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>高姿态并不能逃避惩罚，让伤愈士兵尽快返回战场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_ANTIMONARCHISTS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective antimonarchists are protesting, saying that the religious institutions don't have enough power compared to the King.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的一些宗教人士发动示威抗议君主专制，要求提高教会的地位以制衡国王的权力。 </Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BARDS_TALE_2</Tag>
		<English>Fund the writing of a play that revolves around this ballad, to be performed at the local Theatre.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>出资将这首民谣改编为歌剧，并在当地的剧场演出。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ANCIENTOLYMPICS_2</Tag>
		<English>These Games are grand! We should invite and sponsor athletes from neighboring civilizations to attend.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>真是一场盛大的赛事！我们应该邀请邻近文明参加进来。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_DEFECTING_AGENT</Tag>
		<English>A high-ranking %s1_civ_adjective intelligence agent has defected to the %s4_civ_adjective government.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的一名高级特工叛变投靠了%s4_civ_adjective的情报部门。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_BREAKTHROUGH_2</Tag>
		<English>Discoveries made by the %s1_civ_adjective Empire have boosted progress on their current research project.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的最新发现使他们在现有研究项目上取得突破。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_CHAMPION_1</Tag>
		<English>Our military leaders have held internal war games to strengthen our training and grit. One unit has emerged as the champion.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的指挥官通过组织内部兵棋推演强化作战能力，其中一支部队最终赢得冠军。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_OVERWHELM_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Congratulations! You have built a powerful Aircraft Carrier battle fleet capable of conquering enemy cities in a single attack. A force capable of executing the Overwhelm Doctrine is now yours to command. Please choose your reward.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祝贺你！你已经建立了一个强大的航空母舰战斗群，能够作为推行“绝对优势”战略的利器，向敌国城市发动毁灭性的海空打击。请选择你的奖励。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WEDDING_FEUD_3_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]%D1[COLOR_REVERT] relations boost with all %F2_religion leaders</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]所有信仰%F2_religion的领袖态度[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]%D1[COLOR_REVERT]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_LEFT_AT_ALTAR_3</Tag>
		<English>An %s1_civ_adjective industrial heiress has been left at the altar by one of our prominent business tycoons, who had proposed marriage to her. The fiasco has outraged the families on both sides, who are now feuding over the collapsed marriage.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一家%s1_civ_adjective企业的女继承人被一位向她求婚的我国商业大亨抛弃在婚礼的圣坛上。这场可怕的意外使双方家族都非常愤怒，不断彼此指责。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REFORMATION_TOLERATE_STATE</Tag>
		<English>Your state religion remains Catholic. Protestantism can spread to your cities and even replace Catholicism.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你的官方信仰仍然为天主教。但新教会传播至你的城市，甚至取代天主教。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_HEROIC_GESTURE_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective forces have unexpectedly shown mercy and compassion for our wounded, tending them on the battlefield and then returning the survivors safely to us.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective军队对俘获的我国伤兵显示了出乎意料的仁慈，为他们提供救助并安全送还我方。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_EARTHDAY_HELP_2</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Persuade other nations to convert to [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Public Welfare[COLOR_REVERT] (at least one civilization must have the ability to do so).</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]说服其他文明实行[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]绿色经济[COLOR_REVERT]（至少要有一个文明已达成相应前提条件）。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_SOLO_FLIGHT</Tag>
		<English>A daring %s1_civ_adjective pilot is the first to fly solo around the world, lifting spirits across the globe and winning admiration from all of humanity.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位勇敢的%s1_civ_adjective飞行员首次完成了单人环球飞行，他的英雄壮举赢得了全世界的赞誉。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_FARM_BANDITS_1</Tag>
		<English>Farmers outside %s2_city are complaining of bandits robbing them regularly.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city附近的农民因盗匪肆虐而苦不堪言。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ELECTRIC_COMPANY_1</Tag>
		<English>Freedom is the best motivator. We are lucky to have workers like these, who keep the power flowing to our citizenry.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>自由的环境是最好的工作激励，我们很高兴拥有这样爱岗敬业的电力工人。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_RURAL_FARMERS_1</Tag>
		<English>Enterprising %s1_civ_adjective grocers in %s2_city have struck a deal to import surplus food from rural farmers outside the normal range of city business.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective%s2_city的杂货商与远郊区的农民签订了粮食收购协议。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FOREST_FIRE_1</Tag>
		<English>Organize a replanting effort.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>重新植树造林。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_VOLCANO_1</Tag>
		<English>A volcano has erupted near %s2_city, spewing deadly ash clouds, lava flows, and mud- and debris-filled snow melts.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city附近的火山突然喷发，炽热的火山灰云将天空完全遮蔽。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_LOOTERS_1</Tag>
		<English>There is civil unrest near the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s6_city. Our scouts in the area tell us there may be an opportunity to aggravate the situation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的%s6_city周边的局势已经失控。我们派往该处的间谍提议乘机采取行动。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_MASTER_SMITH</Tag>
		<English>A grand master blacksmith has overseen improvements to the Forge in the %s1_civ_adjective city of %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在%s1_civ_adjective的%s2_city，一位煅造大师改进了熔炉设计。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TEA_OTHER_1</Tag>
		<English>Tea exports to %s1_civ_adjective customers have provided a nice boost to our relations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>对%s1_civ_adjective的茶叶出口增进了我们之间的关系。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_RUNNING_BULLS_1</Tag>
		<English>We are glad to see that the local culture is thriving.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们很高兴看到当地文化的繁荣。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUCLEAR_REACTOR_LEAK_3</Tag>
		<English>This shows that nuclear energy is too dangerous for our society. Make plans to transition out of nuclear power as soon as possible.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这表明核能对我们的社会太危险了。尽快制定退出核电的计划。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LOOTERS_2</Tag>
		<English>See that aid reaches those organizing local criminal activity. Be discrete.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>向当地的犯罪组织提供协助，要注意小心行事。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_FAIL_CLASSIC_LITERATURE</Tag>
		<English>You have failed the quest of Classic Literature.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你没能完成“经典文学”任务！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_OVERWHELM_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Our intent is to keep the peace through strength. Leverage our might in to commercial opportunity.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>通过武力威慑确保和平，利用我们的制海权控制世界贸易。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_EXPERIENCED_CAPTAIN_1</Tag>
		<English>A retiring captain from one of our most elite naval vessels has pledged his wisdom and abilities toward shipbuilding at the drydock in %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我国海军一位曾经叱咤风云的退休舰长请求到%s2_city的干船坞工作，继续发挥他的才干。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WARSHIPS_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Leverage our dominance of the sea to better protect our trade routes.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用我们的制海权加强对商路的保护。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_DUSTBOWL</Tag>
		<English>Excessive farming with poor techniques has led to soil erosion and a dustbowl effect in the %s1_civ_adjective Empire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>由于低劣的技术和过度的耕种，%s1_civ_adjective境内出现水土流失和土地沙化现象。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_NUCLEAR_REACTOR_LEAK_AGAIN_1</Tag>
		<English>Our inspectors are still reporting radiation leaks in the Nuclear Plant in %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的检查人员仍在报告 %s2_city 的核电站发生辐射泄漏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_PASTURE_BUILT</Tag>
		<English>Industrious villagers have built a Pasture in %s1_civ_adjective lands.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective某地勤劳的村民新建了一个大牧场。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_WARSHIPS_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The %s1_civ_adjective people have trained the largest fleet of warships. Advisors across the known world whisper of their fears that this fleet will dominate the seas for centuries to come.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective建立了全世界最强大的海军。各国统治者都在担心这支无敌舰队将长期称霸海洋。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NOBLE_KNIGHTS_DONE_3</Tag>
		<English>From among our most faithful lancers emerges one with holy vision.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位信仰坚定的骑士以其英雄壮举被人们尊为“圣骑士”。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_IMMIGRANTS</Tag>
		<English>Immigrants are flowing to %s2_city inspired by stories of its culture!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city悠久的历史文化吸引了许多新移民前往定居！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_FIRING_PINS_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective Grenadier units have been issued more effective explosives: bombs that do not need a fuse.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的掷弹兵开始装备不需要导火线的新式手榴弹。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CRUSADE_DONE_HELP_2</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Build [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s1_building[COLOR_REVERT] in %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]在%s2_city建成[COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]%s1_building[COLOR_REVERT]。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_AXE_HAFT_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective craftsmen have improved the design of their axe manufacturing. These are the finest axes in the world.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的工匠改进了斧柄设计，制造出全世界最精良的战斧。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_RUNNING_BULLS_1</Tag>
		<English>The people of %s2_city have launched a popular new tradition called "Running With the Bulls."</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的“奔牛节”成为广受欢迎的传统娱乐项目。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_LONG_RANGE_FIGHTERS_1</Tag>
		<English>Begin production of the new fighter.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>立即投产新型战斗机。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_VOLCANO_1_HELP</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]Suffer loss of plot improvements near the eruption</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]火山附近的区域设施被摧毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_ICE_SCULPTURE_1</Tag>
		<English>An artist in the frozen tundra near %s2_city has perfected a means of crafting beautiful ice sculptures.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一位艺术家在%s2_city附近的冰天雪地中完善了制作美丽冰雕作品的方法。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_ELITE_SWORDS_DONE_2</Tag>
		<English>Our monarch will establish an institution that will enable current and future troops to obtain additional training.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们的君主将建立一所军事学院，加强对所有现役和新建部队的训练。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_STAINED_GLASS</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective stained glass sales are booming.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective的彩色玻璃销售量大幅增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_HOLY_MOUNTAIN_DONE</Tag>
		<English>The faithful %s3_religion_adjective people are inspired by the divine providence of the %s1_civ_adjective Empire for completing the Quest of the Holy Mountain!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s1_civ_adjective人民在神的指引下找到了圣山，虔诚的%s3_religion_adjective信众因而备受鼓舞。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_WAR_CHARIOTS_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[PARAGRAPH:1]To complete this quest, you must train %d1 [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Chariot[COLOR_REVERT] [NUM1:unit:units]. A source of Horses will be required.[PARAGRAPH:1]An additional reward option will be available if your civilization has a state religion.[PARAGRAPH:1]You will fail this quest if a rival civilization completes it first, or if you arrive at the Classical Era without having met the conditions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[PARAGRAPH:1]要完成这项任务，你必须训练%d1个[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]战车[COLOR_REVERT]单位，这需要拥有马匹资源。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果你的国家设立了官方信仰，将可以获得一个额外奖励选项。[PARAGRAPH:1]如果其他文明率先达成目标，或者当你进入古典时代仍未达成目标，你的任务将宣告失败。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CIGARETTE_SMOKER_2</Tag>
		<English>Investigate the cause of the fire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>调查火灾起因。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_REFORMATION_3</Tag>
		<English>Join the Counter-Reformation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>加入反宗教改革的阵营。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BARDS_TALE_3</Tag>
		<English>See that the artist is given a recording contract.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>建议唱片公司与这位艺术家签约。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_INDUSTRIAL_FIRE</Tag>
		<English>An industrial accident started a fire that gutted the Factory in %s2_city.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一次事故引发的火灾摧毁了%s2_city的工厂.</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_JAIL</Tag>
		<English>The citizens of %s2_city are worried about their safety because of the city's Jail.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的市民为当地监狱的安全状况感到担忧。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_MONEY_CHANGERS_1</Tag>
		<English>These dealings in foreign currency increase the Market's profitability? That is welcome news.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>活跃的外汇交易将增加市场的收益？真是个好消息。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_BREAKTHROUGH_1</Tag>
		<English>Good job, knowledge is power!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>干得好，知识就是力量！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_JAIL</Tag>
		<English>People of %s2_city are not feeling safe. They are worried that criminals may escape from the local Jail.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_city的市民缺乏安全感，他们担心在当地监狱里服刑的犯人可能越狱。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_THE_PHILISTINES_HELP_1</Tag>
		<English>[ICON_BULLET]A dangerous number of barbarian [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Spearman[COLOR_REVERT] units have spawned near our border.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[ICON_BULLET]大量蛮族[COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]矛兵[COLOR_REVERT]出现在我国边境地区。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_OVERWHELM_DONE_1</Tag>
		<English>Take advantage of our momentum to provide additional training for these crews. Prepare them for battle.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>我们应该加强对这支强大海军的训练，随时准备投入战斗。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_CIGARETTE_SMOKER_1</Tag>
		<English>Organize a rebuilding effort.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>立即组织重建。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_NUM_BUILDINGS_DESTROYED</Tag>
		<English>%d1 %s2_civ_adjective [NUM1:building has:buildings have] been destroyed in %s3_city</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2_civ_adjective的%s3_city中的%d1座建筑被摧毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENT_TRIGGER_SEA_TURTLES_1</Tag>
		<English>The locals have figured out the mating cycles of the sea turtles who flock to the shore in massive quantities. They have begun to harvest the turtles and eggs, in a way that does not endanger the long term survival of the creatures.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>滨海居民发现了海龟的洄游规律，特定季节会有大量海龟在沙滩上聚集。人们在那时大量捕捉海龟并收获海龟蛋，当然以不影响该物种的长期生存为基础。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_EVENTTRIGGER_STRONGER_FITTINGS_1</Tag>
		<English>%s1_civ_adjective Crossbow units are rumored to be carrying improved weapons. Specifics on how or why their bows are stronger remains a mystery.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>据报%s1_civ_adjective军队开始装备新式劲弩，这种强大武器的技术细节被严格保密。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
