<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Civ4GameText>
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HANDICAP_HEIR_HELP</Tag>
		<English>The Heir difficulty is the right level for beginners. Your cities receive additional happiness and your research, unit production and upkeep costs are lower than those of your AI opponents.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>王储难度适合初学者。你们的城市获得了额外的快乐，你们的研究、单位生产和维护成本比你们的人工智能对手要低。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HANDICAP_PARAGON</Tag>
		<English>Paragon</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>神级（Paragon）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HANDICAP_PARAGON_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Can you beat this game on this level and prove that you are truly a Paragon? Compared to Emperor, your AI adversaries will receive even more unit production and research advantages.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你能在这个水平上击败这场比赛并证明你真的是一个神级选手吗？与皇帝相比，你的人工智能对手将获得更多的单位生产和研究优势。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HANDICAP_REGENT_HELP</Tag>
		<English>As a Regent, you are facing a fairly balanced challenge and are evenly matched in terms of modifiers with your AI adversaries.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>作为摄政者，你面临着一个相当平衡的挑战，并且在修改器方面与你的人工智能对手是平衡的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HANDICAP_VICEROY</Tag>
		<English>Viceroy</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>总督(Viceroy)</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HANDICAP_MONARCH_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Monarch players play under the same conditions as Regents, but will face more formidable AI opponents.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>国王级（Monarch），挑战难度从此开始急剧增加了。维修费更高了，研发也更慢了，你的人民也更难取悦，你的电脑对手们显然更加聪明了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HANDICAP_EMPEROR_HELP</Tag>
		<English>The Emperor level is for experienced players. You will play under significant research, unit production, upkeep and happiness penalties, while the AI receives even more advantages in these areas.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你准备好做个皇帝了？如果是这样的话，你需要战胜发展比你快而且更具侵略性的对手，同时还要面对难以取悦和满足的民众。这个级别真的是对文明专家级玩家们的考验。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HANDICAP_REGENT</Tag>
		<English>Regent</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>摄政(Regent)</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HANDICAP_HEIR</Tag>
		<English>Heir</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>王储（Heir）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
