<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Civ4GameText>
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_69</Tag>
		<English>The number of National Wonders and Great Wonders that can be built in a city is limited by its culture level.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一个城市能够建造的民族奇观和世界奇观的数量受到其文化水平的限制。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_30</Tag>
		<English>Naval Units performing "Blockade" Missions prevent all enemy trade from passing within their blockading range. Making sure an enemy city is within that range is a sure-fire way to stop enemy trade routes.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>执行“封锁”任务的海军部队阻止所有敌方贸易进入其封锁范围。确保敌人的城市在这个范围内是阻止敌人贸易路线的一种可靠的火力方法。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_78</Tag>
		<English>Cities no longer just lose one population when captured. Large cities can lose additional population, especially if you decide to sack them.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一些主要文明有第二个独特的单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_23</Tag>
		<English>In Rhye's and Fall of Civilization, many wonder effects have been changed</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，许多奇迹的影响已经改变了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_29</Tag>
		<English>Intercontinental trade routes now yield more gold than normal trade routes. Build a Customs House to further cash in.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>洲际贸易路线现在比正常贸易路线产出更多的黄金。建一个海关以进一步兑现。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_20</Tag>
		<English>In Rhye's and Fall of Civilization, city founding is not allowed in tundra, ice or desert if far from water.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，如果远离水的话，苔原、冰原或沙漠是不允许建立城市的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_6</Tag>
		<English>The civilization you choose to play affects your difficulty every bit as much as the difficulty level you choose. Make sure to pick a civ that suits your playing style and your level of expertise.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你选择玩的文明程度会影响你的难度和你选择的难度等级。一定要选择一个适合你的风格和你的水平的文明。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_56</Tag>
		<English>Religions spread faster in regions where they were historically present. In some regions religions can only spread if they are the state religion of the owner.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宗教在历史上存在的地区传播得更快。在某些地区，宗教只有在它是所有者的国教时才能传播。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_6</Tag>
		<English>Pagan Temples cannot be built in cities that have a religion, and when a religion spreads to a city with a Pagan Temple, it is replaced by that religion's temple instead.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>异教徒庙宇不能建在有宗教的城市里，当一种宗教传播到有异教徒庙宇的城市时，它就会被该宗教的庙宇所取代。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_29</Tag>
		<English>Defeating Native units on your territory while using Slavery has a chance to create a slave unit.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在使用奴隶制度的时候击败你领土上的原住民有机会创造一个奴隶单位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_16</Tag>
		<English>In Dawn of Civilization, many wonders have religion or civic prerequisites to encourage their historical distribution.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，许多奇迹都有宗教或政体的先决条件来鼓励它们的历史分布。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_44</Tag>
		<English>Instead of spreading their culture in rings with every new culture level, cities spread cultural control over individual tiles as their culture grows.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>城市没有在每一个新的文化层次上把他们的文化传播成环状，而是随着文化的发展，把文化控制力分散到各个瓷砖上。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_52</Tag>
		<English>Spy specialists have been removed. Instead, global spy experience is accumulated similar to military experience. If the bar is full, your most experienced spy becomes a Great Spy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>间谍专家已被撤职。相反，全球间谍经验的积累与军事经验类似。如果间谍点数槽满了，你最有经验的间谍就会成为一个大间谍。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_75</Tag>
		<English>The late game has been expanded: the last technologies in the tech tree are more expensive to research, but also provide more content in the form of additional buildings and projects as well as the ability to build satellites.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>后期的游戏已得到扩展：科技树中的最新科技研究成本更高，但还可以通过其他建筑物和项目以及建造卫星的能力提供更多内容。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_67</Tag>
		<English>Bad health from power is multiplied by the number of buildings that consume power.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>电力造成的健康不良会乘以消耗电力的建筑物的数量。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_30</Tag>
		<English>Acquire slaves to build slave plantations or settle them in your cities. This option is only available in North America or in Africa unless your capital is in Africa.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>获得奴隶来建造奴隶种植园或在你们的城市定居。此选项仅在北美或非洲可用，除非您的首都在非洲。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_36</Tag>
		<English>The Tamil, Moorish, Tibetan, Polish and Congolese civilizations can be configured not to appear in every game. Edit the XML\GlobalDefinesAlt.xml file.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>泰米尔、摩尔、西藏、波兰和刚果的文明可以配置为不出现在每一个游戏中。编辑XML\GlobalDefinesAlt.XML文件。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_27</Tag>
		<English>When on the defense, be sure to set your Fighters and Jet Fighters to the "Intercept" mission when they're not running missions. They will defend the skies from opposing Air Units, earning them valuable experience points.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>当你处于防守状态时，确保你的战斗机和喷气式战斗机在不执行任务的情况下执行“拦截”任务。他们将保护天空免受敌方空军的攻击，为他们赢得宝贵的经验值。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_25</Tag>
		<English>Good things come to spies who wait. Leaving a spy on a tile will reduce the costs of all Espionage Missions performed against objects in that tile. So leaving a Spy in an enemy city will make your Missions in that city significantly cheaper.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>等待的间谍会得到好处。将间谍留在一个地块上将减少对该地块中执行的所有间谍任务的成本。所以把间谍留在敌人的城市会使你在那个城市的任务难度大大降低。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_1</Tag>
		<English>AI Mongols receive additional armies to attack Russia and the Middle East. Be prepared!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>电脑控制的蒙古人将得到额外的军队攻击俄罗斯和中东。准备好了！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_9</Tag>
		<English>You need to discover Exploration before you can train settlers on other continents than your capital's.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你需要先发现地理探索科技，然后才能在首都以外的其他大陆训练定居者。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_1</Tag>
		<English>You can check the parameters influencing your stability in the Financial Advisor</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>您可以在财务顾问栏中检查影响您稳定性的参数</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_37</Tag>
		<English>The Polynesian civilization is intended for the human player only. You can enable it for the AI in XML\GlobalDefinesAlt.xml, however its AI will not be geared towards playing successfully or realistically.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>波利尼西亚文明只为人类玩家设计。您可以在XML\GlobalDefinesAlt.XML中为人工智能启用它，但是它的人工智能不适合成功或真实地游玩。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_48</Tag>
		<English>A purple circle marks the next tile to be culturally covered in the city screen.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>城市屏幕上一个紫色的圆圈标志着下一个将会被文化覆盖的地块。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_4</Tag>
		<English>In Dawn of Civilization, free technology effects like the Oracle only allow you to choose technologies of your current or earlier eras.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，像神谕宣示所这样的免费科技效果只允许你选择当前或更早时代的技术。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_12</Tag>
		<English>Combining Totalitarianism and Constitution isn't a good idea.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>把极权主义和宪法结合起来不是个好主意。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_61</Tag>
		<English>Siege units are now much more expensive, but their increased withdrawal chance also makes them less expendable.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>攻城单位现在要贵得多，但是他们增加的撤退机会也使他们的消耗量减少。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_25</Tag>
		<English>Confused about the expansion and civic stability rules? Look them up under the Concepts section in the Civilopedia!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>对扩张和政体稳定规则感到困惑？在文明百科的概念部分中查找它们！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_3</Tag>
		<English>Not every lake produces 2 food. Some are salt lakes, and thus produce 1 food, like coast.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>不是每个水域地块都能产两个食物。有些是咸水水域，因此产生1个食物，如海岸。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_</Tag>
		<English></English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese></Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_10</Tag>
		<English>You can't see the current year until you discover calendar.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在发现历法之前，您无法看到当前年份。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_15</Tag>
		<English>To attract a corporation, acquire more of its resources, build associated buildings, or adopt the Free Enterprise civic.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>吸引公司，获取更多资源，建造相关建筑，或采用自由市场政体</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_2</Tag>
		<English>Discovering Microbiology will keep you safe from plagues</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>发现微生物学可以让你远离瘟疫</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_19</Tag>
		<English>In Rhye's and Fall of Civilization, camera flying mode hotkey has changed to [CTRL + F]</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，相机飞行模式热键已更改为[CTRL+F]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_68</Tag>
		<English>Enemy workers cannot be captured unless enabled by a civic.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>除非有政体的支持，否则敌人的工人是不能被俘虏的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_11</Tag>
		<English>Remember that you can always take control of a newborn civ if you don't like the civilization you started with. You can also use this feature to play from 3000BC even when you want to pick a civ that starts later on.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>记住，如果你不喜欢你开始的文明，你总是可以控制一个新生的文明。您也可以使用此功能从公元前3000年开始游玩，即使您想选择以后开始游玩的文明。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_34</Tag>
		<English>The core of several civilisations expands on certain conditions, such as entering a new era.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>几个文明的核心在某些条件下扩展，例如进入一个新时代。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_46</Tag>
		<English>City culture will never expand beyond the third ring.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>城市文化绝不会扩展到三环以外。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_35</Tag>
		<English>Short on gold? Send your spies to steal from your neighbors!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>黄金短缺？派你的间谍去偷你邻居的东西！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_31</Tag>
		<English>The game is won when a Spaceship arrives on Alpha Centauri, not when it is launched. The more Engines and Thrusters you build, the faster the Spaceship will arrive.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>当宇宙飞船到达半人马座阿尔法星时，而不是当它发射时，游戏就赢了。你制造的发动机和推进器越多，宇宙飞船到达的速度就越快。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_38</Tag>
		<English>Watch your stability level closely. Depending on your situation, it can increase or decrease after significant game events. If your civilisation is collapsing and your stability does not improve until the next check, it will collapse!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>仔细观察你的稳定性度。根据你的情况，它可以在重大游戏事件后增加或减少。如果你的文明的稳定度处于“崩溃中”，而你的稳定在下一次检查之前没有改善，它就会崩溃！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_8</Tag>
		<English>You need to discover Exploration before you can vassalize far away civilizations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你需要先发现地理探索科技，然后才能将遥远的文明附庸。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_21</Tag>
		<English>Dawn of Civilization is still actively developed. You can get the latest bugfixes and additions by using the Git version of the mod. Visit the forum under http://forums.civfanatics.com/forumdisplay.php?f=452 to find out how.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>文明的曙光仍在积极发展。您可以通过使用Git版本的mod获得最新的错误修复和添加。访问论坛http://forums.civfanatics.com/forumdisplay.php？f=452来找出原因。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_72</Tag>
		<English>Some units are stronger in open terrain. Tiles that are flat, have no features with defensive bonuses, and do not contain a city or fort count as open terrain.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>有些单位在开阔的地形上更强大。平坦的地貌，没有防御加值的特征，并且不包含城市或堡垒，被视为开放地形。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_10</Tag>
		<English>In Dawn of Civilization, military units cannot be killed by the plague, only weakened.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，军队不能被瘟疫杀死，只能被削弱。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_17</Tag>
		<English>If you like the mod, and if you have any ideas to improve it, or you just have a bug to report, make sure to check out the development forum at CivFanatics.com.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>如果你喜欢mod，如果你有任何改进的想法，或者你只是有一个bug要报告，一定要查看CivFanatics.com上的开发论坛。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_54</Tag>
		<English>Civic combinations with positive or negative effects on stability are highlighted in the civics advisor.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>政体顾问中强调了对稳定性有正面或负面影响的城市组合。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_28</Tag>
		<English>During wartime, your ships may sever all naval trade routes entering an enemy city by using the "Blockade" Mission within range of the opposing metropolis. Using a Privateer to blockade a city during peace time will even allow you to plunder gold from your enemy's treasury!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在战时，你的船可能会切断所有进入敌方城市的海上贸易路线，在敌方城市范围内执行“封锁”任务。在和平时期用私人船封锁一座城市甚至可以让你从敌人的宝库里掠夺黄金！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_22</Tag>
		<English>If you attempt to stop the growth of newborn civs, some of your units will flip to their side.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>如果你试图阻止新生文明的崛起，你的一些单位会倒戈。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_24</Tag>
		<English>Train a persecutor to remove non-state religions from your cities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>训练宗教审判官将非国教宗教从你们的城市中移除。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_13</Tag>
		<English>Corporation headquarters and executives have been removed, corporations spread on their own if the prerequisites are met.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>公司总部和高管已经被移除，如果满足了先决条件，公司将自行扩张。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_42</Tag>
		<English>In DoC, Ocean tiles start out yielding no food. Improvements on Ocean tiles require Compass, but in turn provide one additional food.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在DoC中，海洋地块开始不产生食物。在海洋地块修建设施需要罗盘科技，但反过来又提供了一个额外的食物。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_47</Tag>
		<English>The amount of culture required for the next tile to be covered is displayed as tick marks on the culture bar in the city screen.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在城市屏幕的文化栏上，将要覆盖下一个地块所需的文化量显示为刻度线。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_23</Tag>
		<English>The amount of cultures that Great Artists can generate using Great Works depends on the game era.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>大艺术家能用巨作创造多少文化取决于游戏时代。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_76</Tag>
		<English>To win the Space Victory, you now have to construct a permanent base on Mars, instead of sending a colony ship to Alpha Centauri</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>为了赢得太空胜利，你现在必须在火星上建立一个永久性的基地，而不是把殖民地飞船送到半人马座阿尔法星。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_65</Tag>
		<English>City defense now also protects against collateral damage: unit strength can never be reduced below the current defense modifier.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>城市防御现在也可以防止附带伤害：单位强度永远不能降低到低于当前防御修正值。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_16</Tag>
		<English>In Rhye's and Fall of Civilization, vassal states are enabled by the discovery of Contract.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，附庸关系需要点出契约精神科技。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_34</Tag>
		<English>Keep some spies in your borders for counter-espionage. Enemy spies can wreak havoc!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在你的边境保留一些间谍进行反间谍活动。敌人的间谍会造成严重破坏！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_77</Tag>
		<English>When capturing a city, you now have the additional options to sack or spare it. More gold can be plundered in sacked cities, at the cost of more severe building damage and unrest. Sparing cities reduces unrest and building damage but instead costs money.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>太空竞赛已经变得更加详细：需要许多项目来实现太空胜利，而每一个项目都会给完成它们的第一个文明带来额外的利益。 与太空胜利无关的几个项目也与对太空竞赛的投资相互配合。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_80</Tag>
		<English>You can use a settler to immediately construct buildings in a city. This will give all buildings that a new city would receive for free when founded.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你可以使用一个移民立即在一个城市建造建筑物。这将提供一个新城市建成后将免费获得的所有建筑。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_40</Tag>
		<English>Rival civilizations led by computer opponents now pose a more significant threat from the sea. Stronger fleets, amphibious invasions... Don't be caught unprepared! The more warlike leaders can be very sneaky with their attack plans, as they have learned to think beyond the sword.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>以计算机对手为首的敌对文明现在构成了来自海洋的更大威胁。更强大的舰队，两栖入侵……别措手不及！越是好战的领导者，他们的攻击计划就越狡猾，因为他们已经学会了用剑以外的思维。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_26</Tag>
		<English>The soundtracks you hear during the Classical, Medieval and Renaissance eras depend on your state religion.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你在古典、中世纪和文艺复兴时期听到的原声取决于你的国教。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_33</Tag>
		<English>The area certain civilisations flip on spawn is not always identical to their core. Several civilizations can flip larger areas.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>某些文明在出生时翻转的区域并不总是与其核心相同。几个文明可以翻转更大的区域。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_39</Tag>
		<English>Stability checks are triggered by a variety of events including discovering techs, changing civics and losing or acquiring cities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>稳定性检查是由各种各样的事件触发的，包括发现技术，改变公民和失去或收购城市。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_5</Tag>
		<English>Plague can spread in many ways - through trade routes, along roads and between neighbouring cities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>瘟疫可以通过多种途径传播——通过贸易路线、公路和邻近城市之间传播。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_71</Tag>
		<English>Mounted units have been split into Light Cavalry and Heavy Cavalry.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>骑兵单位分为轻骑兵和重骑兵。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_40</Tag>
		<English>Golden Ages protect you from most negative effects of being unstable. The protection only lasts as long as the Golden Age, however.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>黄金时期保护你免受不稳定的负面影响。然而，这种保护只持续到黄金时代。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_8</Tag>
		<English>You can declare war on independent states and minor civs only by moving your units into their territory.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你可以向独立国家和小型文明宣战，只需把你的部队转移到他们的领土上。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_26</Tag>
		<English>If you spend more Espionage Points than an opponent, then your missions towards that opponent will be cheaper. Every point you spend throughout the game is added towards this total, so if you see a fierce rival outspending you in Espionage Points, it would be wise to increase your Espionage spending.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>如果你比对手花费更多的间谍点数，那么你对对手的任务将更便宜。你在整个游戏中花费的每一分都会加到这个总数上，所以如果你看到一个劲敌在间谍点数上超过了你，那么增加你的间谍花费是明智的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_53</Tag>
		<English>If you have problems with game performance in the late game, enabling graphics paging in the BUG menu can help on some machines.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>如果您在游戏后期遇到游戏性能问题，在BUG菜单中启用图形分页可以帮助某些设备。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_62</Tag>
		<English>Instead of starting with no religion, each civilisation starts with its own specific pagan religion. These religions do not have any of the benefits of major religions, however.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>每个文明不是从没有宗教开始的，而是从自己特定的异教徒宗教开始的。然而，这些宗教没有任何主要宗教的好处。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_18</Tag>
		<English>If it's been a while since the last time you got an updated version of the mod, make sure to check CivFanatics.com for a new version. The mod is in active development, and updates are uploaded often. Every update is full of fixes and new features.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>如果你已经有一段时间没有得到更新版本的mod了，一定要在CivFanatics.com上找到一个新版本。我们正在积极开发中，经常有更新被上传。每个更新都充满了修复和新功能。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_31</Tag>
		<English>If you run Slavery or Colonialism, you can trade slaves when interacting with other civilizations in the diplomacy interface.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>如果你经营奴隶制度或殖民主义，你可以在与其他文明的外交交往中交换奴隶。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_37</Tag>
		<English>Random events are tied to what is happening within your civilization. If you want to experience all of the events that are possible, you will have to play numerous games using different approaches and strategies: war and peace, different religious approaches, different technological paths, different civics and more!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>随机事件与你们文明中正在发生的事情联系在一起。如果你想体验所有可能发生的事件，你将不得不用不同的方法和策略玩很多游戏：战争与和平，不同的宗教方法，不同的技术途径，不同的文明等等！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_60</Tag>
		<English>The last two eras are now called the Global and Digital eras.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>最后两个时代现在被称为全球化时代和数字化时代。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_51</Tag>
		<English>Spies can now accumulate experience and acquire promotions by successfully completing missions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>间谍现在可以通过成功完成任务来积累经验和获得晋升。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_11</Tag>
		<English>Related religions like Hinduism and Buddhism or Confucianism and Taoism don't create unhappiness if one of them is your state religion</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>相关联的宗教，如印度教和佛教或儒教，如果其中一个是你的国教，就不会产生不快乐</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_64</Tag>
		<English>Units lose all their promotions when upgraded. A portion of the experience earned is refunded, depending on the strength difference between the previous and current unit type.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>单位升级后会失去所有的晋升。所获经验的一部分将退还，这取决于以前和当前单位类型之间的战斗力差异。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_18</Tag>
		<English>In Dawn of Civilization, vassals do not have to give up tile control to their masters in the first ring around their cities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，附庸不必在城市周围的第一圈把控制权交给他们的主人。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_66</Tag>
		<English>Entering enemy waters consumes all remaining movement points.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>进入敌方水域消耗所有剩余的移动点。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_28</Tag>
		<English>Cities on islands of size five or less also act as improvements for the resource they are founded on, yielding the full production and commerce increase for the city tile.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>五个或以下地块岛屿上的城市也可以作为设施利用其所建立的资源，使城市地块的产能和商业得到充分的增长。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_49</Tag>
		<English>A Great Statesman can put an end to war or anarchy, improve diplomatic relations, build an Administrative Center or reform your civics for free.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一个大政治家可以结束战争或无政府状态，改善外交关系，建立一个行政中心或免费改革你的政体。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_7</Tag>
		<English>In Dawn of Civilization, civilisations can respawn in historically appropriate time periods, even before Nationalism has been discovered.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，文明可以在历史上适当的时期重生，甚至在民族主义被发现之前。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_9</Tag>
		<English>Combining certain civics will improve or harm the stability of your empire.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>某些政体组合将改善或损害你的帝国的稳定。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_74</Tag>
		<English>Resources now only supply a limited number of cities with happiness or health. Acquire additional instances of a resource to keep your growing empire supplied!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>现在，资源只能为有限数量的城市带来幸福或健康。 获取更多的资源，以保持您不断发展的帝国！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_70</Tag>
		<English>Many classical wonders can only be built with no state religion in cities without any religions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在没有宗教的城市中，只有没有国教才能建立许多古典奇观。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_33</Tag>
		<English>Use the Submarine's stealth along with its ability to carry conventional and tactical nuclear missiles to launch a devastating opening attack on another landmass.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用潜艇的隐身能力以及携带常规和战术核导弹的能力，对另一块陆地发动毁灭性的开放式攻击。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_73</Tag>
		<English>In addition to discovering the associated technology, to found a religion you also need to control a city in its historical core region.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>除了发现相关的科技，要发现一个宗教，你还需要控制这个宗教历史核心区域的一个城市。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_14</Tag>
		<English>In Rhye's and Fall of Civilization, movement through ocean tiles costs ½ a movement point.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，穿越海洋瓦片的移动需要半个移动点。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_13</Tag>
		<English>In Rhye's and Fall of Civilization, vassals can declare war.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，附庸国可以宣战。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_50</Tag>
		<English>Oases provide more food and less commerce. It is also possible to build Cottages on Oases.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>绿洲提供更多的食物和更少的商业。在绿洲上建小屋也是可能的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_59</Tag>
		<English>Dawn of Civilization features a completely new tech tree, consisting of 141 technologies spread over 7 eras.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>文明的曙光拥有一棵全新的科技树，由遍布7个时代的141项科技组成。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_20</Tag>
		<English>Areas that are relevant to your UHV are displayed in light blue in the tile tooltip.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>与历史胜利相关的区域在平铺工具提示中显示为浅蓝色。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_7</Tag>
		<English>Every civ has hidden modifiers that influence their growth. This way, modern civs are not disadvantaged by their late start.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>每个文明都有隐藏的修正，影响他们的成长。这样，现代文明就不会因为起步晚而处于不利地位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_58</Tag>
		<English>Only proselytizing religions, that is Buddhism, Christianity and Islam, can be spread by missionaries in civilizations with a different state religion.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>传教士只能在不同国家宗教的文明中传播传教宗教，即佛教、基督教和伊斯兰教。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_3</Tag>
		<English>Several AI civilizations flip larger areas on spawn to help them along.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>几个计算机文明在出生时翻转更大的区域来帮助它们前进。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_12</Tag>
		<English>Related religions like Hinduism and Buddhism or Confucianism and Taoism create reduced diplomacy penalties</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>印度教、佛教、儒教等相关联的宗教减少了外交惩罚</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_24</Tag>
		<English>Never attack a city with only siege weapons. They may be the best way to damage a large number of enemy units, but once they inflict their maximum amount of damage, they will be unable to attack enemy units.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>不要只用攻城武器攻击城市。它们可能是破坏大量敌军的最佳方式，但一旦造成最大程度的破坏，就无法攻击敌军。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_41</Tag>
		<English>DoC adds a new terrain feature, Rainforests. They resemble Jungles, but cause no unhealthiness and can be improved after the discovery of Alloys.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>DoC增加了一个新的地形特征，雨林。它们类似于丛林，但不会造成不健康，在发现合金科技后可以在其上修建设施。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_32</Tag>
		<English>Your Fighters can intercept multiple enemy planes per turn, but become less effective at it as they get damage, so take care to repair your defensive planes.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你的战斗机可以每回合拦截多架敌机，但当它们受到伤害时，效果会降低，所以要注意修理你的防御机。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_14</Tag>
		<English>The Silk Route and Trading Company corporations can only spread in historically appropriate regions.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>丝绸之路和贸易公司只能在历史上合适的地区进行扩张。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_17</Tag>
		<English>Researching Academia as a Catholic civilization starts the Reformation, prompting all Catholic civilizations to decide if they want to convert to Protestantism.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>天主教文明研究完成学术精神科技将会开始改革，促使所有天主教文明决定是否要皈依新教。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_27</Tag>
		<English>AI Romans and Greeks will receive armies to conquer the Mediterranean and Mesopotamia. Be prepared!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>计算机控制的罗马和希腊人将接受军队征服地中海和美索不达米亚。准备好了！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_57</Tag>
		<English>There is a chance that an existing religion disappears when a new religion spreads to a city. Religions can also disappear when too many of them are present, especially in smaller cities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>当一个新的宗教传播到一个城市时，一个现存的宗教有可能消失。宗教也会在宗教太多的时候消失，特别是在小城市。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_63</Tag>
		<English>The presence of non-state religions causes unhappiness in your cities, unless you adopt the Tolerance civic.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>非国教宗教的存在会导致你们城市的不幸福，除非你们采取求同存异的政体态度。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_21</Tag>
		<English>In Rhye's and Fall of Civilization, jungle, rainforest and marshes are impassable to most land units.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，丛林、雨林和沼泽对大多数陆地单位来说都是无法逾越的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_32</Tag>
		<English>Tribal villages are placed randomly at the beginning of the game.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>部落村庄在游戏开始时是随机放置的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_38</Tag>
		<English>You may be wise to keep some reserve gold in your treasury. You never know when your savings may help mitigate the effects of a disastrous event or grant you access to additional opportunities when a positive event rolls around.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>你最好把一些储备黄金放在你的金库里。你永远不知道什么时候你的储蓄可能有助于减轻灾难性事件的影响，或者在积极事件发生时给你提供更多的机会。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_15</Tag>
		<English>In Rhye's and Fall of Civilization, the max income from a shrine is 20 gold per turn.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，圣迹的最大收入是每回合20金币。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_2</Tag>
		<English>In Dawn of Civilization, several civilizations like Byzantium, Italy and Thailand have conditional spawns, and don't appear in every game.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在文明的曙光中，像拜占庭、意大利和泰国这样的几个文明都有出现的条件，并没有出现在每一局游戏中。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_55</Tag>
		<English>Religions spread gradually from around cities where the religion is already present. The presence of religious buildings increases the spread range.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宗教逐渐从宗教已经存在的城市周围传播开来。宗教建筑的存在增加了传播范围。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_4</Tag>
		<English>If you get a skull over your cities, it means they have the plague! The population and units in the city and in the surrounding region will probably decrease dramatically. To reduce the effects and the duration of plague, keep your cities healthy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>如果你在你的城市发现一个头骨符号，那就意味着他们有瘟疫！城市和周边地区的人口和单位可能会急剧减少。为了减少瘟疫的影响和持续时间，保持你们城市的健康。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_22</Tag>
		<English>Catholicism is founded by the Great Schism, which occurs when more than half of all Orthodox cities fall outside of the control of Orthodox civilisations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>天主教是由大分裂建立的，当超过一半的东正教城市不受东正教文明的控制时，就会发生大分裂。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_36</Tag>
		<English>Mounted units cause flanking damage to certain Siege weapons. For example, all Cannons in an enemy stack are damaged if an attacking Cavalry unit survives the battle!</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>骑兵对某些攻城武器造成迂回攻击。例如，如果一支进攻骑兵部队在战斗中幸存下来，那么敌军堆栈中的所有大炮都会受到损坏！</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_19</Tag>
		<English>When a UHV goal asks to control a civilization, you need to own more cities in their core than they do.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>当一个历史胜利目标要求控制一个文明，你需要拥有在他们的核心比他们更多的城市。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_43</Tag>
		<English>Islands are a new maritime terrain feature that provides additional production, tile defense and faster culture spread.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>岛屿是一个新的海洋地形特征，提供额外的产能，地块防御和更快的文化传播。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_39</Tag>
		<English>A negative event that afflicts one of your rivals is, in effect, like a positive event for you! Keep an eye on the world news reports in case an event happening to other nations opens new opportunities for you.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>一个消极的事件，折磨你的竞争对手之一，实际上，就像一个积极的事件为你！留意世界新闻报道，以防其他国家发生的事件为你打开新的机会。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_5</Tag>
		<English>If you're playing as a Western European civilization, build a Trading Company to expand to Africa or Asia.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>如果你是在扮演西欧文明的角色，那就建立一家贸易公司，将业务扩展到非洲或亚洲。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_45</Tag>
		<English>The amount of culture needed to cover a tile depends on its terrain type and features, as well as the distance to cities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>覆盖地块所需的文化量取决于其地形类型和特征，以及与城市的距离。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_35</Tag>
		<English>The stability and flip zone maps for all civilizations can be found in the Maps folder.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>所有文明的稳定性和翻转区域地图都可以在“地图”文件夹中找到。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_DOC_79</Tag>
		<English>Cities cannot be instantly razed anymore. After ordering a city to be razed, it will lose population each turn while in unrest, and finally be destroyed when the population reaches zero.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>城市不能马上被夷为平地。命令摧毁城市后，它在动乱中每经过一个回合就会失去人口，最后在人口达到零时被摧毁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
