<?xml version='1.0' encoding='GBK'?>
<Civ4GameText>
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_MILLET</Tag>
		<English>Millet</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>粟子</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_RUBBER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In its native Central America and South America, rubber has been collected for a long time. The Mesoamerican civilizations used rubber mostly from Castilla elastica. The Ancient Mesoamericans had a ball game using rubber balls, and a few Pre-Columbian rubber balls have been found (always in sites that were flooded under fresh water), the earliest dating to about 1600 BC. According to Bernal D铆az del Castillo, the Spanish Conquistadores were so astounded by the vigorous bouncing of the rubber balls of the Aztecs that they wondered if the balls were enchanted by evil spirits. The Maya also made a type of temporary rubber shoe by dipping their feet into a latex mixture. Rubber was used in various other contexts, such as strips to hold stone and metal tools to wooden handles, and padding for the tool handles. While the ancient Mesoamericans did not have vulcanization, they developed organic methods of processing the rubber with similar results, mixing the raw latex with various saps and juices of other vines, particularly Ipomoea alba, a species of Morning glory. In Brazil, the natives understood the use of rubber to make water-resistant cloth. A story says that the first European to return to Portugal from Brazil with samples of such water-repellent rubberised cloth so shocked people that he was brought to court on the charge of witchcraft.[PARAGRAPH:1]When samples of rubber first arrived in England, it was observed by Joseph Priestley, in 1770, that a piece of the material was extremely good for rubbing out pencil marks on paper.[PARAGRAPH:1]The para rubber tree initially grew in South America, where it was the main source of what limited amount of latex rubber was consumed during much of the 19th century. About 100 years ago, the Congo Free State in Africa was a significant source of natural rubber latex, mostly gathered by forced labor. The Congo Free State was forged and ruled as a personal colony by the Belgian King Leopold II where millions of Africans died as a result of lust for rubber and rubber profits. After repeated efforts rubber was successfully cultivated in Southeast Asia, where it is now widely grown.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[TAB]在其原产的中美洲和南美洲，橡胶已经被收集了很长时间。中美洲文明使用的橡胶主要来自卡斯蒂利亚弹性体。古代的中美洲人有一种使用橡皮球的球类游戏，并且发现了一些前哥伦布时代的橡胶球（总是在被淡水淹没的地方），最早的可以追溯到公元前1600年。根据贝尔纳德尔卡斯蒂略的说法，西班牙征服者对阿兹台克人的橡皮球的剧烈弹跳感到非常震惊，以至于他们怀疑这些球是否被恶魔附身。玛雅人还将脚浸入乳胶混合物中，制成了一种临时胶鞋。橡胶也被用于其他各种场合，比如把石头和金属工具固定在木把手上的条带，以及工具手柄的衬垫。虽然古代中美洲人没有硫化，但他们发展出有机方法加工橡胶，结果相似，将生胶乳与其他藤本植物的各种汁液和汁液混合，特别是牵牛花的一种。在巴西，当地人懂得用橡胶制作防水布。有个故事说，第一个从巴西带着这种防水橡胶布样品返回葡萄牙的欧洲人震惊了人们，他被以巫术罪名告上法庭[段落：1]1770年，约瑟夫・普里斯特利（Joseph Priestley）首次发现橡胶样品时，一块材料非常适合在纸上擦去铅笔的痕迹[段落：1]准橡胶树最初生长在南美洲，在19世纪的大部分时间里，它是消耗有限量乳胶的主要来源。大约100年前，非洲的刚果自由邦是天然胶乳的重要来源，大部分是通过强迫劳动收集的。刚果自由国家是由比利时国王利奥波德二世（Leopold II）打造和统治的个人殖民地，那里数百万非洲人死于对橡胶和橡胶利润的贪欲。经过反复的努力，橡胶在东南亚地区得到了成功的种植，现在在那里广泛种植。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_JADE</Tag>
		<English>Jade</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>翡翠</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_COTTON</Tag>
		<English>Cotton</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>棉花</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_MILLET_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The cultivation of common millet as the earliest dry crop in East Asia has been attributed to its resistance to drought, and this has been suggested to have aided its spread. Asian varieties of millet made their way from China to the Black Sea region of Europe by 5000 BCE.[PARAGRAPH:2]Millet was growing wild in Greece as early as 3000 BCE, and bulk storage containers for millet have been found from the Late Bronze Age in Macedonia and northern Greece. Hesiod describes that "the beards grow round the millet, which men sow in summer."[25][26] And millet is listed along with wheat in the third century BCE by Theophrastus in his "Enquiry into Plants".[PARAGRAPH:2]Pearl millet is one of the two major crops in the semiarid, impoverished, less fertile agriculture regions of Africa and southeast Asia.[28] Millets are not only adapted to poor, droughty, and infertile soils, but they are also more reliable under these conditions than most other grain crops. This has, in part, made millet production popular, particularly in countries surrounding the Sahara in western Africa.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>作为东亚最早的旱作作物，普通谷子的种植被认为是其抗旱性的原因，这有助于其推广。亚洲的谷子品种在公元前5000年从中国传入欧洲的黑海地区[段落：2]早在公元前3000年，谷子就在希腊野生生长，在马其顿和希腊北部发现了大量储存小米的容器，这些容器是青铜时代晚期的。赫西奥德描述道：“胡须长在谷子周围，人们在夏天播种。”[25][26]而在公元前三世纪，小米和小麦一起被提奥弗拉斯托斯（Theophrastus）在他的《植物探究》中列出[段落：2]珍珠粟是半干旱、贫困地区的两大农作物之一，非洲和东南亚较贫瘠的农业区。[28]谷子不仅适应贫瘠、干旱和贫瘠的土壤，而且在这些条件下比其他大多数粮食作物更可靠。这在一定程度上使小米生产受到欢迎，特别是在西非撒哈拉沙漠周边国家。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_HIT_SINGLES</Tag>
		<English>Hit Singles</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>热门单曲</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_RARE_EARTHS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Needs to be written.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>暂缺</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_RUBBER</Tag>
		<English>Rubber</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>橡胶</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_DYE_HENNA</Tag>
		<English>Dye (Henna)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>染料（散沫花）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_GEMS_SAPPHIRES</Tag>
		<English>Gems (Sapphires)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宝石（蓝宝石）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_AMBER</Tag>
		<English>Amber</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>琥珀</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_TOBACCO</Tag>
		<English>Tobacco</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>烟草</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_OBSIDIAN</Tag>
		<English>Obsidian</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>黑曜石</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_DATES</Tag>
		<English>Dates</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>椰枣</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_SPICES_CINNAMON</Tag>
		<English>Spices (Cinnamon)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>香料（肉桂）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_CITRUS</Tag>
		<English>Citrus</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>柑橘</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_SWAMP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Swamp</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>沼泽</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_SPICES_SAFFRON</Tag>
		<English>Spices (Saffron)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>香料（藏红）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_OPIUM</Tag>
		<English>Opium</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>鸦片</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_COFFEE</Tag>
		<English>Coffee</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>咖啡</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_PEARL</Tag>
		<English>Pearls</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>珍珠</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_HIT_MOVIES</Tag>
		<English>Hit Movies</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>热门电影</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_DATES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The date palm (Phoenix dactylifera) is a palm in the genus Phoenix, cultivated for its edible sweet fruit. Although its place of origin is unknown because of long cultivation, it probably originated from lands around the Persian Gulf. It is a medium-sized plant, 15 - 25 m tall, growing singly or forming a clump with several stems from a single root system. The leaves are 3 - 5 m long, with spines on the petiole, and pinnate, with about 150 leaflets; the leaflets are 30 cm long and 2 cm wide. The full span of the crown ranges from 6 to 10 m.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>枣椰（Phoenix dactylifera）是凤梨属的一种棕榈，因其可食用的甜果而种植。虽然由于长期的栽培，它的起源地不得而知，但它可能起源于波斯湾周围的土地。它是一种中等大小的植物，15-25米高，单株生长或形成由一个单一根系的多个茎组成的丛。叶长3-5米，叶柄上有刺，羽状，约150个小叶；小叶长30厘米，宽2厘米。树冠的全跨度为6到10米。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_GEMS_DIAMONDS</Tag>
		<English>Gems (Diamonds)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宝石（钻石）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_SALT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Edible salt is a mineral, one of the few rocks humans eat. Salt is necessary for the survival of all living creatures, including humans. Salt is involved in regulating the water content (fluid balance) of the body. Salt flavor is one of the basic tastes. In the past, salt was difficult to obtain, but had a great importance in food preservation and as a vital food additive. Therefore, it was a highly valued trade item throughout history. Wars were fought over it; states were formed and destroyed because of it. Roman soldiers were partially paid with salt, and this is still evident in the English language as the word salary derives from the Latin word salarium that means payment in salt (Latin sal), as well as the phrase "worth one's salt". It was also of high value to the Hebrews, Greeks and other peoples of antiquity. During the late Roman Empire and throughout the Middle Ages salt was a precious commodity carried along the salt roads into the heartland of the Germanic tribes. Cities, states and dukedoms along the salt roads exacted heavy duties and taxes for the salt passing through their territories. This practice caused wars, it even caused the formation of cities such as the city of Munich in 1158 when the then Duke of Bavaria Henry XII, called The Lion, decided that the bishops of Freising no longer needed their salt revenue.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>食用盐是一种矿物，是人类食用的少数几种岩石之一。盐是包括人类在内的所有生物生存所必需的。盐参与调节身体的含水量（体液平衡）。盐味是最基本的口味之一。在过去，盐很难获得，但在食品保存和作为一种重要的食品添加剂有着重要的意义。因此，它在历史上是一个很有价值的贸易项目。战争为之而战，国家也因此而形成和毁灭。罗马士兵的工资中有一部分是用盐支付的，这一点在英语中仍然很明显，因为salarium这个词来源于拉丁语salarium，意思是用盐支付（拉丁语sal），以及短语“值一个人的盐”。它对希伯来人、希腊人和其他古代民族也有很高的价值。在罗马帝国晚期和整个中世纪，盐是一种珍贵的商品，沿着盐路运到日耳曼部落的中心地带。盐路沿线的城市、州和公国对通过其领土的盐征收沉重的关税和税收。这种做法引发了战争，甚至导致了一些城市的形成，比如1158年，当时的巴伐利亚公爵亨利十二世（Duke of Bavaria Henry XII，又称狮子）决定弗雷辛的主教们不再需要他们的食盐收入。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_OBSIDIAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Obsidian is a naturally occurring glass formed as an extrusive igneous rock. It is produced when felsic lava extruded from a volcano cools without crystal growth. Obsidian is commonly found within the margins of rhyolitic lava flows known as obsidian flows, where the chemical composition (high silica content) induces a high viscosity and polymerisation degree of the lava. The inhibition of atomic diffusion through this highly viscous and polymerized lava explains the lack of crystal growth. Because of the lack of crystal structure, obsidian blade edges can reach almost molecular thinness, leading to its ancient use as projectile points, and its modern use as surgical scalpel blades.[PARAGRAPH:2]Obsidian is mineral-like, but not a true mineral because as a glass it is not crystalline; in addition, its composition is too complex to comprise a single mineral. It is sometimes classified as a mineraloid. Though obsidian is dark in color similar to mafic rocks such as basalt, obsidian's composition is extremely felsic. [PARAGRAPH:2]Pure obsidian is usually dark in appearance, though the color varies depending on the presence of impurities. Iron and magnesium typically give the obsidian a dark green to brown to black color. A very few samples are nearly colorless. In some stones, the inclusion of small, white, radially clustered crystals of cristobalite in the black glass produce a blotchy or snowflake pattern (snowflake obsidian). It may contain patterns of gas bubbles remaining from the lava flow, aligned along layers created as the molten rock was flowing before being cooled. These bubbles can produce interesting effects such as a golden sheen (sheen obsidian) or a rainbow sheen (rainbow obsidian). [PARAGRAPH:2]Obsidian was valued in Stone Age cultures because, like flint, it could be fractured to produce sharp blades or arrowheads. Like all glass and some other types of naturally occurring rocks, obsidian breaks with a characteristic conchoidal fracture. It was also polished to create early mirrors. Pre-Columbian Mesoamericans' use of obsidian was extensive and sophisticated, including carved and worked obsidian for tools and decorative objects. Mesoamericans also made a type of sword with obsidian blades mounted in a wooden body. Called a macuahuitl, the weapon was capable of inflicting terrible injuries, combining the sharp cutting edge of an obsidian blade with the ragged cut of a serrated weapon. Lithic analysis can be instrumental in understanding prehispanic groups in Mesoamerica. A careful analysis of obsidian in a culture or place can be of use to reconstruct commerce, production, distribution and thereby understand economic, social and political aspects of a civilization. This is the case in Yaxchil谩n, a maya city where even warfare implications have been studied linked with obsidian use and its debris. [PARAGRAPH:2]Obsidian is used in cardiac surgery, as well-crafted obsidian blades have a cutting edge many times sharper than high-quality steel surgical scalpels, with the edge of the blade being only about 3 nanometres wide. Even the sharpest metal knife has a jagged, irregular blade when viewed under a strong enough microscope. When examined under an electron microscope an obsidian blade is still smooth and even. One study found that obsidian produced narrower scars, fewer inflammatory cells, and less granulation tissue in a group of rats. [PARAGRAPH:2]Obsidian is also used for ornamental purposes and as a gemstone. It possesses the property of presenting a different appearance according to the manner in which it is cut. When cut in one direction it is a beautiful jet black; when cut across another direction it is glistening gray. "Apache tears" are small rounded obsidian nuggets embedded within a grayish-white perlite matrix.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>黑曜石是一种自然形成的玻璃，形成于喷出的火成岩中。它是由火山喷出的长英质熔岩冷却而没有晶体生长时产生的。黑曜岩通常存在于流纹岩熔岩流的边缘，即黑曜岩流，其化学成分（高硅含量）导致熔岩具有高粘度和高聚合度。通过这种高粘性和聚合熔岩原子扩散的抑制解释了晶体生长的缺乏。由于缺乏晶体结构，黑曜石刀片的边缘几乎可以达到分子的厚度，这就导致了它在古代被用作发射点，而在现代被用作外科手术刀刀片[段落：2]黑曜石是类似矿物的，但不是真正的矿物，因为作为玻璃，它不是晶体；此外，它的成分太复杂，不足以组成一种矿物。它有时被归类为类矿物。虽然黑曜石的颜色与玄武岩等镁铁质岩石相似，但黑曜岩的成分却极其长英质。[段落：2]纯黑曜石的外观通常是深色的，但颜色因杂质的存在而变化。铁和镁通常会使黑曜石呈现深绿色、棕色到黑色。极少数样品几乎无色。在一些石头中，黑色玻璃中夹杂着白色的放射状方石英晶体，会产生斑点状或雪花状图案（雪花黑曜石）。它可能包含熔岩流中残留的气泡图案，沿着熔融岩石在冷却前流动时形成的层排列。这些气泡可以产生有趣的效果，如金色光泽（黑曜石光泽）或彩虹光泽（彩虹黑曜石）。[段落：2]黑曜石在石器时代的文化中很受重视，因为它像燧石一样，可以被折断，产生锋利的刀片或箭头。像所有的玻璃和其他类型的天然岩石一样，黑曜石的破裂具有典型的贝壳状破裂。它也被抛光，以创造早期的镜子。前哥伦布时代的中美洲人对黑曜石的使用是广泛而复杂的，包括雕刻和加工黑曜石作为工具和装饰物。中美洲人还制造了一种剑，剑身镶有黑曜石的刀刃。这种武器被称为macuahuitl，能够造成可怕的伤害，将黑曜石刀片的锋利刃口与锯齿状武器的粗糙切口结合在一起。岩屑分析有助于了解中美洲的前氏族群。仔细分析黑曜石在一种文化或一个地方，可以用来重建商业、生产、分配，从而了解一个文明的经济、社会和政治方面。雅克奇兰就是这样，一个玛雅城市，在那里，甚至战争的影响都被研究与黑曜石的使用及其碎片有关。[段落：2]黑曜石用于心脏手术，因为精心制作的黑曜石刀片的刃口锋利度是优质钢手术刀的数倍，刃口宽度只有3纳米左右。即使是最锋利的金属刀，在足够强的显微镜下也有锯齿状的不规则刀片。当在电子显微镜下检查时，黑曜石的刀片仍然光滑而均匀。一项研究发现黑曜石在一组大鼠体内产生了更窄的疤痕、更少的炎性细胞和更少的肉芽组织。[段落：2]黑曜石也用于装饰目的和宝石。它具有根据切割方式呈现不同外观的特性。当朝一个方向切时，它是一种美丽的深黑色；当它横穿另一个方向时，它是闪亮的灰色。”“阿帕奇之泪”是嵌在灰白色珍珠岩基质中的小型圆形黑曜石块。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_GEMS_TURQUOISE</Tag>
		<English>Gems (Turquoise)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宝石（绿松石）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_CAMEL</Tag>
		<English>Camel</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>骆驼</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_CITRUS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Citrus is a genus of flowering trees and shrubs in the rue family, Rutaceae. Plants in the genus produce citrus fruits, including important crops such as oranges, lemons, grapefruits, pomelos, and limes. The genus Citrus is native to South Asia, East Asia, Southeast Asia, Melanesia, and Australia. Various citrus species have been utilized and domesticated by indigenous cultures in these areas since ancient times. From there its cultivation spread into Micronesia and Polynesia by the Austronesian expansion (c. 3000171500 BCE); and to the Middle East and the Mediterranean (c. 1200 BCE) via the incense trade route, and onwards to Europe.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>柑橘是芸香科芸香科开花乔木和灌木的一个属。该属植物生产柑橘类水果，包括重要的作物，如橘子、柠檬、柚子、柚子和酸橙。柑橘属原产于南亚、东亚、东南亚、美拉尼西亚和澳大利亚。自古以来，这些地区的土著文化就利用和驯化了各种柑橘品种。从那里开始，它的种植通过南岛的扩张（约公元前3000-1500年）扩展到密克罗尼西亚和波利尼西亚；通过熏香贸易路线传播到中东和地中海（约公元前1200年），并一直延伸到欧洲。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_CITRUS_ORANGES</Tag>
		<English>Citrus (Oranges)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>柑橘（橙子）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_COCOA</Tag>
		<English>Cocoa</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>可可粉</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_SHEEP_LLAMA</Tag>
		<English>Sheep (Llama)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>绵羊（美洲鸵）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_SALT</Tag>
		<English>Salt</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>盐矿</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_COW_BROWN</Tag>
		<English>Cow (Brown)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>奶牛（棕色）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_RARE_EARTHS</Tag>
		<English>Rare Earths</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>稀土</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_PIG_FURRY</Tag>
		<English>Pig (Furry)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>猪（毛猪）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_GEMS_RUBIES</Tag>
		<English>Gems (Rubies)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宝石（红宝石）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_ARCTIC_COAST_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Needs to be written.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>暂缺</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_OPIUM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The opium poppy (Papaver somniferum) is the type of poppy from which opium and all other refined opiates such as morphine can be extracted. The opium poppy probably originated in the eastern Mediterranean area and was subsequently spread to its modern range which covers much of southern Asia and beyond. Opium was used in the ancient Mediterranean for its medicinal qualities and as recreational narcotic. The use of the opium poppy most likely predates written history, but the first known historical occurrences of opium poppies are images found in ancient Sumerian artefacts dating to approximately 4000 B.C. Use of the opium poppy spread and by the 5th century B.C. was also known to the Greeks, who gave opium its current name.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>罂粟（Papaver somniferum）是一种罂粟，可以从中提取鸦片和所有其他精制鸦片剂，如吗啡。罂粟很可能起源于地中海东部地区，后来传播到其现代范围，包括南亚和其他地区的大部分地区。鸦片在古地中海地区因其药用价值和作为娱乐性麻醉剂而被使用。罂粟的使用很可能早于有文字记载的历史时期，但已知的最早的罂粟历史事件是在古代苏美尔手工艺品中发现的图像，可追溯到公元前4000年。使用罂粟传播，到公元前5世纪，希腊人也知道了罂粟，他们给鸦片起了现在的名字。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_SHEEP_BLACK</Tag>
		<English>Sheep (Black)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>羊（黑羊）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_SPICES_NUTMEG</Tag>
		<English>Spices (Nutmeg)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>香料（豆蔻）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_JADE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A greenish mineral, Jade is extremely hard and robust, and has been in use for many thousands of years. Jade was originally used in tools and weapons, but as other more effective substances (like bronze and iron) were discovered, jade would become used largely for ornamental purposes. Jade was first widely used in China during the Neolithic period. Over time as the most accessible sources were depleted, it became more valuable than gold. Today jade is still used in jewellery and in a variety of trinkets, though it no longer carries the prestige or value it once did.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>翡翠是一种绿色矿物，非常坚硬和坚固，已经使用了数千年。玉石最初用于工具和武器，但随着其他更有效的物质（如青铜和铁）的发现，玉将主要用于装饰目的。玉器最早在新石器时代在中国被广泛使用。随着时间的推移，最容易获得的资源枯竭，黄金变得比黄金更有价值。今天，翡翠仍然被用于珠宝和各种小饰物中，尽管它不再具有它曾经的威望和价值。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_DYE_MUREX</Tag>
		<English>Dye (Murex)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>染料（骨螺）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_AMBER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Amber is the petrified remnant of ancient tree resins, mostly dating back to the Cretaceous period or later; before that time, evergreen trees did not exist. Amber is rare and prized for its distinctive translucent, typically yellow color, and also for the relative ease with which it can be carved and worked compared to other gem and gem-like materials. It is in effect a semi-precious stone.[PARAGRAPH:2]Amber is found in a variety of sources, although large deposits of this semi-precious stone are rare. Trade in amber flourished in the Baltic sea, chiefly in what is currently the Kaliningrad Oblast of Russia (which still contains 90% of known amber reserves). Certain other deposits exist elsewhere in the world, such as the exotic blue amber of the Dominican Republic.[PARAGRAPH:2]One interesting scientific feature of amber is that, being the fossilized remnant of a sticky organic resin, it can entrap things. There were many cases in the prehistoric past of insects and plant material becoming stuck and "included" inside the resin as it petrified into amber. This has resulted in very well-preserved specimens of flies, mosquitos, and other biological remnants, trapped inside the translucent amber.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>琥珀是古代树木树脂的石化残余物，大多可以追溯到白垩纪或更晚的时期；在此之前，常绿树木并不存在。琥珀是稀有和珍贵的，因为它独特的半透明，典型的黄色，而且与其他宝石和类似宝石的材料相比，它可以相对容易地雕刻和加工。它实际上是一种半宝石[段落：2]琥珀的来源多种多样，尽管这种半宝石的大量沉积非常罕见。在波罗的海，琥珀贸易蓬勃发展，主要是在目前俄罗斯加里宁格勒州（该州仍有90%的已知琥珀储量）。世界其他地方也有一些其他的矿藏，比如多米尼加共和国的奇异蓝琥珀[段落：2]琥珀的一个有趣的科学特征是，它是一种粘性有机树脂的化石残留物，它可以夹住东西。在史前的历史上，有很多昆虫和植物材料在树脂石化成琥珀时被粘住并“包含”在树脂中。这使得苍蝇、蚊子和其他生物残留物保存得非常完好，被困在半透明的琥珀里。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_POTATO</Tag>
		<English>Potatoes</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>土豆</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_SPICES_VANILLA</Tag>
		<English>Spices (Vanilla)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>香料（香草）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_CRAB_SHRIMP</Tag>
		<English>Crab (Shrimps)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>蟹（虾）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_IVORY_AFRICAN</Tag>
		<English>Ivory (African)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>象牙（非洲）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_TEA</Tag>
		<English>Tea</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>茶叶</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_HIT_FOOTBALL_EVENT</Tag>
		<English>Hit Football Event</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>热门足球赛事</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_GEMS_EMERALDS</Tag>
		<English>Gems (Emeralds)</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宝石（绿宝石）</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_LAGOON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Needs to be written.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>暂缺</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
