<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Civ4GameText>
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HERITAGE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"And how can man die better, than facing fearful odds, for the ashes of his fathers, and the temples of his gods?"[PARAGRAPH:2]- Thomas Macaulay, Lays of Ancient Rome</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“人怎么能死得比面对可怕的厄运，死得比死得好呢？死得比死得好，死得比死得好，死得比死得好，死得比死得好，死得比死得好，死得好，死得好，死得好，死得好，死得好，死得好〔段落：2〕古罗马的Thomas Macaulay</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LITERATURE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Some books are to be tasted, others to be swallowed, and some few to be chewed and digested."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Francis Bacon, Of Studies</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“有些书是要尝的，有些是要吞咽的，有些是要咀嚼消化的。”[段落：2 ]——弗朗西斯·培根研究</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MEDICINE</Tag>
		<English>Medicine</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>传统医学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPOSITES_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The whole is greater than the sum of its parts."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Aristotle</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“整体大于其部分之和。”[段落：2 ] -亚里士多德</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FERTILIZER_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"If the grass on the other side of the fence appears greener, it must be all the fertilizer they are using."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Kevin Rodowicz</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“如果篱笆那边的草看起来更绿，那一定是他们所用的肥料。”[段落：2 ] - Kevin Rodowicz</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HYDRAULICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The word "hydraulics" comes from a root word for "water". Hydraulic technology manipulates water or another fluid, for a variety of purposes.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Civilization is intimately tied to water. People need water to live, to raise crops, to move cargo along rivers, canals, and the sea. As the understanding of water and water pressure became more complete and mathematical in late pre-industrial times, traditional projects of water-manipulation grew more ambitious. Many civilizations built or improved great canals, for instance, making artificial waterways where nature did not provide an easy path. In areas where river valleys posed a flooding hazard, great levees and dikes were built to stem the flow of water. Existing innovations like waterwheels were used on a larger and larger scale, to provide greater reserves of power for manufacturing.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“液压”一词来源于“水”的词根。水力技术操纵水或其他流体，有多种用途。[新线][新线]文明与水紧密相连。人们需要水来生活，种植庄稼，沿着河流、运河和海洋运输货物。随着前工业时代后期对水和水压的理解变得更加完整和数学化，传统的水处理项目变得更加雄心勃勃。例如，许多文明建造或改进了运河，在自然条件不允许的地方建造了人工水道。在河谷造成洪水灾害的地区，修建了大堤和堤坝来阻止水流。像水车这样的现有创新被越来越大规模地使用，为制造业提供更大的能源储备。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRICITY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"We will make electricity so cheap that only the rich will burn candles."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Thomas Edison</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我们的电会很便宜，只有富人才会点燃蜡烛。”[段落：2 ] - Thomas Edison</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMMUNE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In the high and late middle ages, increase in agricultural production meant there was an excess of additional population. These people gravitated to urban centers, leading to a degree of urbanisation not seen in Europe since the collapse of the Roman Empire.[PARAGRAPH:2]Within these often fortified cities, a new class of people developed. These so called burghers often engaged in trade and commerce and began to accrue wealth independent of the nobility. As these trends continued, cities began to assert their newfound powers to gain additional privileges.[PARAGRAPH:2]This put them in opposition to the traditional feudal power structure. Where central power was weak and cities were affluent, such as the Netherlands, Switzerland and Northern Italy, cities were successful in defending their sovereignty from feudal overlords. Their success can be linked both to their organisation in regional leagues and alliances as well as innovative military organisation relying on mercenary companies, paving the way to professionalised armies.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在中世纪中后期，农业生产的增加意味着人口的增加。这些人被吸引到城市中心，导致罗马帝国垮台后欧洲的城市化程度不高。[段落：2 ]在这些经常设防的城市里，一个新的阶级发展起来了。这些所谓的市民经常从事贸易和商业，开始积累独立于贵族的财富。随着这些趋势的继续，城市开始主张他们新获得的权力以获得额外的特权。[第2段]这使他们反对传统的封建权力结构。在中央权力薄弱、城市富裕的地区，如荷兰、瑞士和意大利北部，城市成功地捍卫了自己的主权，不受封建霸主的侵犯。他们的成功可以与他们在地区联盟和联盟中的组织以及依靠雇佣军公司的创新军事组织联系起来，为专业化军队铺平道路。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MACHINE_TOOLS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I can make just such ones if I had tools, and I could make tools if I had tools to make them with."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Eli Whitney</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“如果我有工具，我就可以制造这样的工具，如果我有工具可以制造工具，我就可以制造工具。”[段落：2 ] -伊莱·惠特尼</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NANOTECHNOLOGY</Tag>
		<English>Nanotechnology</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>纳米技术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LAW_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The earliest tribal civilizations were bonded together by mutual needs and beliefs. A tribal chieftain, who acted as an advisor and enforcer of the will of the gods, ruled these groups. No formal laws existed in these early cultures, but fear of the gods and a sense of tribal customs and morality kept order in the tribe. As societies became larger and more diverse, the need arose for established rules of conduct. The earliest known codes of laws existed in Babylon, India, and Palestine. The Twelve Tables of Rome, written in 500 BC, and its successors such as the Justinian Code, were the first codes of law to distinguish between public law, which involves the state, and private law, which concerns disputes between citizens. Roman law was the first formalized written system of laws, and went on to influence many of the legal systems of the modern world.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>最早的部落文明是由相互的需要和信仰联系在一起的。一个部落首领，作为上帝意志的顾问和执行者，统治着这些群体。在这些早期文化中没有正式的法律，但是对神的恐惧和对部落习俗和道德的感觉维持了部落的秩序。随着社会变得越来越大，越来越多样化，就需要有既定的行为规则。已知最早的法典存在于巴比伦、印度和巴勒斯坦。公元前500年写成的《罗马十二表》及其后继的《查士丁尼法典》是第一部区分涉及国家的公法和涉及公民之间争端的私法的法典。罗马法是第一个正式成文的法律体系，并对现代世界的许多法律体系产生了影响。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BLOOMERY</Tag>
		<English>Bloomery</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>铁器</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HORTICULTURE</Tag>
		<English>Horticulture</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>园艺</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ENGINEERING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"A designer knows he has achieved perfection not when there is nothing left to add, but when there is nothing left to take away."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Antoine de Saint-Exupéry, Wind, Sand and Stars</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“设计师知道他已经完成了完美，而当没有什么可以补充的时候，但当没有什么东西可以拿走的时候。”[段落：2 ]——安托万·德·圣·埃克苏，《风，沙，星星》。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CONTRACT</Tag>
		<English>Contract</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>契约精神</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FINANCE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Finance refers to the organized processes of handling money. While money is an ancient innovation, for most of history currency was handled in simple ways. Coins were just another commodity, fixed volumes of precious metal that had some kind of official sanction. A rich person would simply have large numbers of coins, much as they might have a large herd of cattle or a warehouse full of pottery. Anyone who wanted to buy something would simply pile up coins into a large heap that could be exchanged for the good, usually by earning them a few at a time.[PARAGRAPH:2]This had limits. Starting a business, making major purchases or engaging in large scale public works were difficult because the buyer needed to have all their money at once, and at the beginning of the process, in order to accomplish anything. Travel was more dangerous because there was no way to store money during travel except on your person. If you needed money at your destination to do business, you would have to carry it with you.[PARAGRAPH:2]Around 1000 CE solutions to this problem emerged. One obvious solution was the creation of banks - dedicated storehouses that would hold onto money and which could contact other banks in other cities. Instead of traveling with a hundred gold coins on your person, you could deposit the gold in a bank at home, travel to a destination, and 'withdraw' coins from the other city's bank: their records would tell them that you owned the money, but in another place. Banks could also make loans; a large sum of money up-front, to be paid back over a period of time with interest. This allowed the wealthy to invest with more safety and gave the poor an option for buying expensive capital goods.[PARAGRAPH:2]The rise of financial institutions has come with costs. Professional money-manipulators have a great deal of power in society, and sometimes use it at others' expense. But it greatly increases the economic power and flexibility of a civilization.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>财务是指有组织的处理资金的过程。虽然货币是一项古老的创新，但在历史上，大多数货币都是以简单的方式处理的。硬币只是另一种商品，固定数量的贵金属，有某种官方认可。一个有钱人只会拥有大量的硬币，就像他们可能拥有一大群牛或一个装满陶器的仓库一样。任何想买东西的人都会把硬币堆成一个大的堆，可以换成好的，通常是一次挣几个。创业、重大采购或从事大规模公共工程都很困难，因为买家需要在一开始就把所有的钱都拿到手，才能完成任何事情。旅行是更危险的，因为在旅行期间除了你的人没有办法储存钱。如果你在目的地需要钱来做生意，你就必须随身携带。[段落：2 ]大约1000 CE解决了这个问题。一个明显的解决办法是建立银行——专门存放资金的仓库，可以联系其他城市的其他银行。你不必随身携带一百枚金币旅行，你可以将金币存入家中的银行，前往目的地，然后从另一个城市的银行“提取”金币：他们的记录会告诉他们你拥有这些钱，但在另一个地方。银行也可以发放贷款；一大笔预先支付的款项，在一段时间内用利息偿还。这使得富人可以更安全地投资，给穷人购买昂贵资本商品的选择。[第2段]金融机构的崛起伴随着成本。专业的货币操纵者在社会上拥有巨大的权力，有时会以牺牲他人利益为代价。但它大大提高了一个文明的经济实力和灵活性。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HORTICULTURE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The first farmer was the first man. All historic nobility rests on the possession and use of land."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Ralph Waldo Emerson, Farming</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“第一个农夫是第一个人。所有的历史贵族都依靠土地的占有和使用。“[段：2 ] -拉尔夫·沃尔多·爱默生，农业</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HUNTING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"If you chase two rabbits, you will lose them both."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Native American proverb</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“如果你追逐两只兔子，你就会失去它们。”[段落：2 ] -美国土著谚语</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PROPERTY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The first man who, having fenced in a piece of land, said "This is mine," and found people naive enough to believe him; that man was the true founder of civil society."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Jean Jacques Rousseau, Discourse on Inequality</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“第一个在一块土地上围起来的人说：“这是我的，”他发现人们天真地相信他；那个人是公民社会的真正创立者。”[段落：2 ]——Jean Jacques Rousseau，关于不平等的论述</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FORTIFICATION</Tag>
		<English>Fortification</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>防御工事</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_SERVICE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The bureaucracy is expanding to meet the needs of the expanding bureaucracy."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Oscar Wilde</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“官僚机构正在扩张以满足不断扩张的官僚体制的需要。”[段落：2 ] -奥斯卡·王尔德</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_WRITING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I deem those blessed to whom, by favour of the gods, it has been granted either to do what is worth writing of, or to write what is worth reading."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Pliny the Younger, Letter to Tacitus</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我认为那些受上帝祝福的人，无论是做了值得写的事，还是写值得读的书，都是被允许的。”[段落：2 ]——小普林尼，给塔西佗的信。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CONSUMERISM</Tag>
		<English>Consumerism</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>消费主义</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PAPER_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I cannot live without books."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Thomas Jefferson</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“没有书我就活不了。”[段落：2 ] -托马斯·杰斐逊</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TELECOMMUNICATIONS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The new electronic interdependence recreates the world in the image of a global village."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Marshall McLuhan, The Gutenberg Galaxy</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“新的电子相互依赖在世界村的形象中重塑世界。”[段落：2 ] -马歇尔·麦克卢汉，Gutenberg Galaxy</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SOCIAL_SERVICES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A social or public service is a service which is provided by government to people living within its jurisdiction, either directly (through the public sector) or by financing provision of services. The term is associated with a social consensus (usually expressed through democratic elections) that certain services should be available to all, regardless of income, physical ability or mental acuity. Even where public services are neither publicly provided nor publicly financed, for social and political reasons they are usually subject to regulation going beyond that applying to most economic sectors. Public policy when made in the public's interest and motivations can provide public services. Public service is also a course that can be studied at a college or university. Examples of public services are the fire brigade, police, air force, and paramedics.[PARAGRAPH:2]A public service may sometimes have the characteristics of a public good (being non-rivalrous and non-excludable), but most are services which may (according to prevailing social norms) be under-provided by the market. In most cases public services are services, i.e. they do not involve manufacturing of goods. They may be provided by local or national monopolies, especially in sectors which are natural monopolies.[PARAGRAPH:2]Historically, the widespread provision of public services in developed countries usually began in the late nineteenth century, often with the municipal development of gas and water services. Later, governments began to provide other services such as electricity and healthcare. In most developed countries such services are still provided by local or national government, the biggest exceptions being the U.S. and the UK, where private provision is more significant.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>社会或公共服务是政府直接（通过公共部门）或通过资助提供服务，向其管辖范围内的人民提供的服务。这一术语与一种社会共识（通常通过民主选举表达）有关，即不论收入、身体能力或精神智商如何，人人都应享有某些服务。即使公共服务既不是公共提供的，也不是公共资助的，出于社会和政治原因，它们通常受到超出适用于大多数经济部门的监管。公共政策是为了公众的利益和动机而制定的，可以提供公共服务。公共服务也是一门可以在学院或大学学习的课程。公共服务的例子有消防队、警察、空军和护理人员。[第2段]公共服务有时可能具有公益性（非竞争性和非排他性）的特征，但大多数是可以根据市场提供的服务（根据当时的社会规范）。在大多数情况下，公共服务是服务，即不涉及商品制造。它们可能是由地方或国家垄断提供的，特别是在自然垄断行业。[段：2 ]从历史上看，发达国家普遍提供公共服务通常始于十九世纪下旬，通常是城市发展的天然气和水服务。后来，政府开始提供电力和医疗等其他服务。在大多数发达国家，此类服务仍由地方或国家政府提供，最大的例外是美国和英国，在英国，私人提供的服务更为重要。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MICROBIOLOGY</Tag>
		<English>Microbiology</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>微生物学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CONSUMERISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Marketing is the practice of persuading people that an object, idea, or behavior is desirable (and worth paying for). Marketing has existed in some form since prehistoric times; one may speculate that the first marketing activities were invented within five minutes of the first invention of commerce.  The development of mass media such as broadcast radio, print journalism, and film made it possible to market on a larger scale. The rise of a working and middle class in developed societies with enough disposable income to buy luxury goods made it desirable to do so. The growth of modern industrial corporations that could produce goods in immense quantities made it necessary to do so.[PARAGRAPH:2]Common practices in modern marketing include direct personal approaches, flattery of the customer, praise of the product (intellectually honest or otherwise), and efforts to make the seller appear sympathetic and likeable to the prospective buyer. The main difference is that all these things are now transmitted from the individual advertiser to the mass of the population through new communications technology such as printing, broadcasts, or the Internet.[PARAGRAPH:2]The practice of marketing is often criticized for dishonesty, for misleading people into paying for that which is useless to them, for encouraging people to go into debt, and for discouraging people from thrift and from building up savings for the future. It is also criticized for the increasingly intrusive way in which, in the modern computerized era, marketers use "big data" to analyze individuals' purchasing habits and tailor advertisements to them. This is widely regarded as intrusive, and as having ominous implications for the individual's privacy and control over their own life in the future.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>市场营销是说服人们相信某个目标、想法或行为是可取的（并且值得付出代价）。从史前时代起，营销就以某种形式存在；人们可以推测，第一种营销活动是在商业第一次发明的五分钟内发明的。广播电台、新闻印刷业、电影等大众传媒的发展，使大规模的市场化成为可能。发达社会中有足够可支配收入购买奢侈品的工人阶级和中产阶级的崛起，使得购买奢侈品成为人们的愿望。现代工业企业的发展，可以产生大量的产品，使得有必要这样做。[段落：2 ]现代营销中的常见做法包括直接的个人方法，客户的奉承，对产品的赞美（智力诚实或其他），努力使卖方看起来对潜在的买方有同情心和好感。主要的区别是，所有这些东西都是通过印刷、广播或互联网等新的通讯技术从个人广告商传播到大众的。〔2〕市场营销的做法常因不诚实而受到批评。为了误导人们去为那些对他们毫无用处的东西买单，为了鼓励人们去负债，为了阻止人们节俭和为将来积累储蓄。在现代电脑时代，营销人员使用“大数据”分析个人的购买习惯，并根据个人的购买习惯定制广告，这种方式越来越具有侵入性，因此也受到批评。这被广泛认为是侵入性的，对个人隐私和未来对自己生活的控制有不祥的影响。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AGRICULTURE</Tag>
		<English>Agriculture</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>农业</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SEAFARING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Seafaring is the art of directing, maintaining, and preserving ships that travel across the ocean. The earliest human vessels such as rafts, small canoes, and reed boats would have been extremely unsafe on the open ocean. However, there is extensive evidence for the practice of seafaring stretching back to the Bronze Age, or the Neolithic in the case of Polynesian long-distance sailing canoes.[PARAGRAPH:2]In general, successful seafarers must make use of some source of power other than their own muscles (in the early days of navigation, a sail) to ensure they were not trapped by ocean currents. They must know how to construct reasonably sturdy craft that would resist ocean waves. They had to make use of a great knowledge of weather conditions to ensure the craft was not caught by a storm too powerful to be survived - which in premodern times weather could be predicted only by experience.[PARAGRAPH:2]All this represented a significant advance over the earliest Stone Age boats and their operations... and yet, all these things were necessary in order for coastal civilizations to make any serious use of maritime travel for trade or exploration.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>航海是指挥、维护和保护穿越海洋的船只的艺术。最早的人类船只，如木筏、小独木舟和芦苇船，在公海上是极不安全的。然而，有大量证据表明，航海实践可以追溯到青铜时代，或波利尼西亚远航独木舟的新石器时代。[段落：2 ]一般来说，成功的海员必须利用除自己的肌肉以外的其他力量（在航行的早期，帆）来确保它们是没有被洋流困住。他们必须知道如何建造能抵抗海浪的坚固船只。他们必须利用天气条件的巨大知识来确保飞船不会被太强而无法生存的风暴所捕获——在前现代时代，天气只能通过经验来预测。[第2段]所有这些都代表了最早的石器时代船只及其运行的重大进展。然而，所有这些都是必要的，以便沿海文明能够认真利用海上旅行进行贸易或勘探。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SYNTHETICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Nothing on this earth lasts forever. Except maybe plastic."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Patricia Dunn</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“世上没有永恒的东西。“除了塑料，”[段落：2 ] - Patricia Dunn</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FEUDALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Land tenure is the idea of a fixed, legalized ownership of land with a formal relationship between the landowner and their ruler. "Tenure" comes from a root verb meaning "to hold" the land in question. Under a land tenure system, all land is the property of the sovereign by default, but this land is granted to trusted individuals in permanent, usually inherited titles. This forms the foundation of what we now know as feudalism. In exchange for a grant of land for themself and their heirs, a feudal noble might promise to supply their ruler with troops, money, food, or other goods obtained from the productivity of the land itself.[PARAGRAPH:2]This saved the monarch from the burden of administering the territory directly and trying to collect taxes from it, and created a large class of aristocrats who owed their fortune and power to the throne. The pattern of tenancy could be scaled up and down easily, ranging from great territories held by powerful nobles down to individual farmers on their own plots granted to them by a local warlord.[PARAGRAPH:2]A feudal tenure-based system has drawbacks, however. Tenants' loyalty to the sovereign is often conditional, based on complicated webs of mutual obligations and exceptions to the legal code which make it difficult to change or reform the economy. Powerful feudal nobles may defect to an enemy intact to preserve their status in the face of invasion - or even scheme to seize control of the land themselves.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>土地保有权是指土地所有权固定、合法，土地所有者与其统治者之间有正式关系的概念。”“保有权”来自一个词根动词，意思是“持有”所讨论的土地。在土地保有制下，所有土地默认为主权的财产，但这片土地是以永久的、通常是继承的所有权授予受信任的个人的。这是我们现在所知道的封建制度的基础。一个封建贵族为了换取自己和他们继承人的土地，可以承诺为统治者提供土地、土地、金钱、食物或其他从土地生产力中获得的其他物品。〔2〕这使君主免于直接管理领土并试图从中征税。创造了一大批贵族，他们的财富和权力都要归功于王位。租佃模式可以很容易地上下浮动，从大贵族的大领地到当地的军阀授予他们自己的地块的个体农场主。〔2〕一个封建任期制有缺点。租客对主权的忠诚往往是有条件的，因为他们之间有着错综复杂的相互义务和法律法规的例外，这使得改变或改革经济变得困难。强大的封建贵族可能会叛变到一个敌人身上，以保持他们在面对侵略时的地位，甚至是夺取土地控制权的阴谋。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SPACEFLIGHT_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"That's one small step for man; one giant leap for humanity."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Neil Armstrong</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“这是迈向人类的一小步，是人类的一大步。”[段落：2 ] - Neil Armstrong</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MEDICINE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"As to diseases make a habit of two things - to help, or at least, to do no harm."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Hippocrates</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“对疾病来说，养成两样东西的习惯——帮助或至少不伤害他人。”[段落：2 ] -希波克拉提斯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARCHITECTURE</Tag>
		<English>Architecture</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>建筑</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FEUDALISM_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I will to my lord be true and faithful and love all which he loves and shun all which he shuns."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Anglo-Saxon Oath of Fealty</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我要对我的主忠诚忠诚，爱他所爱的一切，回避他所回避的一切。”[段：2 ] -盎格鲁-撒克逊效忠誓言</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MATHEMATICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"If in other sciences we should arrive at certainty without doubt and truth without error, it behooves us to place the foundations of knowledge in mathematics."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Roger Bacon, Opus Majus</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“如果在其他科学中，我们毫无疑问地到达毫无疑问的真理，我们就必须把知识的基础放在数学中。”[段落：2 ] -罗杰·培根，Opus Majus</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PROPERTY</Tag>
		<English>Property</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>私有制</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_JOURNALISM_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The press is the best instrument for enlightening the mind of man, and improving him as a rational, moral and social being."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Thomas Jefferson</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“新闻是启迪人的心灵的最好工具，并把他作为一个理性的、道德的和社会的存在来改进。”[段落：2 ] -托马斯·杰斐逊</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LOGISTICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Logistics is the art of producing, moving, storing, controlling, and distributing supplies, in order to carry out a large project, especially in war. Logistics has governed the conduct of armies since ancient times.[PARAGRAPH:2]Ancient historians often recount the use of vast armies of hundreds of thousands, or even millions, in great campaigns. This is generally deemed unlikely, entirely because of logistics. To set great masses of people to work, one must have plenty of food and other goods, and ways to move them. For domestic labor this is relatively easy, since grain and supplies can be stockpiled near a fixed workplace and used as necessary. But in war, the supplies have to be transported and guarded from enemy raiders.[PARAGRAPH:2]Human porters, pack animals, and animal-drawn wagons have limits; all these forms of transport have to eat and are vulnerable to exhaustion. Past a certain distance, the weight of food a man or animal carries to feed themself is so great that there's no room to transport anything else. Smaller armies can survive by hunting, foraging, and (most often) stealing the food of the local populace. But a large enough army will strip the land bare and potentially drink rivers dry; without a better means of supply the army will die of thirst or hunger even if it never sees an armed enemy.[PARAGRAPH:2]In ancient times (and even today) the cheapest, most cost-effective way of moving bulk cargo was by sea. Even an ancient ship could carry many tons of cargo, much faster than man or beast could walk. Therefore, large ancient armies were tied to the seas and rivers; traveling any great distance from water was very risky.  This constraint remained throughout pre-industrial history, although areas with strong governments that built good roads could simplify the problem by allowing land transport to move faster and carry more; the Roman and Inca empires both thrived because they built excellent road networks throughout their land, and used them to move large armies.[PARAGRAPH:2]In modern times, logistics has become more demanding, but more powerful. Railroads and modern ships carry totally unprecedented weights of cargo at incredible speed. But industrial armies demand tons upon tons of fuel, artillery, ammunition, spare parts, and other goods not needed by an ancient army. Logistics is no less important than it ever was, whether the goods move by sea, railway, highway, or even through the air.[PARAGRAPH:2]A cunning enemy may always strike at an army's logistics. This has caused countless defeats throughout history, from the Horns of Hattin to the jungles of Dien Bien Phu. Therefore, much of what we call generalship revolves around making sure one's own logistics are secure, giving one the advantages of well fed troops with plenty of weapons - and denying those advantages to the enemy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>物流是一门生产、运输、储存、控制和分配物资的艺术，目的是为了执行一项大型工程，特别是在战争中。自古以来，后勤统治了军队的行为。[段：2 ]古代历史学家经常叙述数十万军队，甚至数百万人的庞大军队在伟大战役中的使用。这通常被认为不太可能，完全是因为物流。要使广大人民群众工作，就必须有充足的食物和其他物品，以及运送这些物品的方法。对于家庭劳动力来说，这相对容易，因为粮食和物资可以储存在固定的工作场所附近，并在必要时使用。但是在战争中，供应品必须从敌人的袭击者那里运输和守卫。[段落：2 ]人类搬运工人、驮畜和动物牵引车都有限制，所有这些运输方式都必须吃，而且容易疲劳。经过一定的距离，一个人或动物携带的食物的重量是如此之大，以至于没有空间运输其他东西。较小的军队可以通过狩猎、觅食和（通常）偷取当地民众的食物来生存。但是一支足够大的军队会把土地裸露出来，并可能使河流干涸；如果没有更好的供给手段，军队即使在没有看到武装敌人的情况下也会因口渴或饥饿而死亡。（2段）古代（甚至今天）运送大宗货物最便宜、最划算的方式是海运。即使是一艘古船也能运载许多吨的货物，比人类或野兽行走的速度要快得多。因此，古代庞大的军队被束缚在海洋和河流上，在离水很远的地方旅行是非常危险的。这一限制在工业化前的历史上一直存在，尽管拥有强大政府的地区修建了良好的道路，可以通过让陆路运输更快、运输量更大来简化问题；罗马帝国和印加帝国之所以繁荣，是因为它们在其土地上修建了良好的道路网络，在现代，后勤变得更加苛刻，但更强大。铁路和现代船舶以惊人的速度运载着前所未有的货物重量。但是工业军队需要一吨又一吨的燃料、大炮、弹药、备件和其他古代军队不需要的物资。物流不比以往任何时候都重要，无论货物是通过海运、铁路、公路，还是通过空中运输。[段落：2 ]狡猾的敌人可能总是攻击军队的后勤。这在历史上造成了无数的失败，从哈丁角到奠边府的丛林。因此，我们所说的将军制，大多是围绕着确保自己的后勤安全，让自己拥有拥有充足武器的精兵强将的优势，并把这些优势否认给敌人。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SOCIAL_CONTRACT_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Each person possesses an inviolability founded on justice that even the welfare of society as a whole cannot override."[PARAGRAPH:2]- John Rawls, A Theory of Justice</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“每个人都有一种不可侵犯性，建立在正义之上，即使整个社会的福利也不能推翻。”[段落：2 ]——John Rawls的正义理论。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SPACEFLIGHT</Tag>
		<English>Spaceflight</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>太空飞行</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SUPERCONDUCTORS</Tag>
		<English>Superconductors</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>超导</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MEASUREMENT</Tag>
		<English>Measurement</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>测量学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ALCHEMY</Tag>
		<English>Alchemy</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>炼金术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TELEPHONE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>Mr. Watson, come here - I want to see you."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Alexander Graham Bell</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>Watson先生，过来，我想见你。”[段落：2 ] -亚历山大·格拉汉姆·贝尔</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AUTOMATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"We are becoming the servants in thought, as in action, of the machine we have created to serve us."[PARAGRAPH:2]- John Kenneth Galbraith, The New Industrial State</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我们正在成为思想中的仆人，就像我们在为我们服务而创造的机器一样。”[段落：2 ]——约翰加尔布雷斯，新工业国</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HERITAGE</Tag>
		<English>Heritage</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>遗产</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REPRESENTATION</Tag>
		<English>Representation</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>民意代表</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GUILDS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"People of the same trade seldom meet together, even for merriment and diversion, but the conversation ends in a conspiracy against the public."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Adam Smith, The Wealth of Nations</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“同行业的人很少见面，即使是为了欢笑和消遣，但谈话最终以对公众的阴谋告终。”[段落：2 ]——亚当·斯密，《国家财富》</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ACADEMIA</Tag>
		<English>Academia</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>学术精神</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOTECHNOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The nitrogen in our DNA, the calcium in our teeth, the iron in our blood, the carbon in our apple pies were made in the interiors of collapsing stars. We are made of star stuff."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Carl Sagan, Cosmos</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我们DNA中的氮，牙齿中的钙，血液中的铁，苹果派中的碳都是在坍塌的恒星内部形成的。我们是由星星组成的。”[段落：2 ] - Carl Sagan，宇宙</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GLOBALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Globalization is the process by which different peoples spread across the world become united by ties of ideology, economics, and politics. The first wave of globalization took place during the 19th century Age of Imperialism, when steam power and telegraphy allowed European empires to spread zones of influence across most of the world, creating a web of transport, communication, and government. However, access to these networks was limited and patchy and many people neither knew nor cared about events in far-off lands.[PARAGRAPH:2]The World Wars sped up the process. The staggering, apocalyptic scale of combat caught up many colonial possessions in Africa and Asia, permanently undermining European rule at the same time that people in economic backwaters were exposed to a wide variety of modern products and weapons. After World War Two, ideologies such as nationalism or communism spread into regions that had previously been dominated by traditional cultures that were less inclined to resist foreign rule. A wave of "decolonization" swept the world.[PARAGRAPH:2]But this was not the end. Direct imperial rule of poor nations by rich ones went out of fashion, the economic bonds between rich and poor were not so easily broken. The industrial giants of the developed world could easily produce enough goods to supply massive export markets, while needing to import raw materials on an ever-growing scale as their own supplies of timber, coal, ore, and oil became depleted. Along with these flows of goods came flows of popular products and the culture that came with them, particularly from the United States. Artifacts of American culture (Hollywood movies, blue jeans, Coca-Cola) became world-spanning; to a lesser extent this diffusion worked from other sources, and even worked the other way, with foreign customs being adopted in the former colonial metropoles.[PARAGRAPH:2]Along with these economic ties came an entangled world political stage. Dictators of small, remote countries could no longer count on isolation and control of the media to keep their people from becoming restless, or to keep large foreign powers from intruding on their business. The only security for small nations was to align themselves with the economic interests of the great power blocs, supplying cheap resources and labor and giving themselves a place in the new world order.[PARAGRAPH:2]Today the world is extensively globalized, a product of the capitalist triumph of the post-Cold War era. Whether this is socially desirable, economically sustainable, or even ecologically survivable remains to be seen, and is likely to become one of the great questions of the 21st century.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>全球化是一个过程，通过意识形态、经济和政治的联系，不同的民族在世界各地传播。全球化的第一次浪潮发生在19世纪帝国主义时代，当时蒸汽动力和电报使欧洲帝国得以在世界大部分地区传播影响区，建立了一个运输、通讯和政府网络。然而，对这些网络的访问是有限的和零星的，许多人既不知道也不关心遥远的土地上的事件。[第2段]，世界大战加速了这一进程。这场令人震惊的世界末日式的战争占领了非洲和亚洲的许多殖民地，永久地破坏了欧洲的统治，与此同时，经济落后地区的人民也接触到各种各样的现代产品和武器。第二次世界大战后，民族主义或共产主义等意识形态蔓延到以前由传统文化主导的地区，这些地区不太倾向于抵制外国统治。“非殖民化”浪潮席卷全球。[段落：2 ]，但这还不是结束。富国对穷国的直接帝国统治已经过时，富国和穷国之间的经济纽带并没有那么容易被打破。发达国家的工业巨头可以很容易地生产出足够的产品来供应大规模的出口市场，同时需要进口不断增长的原材料，因为他们自己的木材、煤炭、矿石和石油供应已经枯竭。伴随着这些商品的流动而来的是流行产品的流动和随之而来的文化，特别是来自美国的。美国文化的文物（好莱坞电影、蓝色牛仔裤、可口可乐）成为世界的延伸；在较小程度上，这种扩散从其他来源起作用，甚至以另一种方式运作，在前殖民地大都市中采用了外国风俗。[第2段]，伴随着这些经济联系，出现了一个纠缠不清的世界政治舞台。边远小国的独裁者再也不能指望孤立和控制媒体来阻止人民变得焦躁不安，或阻止外国大国入侵他们的生意。小国的唯一安全是与大集团的经济利益保持一致，提供廉价的资源和劳动力，在新的世界秩序中为自己让位。[第2段]今天，世界广泛全球化，是后冷战时代资本主义胜利的产物。这是否是社会需要的，经济上可持续的，甚至是生态上可以生存的，还有待观察，而且很可能成为21世纪的重大问题之一。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_THERMODYNAMICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The energy of the universe is constant. The entropy of the universe tends to a maximum."[PARAGRAPH:2] - Rudolf Clausius, The Mechanical Theory of Heat</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“宇宙的能量是恒定的。宇宙的熵趋于最大。”[段落：2 ] - Rudolf Clausius，热的机械理论</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CROP_ROTATION</Tag>
		<English>Crop Rotation</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>作物轮作术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GEOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The word geology comes from Greek, meaning "knowledge of the earth." Throughout history, humans have searched for mineral resources valuable to them; the best flint and obsidian for toolmaking, veins of gold, silver, and gems, the ores of useful metals. The systematic rise of science in the 18th century, and the relaxation of old taboos about the nature and origin of the world, allowed scholars to think more freely about the earth, as about other subjects. These 'geologists' examined rock strata, tectonic activity such as earthquakes and volcanoes, and the patterns formed in the landscape by erosion and other forces of nature.[PARAGRAPH:2]In doing so, they replaced the old, naive picture of the world as an unchanging mass of rock. Geologists of the 19th and 20th centuries have learned that the ground we stand on is actually a series of plates of stone floating on the sea of lava that makes up most of the Earth's mass. Over the eons ("geologic time") powerful forces slowly reshape the landscape, bringing new rock closer to the surface and rearranging the terrain to form mountains and seas.[PARAGRAPH:2]Understanding geology helps us understand where to find mineral resources, and how to channel the elemental forces of earth and water to our advantage.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>地质学这个词来源于希腊语，意思是“对地球的知识”。在整个历史中，人类一直在寻找对他们有价值的矿产资源；制造工具的最好的燧石和黑曜石，金、银和宝石的矿脉，有用金属的矿石。18世纪科学的系统性崛起，以及对世界自然和起源的古老禁忌的放松，使得学者们能够更自由地思考地球和其他学科。这些“地质学家”研究了岩层、地震和火山等构造活动，以及由侵蚀和其他自然力量在景观中形成的图案。[段落：2 ]，他们将旧的、天真的世界图画替换成一块不变的岩石。19世纪和20世纪的地质学家已经认识到，我们所站的地面实际上是一系列漂浮在熔岩海上的石头板块，构成了地球的大部分质量。在亿万年（“地质时代”），强大的力量慢慢地重塑景观，使新的岩石更靠近地表，重新排列地形，形成山海。[段落：2 ]理解地质学有助于我们了解在哪里找到矿产资源，以及如何将地球和水的元素力量传导到我们的优势。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NUCLEAR_POWER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The greatest peacetime use of the power of the atomic nucleus is in nuclear reactors. In the early days after the discovery of atomic fission, this was a subject of great hope and optimism - the ideal was expressed that atomic energy would make electricity "too cheap to meter".[PARAGRAPH:2]A nuclear reactor consists of a number of 'fuel rods' or 'fuel pellets' made up of fissile materials, kept at a concentration below that needed for a critical mass. Thus, the chain reaction cannot run away as in a nuclear bomb, and simply keeps the fuel running at a high temperature, steadily heated by rapid fission of the uranium. The heat is used to power turbines through a variety of media- pressurized water, steam, or liquid sodium, for instance; the turbines power electric generators.[PARAGRAPH:2]Design of a nuclear reactor is extremely challenging. The radiation environment inside the reactor core is intense, and all substances used inside the reactor must be chosen with an eye to their resistance and behavior when faced with radioactive bombardment of neutrons. Beyond this, there are also safety concerns- a nuclear reactor contains enough radioactive materials to contaminate a large area, if those materials were spread across the landscape.[PARAGRAPH:2]Early plant designs, dating to the 1950s, often had serious safety problems associated with the designs. Since then, the nuclear industry has learned much, but its tracks are dogged by anti-nuclear advocates opposed to the use of nuclear energy. This opposition points to nuclear accidents at Chernobyl and Fukushima and questions whether modern plants are truly safe from such disasters; they also object to the fact that nuclear reactors generate radioactive waste which remains dangerous to human life for thousands of years and must be stored under special conditions.[PARAGRAPH:2]Supporters of nuclear energy reply that there are viable ways to store the waste safely, but the controversy continues to rage. The dream of power "too cheap to meter" has foundered on this, along with a host of practical issues that come with designing the heavily reinforced, disaster-resistant facilities required for the reactor and its wastes.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>和平时期使用原子核能量最多的是核反应堆。在发现原子裂变后的早期，这是一个充满希望和乐观的主题——理想的是原子能使电“太便宜而不能计量”。[段落：2 ]一个核反应堆由许多“燃料棒”或“燃料颗粒”组成，由易裂变材料组成，保持在低于所需的浓度。对于临界质量。因此，连锁反应不能像在核弹中那样跑掉，而只是保持燃料在高温下运行，通过铀的快速裂变稳定地加热。热被用来通过各种介质-加压水、蒸汽或液体钠来驱动涡轮机，例如，涡轮为发电机提供动力。[段：2 ]核反应堆的设计极具挑战性。反应堆堆芯内的辐射环境很强，在选择反应堆内使用的所有物质时，必须注意它们在面对中子的放射性轰击时的阻力和行为。除此之外，还有安全问题——如果反应堆的材料散布在景观中，核反应堆含有足够的放射性物质来污染大面积。[段落：2 ]早期的工厂设计，可追溯到20世纪50年代，常常与设计相关的严重的安全问题。从那时起，核工业学到了很多东西，但它的发展轨迹却被反对使用核能的反核倡导者所困扰。这一反对意见指出了切尔诺贝利和福岛的核事故，并质疑现代植物是否真正地免受这些灾难的影响；他们还反对核反应堆产生放射性废物的事实，这些放射性废物对人类的生命仍然危险数千年，必须储存在特殊条件下。[第2段]支持者对核能的答复是，有可行的方法来安全储存核废料，但争议仍在继续。电力“太便宜而无法计量”的梦想已经在这一点上破灭，随之而来的还有一系列实际问题，即设计反应堆及其废料所需的加固、抗灾设施。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_JUDICIARY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Society is well governed when its people obey the magistrates, and the magistrates obey the law."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Solon of Athens</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“当人民服从裁判官，治安官服从法律时，社会是很好的统治。”[段落：2 ]——雅典索伦</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STATECRAFT_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"When several villages are united in a single complete community, large enough to be nearly or quite self-sufficing, the state comes into existence, originating in the bare needs of life, and continuing in existence for the sake of a good life."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Aristotle, Politics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“当几个村庄团结在一个完整的社区里，足够大或几乎可以自给自足的时候，这个国家就诞生了，起源于生活的赤裸需求，为了美好的生活而继续存在。”[段落：2 ] -亚里士多德，政治</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNIFIED_THEORY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The universe is not only stranger than we imagine, it is stranger than we can imagine."[PARAGRAPH:2]- J. B. S. Haldane</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“宇宙不仅比我们想象的更离奇，而且比我们想象的更奇怪。”[段落：2 ]——霍尔丹。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_THERMODYNAMICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Thermodynamics is a branch of physics concerned with heat and temperature and their relation to energy and work. The behavior of these quantities is governed by the four laws of thermodynamics, irrespective of the composition or specific properties of the material or system in question. The laws of thermodynamics are explained in terms of microscopic constituents by statistical mechanics. Thermodynamics applies to a wide variety of topics in science and engineering, especially physical chemistry, chemical engineering and mechanical engineering.[PARAGRAPH:2]Historically, thermodynamics developed out of a desire to increase the efficiency of early steam engines, particularly through the work of French physicist Nicolas Léonard Sadi Carnot (1824) who believed that engine efficiency was the key that could help France win the Napoleonic Wars. Scottish physicist Lord Kelvin was the first to formulate a concise definition of thermodynamics in 1854 which stated, "Thermo-dynamics is the subject of the relation of heat to forces acting between contiguous parts of bodies, and the relation of heat to electrical agency."</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>热力学是物理学的一个分支，研究热和温度及其与能量和功的关系。这些量的行为受热力学四定律的支配，而与所讨论的材料或系统的组成或特性无关。热力学定律是用统计力学的微观组分来解释的。热力学在科学和工程，特别是物理化学、化学工程和机械工程中有着广泛的应用。〔2〕历史上，热力学是出于提高早期蒸汽机效率的愿望而发展起来的，尤其是通过法国物理学家尼古拉斯·L·奥朗德-萨迪的工作。卡诺（1824）认为发动机效率是帮助法国赢得拿破仑战争的关键。苏格兰物理学家凯尔文勋爵（Lord Kelvin）在1854年首次提出了热力学的简明定义，该定义指出：“热动力学是热与作用在物体相邻部分之间的力的关系，以及热与电的关系的主题。”</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CROP_ROTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Crop rotation is the practice of planting different species of crops in the same field in a continuous cycle. This is extremely useful as a way to improve farm productivity, because any given crop will absorb certain nutrients from the soil while leaving others in place or even enriching them. Over time, growing the same crops in a field over and over will exhaust its nutrients and make it useless. By rotating crops, a farmer can intersperse these periods of nutrient drain with periods where the crops actively replenish the soil; this is often achieved using legume crops such as beans, which enrich soil with nitrogen that many other plants need to grow.[PARAGRAPH:2]Crop rotation was introduced in various parts of the world during the classical and medieval periods. Over time it has become a more complex practice; each improvement in crop rotation practices provided a boost in agricultural productivity. While today, chemical fertilizers often take the place of crop rotation by replacing soil nutrients artificially, crop rotation remains an important technique for farmers to know, especially if they wish to avoid relying totally on the fertilizer supply.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>轮作是指在同一块地上连续循环种植不同种类的作物。这对于提高农业生产力是非常有用的，因为任何一种作物都会从土壤中吸收某些养分，而其他作物则留在土壤中，甚至使土壤更加肥沃。随着时间的推移，在一块地里一遍又一遍地种植同样的作物会耗尽它的养分，使它变得无用。通过轮作，农民可以将这些养分流失的时期与作物积极补充土壤的时期穿插在一起；这通常是通过豆类作物（如豆类）实现的，其中富含氮的植物是许多其他植物需要生长的。〔2〕作物轮作是在世界各地的古典和中世纪时期传入的。随着时间的推移，这已经成为一种更加复杂的做法；作物轮作做法的每一次改进都提高了农业生产力。虽然现在化肥常常通过人工代替土壤养分来代替轮作，但轮作仍然是农民了解的一项重要技术，特别是如果他们希望避免完全依赖肥料供应的话。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AUTOMATION</Tag>
		<English>Automation</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>自动化</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EDUCATION</Tag>
		<English>Education</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>教育学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STATECRAFT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Statecraft refers to the administration of the internal and external affairs of a state in a professionalised fashion. In the Middle Ages, states were usually administered by feudal rulers who attained their position through birthright, so their approach to administration was mostly guided by tradition and personal experience.[PARAGRAPH:2]The increasing centralisation and bureaucracy of the early modern state meant that rulers increasingly relied on government officials like governors and diplomats. The highest of these officials formed the cabinet or council of their monarch.[PARAGRAPH:2]Internally, this meant that the state was much more effective in accomplishing its goals, such as levying taxes, enforcing laws and raising armies. It also revolutionised international relations. States would transition to maintain ongoing diplomatic contacts and formalise their relationship through a series of treaties.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>治国之道是指以专业化的方式管理国家的内政和对外事务。在中世纪，国家通常由封建统治者管理，他们通过与生俱来的权利获得自己的地位，因此，他们的管理方式主要是由传统和个人经验来指导的。[段落：2 ]早期现代国家日益集中化和官僚化意味着统治者越来越依赖政府官员，如州长和外交官。这些官员中最高的组成了他们的君主内阁或委员会。[第2段]在内部，这意味着国家更有效地实现其目标，比如征税、执法和军队的提升。它也彻底改变了国际关系。各国将通过一系列条约进行过渡，以保持持续的外交接触并使其关系正式化。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SHIPBUILDING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Shipbuilding is the art of constructing large watergoing vessels for travel on large bodies of water. As the demand for larger, safer vessels to cross the oceans of the ancient world grew, so did knowledge of ship construction. By far the preferred method for building such ships was to make them out of wood - preferably the hardest, strongest timber available, even if this had to be imported over long distances. Great strides in the art of carpentry made it possible to assemble large ships that would be strong enough to withstand the forces of the sea, but flexible enough not to break under heavy impact.[PARAGRAPH:2]Larger, heavier ships were generally more useful for trade because they could carry a greater volume of goods. They were also more useful for warfare. Ancient naval war revolved around deliberate ramming attacks, boarding parties and sailors firing musclepowered missile weapons at each other. A larger ship would be harder to damage by ramming, would have the tactical advantage of being 'the high ground' in combat, and could carry a larger army with which to capture enemy ships.[PARAGRAPH:2]Ongoing advances in shipbuilding continued steadily from the Bronze Age up to the present day in many parts of the world. Nations which enjoyed an advantage in the art at any particular time were usually able to dominate the seas for vast distances around their homeland.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>造船是建造大型水运船舶在大型水体上航行的艺术。随着远古世界对更大、更安全的船只越洋需求的增长，造船知识也随之增长。到目前为止，建造这类船只的首选方法是用木材制造——最好是最坚硬、最结实的木材，即使这种木材必须从很远的地方进口。木工技术的巨大进步使得组装大型舰船成为可能，这些船足够强大，足以抵御海上的力量，但在足够大的冲击下不足以折断。（2段）较大、较重的船通常对贸易更有用，因为它们可以运载更多的货物。它们在战争中也更有用。古代的海战围绕着蓄意的撞击攻击，登船队和水兵互相发射肌肉发达的导弹武器。一艘更大的船只将更难被打夯破坏，将具有战术优势，成为战斗中的“高地”，并能携带一支更大的军队来占领敌舰。[段：2 ]在世界许多地区造船业的持续发展从青铜时代一直持续到现在。在任何特定时期在艺术上享有优势的国家，通常能够在其祖国周围的广阔海域中称霸大海。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POLITICS</Tag>
		<English>Politics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>政治学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GEOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Man, a mere inhabitant of the earth, cannot overstep its boundaries! But though he is confined to its crust, he may penetrate into all its secrets."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Jules Verne, The Steam House</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“人类，仅仅是地球上的居民，不能逾越它的疆界！虽然他被困在地壳中，但他可以洞察所有的秘密。”[段落：2 ]——Jules Verne，蒸汽之家。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RADAR_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Vision is the art of seeing things invisible."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Jonathan Swift</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“视觉是看不见事物的艺术。”[段落：2 ] -乔纳森·斯威夫特</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CARTOGRAPHY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Cartography is the art of making maps. Since any traveler will do well to have maps of the territory they move through, good maps have been in demand for as long as the art of writing made it possible to create them. Early maps were often crude, with the shapes of continents and the relative position of cities and landmarks grossly distorted. Portions of the map with which the artist was unfamiliar were often decorated with fanciful place-names and the images of fictional creatures, as in the famous "here there be dragons."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Cartography became more of a science during the medieval period, with advances in mathematics and surveying techniques. Growing and spreading populations helped as well - it's easier and more practical to make an accurate map of cultivated fields and townships than of a howling wilderness. During the European Age of Exploration, the art of mapmaking advanced hand in hand with the art of navigation - the one being nearly impossible without the other.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>制图是制作地图的艺术。因为任何一个旅行者都会很好地拥有他们所穿越的领土的地图，只要写作的艺术使他们有可能创造出好的地图，那么好的地图就一直是人们的需求。早期的地图往往是粗糙的，大陆的形状以及城市和地标的相对位置严重扭曲。艺术家不熟悉的地图部分常常装饰着奇特的地名和虚构的生物形象，如著名的“这里有龙”。[新线][新线]随着数学和测量技术的进步，地图学在中世纪变得更为科学。人口的增长和扩散也起到了一定的作用——与咆哮的荒野相比，准确绘制耕地和城镇地图更容易、更实用。在欧洲探索时代，制图艺术与航海艺术齐头并进——没有航海艺术，几乎不可能有航海艺术。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MATHEMATICS</Tag>
		<English>Mathematics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>数学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CEMENT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A cement is a binder, a substance used in construction that sets, hardens and adheres to other materials, binding them together. Cement is seldom used solely, but is used to bind sand and gravel (aggregate) together. Cement is used with fine aggregate to produce mortar for masonry, or with sand and gravel aggregates to produce concrete.[PARAGRAPH:2]Lime was used on Crete and by the ancient Greeks. It is uncertain where it was first discovered that a combination of hydrated non-hydraulic lime and a pozzolan produces a hydraulic mixture, but concrete made from such mixtures was used by the Ancient Macedonians and three centuries later on a large scale by Roman engineers.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the absence of pozzolanic ash, the Romans used powdered brick or pottery as a substitute and they may have used crushed tiles for this purpose before discovering natural sources near Rome. The huge dome of the Pantheon in Rome and the massive Baths of Caracalla are examples of ancient structures made from these concretes, many of which are still standing. The vast system of Roman aqueducts also made extensive use of hydraulic cement.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>金属铸造是制造金属物体的一种方法。当受到极热时，金属熔化成液体。熔化的金属被倒入模具中，在那里冷却并返回固态，保持模具内部空间的形状。一旦对象被移除，模具就可以被重复使用以形成一个相同的对象。[段落：2 ]金属铸造是一个复杂的过程。首先创建模具。“脱蜡”工艺是一种有效的方法来创造一个模具，已使用自青铜时代。在这个过程中，工匠在蜡中创建一个复制品，或“积极的”副本，对象的铸造。然后工匠用粘土覆盖蜡制品。在窑中烧制时，粘土会在蜡周围变硬，从而产生物体的“负面”图像。这是模具。（原来的蜡在加工过程中是正熔化的，因此它的标题。）模具通常是在两个或两个以上的部件中形成的，这样铸造金属就可以在不破坏模具的情况下被移除。[段落：2 ]金属铸造比早期锻造金属的方法具有一些重要的优点。在铁匠工艺中，铁匠对金属进行加热和锤击，直到达到所需的形状。这是一个困难的过程，需要很多技巧。这也相当耗时，因为史密斯一次只能处理一个对象。另一方面，金属铸造的效率要高得多。一旦一个熟练的工匠创造了一个模具，它可以被不太熟练的工人一遍又一遍地使用，在很大程度上可以确定成品是相同的。实际上，可以创建一个模具，它将生成多个较小对象的副本，例如矛头和匕首。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOTECHNOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Bionics is one name for the effort to create machines that can duplicate functions of human body parts. This has obvious applications in medicine, where it allows people who have lost limbs, sensory organs, or even hearts to survive with mechanical substitutes. Other effects of this growing field, placed as it is at the cutting edge of automation, miniaturization, and our understanding of how brain and body operate, are more subtle but perhaps no less profound.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Advanced bionics might allow the creation of synthetic androids whose superficially human appearance lends itself to a variety of roles. They might become popular as replacements or augmentations for functioning body parts - if an artificial eye sees more clearly, some may prefer it to their natural one. Taken to its logical extreme, bionics might even cause us to call into question the very meaning of what it is to be human, an issue mostly considered the province of science fiction to date.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>仿生学是创造能复制人体各部分功能的机器的一个名称。这在医学上有着明显的应用，它可以让失去四肢、感觉器官甚至心脏的人通过机械替代品存活下来。这个不断增长的领域的其他影响，因为它处于自动化、小型化和我们对大脑和身体如何运作的理解的前沿，更微妙，但可能也同样深刻。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]先进的仿生学可能允许合成机器人的创造，其表面上的人类外表赋予了自己多种角色。它们可能会成为人体功能部件的替代品或增强品，如果人造眼睛看得更清楚，有些人可能更喜欢它而不是自然的。从逻辑上讲，仿生学甚至可能使我们对它是什么样的人的意义产生疑问，这个问题到目前为止大多被认为是科幻小说的范畴。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EXPLOSIVES_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"You can bomb the world to pieces but you can't bomb it into peace."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Michael Franti</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“你可以把世界炸成碎片，但你不能把它轰炸成和平。”[段落：2 ] - Michael Franti</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SCHOLARSHIP_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"There is no wealth like knowledge, no poverty like ignorance."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Ali ibn Abi-Talib, Regarding Knowledge and Wisdom</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“没有财富像知识，没有贫穷像无知。”[段落：2 ] -阿里伊本阿比塔利布，关于知识和智慧</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRICITY</Tag>
		<English>Electricity</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>电学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FIREARMS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In its first centuries, gunpowder was too unstable and metallurgy too crude for the new explosive mix to be used for applications other than demolitions, fireworks, and large, heavily overbuilt artillery pieces. But with advances in metalworking in the 15th and 16th centuries CE, it became possible to create man-portable gunpowder weapons, which began to supplement and then to replace earlier ranged weapons such as the bow, crossbow, and sling.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the 17th century, the world's most modern armies relied in large part on blocks of musket-armed infantry, often supported by pike units to keep cavalry from running down the musketeers while they reloaded their clumsy weapons. The pike units were removed entirely with the development of the bayonet, and ever since that era infantry combat has been dominated by the role of the gun and advances in firearms technology.[PARAGRAPH:2]Even though early firearms were little if any deadlier than a good bow on average, they triggered a revolution in warfare. Firearms were easy to learn to use, and incredibly easy to mass produce compared to the cost of a suit of "bullet proof" steel armor. This helped drive the last nails into the coffin of heavily armored shock cavalry in Europe, ended the dominance of nomadic horse-archer cultures in Asia, and triggered a shift towards mass armies recruited from among the populace, ultimately paving the way for the revolutionary levée en masse of the Napoleonic French.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在它的第一个世纪，火药太不稳定，冶金太粗糙，新的爆炸混合物不能用于除拆除、焰火和大型、严重超建的炮弹之外的其他用途。但是在第十五和第十六世纪CE金属加工方面的进步，可以制造出便携式手榴弹武器，它开始补充，然后取代更早的远程武器，如弓、弩和吊索。[段：2 ]到十七世纪，世界上最现代化的军队在很大程度上依赖于步枪武装的步兵，通常由长矛部队支持，以防止骑兵在他们重新装填笨重武器的时候撞倒火枪手。派克部队完全是随着刺刀的发展而被移除的，从那时起，步兵战斗就被枪的作用和武器技术的进步所支配。[段落：2 ]，尽管早期的枪支几乎没有比平均的弓箭更致命，但却引发了一场战争的革命。与一套“防弹”钢甲的成本相比，火器很容易学会使用，也很容易大量生产。这有助于把最后的钉子钉进欧洲重装突击骑兵的棺材里，结束了亚洲游牧马弓箭手文化的统治，并引发了向从民众中招募的大规模军队的转变，最终为拿破仑法国人的革命大军铺平了道路。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GEOLOGY</Tag>
		<English>Geology</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>地质学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SCIENTIFIC_METHOD_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I do not feel obliged to believe that the same God who has endowed us with sense, reason, and intellect has intended us to forgo their use."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Galileo Galilei, Letter to the Grand Duchess Christina</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我不觉得有必要相信同一位赋予我们理智、理智和智慧的上帝已经让我们放弃了他们的使用。”[段落：2 ]伽利略-伽利略，给大公爵夫人克莉丝汀的信。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARITHMETICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Arithmetic is a branch of mathematics that consists of the study of numbers, especially the properties of the traditional operations between them - addition, subtraction, multiplication and division. Arithmetic is an elementary part of number theory, and number theory is considered to be one of the top-level divisions of modern mathematics, along with algebra, geometry, and analysis.[PARAGRAPH:2]The earliest written records indicate the Egyptians and Babylonians used all the elementary arithmetic operations as early as 2000 BC. The hieroglyphic system for Egyptian numerals, like the later Roman numerals, descended from tally marks used for counting. Early number systems that included positional notation were not decimal, including the sexagesimal (base 60) system for Babylonian numerals and the vigesimal (base 20) system that defined Maya numerals. Because of this place-value concept, the ability to reuse the same digits for different values contributed to simpler and more efficient methods of calculation.[PARAGRAPH:2]The continuous historical development of modern arithmetic starts with the Hellenistic civilization of ancient Greece, although it originated much later than the Babylonian and Egyptian examples. Prior to the works of Euclid around 300 BC, Greek studies in mathematics overlapped with philosophical and mystical beliefs. Greek numerals were used by Archimedes, Diophantus and others in a positional notation not very different from ours.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>算术是数学的一个分支，它包括对数字的研究，特别是对数字之间的传统运算的性质的研究——加、减、乘、除。算术是数论的一个基本部分，数论被认为是现代数学的一个顶级分支，连同代数、几何学和分析。[段落：2 ]最早的书面记录表明埃及人和巴比伦人早在公元前2000年就使用了所有的基本算术运算。埃及数字的象形文字系统，与后来的罗马数字一样，是从用于计数的计数符号发展而来的。早期包括位置记数法的数字系统不是十进制的，包括巴比伦数字的六进制（以60为基数）系统和定义玛雅数字的维格斯梅尔（以20为基数）系统。由于这一地方价值观念，对不同的价值使用相同的数字的能力促成了更简单和更有效的计算方法。[段：2 ]现代算术的连续历史发展始于古希腊的希腊文明，尽管它起源于比比伦和希腊。埃及的例子。在约公元前300年欧几里得的著作之前，希腊的数学研究与哲学和神秘信仰重叠。阿基米德、丢番图和其他人使用希腊数字时所用的位置记法与我们的不太一样。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RIDING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The horse was first domesticated for transportation and warfare by tribesmen on the Asian steppes. These tribesmen used their superior mobility and speed to overwhelm the proto-civilizations just rising in southeast Europe and the Middle East. In approximately 2000 BCE, domestic horses were introduced into Mesopotamia. Within the next several centuries, horses had spread throughout much of Europe and northern Africa. It was not long before nearly every civilization had put horses to work as field animals and as a means of transportation. Horses also went on to play an important role in the military conflicts of nearly every civilization in the world, both as mounts for horsemen and cavalry, and as draft animals for pulling war chariots and heavy weapons into battle.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>这匹马最初是由亚洲大草原上的部落人驯养用来运输和作战的。这些部落人利用其优越的机动性和速度压倒了刚刚在东南欧和中东崛起的原始文明。大约在公元前2000年，家马被引入美索不达米亚。在接下来的几个世纪里，马已经遍布欧洲大部分地区和北非。不久以后，几乎所有的文明都把马当作牲畜和交通工具。马匹在世界上几乎每一个文明的军事冲突中都扮演着重要的角色，既作为骑兵和骑兵的坐骑，又作为战车和重型武器开战的牵引动物。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CALENDAR</Tag>
		<English>Calendar</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>历法</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MINING</Tag>
		<English>Mining</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>采矿</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ACADEMIA_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"It is the mark of an educated mind to be able to entertain a thought without accepting it."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Aristotle, Nicomachean Ethics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一个受过教育的人的头脑是能够接受一个想法而不接受它的标志。”[段落：2 ] -亚里士多德，Nicomachean伦理学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_INSURANCE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Insurance is, at its core, a way of managing risk using contracts and the legal system. An insurance policy guarantees to the individual that, in the event that they suffer some sort of defined loss, they will be compensated for the resulting damages. This is widely desired in the modern world because a single accident can cause life-altering, massive consequences for individuals, or even for large organizations. Durable items of property such as complex machines, homes, and workplaces represent the accumulated hard work of years, and can be lost overnight in case of emergency. It is seldom practical for individuals and corporations to store up enough money to replace the losses quickly, so such emergencies can lead to ruin.[PARAGRAPH:2]Insurance systems operate by collecting small "premiums" of money from a large base of clients, and then pooling this money to use in case a disaster strikes any one of the clients. Since the disasters are generally highly unlikely, spreading the risk of loss and damage among numerous clients can reduce the cost of insurance to a very manageable level. The use of scientific statistical calculations can predict the risk of disaster and allow the insurance provider to tailor their coverage to the individual - those who are deemed 'high risk' typically end up paying larger premiums. This is meant to compensate for the increased danger that the insurer will have to pay to cover the accidents they are likely to suffer.[PARAGRAPH:2]Insurance is an extremely complex field morally, economically, and legally. Insurance companies often hold onto large sums of money, and by the nature of their business tend to extract considerable profit from the fear of crises, from those who fear illness, injury, or property damage. Insurance contracts can be immensely complicated in an attempt to limit the insurance company's payout in case the client acts in ways they deem improper.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, insurance is likely to remain a permanent part of civilized life, a direct result of the human desire to reduce the risks of life in a dangerous world - and to replace them with steady, predictable costs of doing business.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>保险的核心是利用合同和法律制度来管理风险。保险单向个人保证，如果他们遭受某种确定的损失，他们将得到赔偿所造成的损害。在现代社会，这是人们普遍期望的，因为一次事故可以改变生命，给个人，甚至是大型组织带来巨大的后果。耐用的财产，如复杂的机器、房屋和工作场所，代表着多年来积累的辛勤劳动，在紧急情况下可能一夜之间丢失。对于个人和企业来说，储存足够的钱来迅速地弥补损失是很不现实的，所以这样的紧急情况会导致破产。[段：2 ]保险系统通过从一大群客户身上收集小额的“保费”来运作，然后汇集这笔钱以防灾难降临到任何一个客户身上。由于灾害发生的可能性一般不大，在众多客户中分散损失和损害的风险可以将保险成本降低到一个非常可控的水平。使用科学的统计计算可以预测灾难风险，并允许保险公司根据个人情况调整保险范围——那些被视为“高风险”的人通常会支付更高的保费。这是为了补偿保险公司必须支付的风险，以弥补他们可能遭受的事故。[段：2 ]保险是一个极其复杂的领域，在道德上、经济上和法律上。保险公司通常持有大量的资金，并且根据其业务的性质，往往从对危机的恐惧中，从那些害怕生病、受伤或财产损失的人身上获得可观的利润。保险合同可能是非常复杂的，试图限制保险公司的支付，以防止客户采取不正当的方式行事。[段落：2 ]然而，保险很可能仍然是文明生活的永久部分，这是人类希望在危险的世界中减少生命危险的直接结果，并取代它们。以稳定的，可预测的成本做生意。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CEMENT_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"A man who builds his own pedestal had better use strong cement."[PARAGRAPH:2] - Anna Quindlen</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“建造自己的基座的人最好使用坚固的水泥。”[段落：2 ] -安娜·昆德兰</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PAPER</Tag>
		<English>Paper</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>造纸术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SOCIOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Social science is a major category of academic disciplines, concerned with society and the relationships among individuals within a society. It in turn has many branches, each of which is considered a "social science". The social sciences include economics, political science, human geography, demography, psychology, sociology, anthropology, archaeology, jurisprudence, history, and linguistics. The term is also sometimes used to refer specifically to the field of sociology, the original 'science of society', established in the 19th century. A more detailed list of sub-disciplines within the social sciences can be found at Outline of social science.[PARAGRAPH:2]Positivist social scientists use methods resembling those of the natural sciences as tools for understanding society, and so define science in its stricter modern sense. Interpretivist social scientists, by contrast, may use social critique or symbolic interpretation rather than constructing empirically falsifiable theories, and thus treat science in its broader sense. In modern academic practice, researchers are often eclectic, using multiple methodologies (for instance, by combining the quantitative and qualitative researchs). The term social research has also acquired a degree of autonomy as practitioners from various disciplines share in its aims and methods.[PARAGRAPH:2]The history of the social sciences begins in the Age of Enlightenment after 1650, which saw a revolution within natural philosophy, changing the basic framework by which individuals understood what was "scientific". Social sciences came forth from the moral philosophy of the time and were influenced by the Age of Revolutions, such as the Industrial Revolution and the French Revolution. The social sciences developed from the sciences (experimental and applied), or the systematic knowledge-bases or prescriptive practices, relating to the social improvement of a group of interacting entities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>社会科学是一个重要的学科门类，涉及社会和社会中个人之间的关系。它又有许多分支，每个分支都被认为是“社会科学”。社会科学包括经济学、政治学、人文地理学、人口学、心理学、社会学、人类学、考古学、法学、历史学和语言学。这个术语有时也被用来具体指代社会学领域，即19世纪建立的最初的“社会科学”。在社会科学的提纲中可以找到更详细的社会科学的子学科。[段落：2 ]实证主义社会科学家使用类似于自然科学的方法作为理解社会的工具，从而在更严格的现代意义上定义科学。相比之下，解释主义社会科学家可能使用社会批判或象征性解释，而不是构建经验性可证伪的理论，从而从更广泛的意义上对待科学。在现代学术实践中，研究者往往是折衷的，使用多种方法（例如，通过结合定量和定性研究）。社会研究这个术语也获得了一定程度的自主性，因为各个学科的实践者都有其目标和方法。[第2段]社会科学的历史从启蒙时代开始，在1650之后，在自然哲学中看到了一场革命。改变个人理解什么是“科学”的基本框架。社会科学产生于当时的道德哲学，受到工业革命和法国大革命等革命时代的影响。社会科学从科学（实验的和应用的）或系统的知识基础或规定的实践发展而来，与一组相互作用的实体的社会进步有关。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MACROECONOMICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"But this long run is a misleading guide to current affairs. In the long run we are all dead."[PARAGRAPH:2]- John Maynard Keynes, A Tract on Monetary Reform</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“但从长远来看，这是对时事的误导。从长远来看，我们都死了。”[段落：2 ]——约翰·梅纳德·凯恩斯，一个货币改革的领域</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MEASUREMENT_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Measure what is measurable, and make measurable what is not so."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Galileo Galilei</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“衡量什么是可测量的，什么是不可测量的。”[段落：2 ] -伽利略·伽利雷</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARITHMETICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"All things are numbers."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Pythagoras</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“所有的东西都是数字。”[段落：2 ] -毕达哥拉斯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MACROECONOMICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Macroeconomics is a branch of economics dealing with the performance, structure, behavior, and decision-making of an economy as a whole. This includes national, regional, and global economies. Macroeconomists study aggregated indicators such as GDP, unemployment rates, national income, price indices, and the interrelations among the different sectors of the economy to better understand how the whole economy functions. Macroeconomists develop models that explain the relationship between such factors as national income, output, consumption, unemployment, inflation, savings, investment, international trade and international finance.[PARAGRAPH:2]Macroeconomic theory has its origins in the study of business cycles and monetary theory. In general, early theorists believed monetary factors could not affect real factors such as real output. John Maynard Keynes attacked some of these "classical" theories and produced a general theory that described the whole economy in terms of aggregates rather than individual, microeconomic parts. Attempting to explain unemployment and recessions, he noticed the tendency for people and businesses to hoard cash and avoid investment during a recession. He argued that this invalidated the assumptions of classical economists who thought that markets always clear, leaving no surplus of goods and no willing labor left idle.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宏观经济学是经济学的一个分支，它研究整个经济体的表现、结构、行为和决策。这包括国家、区域和全球经济。宏观经济学家研究GDP、失业率、国民收入、物价指数等综合指标，以及不同经济部门之间的相互关系，以便更好地了解整个经济的运行情况。宏观经济学家建立了解释国民收入、产出、消费、失业、通货膨胀、储蓄、投资、国际贸易和国际金融等因素之间关系的模型。〔2〕宏观经济理论起源于对经济周期和货币理论的研究。一般来说，早期的理论家认为货币因素不会影响实际产出等实际因素。约翰梅纳德凯恩斯抨击了其中一些“经典”理论，并提出了一个总体理论，用总量而不是个体微观经济部分来描述整个经济。为了解释失业和衰退，他注意到人们和企业在衰退期间囤积现金和避免投资的趋势。他认为，这使古典经济学家的假设失效，他们认为市场总是清晰的，没有剩余的商品和愿意的劳动力被闲置。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RENEWABLE_ENERGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Renewable energy is a term used in industry to refer to methods of generating electrical power that can be 'renewed' indefinitely, rather than relying on some supply of fuel that will run out in the foreseeable future. We can predict that at some future time the world's reserves of uranium, natural gas, coal, and (especially) oil will run out. Or, more accurately, there will come a time at which it becomes economically impractical to extract the remaining supply of these materials, due to the extreme cost of doing so.[PARAGRAPH:2]By contrast, other sources of power are likely to go on indefinitely. Geothermal power is driven by slow radioactive decay inside the earth, tidal power by the gravitational strength of the moon, and solar power is driven by the sun. All three sources of energy will exist as long as our solar system remains in some recognizable form. Likewise, wind and hydroelectric power take advantage of the Earth's naturally occurring water and air cycles, and are driven by its weather; they will exist so long as there is weather to draw power from.[PARAGRAPH:2]Through the 20th century, renewable energy sources other than hydroelectric energy usually went relatively undeveloped. In some cases this was because of the need for computerized design and coordination to make the systems effective (especially for wind power); in others, it was purely a matter of economics, with power from expendable fuel being cheaper and easier to supply. However, in recent times, many nations have seen fit to explore renewable energy. The hope is that renewable power sources will provide lower environmental impact and longer-term, more sustainable energy into the indefinite future, after other sources of power are exhausted.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>可再生能源是工业界使用的一个术语，指的是可以无限期“更新”的发电方法，而不是依靠在可预见的未来耗尽的某种燃料供应。我们可以预测，在未来的某个时候，世界上的铀、天然气、煤炭和（特别是）石油储备将耗尽。或者，更准确地说，由于这样做的极端成本，将有可能在经济上不切实际地提取这些材料的剩余供应。[第2段]相反，其他的电力来源很可能无限期地持续下去。地热能是由地球内部缓慢的放射性衰变驱动的，潮汐能是由月球的引力驱动的，太阳能是由太阳驱动的。只要我们的太阳系保持某种可识别的形式，这三种能源都将存在。同样地，风能和水力利用地球自然发生的水和空气循环，并受天气影响；只要天气有助于发电，它们就将存在。[段落：2 ]到二十世纪，除水电能源以外的可再生能源通常相对不发达。在某些情况下，这是因为需要计算机化设计和协调，以使系统有效（特别是风力发电）；在另一些情况下，这纯粹是一个经济问题，消耗性燃料的电力更便宜，更容易供应。然而，最近一段时间，许多国家都认为开发可再生能源是合适的。希望在其他能源耗尽后，可再生能源能在不确定的未来提供较低的环境影响和更长期、更可持续的能源。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CHEMISTRY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Chemistry means the difference between poverty and starvation and the abundant life."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Robert Brent</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“化学意味着贫穷、饥饿和丰富的生活之间的差别。”[段落：2 ] - Robert Brent</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PHYSICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"To every action there is always opposed an equal reaction."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Isaac Newton, Philosophiae Naturalis Principia Mathematica</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“对每一个行动总是反对平等的反应。”[段落：2 ] -艾萨克·牛顿，哲学自然原则Mathematica</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DIVINATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Our remedies oft in ourselves do lie, which we ascribe to heaven: the fated sky."[PARAGRAPH:2]- William Shakespeare, All's Well That Ends Well</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我们自己的补救办法是撒谎，我们把它归咎于天堂：命中注定的天空。”[段落：2 ] -威廉·莎士比亚，一切都好，结果很好。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CHARITY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Charity is the virtue of willingness to give, to use one's time, resources, and influence for the benefit of others who need those things. Charity has been an ideal promoted by many cultures and numerous world religions throughout history. In the earliest recorded times and simplest known national governments, the charity of leaders such as kings and priests allowed an orderly redistribution of wealth. This served to take place of the traditional reciprocal behaviours of tribal cultures, implementing sharing and mutual protection on a larger scale.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As the complexity of social systems and the philosophical refinement of social mores evolved through the ages, the practice of charity by hierarchies grew more pronounced. In the modern era, virtually all developed societies provide some degree of organized charity to the groups they deem vulnerable, such as children, the elderly, single parents, the unemployed, the sick, workers in economic sectors threatened by social, economic, and technological change, or underdeveloped foreign countries. This practice is augmented by similar charity practiced by private individuals (e.g. the Gates Foundation) and international organizations (e.g. Medicins Sans Frontieres).</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>慈善是一种愿意付出、愿意利用自己的时间、资源和影响力为需要这些东西的人谋福利的美德。历史上，慈善一直是许多文化和世界宗教提倡的理想。在有记录的最早时期和最简单的已知国家政府中，国王和牧师等领导人的慈善事业允许财富的有序再分配。这有助于取代部落文化的传统互惠行为，在更大的范围内实现共享和相互保护。[新线][新线]随着社会制度的复杂性和社会习俗的哲学精化在各个时代的演变，等级制慈善的做法越来越明显。在现代，几乎所有发达社会都向他们认为脆弱的群体，如儿童、老年人、单亲父母、失业者、病人、受社会、经济和技术变革威胁的经济部门的工人或不发达的外国提供某种程度的有组织的慈善。私人（如盖茨基金会）和国际组织（如无国界医生组织）开展的类似慈善活动进一步加强了这一做法。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FIREARMS</Tag>
		<English>Firearms</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>热兵器军队</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REFRIGERATION</Tag>
		<English>Refrigeration</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>制冷</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GUILDS</Tag>
		<English>Guilds</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>行会</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NANOTECHNOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"In nanotech, matter becomes code."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Steve Jurvetson</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“在纳米技术中，物质变成了代码。”[段落：2 ] - Steve Jurvetson</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPANIES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A company is a legal entity made up of an association of people, be they natural, legal, or a mixture of both, for carrying on a commercial or industrial enterprise. Company members share a common purpose and unite in order to focus their various talents and organize their collectively available skills or resources to achieve specific, declared goals.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Middles Ages saw continuous advances in financial tools, first in China, but later also in the Middle East and Europe. This enabled more successful organised cooperation between people, even over large geographic distances.[PARAGRAPH:2]Companies were often established to engage in trading ventures or for similar business purposes, especially to facilitate long distance trade. A similar development took place in military organisation: private military companies were established who offered their services to various powers in small and large conflicts. The most prominent examples include Swiss mercenaries and Italian condottieri.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>公司是由自然人、法人或两者的混合体组成的法人实体，用于经营商业或工业企业。公司成员有一个共同的目的，并团结起来，以集中他们的各种人才和组织他们的共同可用的技能或资源，以实现具体的，宣布的目标。[段：2 ]中年人看到金融工具的不断进步，首先在中国，但后来也在中东和欧洲。这使得人们之间更成功的有组织的合作，甚至在很大的地理距离上。[段：2 ]公司通常被建立来从事交易风险或类似的商业目的，特别是促进长途贸易。军事组织也出现了类似的情况：成立了私营军事公司，在大小冲突中为不同的国家提供服务。最突出的例子包括瑞士雇佣军和意大利康多蒂耶里。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EVANGELISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Evangelism is an interpretation of religion which sees expanding itself as a sacred duty. This view begins with the idea of a specific religion as being at the centre of one's existence. To the evangelist, it isn't simply a matter of appeasing one's own gods, with other people having other gods. It isn't a matter of trying to become personally enlightened. No, this enlightenment must be spread to others, or the reverence of this god must be something that it would be good for everyone to share.[PARAGRAPH:2]Therefore, to the evangelist, the very existence of unbelievers is a disastrous state of the world. It is a crisis facing the souls of the human race, an emptiness in the collective spirit of humanity, and possibly a personal insult as well. Evangelists will go forth and preach to others, converting outsiders to the faith, and to their own specific versions of the faith- by hook or by crook.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>布道是对宗教的一种诠释，它把扩张自己视为神圣的职责。这种观点从一个特定的宗教作为一个人存在的中心的观点开始。对布道者来说，这不仅仅是安抚自己的神，其他人也有其他神。这不是一个试图让自己开悟的问题。不，这个启蒙必须传播给其他人，或者这个神的敬畏必须是每个人都能分享的东西。[段落：2 ]因此，对于福音传道者来说，不信者的存在是一个灾难性的世界状态。这是人类灵魂面临的危机，是人类集体精神的空虚，也可能是个人的侮辱。福音传道者会出去向其他人布道，使外人皈依信仰，并皈依他们自己的信仰的具体版本——不择手段。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MACROECONOMICS</Tag>
		<English>Macroeconomics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宏观经济学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_INSURANCE</Tag>
		<English>Insurance</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>保险</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POWER_PROJECTION</Tag>
		<English>Power Projection</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>军力投送</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TELEVISION</Tag>
		<English>Television</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>电视机</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DOCTRINE</Tag>
		<English>Doctrine</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宗教教条</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ALLOYS</Tag>
		<English>Alloys</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>合金</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TANNING</Tag>
		<English>Tanning</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>鞣毛制造</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ATOMIC_PHYSICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"By convention, sweet; by convention, bitter; by convention, colour; but, in reality, atoms and the void."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Democritus</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“按惯例，甜，按惯例，苦；按惯例，颜色；但实际上，原子和空虚。”[段落：2 ] -德谟克里特斯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_JURISPRUDENCE</Tag>
		<English>Jurisprudence</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>法理学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AERODYNAMICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Aerodynamics is the study of designing objects so that they will go smoothly through the air, rather than having to constantly waste energy battering through air resistance.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the early days of flight, aerodynamics was a somewhat informal science, and advances in engine power that gave aircraft more brute-force ability to push through the air were often more important. This began to change in the 1920s and 1930s, when aerodynamic designs became more popular not only for monocoque-hulled aircraft, but also for trains and automobiles.[PARAGRAPH:2]Aerodynamics became all the more important when engineers attempted to design more complex and advanced aircraft, such as helicopters (which are inherently unstable, and must be designed carefully to be flyable) and supersonic jets (since passing the speed of sound can rip an aircraft to pieces if the design fails to deflect and make use of shockwaves created by breaking the sound barrier).[PARAGRAPH:2]Today, aerodynamic calculations can be made in greater detail and thoroughness than ever before, using powerful computers. This allows designers to extract the greatest possible speed and efficiency out of a given amount of engine power.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>空气动力学是研究物体的设计，使它们能顺利地通过空气，而不是必须不断地通过空气阻力来浪费能量。[ 2段]在飞行早期，空气动力学是一种非正式的科学，而发动机功率的提高使飞机更具有强大的穿透力。空气往往更重要。这在20世纪20年代和30年代开始发生变化，当时气动设计不仅变得更流行于单壳脱壳飞机，而且也用于火车和汽车。[段落：2 ]当工程师试图设计更复杂和先进的飞机，如直升机（本质上是不稳定的）时，空气动力学变得更为重要。必须仔细设计为可飞行的）和超音速喷气机（因为通过声音的速度可以将飞行器撕成碎片，如果设计不能偏转并利用打破隔音屏障所产生的冲击波）。[段落：2 ]今天，空气动力学计算可以比以往任何时候都更详细和彻底。使用功能强大的计算机。这使得设计师能够从给定的发动机功率中获得最大的速度和效率。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_JURISPRUDENCE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Jurisprudence is the theory of making legal decisions, and is practiced by judges, juries, magistrates, or other individuals or groups that are empowered to determine the right or wrong in matters of law. Jurisprudence can relate to questions about the law in and of itself, such as whether a particular case contradicts some principle enshrined in a particular nation's law. Or it can relate to questions about whether the laws are just and appropriate, and whether they are being appropriately enforced, in light of their social consequences.[PARAGRAPH:2]Many ancient societies developed bodies of law and particular methods by which a case could be judged according to the law. In many cases the law was supplemented by what is called 'precedent' - the idea that if courts have decided in the past that a certain act is legal or illegal, or that certain responses are appropriate to a certain situation, then those same decisions should be repeated in new cases, rather than changed. Observing precedent has the effect of making law more orderly and predictable, making it easier to be certain whether or not one is obeying the law, and minimizing the risk that a judge will make an inappropriate decision for personal reasons.[PARAGRAPH:2]Jurisprudence was further developed in the Middle Ages as scholarship spread and legal systems grew more complex. In Renaissance-era Europe, in Islam during the Golden Age, in China during the Tang and later dynasties, and so forth. An immense variety of philosophies of jurisprudence then evolved and continued to flourish, as each society pursued its respective concepts of law and justice, in an attempt to establish a benevolent order throught their lands.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>法理学是作出法律决定的理论，由法官、陪审团、治安法官或其他有权决定法律问题是非的个人或团体来实践。法理学可以涉及有关法律本身的问题，例如某一特定案件是否与某一特定国家法律所载的某些原则相抵触。或者，它可以涉及到法律是否公正和适当的问题，以及它们是否被适当地执行，根据其社会后果。[段落：2 ]许多古代社会发展的法律机构和特定的方法，可以根据法律来判断一个案件。在许多案件中，法律得到了所谓“先例”的补充，即如果法院过去裁定某一行为是合法或非法的，或者某些反应适合于某一特定情况，那么这些同样的决定应该在新的案件中重复，而不是改变。遵守先例有助于使法律更加有序和可预见，从而更容易确定一个人是否遵守法律，并尽量减少法官因个人原因做出不适当的决定的风险。[段落：2 ]在中世纪，随着学术的普及和法律制度的日益复杂，法理学得到了进一步发展。文艺复兴时期的欧洲，黄金时代的伊斯兰教，唐朝及以后的中国等等。随着每个社会追求各自的法律和正义概念，试图在自己的土地上建立一个仁慈的秩序，各种各样的法理学哲学随之发展并继续繁荣。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PHILOSOPHY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I think, therefore I am."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Rene Descartes, Discourse on the Method</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我想，所以我是。”[段落：2 ] -勒内·笛卡尔，关于方法的论述</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LABOUR_UNIONS</Tag>
		<English>Labour Unions</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>工会</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NOBILITY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Nobility can refer to "the nobility," a class of aristocrats who inherit the right to dominate society at large. Or it can refer to the ideals of "noble" behavior, as favored by this class.[PARAGRAPH:2]Aristocratic elites have been with human civilization for millenia. Any person with enough resources, political influence, or military power would have a great advantage in controlling others, and could use that control to further preserve their power. Naturally, anyone blessed by such a fortunate combination of power and wealth would want to pass it on to their children, so legal systems emerged to make sure that the titles and positions of nobility would be inherited safely.[PARAGRAPH:2]The most common employment for aristocrats in history has been warfare. The nobility can be sure of getting plenty of food and good living conditions, so that their children grow up big and strong. They can afford expensive, carefully crafted weapons like suits of armor, high-quality bows, and fine warhorses. And their political power meant they could easily recruit fighting men from among the people they controlled, making sure they'd have trustworthy retainers to watch their back and handle the supplies while the nobles themselves went off to fight.[PARAGRAPH:2]The ideal of military courage and self-discipline therefore plays a great role in the idea of "nobility." A nobleman is normally expected to be brave in battle, to be prepared to fight either to defend his own interests or the interests of his ruler, and to act in the ways that his society expects of warriors.[PARAGRAPH:2]Noblewomen generally were not expected to fight; for females nobility had relatively fewer attractions, except of course for the freedom it granted from drudge labor like grinding grain or tending crops.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>贵族可以指“贵族”，一类继承统治整个社会权利的贵族。也可以说是“贵族”行为的理想，正如这个阶级所青睐的。[段落：2 ]贵族精英在几千年来一直伴随着人类文明。任何拥有足够资源、政治影响力或军事力量的人，在控制他人方面都有很大的优势，可以利用这种控制来进一步维护自己的权力。当然，任何有幸拥有权力和财富的幸运组合的人都希望把它传给他们的孩子，因此法律体系的出现确保了贵族的头衔和地位将被安全地继承。[段：2 ]历史上贵族们最常见的职业是战争。贵族可以得到充足的食物和良好的生活条件，使他们的孩子长大成人和强大。他们可以负担得起昂贵的，精心制作的武器，如盔甲，高质量的弓和优秀的战马。他们的政治权力意味着他们可以轻易地从他们所控制的人中招募战斗人员，确保他们有可靠的看守人来监视他们的背部，并在贵族们去战斗的时候处理供应。[段：2 ]军事勇气和自律的理想在这个想法中起着重要的作用。贵族通常被认为在战斗中是勇敢的，准备为保卫自己的利益或统治者的利益而战，并以其社会对战士的期望行事。[段：2 ]一般来说，贵族妇女是不可能战斗的，因为女性贵族的吸引力相对较小。当然，除了它给予的自由，从苦力，如研磨谷物或照顾庄稼。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RADAR</Tag>
		<English>Radar</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>雷达技术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SEAFARING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Hoist up sail while the gale doth last. Tide and wind stay no man's pleasure."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Robert Southwell, Loss in Delay</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“趁着大风还没停，扬帆起航。潮汐和风不留人的欢心。”[段落：2 ]——Robert Southwell，耽搁了。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POLITICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Politics is the art of the possible."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Otto von Bismarck</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“政治是可能的艺术。”[段落：2 ] -奥托·冯·俾斯麦</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POWER_PROJECTION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"War is merely the continuation of politics by other means."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Karl von Clausewitz, On War</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“战争只是政治手段的延续。”[段落：2 ] - Karl von Clausewitz，关于战争</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PNEUMATICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Pneumatics is the art of using pressurized air or gas as the basis for working machinery. Pneumatics are made practical by the efficient use of metalworking (to create airtight pipes) and organic chemistry (to create glues, resins, and other substances that can form an airtight seal over cloth or other more flexible substances).[PARAGRAPH:2]Among the advantages of pneumatics are that for many pneumatic systems, the working gas is freely available and nontoxic- to wit, air. Other working gases such as carbon dioxide do present toxicity or asphyxiation hazards, but in exchange tend to allow higher performance. Pneumatic systems tend to be rugged, reliable, and safe due to their being subject to minimal levels of shock from the easily compressed gases acting as a 'cushion'.[PARAGRAPH:2]Applications include brakes, drills, motors, control systems for ventilating structures, musical instruments, automatic tools such as jackhammers, and automatically-reloading firearms.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>气动技术是一门使用压缩空气或气体作为工作机械基础的技术。气动是通过有效利用金属加工（制造密闭管道）和有机化学（创造胶水、树脂和其他物质，可以在织物或其他更柔软的物质上形成气密密封）来实现的。（2：）气动的优点是，对于许多气动系统来说，工作气体是免费提供和无毒的，即空气。其他工作气体，如二氧化碳，确实存在毒性或窒息危险，但作为交换，往往允许更高的性能。气动系统往往是崎岖的、可靠的和安全的，因为它们受到容易被压缩的气体作为“垫子”的最小程度的冲击。[段落：2 ]应用包括制动器、钻机、马达、通风结构的控制系统、乐器、自动工具，如千斤顶，自动重新装弹。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TRANSHUMANISM</Tag>
		<English>Transhumanism</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>未来科技</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POLITICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Politics, from the Greek for "of or pertaining to citizens," is the practice of influencing people, particularly with the aim of acquiring and using power within a government. The tactics and techniques of politics vary depending on the society. In autocratic societies, the key to political success is the personal appeal to the leader and their most trusted subordinates, along with efforts to undermine rivals and make them appear to be threats to the system. In democracies, a massive range of tools and methods are used to appeal to the general public and acquire their support. Likewise, practitioners of politics in democracies also seek to undermine their opponents, generally attacking their popularity - by means both fair and foul.[PARAGRAPH:2]The framework that determines what political methods are allowed in a given society can be viewed as a political 'system.' For example, long-established parliamentary democracies have a system that makes violent overthrow of the government unacceptable, such that even if such a coup succeeded, it is likely that the victorious military leader would have difficulty persuading the public to obey orders. Conversely, autocratic systems generally prohibit any form of politics that would involve organizing the masses to express disapproval of state policy.[PARAGRAPH:2]Formal theorizing on politics dates back to the time of figures such as Plato and Confucius, and represents a major transition in the history of human civilization- because it represents serious, intellectual reflection on the question "how best shall we organize ourselves?"</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>政治，源于希腊语，是指“公民的或与公民有关的”，是影响人们的行为，特别是为了在政府内部获得和使用权力。政治的策略和技巧因社会而异。在专制社会，政治成功的关键在于对领导人及其最信任的下属的个人吸引力，以及削弱竞争对手并使其看起来对体制构成威胁的努力。在民主国家，人们使用大量的工具和方法来吸引公众并获得他们的支持。同样，民主政界的从业者也在试图削弱他们的对手，通常攻击他们的受欢迎程度——即公平和污秽。[段落：2 ]确定一个特定社会允许什么政治方法的框架可以被视为一个政治“系统”。有一个制度，使暴力推翻政府是不可接受的，这样即使这样的政变成功，很可能是胜利的军事领导人将难以说服公众服从命令。相反，专制制度通常禁止任何形式的政治，包括组织群众对国家政策表示不满。[段落：2 ]关于政治的正式理论可以追溯到像Plato和孔子这样的人物时代。它代表了人类文明史上的一次重大转变，因为它代表了对“我们如何才能最好地组织自己”问题的严肃的、理智的思考</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CURRENCY</Tag>
		<English>Currency</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>货币制度</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HUNTING</Tag>
		<English>Hunting</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>狩猎</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_OPTICS</Tag>
		<English>Optics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>光学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NUCLEAR_POWER_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Our children will enjoy in their homes electrical energy too cheap to meter."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Lewis L. Strauss</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我们的孩子在家里会享受到电能太便宜而无法计量。”[段落：2 ] - Lewis L. Strauss</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ACADEMIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Academia refers to an organised community of teachers, educators and researches. The term academia originates from tradition of the classical academy in ancient Greece, especially the Academy of Plato. This early academy was a place where philosophers could teach and their followers assemble and study their philosophies.[PARAGRAPH:2]This ideas was revived in Italy during the 15th century, in particular in Florence and Rome. This new form of academy was influenced by the existing traditions of medieval universities and humanist studies in Christian Europe. Over the course of the 16th and 17th centuries, academies for a variety of fields such as science, linguistics, the arts, the military, literature and philosophy were founded all over Europe, often with the sponsorship of the government.[PARAGRAPH:2]The idea of academia fostered the exchange of ideas and dialogue between people active in these fields and is generally regarded as antecedent to the subsequent development of the scientific method, the modern university and modern forms of research.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>学术界是指由教师、教育家和研究人员组成的有组织的社区。学术界一词起源于古希腊古典学院的传统，尤其是柏拉图学院。这个早期的学院是哲学家们可以教导他们的信徒聚集和研究他们的哲学的地方。〔段落：2〕在十五世纪，尤其是在佛罗伦萨和罗马，这个想法在意大利复活。这种新的学院形式受到中世纪大学传统和基督教欧洲人文主义研究的影响。在16、17世纪，欧洲各地建立了科学、语言学、艺术、军事、文学和哲学等多个领域的学院，〔第2段〕学术界的理念促进了在这些领域活跃的人们之间的思想交流和对话，并被普遍认为是科学方法、现代大学和现代研究形式的后续发展的先行。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NANOTECHNOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Nanotechnology is the craft of creating molecular 'machinery' to perform customized chemical and biological operations at a very small scale.[PARAGRAPH:2]Up through the 20th century, the sciences of chemistry and medicine relied on naturally occuring substances, or large-scale manipulation and processing of those substances, to produce what was needed. Chemicals might be mixed in a vat and heated up, or exposed to some other substance or condition, but there was no direct interaction between the human operator and the molecules themselves: they are simply left to act in accordance to blind forces that affect every part of the material at once.[PARAGRAPH:2]The idea of nanotechnology or 'nanotech,' pioneered by figures like Eric Drexler of MIT, is that we can create complex molecules which act like tiny machine tools. These molecular tools would have identifiable parts like tiny levers, wheels, and 'grippers' made up of varying structures of single atoms. They could then grab hold of a material surface or molecules floating in a solution, and break them up or reassemble them as needed.[PARAGRAPH:2]This would have many applications. Nanotech could be used to 'build' materials with unusual or extreme properties atom by atom, to clean up dangerous chemicals, or to enter into the body and attack cancer cells or toxins. Advocates expect them to perform all manner of tasks which cannot be achieved by simpler, conventional means of industrial chemistry.[PARAGRAPH:2]One example of successful, naturally-occuring 'nanotech' is the use of biological enzymes in industrial chemistry. An enzyme can take a chemical reaction that would normally happen slowly or not at all (like sugar turning into alcohol in a fermented beverage) and greatly speed it up. Nanotechnology researchers hope to take the potential of natural enzymes and generalize them to do whatever we can imagine, by controlling the molecular structure of matter.[PARAGRAPH:2]Some say nanotechnology will totally revolutionize the production of goods and distribution of resources around the world. Others question this, pointing out that nanotech molecular machines will be inherently large, relatively fragile molecules that may not survive well outside a controlled environment. It is also uncertain whether nanotech would ever be more efficient than 'macro-scale' processes for making large objects: nanotech could be a good way to apply a coating to an engine part, but not such a good way to make the part in the first place.[PARAGRAPH:2]Still, it seems likely that 21st century chemistry and biochemistry will be greatly strengthened by advances in this field, even if industry and society as a whole are not changed so much.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>纳米技术是制造分子机械的技术，在非常小的范围内进行定制的化学和生物操作。[第2段]直到二十世纪，化学和医学科学依赖于自然产生的物质，或对这些物质进行大规模的操作和处理，生产所需的东西。化学物质可能会混合在一个大桶中并被加热，或者暴露在其他物质或条件下，但是人类操作员和分子本身之间没有直接的相互作用：它们只剩下一个盲点，它们会同时影响材料的每一个部分。[段落：2 ]纳米技术或“纳米技术”的概念，由麻省理工学院的埃里克德雷克斯勒（Eric Drexler）等人物开创的是，我们可以创造出复杂的分子，其作用就像微型机床。这些分子工具会有可识别的部分，比如由单个原子的不同结构组成的小杠杆、轮子和“夹钳”。然后，他们可以抓住一个物质表面或分子漂浮在溶液中，并根据需要将它们分解或重新组装。[段落：2 ]这将有许多应用。纳米技术可以被用来“制造”具有不寻常或极端性质的材料，一个原子一个原子地清除危险的化学物质，或者进入人体攻击癌细胞或毒素。倡导者希望他们能完成所有不能通过简单、常规的工业化学手段来完成的任务。[段落：2 ]成功的自然产生的“纳米技术”的一个例子是生物酶在工业化学中的应用。一种酶可以采取一种通常缓慢或根本不会发生的化学反应（如糖在发酵饮料中转化为酒精），并大大加快反应速度。纳米技术研究者希望利用天然酶的潜力，并通过控制物质的分子结构来推广我们所能做的任何事情。[段落：2 ]有人说纳米技术将彻底改变世界各地的商品生产和资源分配。另一些人对此提出质疑，指出纳米技术分子机器本身就是大分子、相对脆弱的分子，在受控环境之外可能无法很好地生存。纳米技术是否比制造大型物体的“宏观尺度”过程更为有效：纳米技术可能是将涂层应用于发动机部件的一个好方法，但不是第一个制造零件的好方法。[第2段]21世纪的化学和生物化学似乎有可能因这一领域的进步而大大加强，即使工业和整个社会没有发生太大的变化。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POTTERY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Hath not the potter power over the clay, to make one vessel unto honor, and another unto dishonor?"[PARAGRAPH:2]- The Bible, Romans</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>陶工岂不有权柄管理泥土，使一个器皿得荣耀，一个器皿得羞辱吗[段：2 ] -圣经，罗马人</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_RIGHTS</Tag>
		<English>Civil Rights</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>公民权利</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CONTRACT_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Men keep their agreements when it is an advantage to both parties not to break them; and I shall so frame my laws that it will be evident to the Athenians that it will be for their interest to observe them."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Solon of Athens</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“当双方都不违背协议的时候，他们就保留了他们的协议，我将制定我的法律，这对雅典人来说是显而易见的，观察他们将是他们的利益。”[段落：2 ]——雅典索伦</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPUTERS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I do not fear computers. I fear the lack of them."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Isaac Asimov</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我不怕电脑。“我害怕它们的缺乏。”[段落：2 ] -艾萨克·阿西莫夫</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SMELTING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"God has concealed in every place huge masses of silver, copper and iron, and has bestowed upon you the means of discovering them, placing upon the surface of the earth signs of the treasures hidden below; and yet do you say that you have received no benefit?"[PARAGRAPH:2]- Seneca, On Benefits</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>神在各处藏了大量的银、铜、铁，又赐给你们发现的方法，把藏在地下的财宝的记号放在地上，你们还说没有得益处吗〔2〕- Seneca，关于福利</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HYDRAULICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Water is the driving force of all nature."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Leonardo da Vinci</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“水是一切自然的动力。”[段落：2 ] -达·芬奇</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FEUDALISM</Tag>
		<English>Feudalism</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>封建制度</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CROP_ROTATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Don't judge each day by the harvest you reap but by the seeds that you plant."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Robert Louis Stevenson</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“不要用收获的种子来判断每一天，而是要根据你种下的种子来判断。”[段落：2 ] -罗伯特·路易斯·史蒂文森</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NAVIGATION</Tag>
		<English>Navigation</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>导航学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AUTOMOBILE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The earliest attempts at producing a self-propelled vehicle date back to the late 1770s. These early vehicles used bulky steam engines for power. Despite constant improvements, the steam engine ultimately proved impractical for small vehicles. The development of the internal combustion engine in the late 1800s provided a small but powerful replacement for steam engines, and were able to achieve much higher speeds. The first practical automobiles were developed in the late 19th century, by automotive pioneers in France, Germany, and the United States. By the 1920s, a number of automotive manufacturing companies were operating in the U.S., including Ford and General Motors. By 1980, more than 300 million cars and 85 million trucks were in operation throughout the world. The popularity of the automobile has led to massive improvements in the highway systems in most industrialized countries. Unfortunately, automobiles are also one of the primary sources of air pollution, and have resulted in an all time high demand for petrochemical fuels.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>最早尝试生产一种自行式车辆可以追溯到17世纪70年代末。这些早期的车辆使用笨重的蒸汽机作为动力。尽管不断改进，蒸汽机最终还是被证明不适用于小型车辆。19世纪末内燃机的发展为蒸汽机提供了一个小而强大的替代品，并且能够达到更高的速度。第一批实用汽车是19世纪末由法国、德国和美国的汽车先驱开发的。到20世纪20年代，包括福特和通用在内的许多汽车制造公司都在美国开展业务。到1980年，全世界有超过3亿辆汽车和8500万辆卡车投入使用。汽车的普及使大多数工业化国家的公路系统有了很大的改善。不幸的是，汽车也是空气污染的主要来源之一，导致对石化燃料的需求一直很高。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FISSION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"If the radiance of a thousand suns were to burst forth at once in the sky, that would be like the splendour of the mighty One. I am become Death, destroyer of worlds."[PARAGRAPH:2]- J. Robert Oppenheimer, quoting from the Bhagavat Gita</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“如果一千个太阳的光辉立刻在天空中迸发，那就如同大能者的光辉。我成了死亡，世界的毁灭者。”[段落：2 ]——罗伯特·奥本海默，从《博伽达吉塔》中引用。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_JUDICIARY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The judiciary (also known as the judicial system or court system) is the system of courts that interprets and applies the law in the name of the state. The judiciary also provides a mechanism for the resolution of disputes.[PARAGRAPH:2]Roman law was heavily influenced by Greek philosophy, but its detailed rules were developed by professional jurists and were highly sophisticated. Although codes were replaced by custom and case law during the Dark Ages, Roman law was rediscovered around the 11th century when medieval legal scholars began to research Roman codes and adapt their concepts. Latin legal maxims (called brocards) were compiled for guidance. In medieval England, royal courts developed a body of precedent which later became the common law. A Europe-wide Law Merchant was formed so that merchants could trade with common standards of practice rather than with the many splintered facets of local laws. The Law Merchant, a precursor to modern commercial law, emphasised the freedom to contract and alienability of property.[PARAGRAPH:2]As nationalism grew in the 18th and 19th centuries, the Law Merchant was incorporated into countries' local law under new civil codes. The Napoleonic and German Codes became the most influential.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>司法系统（也称为司法系统或法院系统）是以国家名义解释和适用法律的法院系统。司法机关也提供了解决争端的机制。〔2〕罗马法深受希腊哲学的影响，但其详细规则是由专业法学家发展而成的。尽管法典在黑暗时代被习惯法和判例法所取代，但罗马法在11世纪左右被重新发现，当时中世纪的法律学者开始研究罗马法典并调整其概念。拉丁法律格言（称为布罗德）是为指导而编写的。在中世纪的英国，皇家法院形成了一系列先例，后来成为普通法。一个欧洲范围的法律商人的成立，使商人可以用共同的实践标准，而不是与当地法律的许多分裂的方面进行贸易。《商人法》是现代商法的先驱，强调财产自由和可让渡的自由。〔2〕随着第十八、第十九世纪民族主义的兴起，商人法被纳入新的民法典下的国家地方法。拿破仑法典和德国法典成为最具影响力的法典。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TRANSHUMANISM_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"What has the future in store for this strange being, born of a breath, of perishable tissue, yet immortal, with his powers fearful and divine?"[PARAGRAPH:2]- Nikola Tesla, Man's Greatest Achievement</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“这个奇怪的生物，凭着一口呼吸，用易腐烂的组织而生，却以他可怕而神圣的力量而不朽，未来会怎样呢？”[段：2 ] -尼古拉特斯拉，人类最大的成就</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MYTHOLOGY</Tag>
		<English>Mythology</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>神话</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TELEVISION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"In the age of television, image becomes more important than substance."[PARAGRAPH:2]- S. I. Hayakawa</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“在电视时代，图像比物质更重要。”[段落：2 ] - S. I. Hayakawa</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MINING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The man who moves a mountain begins by carrying away small stones."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Confucius</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“搬山的人是从搬运小石子开始的。”[段落：2 ]——Confucius</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PATRONAGE</Tag>
		<English>Patronage</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>艺术赞助</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SAILING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"You cannot direct the wind, but you can adjust your sails."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Unknown</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“你不能指挥风，但你可以调整风帆。”[段落：2 ] -未知</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BALLISTICS</Tag>
		<English>Ballistics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>弹道学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SEAFARING</Tag>
		<English>Seafaring</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>航海</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEEL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The iron alloys produced up until about the 14th century were made by heating a mixture of iron ore and charcoal in a forge, then pounding the molten metal to drive out the impurities or "slag". Occasionally, the iron mixture would absorb more carbon, creating steel rather than wrought iron. Because steel proved to be less brittle and more resistant to corrosion than iron, techniques were developed to produce steel. This was done by blowing a coal derivative called coke through molten iron. Most modern steel making utilizes the "blast furnace", developed by Henry Bessemer in 1855, to accomplish this task on a large-scale basis. The strength and other qualities of steel make it the material of choice for warships, planes, and many other vehicles.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>14世纪以前生产的铁合金是通过在锻炉中加热铁矿石和木炭的混合物，然后将熔化的金属捣碎以除去杂质或“炉渣”而制成的。偶尔，铁的混合物会吸收更多的碳，产生钢而不是锻铁。由于钢比铁更不脆，更耐腐蚀，因此开发了生产钢的技术。这是通过将一种叫做焦炭的煤衍生物吹过铁水来实现的。大多数现代炼钢厂利用亨利·贝塞默（Henry Bessemer）于1855年开发的“高炉”大规模地完成这项任务。钢的强度和其他质量使其成为军舰、飞机和许多其他车辆的首选材料。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DOCTRINE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Clearly the person who accepts the church as an infallible guide will believe whatever the church teaches."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Thomas Aquinas, Summa Theologica</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“显然，接受教会作为一个可靠的向导的人会相信教会所教的一切”（段落：2）——神学总论托马斯·阿奎纳。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LEVERAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Leverage is the general principle behind all early mechanisms that rely on mechanical advantage. The six classical simple machines are: lever, wheel and axle, pulley, inclined plane, wedge and screw. [PARAGRAPH:2]A simple machine uses a single applied force to do work against a single load force. Ignoring friction losses, the work done on the load is equal to the work done by the applied force. The machine can increase the amount of the output force, at the cost of a proportional decrease in the distance moved by the load. The ratio of the output to the applied force is called the mechanical advantage.[PARAGRAPH:2]Simple machines can be regarded as the elementary "building blocks" of which all more complicated machines (sometimes called "compound machines") are composed. For example, wheels, levers, and pulleys are all used in the mechanism of a bicycle. The mechanical advantage of a compound machine is just the product of the mechanical advantages of the simple machines of which it is composed.[PARAGRAPH:2]The idea of a simple machine originated with the Greek philosopher Archimedes around the 3rd century BC, who studied the Archimedean simple machines: lever, pulley, and screw. He discovered the principle of mechanical advantage in the lever. Later Greek philosophers defined the classic five simple machines (excluding the inclined plane) and were able to roughly calculate their mechanical advantage.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>杠杆作用是所有依赖机械优势的早期机制背后的一般原则。六种典型的简易机械是：杠杆、轮轴、滑轮、斜面、楔块和螺杆。[段落：2 ]一个简单的机器使用一个单一的作用力来抵抗单一的负载力。忽略摩擦损失，在负载上所做的功等于所施加的力所做的功。机器可以增加输出力的数量，但代价是负载移动的距离成比例减少。输出与外加力之比称为机械优势。[段落：2 ]简单的机器可以被看作是基本的“积木”，其中所有更复杂的机器（有时也称为“复合机”）组成。例如，轮子、杠杆和滑轮都用在自行车的机械装置上。复合机的机械优点只是它所组成的简单机器的机械优点的产物。[段落：2 ]一个简单的机器的想法起源于希腊哲学家阿基米德在公元前三世纪，研究阿基米德简单的机器：杠杆、滑轮和螺丝。他发现了杠杆的机械优势原理。后来的希腊哲学家定义了经典的五种简单机械（不包括斜面），并能够粗略计算它们的机械优势。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RIDING</Tag>
		<English>Riding</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>骑术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRONICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The complexity for minimum component costs has increased at a rate of roughly a factor of two per year."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Gordon Moore, Cramming More Components onto Integrated Circuits</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“最小组件成本的复杂性以每年大约两倍的速度增长。”[段落：2 ]——戈登·摩尔，将更多的组件塞进集成电路。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GENETICS</Tag>
		<English>Genetics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>遗传学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HUMANITIES_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I am a man. Nothing human is alien to me."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Terence, The Self-Tormentor</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我是个男人。“没有人对我是陌生的。”[段落：2 ] -特伦斯，自我折磨者</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_URBAN_PLANNING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I found Rome a city of bricks and left it a city of marble."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Augustus Caesar</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我发现罗马是一座砖砌的城市，留下了大理石般的城市。”[段落：2 ] - Augustus Caesar</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FIREARMS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"One man with a gun can control a hundred without one."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Vladimir Lenin</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一个带枪的人可以控制一百个，没有一个。”[段落：2 ] - Vladimir Lenin</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FILM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>One of the many great inventions of the mid-19th century was 'moving pictures'. By creating a narrow strip of transparent film with tiny still images impressed on it, and rapidly moving this film past a light source, the images could be projected onto a wall or screen. Changing the image fast enough (~10 times per second) creates the illusion of motion, allowing artists to show an audience a moving, lifelike image of events on screen.[PARAGRAPH:2]This gave rise to the first "mass media." The creation of motion pictures became a professionalized industry, with a special class of artists who were experts at using techniques like camera angles and special effects to evoke emotion. It also created a new class of celebrity - the movie star, who was seen by millions on a regular basis where an ordinary actor would never appear before more than a few thousand people at a time.[PARAGRAPH:2]Film was not just used for entertainment, it became a powerful medium for education, journalism, and advertising. It also became a popular vehicle for state propaganda.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>19世纪中叶许多伟大的发明之一是“电影”。通过制作一个带有微小静止图像的窄条透明胶片，并快速将该胶片移过光源，图像可以投射到墙上或屏幕上。改变图像足够快（每秒10次）会产生运动幻觉，让艺术家在屏幕上向观众展示一个生动、生动的画面。[段落：2 ]这引起了第一个“大众媒体”。电影的创作变成了一个专业化的行业，有一个特殊的艺术家。像相机角度和特殊效果来唤起情感的技术。它还创造了一个新的明星阶层——电影明星，经常被数百万人看到，一个普通演员一次不会出现超过几千人。[段落：2 ]电影不仅仅用于娱乐，它成为教育、新闻和广告的有力媒介。它也成为国家宣传的一种流行工具。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ALCHEMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Alchemy is the study of chemical substances, in its pre-scientific form. This was often an informal art; mysticism and superstition were mixed seamlessly with pragmatic efforts to manipulate flame, metal, and liquids. Many alchemists sought out impossible goals such as the universal solvent, the elixir of youth, the secret of immortality, or means by which common metals like iron or lead might be transmuted into gold. Alchemy was fraught with frauds, cheats, and liars.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, alchemists made real contributions to society. Alchemists were the first to invent many of the basic techniques of processing chemicals, and the equipment needed to do so. Operating on a rough-and-ready empirical basis, they were able to develop substances such as acids, distilled alcoholic spirits, incendiaries, and gunpowder, which had great effects on their societies in both war and peace.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>炼金术是研究化学物质的科学前形式。这通常是一种非正式的艺术；神秘主义和迷信与操纵火焰、金属和液体的务实努力完美地结合在一起。许多炼金术士寻找不可能的目标，如万能的溶剂，青春的长生不老药，永生的秘密，或是普通金属如铁或铅可以转化成黄金的方法。炼金术充满了骗子、骗子和骗子。[段落：2 ]然而，炼金术士对社会做出了真正的贡献。炼金术士最早发明了许多处理化学物质的基本技术，并且发明了这些技术所需的设备。他们在粗糙和现成的经验基础上，能够开发出酸、蒸馏酒精、燃烧物和火药等物质，这些物质在战争和和平时期对他们的社会产生了重大影响。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_URBAN_PLANNING</Tag>
		<English>Urban Planning</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>城市规划</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SOCIAL_CONTRACT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In both moral and political philosophy, the social contract or political contract is a theory or model, originating during the Age of Enlightenment, that typically addresses the questions of the origin of society and the legitimacy of the authority of the state over the individual. Social contract arguments typically posit that individuals have consented, either explicitly or tacitly, to surrender some of their freedoms and submit to the authority of the ruler or magistrate (or to the decision of a majority), in exchange for protection of their remaining rights. The question of the relation between natural and legal rights, therefore, is often an aspect of social contract theory.[PARAGRAPH:2]Although the antecedents of social contract theory are found in antiquity, in Greek and Stoic philosophy and Roman and Canon Law, the heyday of the social contract was the mid-17th to early 19th centuries, when it emerged as the leading doctrine of political legitimacy. The starting point for most social contract theories is an examination of the human condition absent any political order that Thomas Hobbes termed the "state of nature". In this condition, individuals' actions are bound only by their personal power and conscience. From this shared starting point, social contract theorists seek to demonstrate, in different ways, why a rational individual would voluntarily consent to give up their natural freedom to obtain the benefits of political order.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在道德哲学和政治哲学中，社会契约或政治契约都是一种理论或模式，起源于启蒙时代，典型地解决了社会起源和国家对个人权威合法性的问题。社会契约论据通常假定，个人已明确或默许放弃部分自由，并服从统治者或治安官的权威（或多数人的决定），以换取对其剩余权利的保护。因此，自然与合法权利的关系问题往往是社会契约论的一个方面。〔2〕虽然社会契约论的先例在古希腊、斯多葛哲学和罗马法和教会法中都存在，但社会契约的鼎盛时期是17世纪中期至第十九世纪初。当它成为政治合法性的主导理论时。大多数社会契约理论的出发点都是在没有任何政治秩序的情况下对人的状况进行考察，托马斯·霍布斯称之为“自然状态”。在这种情况下，个人的行为只受其个人权力和良心的约束。从这一共同的出发点出发，社会契约论者试图以不同的方式证明，为什么理性的个体会自愿同意放弃他们的自然自由，以获得政治秩序的利益。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ASSEMBLY_LINE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"One cannot walk through an assembly factory and not feel that one is in Hell."[PARAGRAPH:2]- W. H. Auden</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一个人不能穿过装配工厂而不觉得自己在地狱。”[段落：2 ] - W. H. Auden</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RENEWABLE_ENERGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Ere many generations pass, our machinery will be driven by a power obtainable at any point of the universe."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Nikola Tesla, Experiments with Alternate Currents</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“在很多代人之前，我们的机器将由宇宙中任何一个点所能获得的能量驱动。”[段落：2 ] -尼古拉特斯拉，交变电流实验</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TELECOMMUNICATIONS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The value of computers increases sharply when they can be used to send information by remote access over long distances. An isolated computer is just a machine for doing calculations and controlling fixed installations. A computer network can coordinate the activities of a large organization, give all members of the group access to a single central database, or allow scattered groups of people to interact in ways limited only by the power of their computers.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Early computer networks were piggybacked onto the existing infrastructure of the telephone system, and made use of simple communication protocols devised by computer scientists and enthusiasts. Over time, the complexity of networks has increased, as has the body of technical literature and specialist skills devoted to designing, building, and maintaining them. Today, most of the world's computer networks flow together seamlessly into the Internet, a world-spanning system that allows nearly anyone on Earth to communicate with anyone else, given computer access.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>当计算机可以通过远程访问发送信息时，其价值急剧增加。一台孤立的计算机只是一台进行计算和控制固定装置的机器。一个计算机网络可以协调一个大型组织的活动，让所有成员都能访问一个中央数据库，或者允许分散的人群以仅受计算机功率限制的方式进行交互。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]早期的计算机网络被承载在电话系统的现有基础设施上，并利用计算机科学家和发烧友设计的简单通信协议。随着时间的推移，网络的复杂性增加了，专门设计、构建和维护网络的技术文献和专业技能也在增加。今天，世界上大多数的计算机网络无缝地汇合到互联网上，这是一个跨越世界的系统，只要有计算机接入，几乎地球上的任何人都可以与其他人通信。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PSYCHOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Psychology is the science of behavior and mind, embracing all aspects of conscious and unconscious experience as well as thought. It is an academic discipline and a social science which seeks to understand individuals and groups by establishing general principles and researching specific cases.[PARAGRAPH:2]In this field, a professional practitioner or researcher is called a psychologist and can be classified as a social, behavioral, or cognitive scientist. Psychologists attempt to understand the role of mental functions in individual and social behavior, while also exploring the physiological and biological processes that underlie cognitive functions and behaviors.[PARAGRAPH:2]Psychologists explore behavior and mental processes, including perception, cognition, attention, emotion (affect), intelligence, phenomenology, motivation (conation), brain functioning, and personality. This extends to interaction between people, such as interpersonal relationships, including psychological resilience, family resilience, and other areas. Psychologists of diverse orientations also consider the unconscious mind.[PARAGRAPH:2]Psychologists employ empirical methods to infer causal and correlational relationships between psychosocial variables. In addition, or in opposition, to employing empirical and deductive methods, some-especially clinical and counseling psychologists-at times rely upon symbolic interpretation and other inductive techniques. Psychology has been described as a "hub science", with psychological findings linking to research and perspectives from the social sciences, natural sciences, medicine, humanities, and philosophy.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>心理学是行为和心理的科学，包括有意识和无意识经验以及思想的所有方面。它是一门通过建立一般原则和研究具体案例来理解个人和群体的学科和社会科学。[第2段]在这一领域中，专业的实践者或研究者被称为心理学家，可以被分为社会科学家、行为科学家或认知科学家。心理学家试图理解心理功能在个体和社会行为中的作用，同时也探索认知功能和行为的生理和生物学过程。[段落：2 ]心理学家探索行为和心理过程，包括感知、认知、注意、情感（情感），智力，现象学，动机，大脑功能和个性。这延伸到人与人之间的互动，如人际关系，包括心理弹性、家庭弹性等领域。不同取向的心理学家也考虑无意识心理。[段落：2 ]心理学家使用经验方法来推断心理社会变量之间的因果关系和相关关系。除此之外，或者与之相反，一些心理学家，特别是临床和心理咨询心理学家，有时依赖于符号解释和其他归纳方法。心理学被描述为一门“中心科学”，心理学的发现与社会科学、自然科学、医学、人文科学和哲学的研究和观点相联系。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_THEOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Two cities have been formed by two loves: the earthly by the love of self; the heavenly by the love of God."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Augustine of Hippo, The City of God</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“两个城市是由两种爱构成的：人间的爱，上帝的爱。”（段落：2）——河马，上帝之城的奥古斯丁。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MEASUREMENT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>After the establishment of the scientific method, the next step in the scientific revolution was the development of accurate and reliable means of measurement. Refinements and developments of scientific instruments such as the microscope or thermometer were essential for the subsequent advances in scientific fields like biology or chemistry.[PARAGRAPH:2]Measurement was also very important during the ongoing exploration of the world. Accurate navigation was finally possible with the invention of accurate mechanical clocks. And international effort was undertaken to measure as many aspects of the natural world as possible. This led to the development of an international system for units of measurement, the metric system.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>科学方法建立后，科学革命的下一步是发展准确可靠的测量手段。科学仪器如显微镜或温度计的改进和发展对于科学或生物学等领域的后续进展至关重要。[段落：2 ]在进行世界探索期间，测量也是非常重要的。随着精密机械钟的发明，精确导航终于成为可能。国际社会也在尽可能多地测量自然世界的各个方面。这导致了国际计量单位制的发展，即公制。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SUPERMATERIALS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The matter lies before the eyes of all; everybody sees it, touches it, loves it, but knows it not."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Lucas Jennis, The Hermetic Library</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“这件事就在所有人的眼前，每个人都看到它，触摸它，爱它，但不知道它。”[段落：2 ] - Lucas Jennis，密闭图书馆</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DOCTRINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>"Dogma" refers to a firmly established body of beliefs and opinions, generally associated with religion and laid out by respected theologians within the faith. Within that religion, the dogma is considered authoritative and final - it may be clarified or expanded upon, but not contradicted. To call the basic facts of the dogma into question is, by definition, to leave the religion for some other path which may be deemed heretical.[PARAGRAPH:2]Different religions have different core bodies of dogma, which usually focus on key points of doctrine that the religious leaders consider to be of extreme importance. In Christianity, the concept of salvation through faith in Christ is a matter of dogma, although the details of how this salvation may best be achieved can vary. In Islam, it is a point of dogma that Muhammed was the last of the divinely inspired prophets.[PARAGRAPH:2]Dogma is particularly important to organized religions, since it serves to define the limits of what can and cannot be accepted as part of the faith. Learning the basic principles outlined by the dogma is considered the universal foundation of education within the religious tradition, and among the scholarly figures of the religion, all knowledge and all philosophy is likely to be interpreted through the dogma's lens. Groups which defy dogma are often forced to recant, removed from positions of official responsibility, and even violently persecuted until they rejoin the fold, flee, or die.[PARAGRAPH:2]The concept of points of dogma that a society will not tolerate violation of is not unique to religion. Many totalitarian societies feature secular political 'dogma', de facto or de jure, which cannot be violated without the hostile attentions of the state.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“教条”是指一个牢固确立的信仰和意见体系，通常与宗教有关，并由信仰内受尊敬的神学家提出。在这一宗教中，教条被认为是权威的和最终的——它可以被澄清或扩展，但不矛盾。把教条的基本事实称为问题是，将宗教留给其他可能被视为异端的路径。[段落：2 ]不同的宗教有不同的教义核心体，通常集中在宗教领袖认为极为重要的教义的要点上。在基督教中，通过对基督的信仰而得救的概念是一个教条问题，尽管如何最好地实现这种得救的细节可能会有所不同。在Islam，教条是一个教条，Muhammed是神圣的先知中的最后一位。[段落：2 ]教条对于有组织的宗教来说特别重要，因为它可以定义什么是可以接受的，什么是不能接受的，这是信仰的一部分。学习教条所概括的基本原则被认为是宗教传统中教育的普遍基础，在宗教的学术人物中，所有的知识和哲学都可能通过教条的镜头来解释。反对教条的群体往往被迫放弃，从官方责任的立场上撤除，甚至迫害，直到他们重新加入，逃跑，或死亡。[段落：2 ]一个社会不能容忍违反教义的教条的概念不是宗教独有的。许多极权主义社会的特点是世俗的政治“教条”，事实上或法律上，如果没有国家的敌对关注，这些教条是不能被违反的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SCHOLARSHIP</Tag>
		<English>Scholarship</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>奖学金制度</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SUPERMATERIALS</Tag>
		<English>Supermaterials</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>超级材料</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NOBILITY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Nonsense is the privilege of the aristocracy. The worries of the world are for the common people."[PARAGRAPH:2]- George Jean Nathan</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“胡说八道是贵族的特权。世界的忧虑是为了普通人。”[段落：2 ] - George Jean Nathan</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CALENDAR_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"For everything there is a season and a time for every purpose under heaven."[PARAGRAPH:2]- The Bible, Ecclesiastes</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“万事万物都有一个季节，一个时间在天堂下的每一个目的。”[段落：2 ] -圣经，传教士</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SUPERCONDUCTORS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Superconductivity is a phenomenon of exactly zero electrical resistance and expulsion of magnetic flux fields occurring in certain materials, called superconductors, when cooled below a characteristic critical temperature. It was discovered by Dutch physicist Heike Kamerlingh Onnes on April 8, 1911, in Leiden. Like ferromagnetism and atomic spectral lines, superconductivity is a quantum mechanical phenomenon. It is characterized by the Meissner effect, the complete ejection of magnetic field lines from the interior of the superconductor as it transitions into the superconducting state. The occurrence of the Meissner effect indicates that superconductivity cannot be understood simply as the idealization of perfect conductivity in classical physics.[PARAGRAPH:2]The electrical resistance of a metallic conductor decreases gradually as temperature is lowered. In ordinary conductors, such as copper or silver, this decrease is limited by impurities and other defects. Even near absolute zero, a real sample of a normal conductor shows some resistance. In a superconductor; the resistance drops abruptly to zero when the material is cooled below its critical temperature. An electric current flowing through a loop of superconducting wire can persist indefinitely with no power source.[PARAGRAPH:2]Superconducting magnets are some of the most powerful electromagnets known. They are used in MRI/NMR machines, mass spectrometers, the beam-steering magnets used in particle accelerators and plasma confining magnets in some tokamaks. They can also be used for magnetic separation, where weakly magnetic particles are extracted from a background of less or non-magnetic particles, as in the pigment industries.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the 1950s and 1960s, superconductors were used to build experimental digital computers using cryotron switches. More recently, superconductors have been used to make digital circuits based on rapid single flux quantum technology and RF and microwave filters for mobile phone base stations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[TAB]超导是某些金属和陶瓷的一种特性，使它们能够在完全没有电阻的情况下传导电流。因为这种超导特性仅仅在极其低温的环境中出现，这意味着它必须要以人们对低温技术的深刻认识为前提。[PARAGRAPH:1]从人们发现超导现象开始，超导体就被应用在高能磁场中——核磁共振成像系统和能量储存设备如果离开了这种独特的性质是绝对无法实现的。更让人感兴趣的是超导体的间接功劳。得益于超导体的强磁场能够产生一种悬浮效应——迈斯纳效应。这种效应有望能使过去仅出现在科幻小说中的悬浮交通工具成为现实。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNIFIED_THEORY</Tag>
		<English>Unified Theory</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>统一场论</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARITHMETICS</Tag>
		<English>Arithmetics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>算术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CARTOGRAPHY</Tag>
		<English>Cartography</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>地图学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_THERMODYNAMICS</Tag>
		<English>Thermodynamics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>蒸汽机</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PSYCHOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The mind is like an iceberg, it floats with one-seventh of its bulk above water."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Sigmund Freud</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“头脑就像冰山一样，漂浮在水面上七分之一的体积。”[段落：2 ] -西格蒙德·弗洛伊德</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MACHINERY</Tag>
		<English>Machinery</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>机械</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_METALLURGY</Tag>
		<English>Metallurgy</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>冶金术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HERITAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Heritage is that which, having been created by our ancestors, is given to us because our ancestors willed that it be given to us. The concept of heritage and similar words with the same root such as "inheritance" and "heredity" are fundamental to the human self-image. Nearly everyone feels affectionate bonds to both their ancestors and their descendants. As a result, there is a near-universal desire to make sure that one's descendants inherit the virtues, resources, and opportunities that made one's own successes possible. Conversely, there is a near-universal belief that one is entitled to practice the traditions, use the assets, and partake of the opportunities that one's ancestors enjoyed.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]More broadly, heritage can refer to the collective legacy left behind by the ancestral generations of an entire town, nation, culture, or civilization. This heritage can be material (natural resources cultivated and preserved by past generations), economic (control over property owned by ancestors), aesthetic (works of art that have endured through multiple generations), cultural (practices that protected or enriched the society in the past), or spiritual (the presumed supernatural protection of ancestral spirits, and the idea of following "the faith of one's fathers" as a gesture of unity with that which came before and that which will come in the future.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]How to efficiently preserve one's heritage, to obtain as large a share of its rewards as possible, while passing it down to the next generation in turn, is a preoccupation of most humans and most human societies. Individuals do this with legal procedures such as wills or through the practices of childrearing (intended to instill traditional virtues in the young). Nations fund museums and preservation projects, make laws regarding cultural practices, and sometimes even go to war for the sake of preserving their heritage from that which they perceive to threaten it.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>遗产是由我们的祖先创造的，由于我们的祖先的意愿而给予我们的。传承的概念和“传承”、“遗传”等具有相同根源的相似词语是人类自我形象的基础。几乎每个人都对自己的祖先和后代有着深情的纽带。因此，人们有一种近乎普遍的愿望，希望确保自己的后代继承使自己成功成为可能的美德、资源和机会。相反，有一种近乎普遍的信仰，认为一个人有权实践传统，使用资产，并分享祖先享有的机会。[新线][新线]更广泛地说，遗产是指整个城镇、民族、文化或文明的祖辈留下的集体遗产。这种遗产可以是物质的（过去几代人培育和保存的自然资源）、经济的（对祖先财产的控制）、美学的（经过几代人的艺术作品）、文化的（过去保护或丰富社会的实践）或精神的（假定的超自然保护祖先的精神，以及遵循“祖先的信仰”的理念，以此作为一种与过去和未来的统一的姿态。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]如何有效地保护自己的遗产，获得尽可能多的回报，同时将其传给下一代，是大多数人类和大多数人类社会所关注的问题。个人通过法律程序如遗嘱或育儿实践（旨在向年轻人灌输传统美德）做到这一点。各国为博物馆和保护项目提供资金，制定有关文化习俗的法律，有时甚至为了保护自己的遗产免受威胁而发动战争。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_INSURANCE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Insurance - an ingenious modern game of chance in which the player is permitted to enjoy the comfortable conviction that he is beating the man who keeps the table."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Ambrose Bierce</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“保险——一种巧妙的现代机会游戏，在这种游戏中，玩家被允许享受他打人桌的舒适信念。”[段落：2 ] -安布鲁斯·布尔斯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PATRONAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Patronage is the practice of a wealthy or powerful individual choosing to support an artist, charitable organization, scholar, or other worthy cause. This support generally takes the form of donations of money or the exercise of political influence. Patronage is vital to the survival of the arts, even in the modern era when artists can at least occasionally rely on state grants to support their activities - which arguably is itself a form of patronage.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the medieval and renaissance eras, in particular, the patronage of aristocrats, wealthy merchants, and even kings and emperors had major consequences for the evolution of human knowledge. Emperors and merchant princes funded great voyages of discovery that traveled across continents. Kings and queens adopted radical philosophers into their courts, giving the philosophers the security they needed to publish ideas about human nature, ethics, and political theory.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[表]从古代开始，艺术赞助在艺术史上占有重要地位。在中世纪和文艺复兴时期的欧洲，人们对它的了解最为详细，但在封建的日本、传统的东南亚王国和其他地方，艺术赞助往往出现在皇室或皇室制度和贵族统治一个社会并控制着大量资源的地方。塞缪尔·强森把一个守护神定义为“一个不关心一个在水中挣扎的人的人，当他到达地面时，用他来帮助他”。[段落：2 ]统治者、贵族和非常富有的人利用艺术的赞助来支持他们的政治野心、社会地位和声望。也就是说，赞助商。一些语言仍然使用mecenate一词，源于Gaius Maecenas的名字，Gaius Maecenas是罗马皇帝奥古斯都慷慨的朋友和顾问。一些赞助人，比如佛罗伦萨的美第奇，利用艺术赞助人来“净化”那些被认为是通过高利贷获得的不义之财。艺术赞助在宗教艺术创作中尤为重要。罗马天主教和后来的新教团体赞助艺术和建筑，如教堂、教堂、绘画、雕塑和手工艺品。[段：2 ]赞助艺术家和艺术作品是赞助制度中最著名的方面，其他学科也受益于赞助，包括那些人。研究自然哲学（前现代科学），音乐家，作家，哲学家，炼金术士，占星家和其他学者。像克雷蒂安·德特洛耶斯、列奥纳多·达芬奇和米开朗基罗、威廉·莎士比亚和本·琼森这样多样而重要的艺术家，都寻求并获得了贵族或教会赞助人的支持。莫扎特和贝多芬等人物也在一定程度上参与了这一体系；直到19世纪资产阶级和资本主义社会形式的兴起，欧洲文化才从其赞助体系转移到更为公开支持的博物馆、剧院、大众观众和大众消费体系，这是人们所熟悉的当代世界。[段落：2 ]这种系统继续在许多艺术领域中延续。虽然赞助商的性质已经从教堂转变为慈善基金会，从贵族到富豪，“赞助”一词在政治上比政治上具有更为中性的内涵。它可能只是指艺术家的直接支持（通常是财政支持），例如通过资助。20世纪下半叶，赞助人研究的学术分支学科开始演变，认识到赞助人现象在前几个世纪的文化生活中所起的重要作用，而且常常被忽视。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CONSTRUCTION</Tag>
		<English>Construction</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>建筑构造学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SHIPBUILDING</Tag>
		<English>Shipbuilding</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>造船</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MACHINERY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Instrumental or mechanical science is the noblest and, above all others, the most useful."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Leonardo da Vinci</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“仪器或机械科学是最高贵的，最重要的是最有用的。”[段落：2 ] -达·芬奇</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPANIES</Tag>
		<English>Companies</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>公司制</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ROCKETRY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"We have guided missiles and misguided men."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Martin Luther King Jr., The Quest for Peace and Justice</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我们已经引导了导弹和被误导的人。”[段落：2 ] -马丁·路德金，寻求和平与正义。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TOURISM</Tag>
		<English>Tourism</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>旅游业</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EVANGELISM</Tag>
		<English>Evangelism</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宗教布道</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SOCIAL_SERVICES_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Therefore a wise prince will seek means by which his subjects will always and in every possible condition of things have need of his government, and then they will always be faithful to him."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Niccolo Machiavelli, The Prince</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“因此，明智的王子将寻求他的臣民将在任何可能的情况下都需要他的政府，然后他们将永远忠实于他。”[段落：2 ] - Niccolo Machiavelli，普林斯。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_ERA_GLOBAL</Tag>
		<English>Global</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>全球化</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NOBILITY</Tag>
		<English>Nobility</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>贵族</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PROPERTY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Property refers to the concept that a certain object, idea, or place is solely under the authority of some specific person or entity, and is not available for the use of others without the consent of that 'owner.' The most basic Neolithic societies known to us usually have concepts of individual ownership of certain items, such as tools and caches of food. This is often combined with widespread sharing of the goods, usually done for purposes of reinforcing social ties.[PARAGRAPH:2]Such a practice results in very cohesive societies. However, such societies often have difficulty organizing their surplus resources to commit to large-scale projects not of immediate use to any one person (such as infrastructure, ceremonial architecture, or military expeditions). Moreover, the system tends to break down in the presence of large numbers of strangers, because it relies on individuals being willing to freely share their belongings with each other. For both these reasons, the rise of cities generally went hand-in-hand with the rise of accumulated property in the hands of social elites, a trend which has persisted throughout recorded history to the present day.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>财产是指一个特定的物体、观念或场所完全由某个特定的人或实体支配，未经“所有者”的同意，不能供他人使用的概念。我们所知的最基本的新石器时代社会通常都有某些物品的个人所有权的概念，如工具和藏品食物。这通常与广泛的货物共享相结合，通常是为了加强社会联系而进行的。[段落：2 ]这样的做法导致了非常有凝聚力的社会。然而，这些社会往往很难将其剩余资源组织起来，用于任何人都不能立即使用的大型项目（如基础设施、礼仪建筑或军事考察）。此外，该系统往往会在大量陌生人面前崩溃，因为它依赖于个人愿意自由分享自己的物品。由于这两个原因，城市的崛起通常与社会精英手中积累的财产的崛起齐头并进，这一趋势在有史以来一直持续到今天。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RAILROAD</Tag>
		<English>Railroad</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>铁路</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FLIGHT</Tag>
		<English>Flight</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>航空</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CHEMISTRY</Tag>
		<English>Chemistry</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>化学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TELEPHONE</Tag>
		<English>Telephone</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>电话</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CEMENT</Tag>
		<English>Cement</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>水泥</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GENETICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Every human gene is related to the genes of other animals and bacteria, to this great chain of being."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Walter Gilbert</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“每一个人类基因都与其他动物和细菌的基因有关，与这个伟大的生命链有关。”[段落：2 ] -沃特·吉尔伯特</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LABOUR_UNIONS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Let the workers organize. Let the toilers assemble. Let their crystallized voice proclaim their injustices and demand their privileges. Let all thoughtful citizens sustain them."[PARAGRAPH:2]- John L. Lewis</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“让工人组织起来。让劳苦的人聚集起来。让他们明确的声音宣告他们的不公正，要求他们的特权。让所有有思想的公民支持他们。”[段落：2 ] -约翰·刘易斯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FINANCE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Banking establishments are more dangerous than standing armies."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Thomas Jefferson</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“银行机构比常备军队更危险。”[段落：2 ] -托马斯·杰斐逊</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ENGINE</Tag>
		<English>Engine</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>内燃机</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AGRICULTURE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"When tillage begins, other arts follow. The farmers therefore are the founders of human civilization."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Daniel Webster, Remarks on Agriculture</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“当耕作开始时，其他的艺术也随之而来。农民是人类文明的奠基人。[ [第2段]——丹尼尔·韦伯斯特，《农业评论》</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EXPLOSIVES</Tag>
		<English>Explosives</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>炸药</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PRINTING</Tag>
		<English>Printing</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>印刷术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ROCKETRY</Tag>
		<English>Rocketry</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>火箭</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LEVERAGE</Tag>
		<English>Leverage</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>简单机械</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ALLOYS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"It is entirely seemly for a young man killed in battle to lie mangled by the bronze spear. In his death all things appear fair."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Homer, The Iliad</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一个在战场上阵亡的年轻人被青铜矛划伤躺在地上是完全合适的。在他的死中，一切都显得公平。“[段：2 ] -荷马，伊利亚特。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SAILING</Tag>
		<English>Sailing</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>航行术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SCHOLARSHIP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The scholarly method or scholarship is the body of principles and practices used by scholars to make their claims about the world as valid and trustworthy as possible, and to make them known to the scholarly public. It is the methods that systemically advance the teaching, research, and practice of a given scholarly or academic field of study through rigorous inquiry. Scholarship is noted by its significance to its particular profession, and is creative, can be documented, can be replicated or elaborated, and can be and is peer-reviewed through various methods.[PARAGRAPH:2]Originally started to reconcile the philosophy of the ancient classical philosophers with medieval theology, scholasticism is not a philosophy or theology in itself but a tool and method for learning which places emphasis on dialectical reasoning. The primary purpose of scholasticism is to find the answer to a question or to resolve a contradiction. It was once well known for its application in medieval theology but was eventually applied to classical philosophy and many other fields of study.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>学术方法或学术是学者们用以使他们对世界的主张尽可能有效和可信，并使他们为学术公众所知的原则和实践。它是通过严格的调查，系统地推进某一学术或学术领域的教学、研究和实践的方法。奖学金是以其对特定职业的重要性而著称的，它具有创造性、可记录性、可复制性或可阐述性，可以通过各种方法进行同行评议。[段：2 ]最初开始调和古代古典哲学家的哲学与中世纪神学，经院哲学本身不是一种哲学或神学，而是一种强调辩证推理的学习工具和方法。经院哲学的主要目的是找到问题的答案或解决矛盾。它曾因在中世纪神学中的应用而闻名，但最终应用于古典哲学和许多其他研究领域。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ETHICS</Tag>
		<English>Ethics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>伦理学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTIFICIAL_INTELLIGENCE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As computer technology advances its capabilities at a geometric rate, the ability of computer software to emulate intelligent decisions grows. Automation first replaces  routine, mundane labor on assembly lines, then an increasing share of service and office jobs. As the process continues, it seems likely that computers will become able to sustain true intelligence, at least for a pragmatic definition of the term.[PARAGRAPH:2]Some predict that the creation of the first artificial intelligences will lead to a 'singularity' beyond which we lose our ability to predict the course of human development: these AIs will rapidly begin to modify and improve themselves until their capabilities are little short of godlike. Others feel that this is an exaggeration of the possibilities. Regardless, artificial intelligence is likely to play a prominent role in the development of human society in the future.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>随着计算机技术以几何速度提高其能力，计算机软件模拟智能决策的能力也在增长。自动化首先取代了流水线上日常的、平凡的劳动，然后是越来越多的服务和办公室工作。随着这一过程的继续，计算机似乎能够维持真正的智能，至少是对术语的实用定义。[段落：2 ]有人预言，创造第一个人工智能将导致一个“奇点”，我们失去了预测人类发展过程的能力：这些AIS会很快开始自我改造和提升，直到他们的能力有点像上帝。其他人认为这是对可能性的夸大。无论如何，人工智能很可能在未来人类社会的发展中发挥突出的作用。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CURRENCY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Everything is worth what its purchaser will pay for it."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Publilius Syrus, Sentences</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一切都值得买主为此付出代价。”[段落：2 ] - Publilius Syrus，句子。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SOCIAL_CONTRACT</Tag>
		<English>Social Contract</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>社会契约</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TELEPHONE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A telephone, from the Greek for 'distant voice,' is an device that converts a speaker's voice into electrical impulses, transmits them to a remote receiver, permits the speaker to receive other similar signals, and converts them back into voice. This permits conversations to be had between any two owners of telephones on the same switching network.[PARAGRAPH:2]There is some debate over who invented the telephone. Many individuals were working to design them, with similar tools, throughout the 1860s and '70s. However, it is clear that within a few years of the first commercially successful telephones being created, systems of the devices were beginning to connect distant cities. The telephone allowed infinitely faster and richer exchanges of information than any pre-19th century mode of communication, and had great advantages compared to the slightly earlier telegraph as well.[PARAGRAPH:2]Early telephone technology was highly diverse, but standardized as the 20th century began and as telephone systems became increasingly networked. It was found that while a specific telephone line from one place to another was valuable, a network permitting every user to call every other user was exponentially more valuable. Elaborate systems of manually operated "switchboards" emerged, allowing connections to be made at will between different telephones on the network.[PARAGRAPH:2]Networks grew larger and the individual telephones grew more compact and user-friendly throughout the early and mid-20th centuries. After the computer revolution began in the 1950s and '60s, automated switching took the place of manually operated systems, touch-tone dialing replaced rotary phones, and long distance calls became a cheaper and more common activity connecting the world together.[PARAGRAPH:2]The next great advance, mobile telephony, came in the 1970s and '80s, reaching maturity around the turn of the millenium. Cellular networks of transceiver towers make it possible for every citizen to carry a miniaturized wireless telephone, permitting near-instant communication throughout the world. Over the past decade, this technology has been further refined and combined with further miniaturization, allowing a single handheld device to serve as telephone, camera, appointment book, a portable device for audiovisual entertainment, and a gaming platform.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>希腊语中的电话是一种装置，可以将说话人的声音转换成电脉冲，传送到远程接收器，允许说话人接收其他类似的信号，并将其转换成声音。这允许在同一个交换网络上的两个电话拥有者之间进行对话。[段：2 ]关于谁发明了电话有一些争论。在整个19世纪60年代和70年代，许多人都在用类似的工具设计它们，然而，很明显，在第一部商业上成功的电话问世的几年内，这些设备的系统开始连接遥远的城市。电话比任何19世纪前的通信模式都允许了无限快和更丰富的信息交换，并且与稍早的电报相比也有很大的优势。[段：2 ]早期电话技术高度多样化，但随着二十世纪开始标准化，电话系统也越来越多。联网。研究发现，虽然从一个地方到另一个地方的特定电话线是有价值的，但允许每个用户呼叫每个其他用户的网络却是指数级的更有价值。精心设计的手动操作的“配电盘”系统，允许在网络上的不同电话之间随意连接。[段：2 ]网络越来越大，各个电话在20世纪初和中期都变得更加紧凑和用户友好。在20世纪50年代和60年代计算机革命开始后，自动交换取代了手动操作系统，用按键拨号代替了旋转电话，长途电话成为连接世界的一种更廉价、更普遍的活动。[第2段]下一个伟大的进步，移动电话，出现在20世纪70年代和80年代，在世纪之交达到成熟。无线发射塔的蜂窝网络使每个公民都有可能携带一部小型无线电话，从而在全世界实现近即时通信。在过去的十年中，这项技术得到了进一步的改进，并与进一步的小型化相结合，使得单个手持设备可以用作电话、照相机、预约簿、用于视听娱乐的便携式设备和游戏平台。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MACHINE_TOOLS</Tag>
		<English>Machine Tools</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>机床</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_METALLURGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Metallurgy is the study of the properties of metals and the methods used to separate metal deposits from metal-bearing ores. Through the course of history, artisans have switched the materials from which they constructed weapons and tools to harder, more durable metals as they were discovered. Constant improvements in metallurgy led to the discovery of new metals and alloys that were stronger, lighter, and cheaper.[PARAGRAPH:2]By the late 19th century, metallurgy was a sophisticated science. The rise of modern chemistry led to the discovery of a vast number of 'new' chemical elements that could be used in alloys, and electric power made it possible to control the conditions under which metals were worked more finely than ever before. Metallurgists developed a vast array of new kinds of steel and other alloys, with different combinations of hardness, flexibility, corrosion-resistance, and other properties. These rapid advances in metallurgy had vast implications for almost every field of engineering.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>冶金学是研究金属的性质以及从含金属矿石中分离金属矿床的方法。在整个历史过程中，工匠们已经将制造武器和工具的材料转变为发现时更坚硬、更耐用的金属。冶金的不断改进导致了新的金属和合金的发现，这些金属和合金更强大、更轻、更便宜。[段：2 ]到十九世纪下旬，冶金是一门复杂的科学。现代化学的兴起导致了大量可用于合金中的“新”化学元素的发现，而电力使控制金属比以往任何时候都更精细工作的条件成为可能。冶金学家开发了大量新型钢和其他合金，具有不同的硬度、柔韧性、耐腐蚀性和其他性能组合。冶金的这些快速发展对几乎所有的工程领域都有着巨大的影响。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ASSEMBLY_LINE</Tag>
		<English>Assembly Line</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>生产流水线</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GENERALSHIP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In the early ancient world, armies mostly consisted of militia and levies that were only raised in the event of war. These armies were usually small enough and the ensuing warfare limited enough to be directly commanded by their political leaders.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the Roman Republic and later Empire, armies became increasingly professionalised, especially after the Marian reforms. The large extent of the Roman Empire also made it impractical for their leadership to exercise direct control over the military. Similar developments also took place in the Chinese Han dynasty.[PARAGRAPH:2]This development conferred more military and political power to the generals entrusted with military command. While this made armies more professional and successful, it also led to a different distribution of power. In the Roman Empire, generals were often the decisive factor in choosing the next emperor or disposing of an unsuccessful sitting emperor, contributing to the empires instability. In China, competing military warlords ultimately caused the collapse of the Han dynasty.[PARAGRAPH:2]This sort of political power based on military authority paved the way for the idea of nobility in the feudal sense and the system of feudalism in the Middle Ages.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在早期的古代世界，军队主要由民兵和征兵组成，只有在战争中才会被征募。这些军队通常是足够小的，随后的战争足够有限，直接由他们的政治领袖指挥。[段：2 ]在罗马共和国和后来的帝国，军队变得越来越专业化，特别是在Marian改革之后。罗马帝国的庞大规模也使得他们的领导层直接控制军队不切实际。中国汉朝也发生了类似的发展。[段落：2 ]这一发展赋予了军事指挥官更多的军事和政治权力。虽然这使军队更加专业和成功，但也导致了不同的权力分配。在罗马帝国，将军往往是选择下一个皇帝或处置一个不成功的在位皇帝的决定性因素，导致帝国的不稳定。在中国，竞争的军阀最终导致了汉朝的崩溃。[段落：2 ]这种基于军事权威的政治权力为封建意义上的贵族思想和中世纪封建制度奠定了基础。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMMUNE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"We shall be a single People of brethren, never to part in danger nor distress."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Friedrich Schiller, William Tell</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我们将成为兄弟姐妹中的一员，永不脱离危险和痛苦。”〔段落：2〕- Friedrich Schiller，William Tell</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GEOGRAPHY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Geography embraces the totality of things as the image of the head depicts it in its entirety."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Ptolemy, Geography</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“地理涵盖了事物的整体性，因为头部的整体形象描绘了它。”[段落：2 ] -托勒密，地理</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RIFLING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Political power grows out of the barrel of a gun."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Mao Zedong</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“政治力量来自枪管”（段落：2）-毛泽东</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SATELLITES</Tag>
		<English>Satellites</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>人造卫星</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GUNPOWDER_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Such I hold to be the genuine use of gunpowder: that it makes all men alike tall."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Thomas Carlyle, Sartor Resartus</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我认为这是火药的真正用途：它使所有的人都一样高。”[段落：2 ] -托马斯·卡莱尔，Sartor Resartus</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_JURISPRUDENCE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"A precedent embalms a principle."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Benjamin Disraeli</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一个先例体现了一个原则。”[段落：2 ] -本杰明·迪斯雷利</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FISHING</Tag>
		<English>Fishing</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>渔业</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LOGISTICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The officer who doesn't know his communications and supply as well as his tactics is totally useless."[PARAGRAPH:2]- George S. Patton</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“不知道他的通讯和供应以及他的战术的军官是完全无用的。”[段落：2 ] -乔治·巴顿</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AUTOMOBILE</Tag>
		<English>Automobile</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>汽车</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_OPTICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"We do not see the lens through which we look."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Ruth Benedict, Patterns of Culture</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我们看不到镜头。”（段落：2）-鲁思·本尼迪克特，文化模式</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SMELTING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Smelting is a form of extractive metallurgy; its main use is to produce a base metal from its ore. This includes production of silver, iron, copper and other base metals from their ores. Smelting makes use of heat and a chemical reducing agent to decompose the ore, driving off other elements as gases or slag and leaving just the metal base behind. The reducing agent is commonly a source of carbon such as coke, or in earlier times charcoal.[PARAGRAPH:2]The carbon (or carbon monoxide derived from it) removes oxygen from the ore, leaving behind the elemental metal. The carbon is thus oxidized in two stages, producing first carbon monoxide and then carbon dioxide. As most ores are impure, it is often necessary to use flux, such as limestone, to remove the accompanying rock gangue as slag.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the Old World, the first metals smelted were tin and lead. After tin and lead, the next metal to be smelted appears to have been copper. How the discovery came about is a matter of much debate. Campfires are about 200 °C short of the temperature needed for that, so it has been conjectured that the first smelting of copper may have been achieved in pottery kilns. The development of copper smelting in the Andes, which is believed to have occurred independently of that in the Old World, may have occurred in the same way.[PARAGRAPH:2]The discovery of copper manufacture had a significant impact on the history of the Old World. Metals were hard enough to make weapons that were heavier, stronger, and more resistant to impact-related damage than their wood, bone, or stone equivalents.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>冶炼是一种萃取冶金，其主要用途是从矿石中生产贱金属，包括从矿石中生产银、铁、铜和其他贱金属。熔炼利用热量和化学还原剂分解矿石，把其他元素如气体或炉渣赶走，只留下金属基。还原剂通常是碳的来源，如焦炭，或在早期的木炭中。〔段落：2〕碳（或来自它的一氧化碳）从矿石中除去氧，留下元素金属。因此，碳被氧化为两个阶段，首先产生一氧化碳，然后产生二氧化碳。由于大多数矿石是不纯的，因此经常需要使用熔剂，如石灰石，以除去伴随的岩石矸石作为矿渣。[段落：2 ]在旧世界，第一金属冶炼的是锡和铅。在锡和铅之后，下一个要熔炼的金属似乎是铜。这个发现是如何产生的，这是一个争论不休的问题。营火的温度比所需的温度低约200摄氏度，因此有人推测，铜的首次熔炼可能是在陶窑中实现的。安第斯山脉的铜冶炼的发展，据信是独立于旧世界发生的，也可能以同样的方式发生。[第2段]铜的发现对旧世界的历史产生了重大影响。金属的硬度足以制造出比木头、骨头或石头更重、更坚固、更能抵抗撞击相关损伤的武器。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CARTOGRAPHY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Not all those who wander are lost."[PARAGRAPH:2]- J. R. R. Tolkien, The Lord of the Rings</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“并不是所有游荡的人都迷路了”（段落：2）——《指环王》中的J·R·R·托尔金</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EVANGELISM_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Just as a candle cannot burn without fire, men cannot live without a spiritual life."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Buddha</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“蜡烛如火不可焚，人若没有精神生活，就无法生存。”[段落：2 ] -佛陀</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FILM</Tag>
		<English>Film</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>电影</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TANNING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"For one whose feet are covered with shoes, is not the earth covered with leather?"[PARAGRAPH:2]- Hitopadesha</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>脚上有鞋的，地上岂不有皮子吗[段落：2 ] - Hitopadesha</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMMUNE</Tag>
		<English>Commune</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>公社</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEEL</Tag>
		<English>Steel</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>炼钢</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CYBERNETICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Cybernetics is a term coined by pioneering computer scientist Norbert Wiener, referring to the science of studying control systems, organization, and information flow. This is a relatively new field of research, dating to the mid-20th century. Cyberneticists seek to understand how decisions are made, and how to improve the process using systematic, scientific methods. This is particularly important in the fields of automation and computer programming. Setting up a computer to do a job in a human's place cannot be done unless the computer's programmers and users understand how it is to make the necessary decisions: how the computer 'thinks.' Cybernetics also finds use in management of human beings, because its theories can be applied to the flow of information and decisions up and down a chain of command, among a peer group, or through other social structures.[PARAGRAPH:2]More colloquially, "cybernetics" is often used to refer to advanced automation, or to a mixture of organic and machine technology, particularly in the context of the newly-dawning Information Age. Naturally, this is tied into the research described above - one can hardly design an advanced robot without knowing how to build a decision-making computer.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>控制论是由计算机先驱诺伯特·维纳（Norbert Wiener）提出的一个术语，指研究控制系统、组织和信息流的科学。这是一个相对较新的研究领域，可以追溯到20世纪中叶。控制论者试图了解决策是如何做出的，以及如何使用系统的、科学的方法来改进过程。这在自动化和计算机编程领域尤为重要。除非计算机的程序员和用户了解如何做出必要的决定：计算机是如何“思考”的，否则无法在人的地方安装计算机来完成工作。控制论也可以用于人的管理，因为它的理论可以应用于一个指挥链、一个同辈群体或其他社会结构中的信息流和决策流程。[第2段]更一般地说，“控制论”经常被用来指先进的自动化，或者是有机和机器技术的混合。尤其是在新信息时代的背景下。很自然，这与上述的研究有关——不知道如何构建决策计算机，就很难设计出先进的机器人。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LABOUR_UNIONS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Labour unions arose in the 18th and 19th century in response to the poor working conditions brought on by an intense competition for jobs, and the increasing dependence of the working class on their employers created by the move toward industrialization. Early labour unions, formed by skilled labourers in specific fields, met with opposition from both employers and the government. In the 19th century, laws were passed legalizing labour unions, and by the 20th century unions were formed in semi- or unskilled fields such as mining, transportation, and dock working. Binding their interests together and bargaining collectively, labour unions forced factory and business owners to provide better working conditions and economic status for their workers.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>工会产生于18和19世纪，是为了应对激烈的就业竞争带来的恶劣的工作条件，以及工业化带来的工人阶级对雇主的日益依赖。早期的工会由特定领域的技术工人组成，遭到雇主和政府的反对。19世纪，通过了使工会合法化的法律，到20世纪，在采矿、运输和码头工作等半技术或非技术领域成立了工会。工会将他们的利益捆绑在一起，集体谈判，迫使工厂和企业主为他们的工人提供更好的工作条件和经济地位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTISANRY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The life so short, the craft so long in the learning."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Geoffrey Chaucer, Parliament of Foules</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“生命如此短暂，学问在学习中如此漫长。”[段落：2 ]——杰弗雷·乔叟的议会</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GENERALSHIP</Tag>
		<English>Generalship</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>指挥学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LEVERAGE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Give me a lever long enough, and a fulcrum on which to place it, and I shall move the world."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Archimedes</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“给我一个足够长的杠杆，一个支点来放置它，我将移动这个世界。”[段落：2 ] -阿基米德</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRONICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The field of electronics deals with the practical application and manipulation of electricity and electromagnetic phenomena. The invention of the vacuum tube in the early 20th century marked the beginning of modern electronics. The vacuum tube was capable of amplifying weak radio signals, allowing them to be transmitted over greater distances. Vacuum tubes also allowed music and voice to be superimposed onto radio waves for transmission. The early study of electronics revolutionized a number of fields, especially the field of communications. Because of the vacuum tube, the technology of radio communications was highly developed by World War II. After the war, electronics research continued to advance rapidly. Post-war advances include the earliest examples of digital computers and, eventually, transistors and integrated circuits: miniaturized replacements for the vacuum tube.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>电子学领域涉及电和电磁现象的实际应用和操作。20世纪初真空管的发明标志着现代电子技术的开始。真空管能够放大微弱的无线电信号，使它们能够传送到更远的距离。真空管还允许音乐和声音叠加到无线电波上进行传输。早期的电子学研究使许多领域发生了革命性的变化，特别是通信领域。由于真空管的存在，无线电通信技术在第二次世界大战中得到了高度发展。战后，电子研究继续快速发展。战后的进步包括最早的数字计算机，以及最终的晶体管和集成电路：真空管的小型化替代品。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EXPLORATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"One doesn't discover new lands without losing sight of the shore."[PARAGRAPH:2]- André Gide, The Counterfeiters</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一个人不会发现新的陆地而不丢失岸边。”[段落：2 ] -安迪·盖德，造假者。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BLOOMERY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"You should hammer your iron when it is glowing hot."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Publilius Syrus, Sentences</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“你应该熨烫你的熨斗，当它炽热。”[段落：2 ] - Publilius Syrus，句子</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPOSITES</Tag>
		<English>Composites</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>复合材料</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ETHICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Act only according to that maxim whereby you can, at the same time, will that it should become universal law."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Immanuel Kant, Groundwork of the Metaphysics of Morals</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“只有按照这一准则行事，你才能同时使之成为普遍规律。”[段落：2 ]——Immanuel Kant道德形而上学的根基</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_RIGHTS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I have a dream that my four little children will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of their skin but by the content of their character."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Martin Luther King Jr.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我梦想有一天，我的四个孩子将生活在一个国家，他们的肤色不会被他们的肤色所决定。”[段落：2 ]——马丁·路德金。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ROBOTICS</Tag>
		<English>Robotics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>机器人</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARCHITECTURE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Architecture is the discipline of designing structures with an eye to specific goals; usually aesthetic appeal, but also functional features such as defensibility. The architect's trade blends that of the ordinary engineer and the artist. On the one hand, all great architecture must be durable enough to stand natural forces and the test of time; on the other, it is often expected to be pleasant to live in and to behold.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>建筑是一门着眼于特定目标设计结构的学科；通常是审美情趣，但也有功能性特征，如防御性。建筑师的职业把普通工程师和艺术家的职业融合在一起。一方面，所有伟大的建筑必须经久耐用，经得起自然力和时间的考验；另一方面，人们通常认为，居住和观赏都是令人愉快的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SOCIAL_SERVICES</Tag>
		<English>Social Services</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>社会服务</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RADAR_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Radar is a method of using radio waves to observe one's surroundings by technological means. Derived from the acronym "RAdio Detection And Ranging," radar permits observation to continue at distances the naked eye cannot reach, in conditions of bad weather and darkness the eye cannot penetrate, with machine-like precision the eye cannot duplicate. It is particularly useful for detecting aircraft at long range, although it can also be used from an aircraft to survey the land, or from a ship to detect another ship at sea.[PARAGRAPH:2]Innovation in radar technology began shortly before the Second World War, with Britain in the lead and other nations such as Germany and the US following close behind. The British capitalized on their advantage and developed the highly effective "Chain Home" system of early warning stations to detect any enemy aircraft trying to attack their island. This proved a very useful defensive asset in resisting the severe German air attacks of 'the Blitz' during late 1940. Combined with other uses of the radio spectrum (such as cunningly mimicking German navigation beacons so that German bombers would get lost in the dark and bomb random wheat fields instead of British cities), Britain used its advantage in radar to wage what Winston Churchill called a "wizards' war" that complemented the air war then being fought.[PARAGRAPH:2]When the tables began to turn in 1943, the Germans too found radar a useful means of defending against British and American air attack, although the sheer mass of the Allied war machine caused their defenses to break down by late 1944. Meanwhile, the Germans' submarine warfare campaign likewise suffered from Allied use of radar to detect submarines; and on the other side of the world, the total lack of effective radar on the part of their allies, the Japanese, played a major role in Japan's defeat in air and naval combat from 1942 on.[PARAGRAPH:2]Radar became far more advanced and developed in the postwar era with the steady rise of electronics technology, especially after the vacuum tube gave way to the integrated circuit. The military continues to make use of radar imaging as the primary means of tracking aircraft, and also employs it to scan the ground from the air. In civilian applications, radar is used to coordinate commercial air traffic to prevent collisions, and is a common, valuable scientific instrument whenever detailed imagery needs to be taken from a distance.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>雷达是利用无线电波通过技术手段观察周围环境的一种方法。雷达源于“无线电探测和测距”的缩写，允许在恶劣天气和黑暗条件下，眼睛无法穿透肉眼无法到达的距离继续观察，具有机器般的精度，眼睛无法复制。它特别适用于远距离探测飞机，虽然它也可以从飞机上用来探测陆地，也可以从船上探测到另一艘船在海上航行。〔2〕雷达技术的革新在第二次世界大战前不久就开始了。英国领先，德国和美国紧随其后。英国人利用他们的优势，开发了高效的“链家”预警站系统，以侦测任何试图攻击他们岛屿的敌机。事实证明，这是抵抗1940年末德国空袭“闪电战”的一项非常有用的防御手段。再加上无线电频谱的其他用途（比如巧妙地模仿德国导航信标，让德国轰炸机迷失在黑暗中，轰炸随意的麦田，而不是英国城市），英国利用其在雷达上的优势来完成温斯顿邱吉尔所称的“巫师战争”，补充了当时的空战。[段：2 ]当1943的战斗机开始转动时，德国人也发现雷达是抵御英国和美国空袭的有用手段。尽管盟军战争机器的庞大规模导致他们的防御系统在1944年末崩溃。与此同时，德国的潜艇作战也同样受到盟军使用雷达探测潜艇的影响；而在世界的另一边，盟军日本则完全缺乏有效的雷达，从1942起，日本在空战中的失败起到了重要作用。[段：2 ]随着电子技术的稳步崛起，尤其是在真空管进入集成电路之后，雷达在战后时代变得更加先进和发达。军方继续利用雷达成像作为跟踪飞机的主要手段，并利用它从空中扫描地面。在民用应用中，雷达用于协调商业空中交通以防止碰撞，并且在需要从远处拍摄详细图像时，雷达是一种常见的、有价值的科学仪器。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_JOURNALISM</Tag>
		<English>Journalism</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>新闻业</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOTECHNOLOGY</Tag>
		<English>Biotechnology</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>生物科技</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HYDRAULICS</Tag>
		<English>Hydraulics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>水利工程</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_THEOLOGY</Tag>
		<English>Theology</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>神学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FUSION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"All stable processes we shall predict. All unstable processes we shall control."[PARAGRAPH:2]- John von Neumann</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我们将预测所有稳定的过程。我们控制的所有不稳定的过程。[ [段：2 ] -约翰·冯·诺依曼</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AERODYNAMICS</Tag>
		<English>Aerodynamics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>空气动力学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CEREMONY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A ceremony is an event of ritual significance, performed on a special occasion. Even in the earliest societies, religious beliefs were often associated with recurring events that required the performance of ceremonies. These ceremonies could take place in smaller, secluded communities, such as in temples, or in public on squares and marketplaces.[PARAGRAPH:2]Ceremonies often strengthen the solidarity within a society and create a sense of belonging and loyalty to the authorities that were organising them. For that reason, they were often employed by monarchs to legitimise their rule, for example through triumphal marches, coronation ceremonies or complicated court rituals.[PARAGRAPH:2]This complicated ceremonial procedure meant that there was only a limited class of people capable of administering rituals. Over time, this led to the emergence of formal priesthood and organised religion.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>仪式是在特殊场合进行的具有仪式意义的活动。即使在最早的社会，宗教信仰也常常与需要举行仪式的反复发生的事件联系在一起。这些仪式可能发生在较小的、僻静的社区，例如寺庙，或广场和市场上的公共场所。[段：2 ]仪式通常加强社会内部的团结，并对组织他们的权威产生归属感和忠诚感。由于这个原因，他们常常被君主雇用来使他们的统治合法化，例如通过胜利的游行、加冕典礼或复杂的法庭仪式。[第2段]这个复杂的仪式程序意味着只有有限的一类人能够管理仪式。随着时间的推移，这导致出现了正式的祭司和有组织的宗教。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TOURISM_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The universe is a sort of book, whose first page one has read when one has seen only one's own country."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Louis-Charles Fougeret de Monbron, Le Cosmopolite</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“宇宙是一本书，它的第一页是在一个人看到自己的国家时才阅读的。”[段落：2 ]——路易斯查尔斯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"From so simple a beginning, endless forms most beautiful and most wonderful have been, and are being, evolved."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Charles Darwin, On the Origin of Species</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“从一个简单的开始，最美丽、最奇妙的无休止的形式已经存在，正在进化，”[段落：2 ] - Charles Darwin，关于物种起源</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LOGISTICS</Tag>
		<English>Logistics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>物流</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FORTIFICATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"It is from their foes, not their friends, that cities learn the lesson of building high walls."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Aristophanes, Birds</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“城市从他们的敌人，而不是他们的朋友那里学到了建造高墙的教训。”[段落：2 ]——阿里斯多芬尼斯，鸟类。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GEOGRAPHY</Tag>
		<English>Geography</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>地理学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PHILOSOPHY</Tag>
		<English>Philosophy</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>哲学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMBINED_ARMS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The whole is greater than the sum of its parts."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Aristotle, Metaphysics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“整体大于其部分之和。”[段落：2 ] -亚里士多德，形而上学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GLOBALISM</Tag>
		<English>Globalism</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>全球化思潮</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MASONRY</Tag>
		<English>Masonry</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>石工术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPANIES_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Wealth unused might as well not exist."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Aesop</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“未使用的财富也可能不存在。”[段落：2 ] -伊索</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PRIESTHOOD_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"From the solemn gloom of the temple, children run out to sit in the dust. God watches them play and forgets the priest."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Rabindranath Tagore, Fireflies</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>”孩子们从庄严的庙宇里跑出来，坐在尘土里。上帝看着他们玩耍，忘记牧师。”[段落：2 ]——Rabindranath Tagore，萤火虫。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REFRIGERATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Tell me what you eat, and I will tell you what you are."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Anthelme Brillat-Savarin, The Physiology of Taste</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“告诉我你吃什么，我会告诉你你是什么。”[段落：2 ] - Anthelme Brillat Savarin，味道的生理学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DIVINATION</Tag>
		<English>Divination</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>占卜学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CYBERNETICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"If the brain were so simple we could understand it, we would be so simple we couldn't."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Lyall Watson</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“如果大脑如此简单，我们就能理解它，我们会如此简单，我们不能。”[段落：2 ] - Lyall Watson</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ECONOMICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The engine which drives enterprise is not thrift, but profit."[PARAGRAPH:2]- John Maynard Keynes, A Treatise on Money</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“驱动企业的引擎不是节俭，而是利润。”[段落：2 ]——约翰·梅纳德·凯恩斯的《货币论著》</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_RIGHTS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Certain inequalities have been a feature of most civilizations since the beginning of recorded history, or earlier. Almost without exception, most women were restricted to low-prestige roles as subordinates to men. Many societies identified a ruling elite or 'native' national majority which was free to condemn religious, racial, or other minorities. Large categories of second-class citizens existed in practically all countries, most frequently women, who lacked the political and economic freedoms enjoyed by men.[PARAGRAPH:2]As great increases in wealth, literacy, and access to communications spread through the developed world in the late 19th and early 20th century, this state of affairs was called into question. Women and racial minorities struggled to achieve equal access to economic opportunities and for the right to vote. Ethnic and linguistic groups overpowered and surrounded by foreigners (especially in the Americas and Australia) fought to preserve their right to raise their own children and maintain their language and traditions in the face of intense pressure to dissolve into the mainstream. In recent decades, issues of sexuality and gender identity have sparked much debate and protest between those striving for equality and those that would deny it to them.[PARAGRAPH:2]The battles for these forms of equality, generally known as "civil rights" were one of the defining social forces of the 20th century, and continue into the 21st.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>自有记录的历史开始以来，或更早以前，某些不平等一直是大多数文明的特征。几乎无一例外，大多数妇女被限制在作为男性下属的低声望角色。许多社会确定了统治精英或“土著”民族的多数，他们可以自由地谴责宗教、种族或其他少数。几乎所有的国家都有大类别的二等公民，其中最常见的是妇女，她们缺乏男性享有的政治和经济自由。〔2〕在第十九年底和二十世纪初，发达国家的财富、识字率和通信量大幅增加，这种情况是这样的。受到质疑。妇女和少数民族努力实现平等获得经济机会和选举权。面对融入主流的巨大压力，被外国人压倒和包围的种族和语言群体（特别是在美洲和澳大利亚）努力维护他们抚养自己孩子的权利，维护自己的语言和传统。近几十年来，性欲和性别认同问题引起了争取平等的人和反对他们的人之间的争论和抗议。[段落：2 ]对于这些平等形式的斗争，一般称为“公民权利”，是二十世纪决定性的社会力量之一，并持续到第二十一。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ATOMIC_PHYSICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Atomic theory is, in simplest form, the idea that all matter is made up of tiny, indivisible particles called "atoms." The first ancient form of this theory comes from the Greek philosopher Democritus. His atomic theory was founded on the Greek ideas of the geometric order of the universe and of the four elements, which led to some strange ideas. For instance, early supporters of the atomic theory suggested that water might flow because it was made up of icosahedral atoms which, being nearly round, tumbled over each other easily; fire was painful because it was made up of tetrahedral atoms which were sharp and thus damaging. Since there was no evidence for this theory at the time, and no obvious reason to prefer it to the alternatives, it was largely ignored for the following two thousand years.[PARAGRAPH:2]The atomic theory re-emerged around 1800, following early chemists' discovery of new types of chemical elements that seemed more fundamental than things like air and fire. The chemist John Dalton proposed again that all matter was made of atoms, which were neither created nor destroyed in chemical reactions, only reshuffled to form different substances. This theory proved fruitful for 19th century chemistry, although many scientists insisted that it was only a theory.[PARAGRAPH:2]Towards the end of the century, advances in the studies of the spectrum of light emitted by different elements, and the discovery of radioactivity, cast doubt on the premise that atoms were indivisible. Perhaps atoms had some kind of internal structure, and were themselves composed of smaller particles with new and intriguing properties of their own. The first of these particles to be discovered was the electron, a tiny and lightweight particle which carries a strong negative charge, and whose motions form the basis for nearly all electrical, magnetic, and chemical interactions.[PARAGRAPH:2]Further investigation into the structure of the atom using ever more precise and complex instruments and mathematical theories opened up broad vistas of scientific discovery. Various models of atomic structure, such as the "plum pudding" model, the Rutherford atom, and the Bohr atom, were considered, modified, or discarded. Scientists gained more understanding of the mechanisms behind atomic structure, and of how atoms could bind together to form molecules.[PARAGRAPH:2]This led to great advances in practical technology in the latter half of the 20th century. Once the atoms that made them up were understood, chemists could tailor-make molecules to suit their needs. Alloys with strange electrical properties could be used to build advanced calculating machines. And the immense forces locked within the atomic nucleus could be released, for good or for evil.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>原子理论是一种最简单的理论，认为所有的物质都是由称为“原子”的微小的、不可分割的粒子组成的。这一理论的第一种古老形式来自希腊哲学家德谟克利特。他的原子理论是建立在希腊的宇宙几何秩序和四元素的基础上的，这导致了一些奇怪的想法。例如，原子理论的早期支持者认为，水之所以流动，是因为它是由二十面体原子组成的，而二十面体原子几乎是圆形的，很容易相互碰撞；火之所以令人痛苦，是因为它是由四面体原子组成的，四面体原子锋利，因而具有破坏性。因为当时没有任何证据证明这一理论，也没有明显的理由把它比作替代品，所以在接下来的二千年里，它被忽略了。[段落：2 ]原子理论重新出现在1800左右，在早期化学家发现了比空气和火更基本的新型化学元素之后。化学家约翰道尔顿再次提出，所有的物质都是由原子构成的，原子在化学反应中既没有被创造也没有被破坏，只是经过重组形成不同的物质。这一理论在十九世纪的化学上证明是卓有成效的，尽管许多科学家坚持认为这只是一个理论。[段落：2 ]到本世纪末，对不同元素发射的光谱的研究和放射性的发现的进展，对原子不可分割的前提产生了怀疑。也许原子有某种内部结构，它们本身是由更小的粒子组成的，这些粒子本身有着新奇有趣的特性。这些被发现的粒子中的第一个是电子，一个微小而轻质的粒子，携带着一个强的负电荷，它的运动形成了几乎所有的电、磁和化学相互作用的基础。[段落：2 ]使用更精密和复杂的仪器进一步研究原子的结构。数学理论开辟了科学发现的广阔前景。原子结构的各种模型，如“李子布丁”模型、卢瑟福原子和玻尔原子，都被考虑、修改或废弃。科学家们对原子结构背后的机制有了更多的了解，以及原子是如何结合在一起形成分子的。[段落：2 ]这导致了在二十世纪后半期实用技术的巨大进步。一旦组成它们的原子被理解，化学家就可以根据它们的需要定制分子。具有奇异电性能的合金可以用来制造先进的计算机器。锁在原子核内的巨大力量可以被释放，不管是好是坏。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARCHITECTURE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"In the architectural structure, man's pride, man's triumph over gravitation, man's will to power, assume a visible form."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Friedrich Nietzsche, The Twilight of the Idols</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“在建筑结构中，人类的骄傲，人类战胜万有引力，人类对权力的意志，呈现出一种可见的形式。”[段落：2 ]——Friedrich Nietzsche，《偶像的暮色》</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FILM_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I have the seized the light. I have arrested its flight."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Louis Daguerre</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我抓住了灯。“我已经逮捕了它的飞行。”[段落：2 ] - Louis Daguerre</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_INFRASTRUCTURE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Infrastructure is the collective term for all those facilities and systems by which it is possible for human civilizations to carry out productive enterprises and maintain a functional economy. Examples of infrastructure assets include but are not limited to transportation facilities, electrical power grids, financial systems, water supplies, waste disposal facilities, flood control facilities, lighthouses, telecommunication networks, and arguably systems designed to provide services directly to the public such as education systems, law enforcement, public housing, and state-funded hospitals.[PARAGRAPH:2]Some types of infrastructure are nearly always created, maintained, and administered by government agencies. Others lend themselves better to privatization. The question of whether infrastructure should be publicly or privately owned is often hotly debated.[PARAGRAPH:2]The increasingly elaborate nature of infrastructure in advanced, developed societies is one of the main reasons they represent such a vast change in terms of lifestyle and quality of life from pre-industrial times. Industrial-scale projects make it possible to provide basic necessities of life to all citizens with little difficulty, enabling people to concentrate on things other than providing for their sustenance. For instance, a public water system that pipes drinkable water into every home saves a great deal of time and energy compared to requiring every individual to operate their own well, or draw water from a nearby river or lake. It is also possible to make such a water system much healthier and safer than individuals could do alone, and to provide quantities of water that would be an immense laborious undertaking in the absence of the general system of waterworks.[PARAGRAPH:2]While infrastructure makes us safe and prosperous, however, it can also make us vulnerable. Managing infrastructure with safety and reliability can require complex bureaucracy and confining regulations. And in times of war or natural disaster, large parts of a society's infrastructure may be destroyed, forcing thousands or millions of people to do without essential things which they had never lacked before.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>基础设施是所有这些设施和系统的总称，通过这些设施和系统，人类文明可以开展生产性企业并维持一种功能性经济。基础设施资产的例子包括但不限于交通设施、电网、金融系统、供水、废物处理设施、防洪设施、灯塔、电信网络，以及可论证的旨在直接向公众提供服务的系统，如教育系统、法律实施、公共住房和国家资助的医院。[段落：2 ]某些类型的基础设施几乎总是由政府机构创建、维护和管理。其他人则更倾向于私有化。基础设施应该是公开还是私有的问题经常引起激烈争论。[段落：2 ]发达发达国家的基础设施日益完善，这是它们代表着工业时代生活方式和生活质量的巨大变化的主要原因之一。工业规模的项目使人们能够毫不费力地向所有公民提供基本生活必需品，使人们能够集中精力解决除维持生计以外的其他问题。例如，公共供水系统将饮用水输送到每家每户，与要求每个人自己打井或从附近的河流或湖泊取水相比，节省了大量的时间和精力。也有可能使这样的水系统比个人所能做到的更健康和更安全，并且在没有水务系统的情况下提供大量的水，这将是一项艰巨的任务。[第2段]，虽然基础设施使我们安全和繁荣，但是它也能使我们变得脆弱。以安全和可靠的方式管理基础设施可能需要复杂的官僚机构和限制性法规。在战争或自然灾害时期，一个社会的大部分基础设施可能会被摧毁，迫使成千上万或数百万人在没有以前从未缺少过的必需品的情况下生活。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TELECOMMUNICATIONS</Tag>
		<English>Telecommunications</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>移动通信</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RIDING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"If you speak the truth, have a foot in the stirrup."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Turkish proverb</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“如果你说真话，就要脚踏马镫。”[段落：2 ]——土耳其谚语</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CHARITY</Tag>
		<English>Charity</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>慈善事业</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PHYSICS</Tag>
		<English>Physics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>物理学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SHIPBUILDING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"He who commands the sea has command of everything."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Themistocles</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“掌管大海的人掌握一切。”[段落：2 ]——地米斯托克利</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPASS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The compass opened the universe."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Montesquieu, The Spirit of the Laws</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“指南针打开了宇宙。”[段落：2 ]——孟德斯鸠的法律精神</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REFINING</Tag>
		<English>Refining</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>石油精炼</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AESTHETICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I believe in the might of design, the mystery of colour, the redemption of all things by Beauty everlasting, and the message of Art that has made these hands blessed."[PARAGRAPH:2]- George Bernard Shaw, The Doctor's Dilemma</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我相信设计的力量，色彩的奥秘，永恒的美，万物的救赎，以及让双手幸福的艺术信息。”[段落：2 ] -萧伯纳，医生的两难处境</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SMELTING</Tag>
		<English>Smelting</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>金属熔炼</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LAW_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"To bring about the rule of righteousness in the land, so that the strong should not harm the weak."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Code of Hammurabi</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“要在地上施行公义，使强者不至于伤害弱者。”〔2〕- Hammurabi密码</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NAVIGATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The winds and the waves are always on the side of the ablest navigators."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Edward Gibbon, The Decline and Fall of the Roman Empire</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“风和浪总是在最能干的航海家旁边。”[段落：2 ]——爱德华·吉本，罗马帝国的衰亡</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_WRITING</Tag>
		<English>Writing</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>文字</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ENGINE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Nature, in providing us with combustibles on all sides, has given us the power to produce, at all times and in all places, heat and the impelling power which is the result of it."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Sadi Carnot, Reflections on the Motive Power of Heat</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“自然界，在为我们提供四面八方的可燃物时，赋予我们在任何时候、在任何地方产生热量的能力，这是它产生的动力。”[段落：2 ]——萨迪·卡诺对热动力的思考</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ROBOTICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"From the moment when the machine first made its appearance it was clear to all thinking people that the need for human drudgery, and therefore to a great extent for human inequality, had disappeared."[PARAGRAPH:2]- George Orwell, Nineteen Eighty-Four</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“从机器首次出现的那一刻起，所有人都清楚地看到，人类的苦役需要，并因此在很大程度上导致了人类的不平等，已经消失了。”[段落：2 ]——乔治奥威尔，1984</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AVIATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>While the earliest powered flying machines proved useless for war except as aerial scout platforms, the demands of World War One accelerated development of fast, powerful aircraft capable of hauling significant weapons or cargo. Steady improvements in the internal combustion engine, and rapid growth of experience in airplane design, led to a boom in the airplane's capabilities in the 1920s and 1930s. Passenger aviation in planes like the Douglas DC-3 (still in service today) turned aircraft construction into a major industry. At the same time, military airplanes became more powerful and capable, diversifying into fast, agile fighters and bombers capable of carrying tons of explosives hundreds of kilometres into enemy territory.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>尽管最早的动力飞行机器被证明除了作为空中侦察平台之外对战争毫无用处，但第一次世界大战的要求加速了能够运载重要武器或货物的快速、强大飞机的发展。内燃机的不断改进和飞机设计经验的迅速增长，导致了20世纪20年代和30年代飞机性能的激增。像道格拉斯DC-3（目前仍在服役）这样的飞机上的乘客航空使飞机制造成为一个主要产业。与此同时，军用飞机变得更加强大和有能力，多样化为快速、灵活的战斗机和轰炸机，能够将数吨炸药运到数百公里外的敌方领土。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PASTORALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Pastoralism is a term for the art of raising livestock. It is also used in sociology, to describe a way of life that revolves around herding and caring for domestic animals. Pastoral societies are generally most successful on poorly productive land such as large, dry stretches of desert, savannah, hills, or tundra. In this sort of terrain, dense stands of food crops cannot be grown naturally, so farming is impossible without modern irrigation. However, in such biomes there is a substantial natural supply of grasses and shrubs; humans cannot eat them, but sheep, cattle, goats, or yaks can.[PARAGRAPH:2]It is often but not always the case that a pastoral people 'follows their herds,' moving from one part of the land they occupy to another to ensure that they have access to the best available grazing, water supplies, and a healthy climate for their animals.[PARAGRAPH:2]Pastoral societies present a common alternative to agricultural societies, and were capable of functioning and thriving on equal terms with them up until the rise of modern technology. They could be particularly effective in warfare, especially when leaders took advantage of their self-sufficient, highly mobile lifestyle to create an army of self-sufficient, highly mobile soldiers. In modern times, however, the inability of small pastoral communities to manufacture modern weapons, coupled with overpopulation problems, have made it less sustainable and practical for these peoples to live in their traditional mode.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>畜牧业是畜牧业的一个术语。它也被用于社会学，用来描述一种围绕放牧和照顾家畜的生活方式。牧民社会通常最成功的是在生产力低下的土地上，如沙漠、草原、丘陵或苔原的大片干旱地带。在这种地形下，密集的粮食作物不能自然生长，因此没有现代灌溉，农业是不可能的。然而，在这样的生物群落中，草和灌木的自然供应量很大；人类不能食用它们，但绵羊、牛、山羊或牦牛也可以食用。[段落：2 ]牧羊人跟随牧群的情况常常是这样，但并非总是如此。他们从土地的一部分迁移到另一块土地，以确保他们能够获得最好的放牧、供水和动物的健康气候。〔2〕牧场社会是农业社会的共同选择，直到现代科技的兴起，他们才能够在平等的条件下运作和繁荣。它们在战争中可能特别有效，特别是当领导人利用其自给自足、高度机动的生活方式创建一支自给自足、高度机动的士兵大军时。然而，在现代，小牧区无法制造现代武器，再加上人口过剩的问题，使这些民族以传统方式生活的可持续性和实用性降低。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LAW</Tag>
		<English>Law</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>律法</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FINANCE</Tag>
		<English>Finance</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>金融学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FLIGHT_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"For once you have tasted flight you will walk the earth with your eyes turned skywards, for there you have been and there you will long to return."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Leonardo Da Vinci</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一旦你尝到了飞翔的滋味，你就会用眼睛向天空走去，因为你曾在那里，你将渴望回到那里。”[段落：2 ] -达·芬奇</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTIFICIAL_INTELLIGENCE</Tag>
		<English>Artificial Intelligence</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>人工智能</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_LIBERTIES_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Give me the liberty to know, to utter, and to argue freely according to conscience, above all liberties."[PARAGRAPH:2]- John Milton</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“给我自由知道，说出，并根据良心自由辩论，凌驾于一切自由。”[段落：2 ] -约翰·弥尔顿</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_INFRASTRUCTURE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Everything in life is somewhere else, and you get there in a car."[PARAGRAPH:2]- E. B. White</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“生活中的每件事都在别的地方，而你在一辆车里到达那里。”[段落：2 ] - E. B. White</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ECOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Ecology is the science of studying biological systems in nature, as distinct from the processes that go on inside individual organisms or species. Ecologists focus on understanding how different species interact in their natural habitats, what causes some to flourish and others to fade, what patterns persist across all examples of a given biome (such as 'forest' or 'savannah'), and what difference may make one area unique compared to others that are superficially similar. Knowledge of ecology helps to predict the future of a living system, control outbreaks of diseases such as blights in the wild, and mitigate certain types of natural disaster such as floods and wildfires.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ecological discoveries over the late 19th and 20th centuries have made humanity far more aware of the complexities of life on Earth, and how human actions impact these complexities.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[TAB]人类几千年来享受着自然的恩惠却不以为意。当文明不断成长，人类遍布了这个星球表面每一个角落，他们不顾自然界的承受力，拿去他们想要的，扔出更多他们不需要的垃圾。在20世纪60年代后期，越来越多的人开始关注污染以及破坏自然环境所引起的越来越多的问题。这个运动导致了如美国环保局等团体的形成。[PARAGRAPH:2]美国环保局的目标是减少各种各样的污染。为了这个目的，该局订制了一系列严格的法律和方针，涉及到有害物质的处理、清洁水的标准以及鼓励固体废弃物处理技术的研究等。环境运动的基本目标是使环境保持安全完好，能够让子孙后代享受。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SUPERCONDUCTORS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"What is happiness? The feeling that power is growing, that resistance is overcome."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Friedrich Nietzsche, The Antichrist</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“什么是幸福？感觉力量在增长，抵抗被克服了。”[段落：2 ] - Friedrich Nietzsche，Antichrist</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_UNIFIED_THEORY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>By late 20th century, physics had converged on a set of well understood theories to describe nature. But there are several gaps, defects, or vulnerabilities in this universal model. Firstly, this set of theories stands on two pillars. One is the nature of gravity, as outlined by Einstein's theory of "general relativity" in 1920 and refined since that time, which treats time and space as flexible things that can be warped by gravity. The other is "quantum field theory," which describes the behavior of subatomic particles, treating each particle as a special instance of a generalized, abstract field of force and probability that permeates the universe.[PARAGRAPH:2]The problem is that quantum field theory, otherwise known as the Standard Model, assumes that time and space are fixed, inflexible, and invariant - that they are the constant and unchanging playing field on which particle interactions are allowed to happen. In other words, the Standard Model does not obey the theory of relativity. Therefore, it cannot be the whole story. General relativity appears to be a solid and essentially complete picture of a key part of reality, the Standard Model is not. It is solid, it explains the behavior of nearly all things that can be seen on Earth or elsewhere in the universe... but it is not complete.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Standard Model explains almost all known phenomena, but some of the ones it cannot explain present very large issues. It does not explain the nature or origins of dark matter or dark energy and yet astronomers have reason to believe that these things make up 95% of all substance in the universe today. The Standard Model does not explain why the ghostly neutrino particles coming from the Sun appear to randomly reshuffle their nature, in a way the Standard Model deems impossible. The Standard Model predicts that in the beginning of the universe, matter and antimatter 'should' have been created in equal quantities, and devoured each other totally, leaving behind nothing but light and radiation in all of space. In hindsight, this appears not to have occurred. For this and other reasons, despite the Standard Model providing huge advances in our understanding compared to anything that came before it, it is not the last step.[PARAGRAPH:2]Research into these matters is ongoing today. It is hoped that future physics will emerge which resolves some of these contradictions. In particular, it is hoped that these new physics will allow us to create a model of quantum physics that is consistent with Einstein's work on gravity - thus the name, "quantum gravity."</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>到了20世纪末，物理学已经融合到一套很好理解的描述自然的理论上。但是，在这个通用模型中有几个漏洞、缺陷或漏洞。首先，这套理论有两个支柱。一个是引力的本质，1920年爱因斯坦的“广义相对论”概述了这一点，并从那时起加以完善，认为时间和空间是可以被引力扭曲的灵活事物。另一种是“量子场论”，它描述了亚原子粒子的行为，把每个粒子看作是一个广义、抽象的力场和渗透宇宙的概率的特殊实例。〔2〕问题是量子场论，否则称为标准模型，假设时间和空间是固定的、不可改变的和不变的，它们是允许粒子相互作用发生的恒定不变的运动场。换句话说，标准模型并不遵循相对论。因此，它不可能是整个故事。广义相对论似乎是一个坚实而基本完整的现实图景的关键部分，标准模型则不然。它是固体的，它解释了几乎所有可以在地球上或宇宙其他地方看到的事物的行为。。。但是它不是完全的。[段落：2 ]标准模型解释了几乎所有已知的现象，但是一些不能解释的现象呈现出非常大的问题。它并不能解释暗物质或暗能量的性质或起源，然而天文学家有理由相信这些物质占了当今宇宙所有物质的95%。标准模型并不能解释为什么来自太阳的幽灵般的中微子粒子会以标准模型认为不可能的方式随机改变它们的性质。标准模型预测，在宇宙诞生之初，物质和反物质“应该”以相等的数量被创造出来，并相互完全吞噬，在整个空间中只留下光和辐射。事后看来，这似乎并没有发生。由于这个和其他的原因，尽管标准模型在我们的理解中提供了巨大的进步，与之前的任何事情相比，它并不是最后的步骤。[段落：2 ]对这些问题的研究正在进行中。人们希望未来的物理学能够出现，从而解决其中的一些矛盾。特别是，人们希望这些新的物理学能让我们创造出一个量子物理学模型，这个模型与爱因斯坦关于引力的工作是一致的，因此被称为“量子引力”</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FERTILIZER</Tag>
		<English>Fertilizer</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>肥料</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SYNTHETICS</Tag>
		<English>Synthetics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>石油化工</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_LIBERTIES</Tag>
		<English>Civil Liberties</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>公民自由</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TANNING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Leather is a hard-wearing, flexible material created by curing and drying animal skins. Forms of leather can be made using Stone Age technology (curing hides with materials like lime or animal brains), or more complex chemical processes. Leather has been in use since at least the second millenium BC, as proven by finds of leather samples over 3000 years old in archaeological digs. Since leather does not last forever under normal conditions, its invention very probably came earlier.[PARAGRAPH:2]Leather can be made from the skin of almost any large animal, with a variety of qualities. Depending on how it is tanned, it can be flexible or stiff, soft or rough. It is generally waterproof, fairly effective at keeping in heat, and resistant to rotting or decay. Properly oiled and maintained, it can survive desert sandstorms or frozen tundra conditions. It can even be boiled for hardness and used as a form of cheap, lightweight armor protection.[PARAGRAPH:2]Unlike other fabrics such as linen, cotton, and silk, leather can be made even by nomadic cultures. If the nomads kill a domestic or wild animal, and have a suitable tanning process. On the other hand, leather remains useful in farming societies, especially those with large herd animals such as cattle.[PARAGRAPH:2]Because it is sturdy and cannot be unraveled like normal cloth, leather can be decorated with a variety of hole-punches, stitches, and decorative studs. Decorative leather goods are a popular form of arts and crafts in many societies. Today, advances in synthetic plastics have made leather less important, and it has now become more of a fashion statement and luxury good than a major fabric in practical use.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>皮革是一种由动物皮肤固化和干燥而成的耐磨、柔软的材料。皮革的形式可以使用石器时代的技术（用石灰或动物脑等材料来固化皮革）或更复杂的化学过程。皮革至少在公元前两千年就开始使用了，在考古发掘中发现的3000多年前的皮革样品证明了这一点。由于皮革在正常情况下不会持续下去，所以它的发明很可能来得更早。[段落：2 ]皮革可以由几乎任何大型动物的皮肤制成，具有多种特性。取决于它是如何被晒黑的，它可以是柔韧的或坚硬的，柔软的或粗糙的。它通常是防水的，在保持热量方面相当有效，并且抗腐烂或腐烂。经过适当的润滑和维护，它可以在沙漠沙尘暴或冻土条件下生存。它甚至可以煮成硬度，用作廉价、轻质装甲防护。[段落：2 ]不同于其他织物，例如亚麻、棉花和丝绸，皮革甚至可以由游牧文化制成。如果游牧民族杀死家畜或野生动物，并有一个合适的晒黑过程。另一方面，皮革在农业社会中仍然有用，尤其是那些有大量牲畜的动物，如牛。[段落：2 ]，因为它是坚固的，不能像普通布一样被解开，皮革可以用各种打孔、缝线和装饰钉装饰。装饰性皮革制品是许多社会中流行的一种工艺品。如今，合成塑料的进步使得皮革不再那么重要，它现在更像是一种时尚宣言和奢侈品，而不是一种实用的主要面料。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NUCLEAR_POWER</Tag>
		<English>Nuclear Power</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>核能</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PHOTOGRAPHY</Tag>
		<English>Photography</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>摄影</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MICROBIOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Healthcare is the practice of acting so as to preserve or restore the health of the individual patient, although this is normally construed to not include basic sustenance needs such as air, water, and food. Healthcare can be divided into a wide range of overlapping categories. These include but are not limited to preventative care (to maintain health through nutrition, exercise, and hygiene), palliative care (to relieve the symptoms of a patient who cannot be cured by the available means), outpatient care (where the patient is able to function and live independently while undergoing treatment), urgent care (treatment of pressing medical problems that are nonetheless not life-threatening), and acute care (where a patient requires detailed monitoring or complex medical support and so must remain in a hospital with physicians in attendance).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Since it affects what may be the foremost concern of nearly all humans - their health - health care occupies a large share of the total time and energy of the human race. Many (though not all) of the professionals involved in providing health care receive unusual prestige and wealth within their own societies. This was the case even in ancient times when the practice of medicine was primitive to the point of being life-threatening.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In modern times, the health care system has become an elaborate and refined infrastructure, especially in developed nations. Not only is it an industry in its own right, it supports various other industries such as the pharmaceutical industry and the insurance industry. The challenge of working out how to efficiently pay for this vast system that keeps us alive and relatively comfortable is a subject of energetic debate in many societies.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>医疗保健是指为了保护或恢复患者个体的健康而采取的行动，尽管这通常被解释为不包括诸如空气、水和食物等基本的营养需要。医疗保健可以分为许多重叠的类别。这些包括但不限于预防性护理（通过营养、锻炼和卫生来保持健康）、姑息性护理（缓解无法通过可用手段治愈的患者的症状）、门诊护理（患者在接受治疗时能够独立工作和生活）、紧急护理（治疗紧迫的医疗问题，但并不危及生命）和急性护理（患者需要详细的监测或复杂的医疗支持，因此必须留在医院，有医生在场）。[新线][新线]因为它影响到几乎所有人类最关心的问题-他们的健康保健占人类总时间和精力的很大一部分。许多（尽管不是全部）参与提供医疗保健的专业人员在他们自己的社会中获得了不寻常的声望和财富。即使在古代，医学的实践还很原始，到了危及生命的地步，这种情况仍然存在。在现代，医疗保健系统已经成为一个精心设计和完善的基础设施，特别是在发达国家。它不仅本身是一个行业，它还支持其他各种行业，如制药业和保险业。在许多社会中，如何有效地为这个让我们保持活力和相对舒适的庞大体系买单，是一个充满活力的争论话题。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPOSITES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The term "composite" refers to any object that is made up of more than one material. Composites were used quite early in human history; composite bows have been discovered dating back to 1300 BC. The composite technology refers the late 20th Century invention of various metal and plastic composites with greater strength, lightness, and other special properties than the base materials.[PARAGRAPH:2]Kevlar, the modern battle armor, is a composite material. Modern tanks are constructed of steel-boron nitride composites. Stealth airplanes use composite materials that are much more difficult to spot on radar. The tungsten-carbide composite is used in drill bits and wedding rings. Composite materials often demand extremely complex and precise manufacturing processes. However expensive the process may be, the resulting material may have superior qualities that make them more than worth the expense.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“复合材料”一词是指由一种以上材料构成的任何物体。复合材料在人类历史上很早就被使用；复合弓的发现可以追溯到公元前1300年。复合材料技术是指二十世纪底发明的各种金属和塑料复合材料，具有比基体材料更大的强度、轻质和其他特殊性能。〔2〕凯夫拉，现代战斗装甲，是一种复合材料。现代坦克是由钢氮化硼复合材料。隐形飞机使用的复合材料在雷达上很难被发现。碳化钨复合材料用于钻头和结婚戒指。复合材料往往需要极其复杂和精确的制造工艺。无论工艺多么昂贵，所得到的材料可能具有优越的质量，使它们比所花的费用更值钱。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_LIBERTIES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Civil liberties are forms of freedom of action which the state is required to give to all citizens, without limits or with very minimal limits.[PARAGRAPH:2]The idea that one's standing in society confers certain rights is ancien t- most traditional societies grant special immunities to nobles and priests, granting them more room to speak their minds and more confidence of avoiding practices like torture and arbitrary arrest. But in most of the world, the notion that these rights should be universal is relatively new. Similarly, the belief that they should apply without exception even when the state has an interest in ignoring them, as a matter of principle date back to no earlier than the Enlightenment of the 1600s and 1700s.[PARAGRAPH:2]Key among these basic rights are freedom of speech, freedom of religion, the right to vote, and freedom from arbitrary use of police powers. Removing any of these rights makes it far easier for a tyrannical government to suppress dissent, while keeping them in place helps to ensure that the state remains honest, forthright, and responsible in its dealings with the citizenry.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>公民自由是国家需要给予公民的行动自由的形式，无限制或极少的限制。[段落：2 ]社会地位赋予某些权利的观念是古老的——大多数传统社会赋予贵族和牧师特殊豁免权，让他们有更多的空间表达自己的想法，更有信心避免酷刑和任意逮捕等做法。但在世界大多数地区，这些权利应该是普遍的这一概念是相对较新的。同样，即使在国家有兴趣忽视他们的情况下，他们也应该毫无例外地适用，原则上追溯到1600年和1700年的启蒙运动。[段落：2 ]这些基本权利中的关键是言论自由、宗教自由、选举权。以及不任意使用警察权力的自由。剥夺这些权利使专制政府更容易压制异见，而保留这些权利有助于确保国家在与公民打交道时保持诚实、直率和负责任。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPUTERS</Tag>
		<English>Computers</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>电子计算机</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRONICS</Tag>
		<English>Electronics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>数码产品</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GEOGRAPHY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Geography is a field of science devoted to the study of the lands, the features, the inhabitants, and the phenomena of Earth. The first person to use the word geography was Eratosthenes (276-194 BC). Geography is an all-encompassing discipline that seeks an understanding of the Earth and its human and natural complexities - not merely where objects are, but how they have changed and come to be. It is often defined in terms of the two branches of human geography and physical geography.[PARAGRAPH:2]The European Age of Discovery during the 16th and the 17th centuries, where many new lands were discovered and accounts by European explorers such as Christopher Columbus, Marco Polo, and James Cook revived a desire for both accurate geographic detail, and more solid theoretical foundations in Europe.[PARAGRAPH:2]The 18th and the 19th centuries were the times when geography became recognized as a discrete academic discipline, and became part of a typical university curriculum in Europe (especially Paris and Berlin).</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>地理学是一门专门研究土地、地貌、居民和地球现象的科学。第一个使用地理这个词的人是埃拉托舍内斯（公元前276-194年）。地理学是一门包罗万象的学科，它寻求对地球及其人类和自然复杂性的理解——不仅仅是物体在哪里，而是它们是如何变化和形成的。它经常被定义为人类地理和自然地理的两个分支。[段落：2 ]在第十六和第十七世纪发现的欧洲时代，许多新的土地被发现，并由欧洲探险家Christopher Columbus、马可波罗和詹姆斯·库克所做的记述恢复了对精确地理的渴望。细节，更坚实的理论基础在欧洲。[段落：2 ]第十八和第十九个世纪是地理被认为是一个离散的学科，并成为一个典型的大学课程在欧洲（尤其是巴黎和柏林）的一部分。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STATECRAFT</Tag>
		<English>Statecraft</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>治国术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AUTOMOBILE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Everything in life is somewhere else, and you get there in a car."[PARAGRAPH:2]- E. B. White</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“生活中的每件事都在别的地方，而你在一辆车里到达那里。”[段落：2 ] - E. B. White</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PRINTING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"What gunpowder did for war, the printing press has done for the mind."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Wendell Phillips</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“火药为战争做了些什么，印刷机为头脑做了些什么。”[段落：2 ] -温德尔·菲利普斯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EXPLOSIVES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An explosive is a chemical compound or mixture that undergoes rapid combustion and produces heat, gas, and pressure effects. The earliest explosive compound known was gunpowder, which was first used in the13th century, and was the only explosive known for hundreds of years. The first modern explosive, a compound known as nitroglycerin, was discovered in 1846. Compounds similar to nitroglycerin are the most commonly used explosives today. Explosives vary in brisance, or shattering effect, and in their stability under various environmental conditions. Aside from their obvious use in weaponry, explosives are also used in such peaceful applications as rocket propellants and for mining and demolition work.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>炸药是一种化合物或混合物，经过快速燃烧，产生热量、气体和压力效应。已知最早的爆炸物是火药，最早使用于13世纪，是数百年来唯一已知的爆炸物。第一种现代炸药，一种叫做硝化甘油的化合物，于1846年被发现。类似硝化甘油的化合物是当今最常用的炸药。炸药在不同的环境条件下，其威力或破碎效果以及稳定性各不相同。爆炸物除了明显用于武器之外，还用于火箭推进剂等和平用途以及采矿和爆破工作。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SCIENTIFIC_METHOD</Tag>
		<English>Scientific Method</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>科学方法</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RAILROAD_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The introduction of so powerful an agent as steam to carriage on wheels will make a great change in the situation of man."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Thomas Jefferson</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“把强大的蒸汽剂引入车轮上，会使人的处境发生巨大的变化。”[段落：2 ] -托马斯·杰斐逊</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_SERVICE</Tag>
		<English>Civil Service</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>文官制度</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CEREMONY</Tag>
		<English>Ceremony</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>宗教仪式</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMBINED_ARMS</Tag>
		<English>Combined Arms</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>联合兵种</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PNEUMATICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"No pressure, no diamonds."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Thomas Carlyle</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“没有压力，没有钻石。”[段落：2 ] -托马斯·卡莱尔</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATIONALISM</Tag>
		<English>Nationalism</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>民族主义</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REPRESENTATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"It has been said that democracy is the worst form of government except all the others that have been tried."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Winston Churchill</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“有人说，民主是最糟糕的政府形式，除了所有其他已经尝试过的政府。”[段落：2 ] -温斯顿邱吉尔</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GUNPOWDER</Tag>
		<English>Gunpowder</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>火药</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PSYCHOLOGY</Tag>
		<English>Psychology</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>心理学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CONTRACT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>A contract is a voluntary arrangement between two or more parties that is enforceable by law as a binding legal agreement. A contract arises when the parties agree that there is an agreement. Formation of a contract generally requires an offer, acceptance, consideration, and a mutual intent to be bound. Some types of contracts may require formalities, such as a memorialization in writing.[PARAGRAPH:2]In The Laws, Plato recognized the same basic categories for cancelling agreements as exist today. Roman law identified discrete categories of contractual transaction, each with its own requirements, which needed to be fulfilled in order for promises to be enforced. More than appeared from the general rules in Ancient Greece, Roman law represented an early division between specific kinds of contract, depending on the transaction's nature.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>合同是两个或多个当事方之间的自愿安排，可作为一项有约束力的法律协议在法律上强制执行。当双方同意有协议时，合同就产生了。合同的订立一般要求要约、承诺、对价和相互的意思表示受约束。某些类型的合同可能需要手续，如书面记述。〔第2款〕在法律中，Plato承认与今天一样取消协议的基本类别。罗马法确定了合同交易的不同类别，每一种都有自己的要求，为了使承诺得到执行，这些要求必须得到履行。罗马法不仅仅出现在古希腊的一般规则中，它还代表着根据交易的性质对特定类型合同的早期划分。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EXPLORATION</Tag>
		<English>Exploration</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>地理探索</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HUMANITIES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The humanities are the academic disciplines which study human behavior, organization, society, and culture. They include but are not limited to philosophy, history, archaeology, anthropology, theology, classical studies, law, semiotics, linguistics, and the arts. The fields collectively known as the humanities are generally pursued by specialized scholars or artists, who work steadily to refine their aesthetic sense, their understanding of the human condition, and their knowledge of the proper order of human affairs.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]While it is generally difficult to point to specific physical benefits garnered from these fields, collectively they make up almost all that motivates the human race. Without art, law, religion, history, and philosophy, human civilizations are at a loss as to how to organize themselves or what goals they should orient themselves towards.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Individuals may pursue self-gratification or bare survival in the absence of these things, but social cohesion tends to break down rapidly when this is all that people have and share with each other. Thus, the humanities form the mortar, the glue, the nuts and bolts, that hold civilizations together.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>人文学科是研究人类行为、组织、社会和文化的学科。它们包括但不限于哲学、历史、考古学、人类学、神学、古典研究、法律、符号学、语言学和艺术。这些统称为人文学科的领域通常是由专门的学者或艺术家所追求的，他们不断地努力完善自己的美感、对人类状况的理解，以及他们对人类事务的正确顺序的知识。[新线][新线]虽然通常很难指出从这些领域获得的具体物质利益，但他们共同构成了几乎所有激励人类的因素。没有艺术、法律、宗教、历史和哲学，人类文明就无法组织自己，也无法确定自己的目标，但是，当人们拥有并分享这些东西时，社会凝聚力往往会迅速瓦解。因此，人文学科形成了灰泥、胶水、螺母和螺栓，它们把文明团结在一起。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SOCIOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Society does not consist of individuals but expresses the sum of interrelations, the relations within which these individuals stand."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Karl Marx, Grundrisse</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“社会不是由个体组成的，而是表达相互关系的总和，这些个体之间的关系。”[段落：2 ] - Karl Marx，Grundrisse</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CEREMONY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Lead them by means of virtue and regulate them through ritual, and they will have a sense of shame and moreover have standards."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Confucius</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“用美德引导他们，通过仪式来规范他们，他们会有羞耻感，而且有标准。”[段落：2 ] - Confucius</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ECOLOGY</Tag>
		<English>Ecology</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>生态学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MACHINE_TOOLS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>One of the most important steps in the move toward industrialization was the ability to precisely shape or 'machine' solid metal into a desired form. Through mechanical, chemical, and other means, machine tools mold and shape raw materials into precision parts for complex machinery. The first machine tool, a horizontal boring device, was produced in the late 1700s.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The development of measuring devices accurate to within thousandths of an inch allowed for the mass production of items with interchangeable parts. The technology of the 20th century has produced computer-controlled machine tools that can be adapted to a wide variety of applications. The speed and accuracy of these machines allows for the economical mass production of extremely complex products.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>工业化进程中最重要的一步是能够精确地将固态金属成形或“加工”成所需的形状。通过机械、化工等手段，将机床模具和成型原材料加工成精密零件，用于复杂机械。第一台机床，一种水平钻孔装置，是在17世纪后期生产的。[新线][新线]测量装置的发展精确到千分之一英寸，允许批量生产具有可互换零件的产品。20世纪的技术已经产生了计算机控制的机床，可以适应各种各样的应用。这些机器的速度和精度允许经济批量生产极其复杂的产品。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PHOTOGRAPHY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"A picture shows me at a glance what it takes a dozen pages to expound."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Ivan Turgenev</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一张照片一目了然地展示了十几页的内容。”[段落：2 ] - Ivan Turgenev</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ATOMIC_PHYSICS</Tag>
		<English>Atomic Physics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>原子物理学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HORTICULTURE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Horticulture is the art of cultivating plants for human use. By the late Middle Ages, the techniques of growing plants by hand and muscle power had been under refinement for millenia. Staple crops like wheat, rice, and potatoes were about as refined and optimized as possible. Immense bodies of farming lore arose, about the best practices for growing plants in a given land, under varying conditions of soil conditions, temperature, day length, rainfall, parasites, disease and predation.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The careful and professional science of crop-growing played a large role in the pre-industrial Age of Colonialism. Knowing how best to produce staple crops also made it easier to mass-cultivate luxury crops for export. Since most luxury crops grew best in certain climates and soils under the eyes of local populations who knew how to cultivate them (tobacco in the New World, tea in the Far East), this opened up new routes for trade and investment around the world.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>园艺是为人类种植植物的艺术。到了中世纪晚期，用手和肌肉力量种植植物的技术已经在千禧年得到改进。小麦、水稻和土豆等主要作物都经过了尽可能精炼和优化。在不同的土壤条件、温度、日长、降雨量、寄生虫、疾病和捕食条件下，关于在特定土地上种植植物的最佳做法的大量农业知识应运而生。知道如何最好地生产主食作物也使大量种植高档作物出口变得更加容易。由于大多数豪华作物在某些气候和土壤中生长得最好，而当地居民知道如何种植（新世界的烟草、远东的茶叶），这为世界各地的贸易和投资开辟了新的途径。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PRIESTHOOD</Tag>
		<English>Priesthood</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>祭司制度</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTISANRY</Tag>
		<English>Artisanry</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>手工业</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ALCHEMY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"All is interrelated. Heaven and earth, air and water. All are but one thing; not four, not two and not three, but one. Where they are not together, there is only an incomplete piece."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Paracelsus</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一切都是相互关联的。天地，空气和水。一切都是一回事，不是四，不是二，不是三，而是一。他们不在一起的地方，只有一个不完整的部分。”[段落：2 ] - Paracelsus</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTISANRY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>As agricultural productivity increased and the demand for specialist goods increased, it became less practical and less desirable to keep control of these industries in the hands of rulers. The invention of currency-based trade made independent life as a merchant or professional easier, especially in urban and semi-urbanized areas. Such trade also contributed to the rising influence of the proto-middle class, and promoted long-range commerce. The availability of rare goods at trading hubs increased, and centers of production where specialist goods were made profited.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>随着农业生产力的提高和对专业产品需求的增加，将这些行业的控制权掌握在统治者手中变得不那么实际和不那么可取。货币贸易的发明使商人或职业人士的独立生活变得更容易，特别是在城市和半城市化地区。这种贸易也促进了原始中产阶级影响力的上升，促进了长期贸易。贸易中心稀有商品的供应量增加，专门生产商品的生产中心获利。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_JOURNALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Journalism is the profession of investigating and reporting on news of interest to the journalist's readers, listeners, or viewers. Journalism plays an important role in economics and politics, by allowing the masses to access information that would otherwise be available only to a lucky, connected few.[PARAGRAPH:2]Journalism as we now know it comes from the rise of news corporations (particularly newspapers, in the 19th and 20th centuries), improved transportation and communications that allowed correspondents to move about, learn things, and report back to headquarters quickly, and the rise of mass literacy among the general public in the 18th and 19th centuries.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the middle and late 20th century the rise of radio and television created new media for journalists to distribute information. At the same time they changed the dynamics of how news flowed through the system, and what sorts of information could be presented, culminating in concepts like the "sound bite" and the "24-hour news cycle." Today, journalism is undergoing a sea change, as the old newspapers struggle to maintain public readership in the age of the internet, while critics argue that the television news have become bland tools for soothing and manipulating the masses instead of informing them. At the same time, vast numbers of enterprising individuals have taken it upon themselves to document and comment on the news online, creating a sphere of private, individualized online journalism.[PARAGRAPH:2]The relationship between the "fourth estate" of journalists and government power is always uneasy. In dictatorships, state control of the media blurs the line between journalism and propaganda. Even in democratic nations, the organized media may be afraid of losing access to the corridors of power, of political concerns, or of undermining their own positions as wealthy information-handling organizations.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>新闻业是调查和报道记者的读者、听众或观众感兴趣的新闻的职业。新闻学在经济和政治中起着重要的作用，它允许大众访问那些只对幸运的、有联系的少数人有用的信息。[第2段]新闻，我们现在知道它来自于新闻公司的崛起（尤其是在第十九和第二十世纪的报纸）。改善了交通和通讯，使通讯员能够快速移动、学习和向总部汇报，第十八和第十九世纪普通大众的大众文化的兴起。[段落：2 ]在二十世纪中后期，广播和电视的兴起为新闻工作者创造了新的传播信息的媒介。与此同时，他们改变了新闻在系统中流动的动态，以及可以呈现的信息种类，最终形成了“声音咬合”和“24小时新闻周期”等概念。今天，新闻业正经历着翻天覆地的变化，因为旧报纸在互联网时代难以保持公众读者，而批评人士认为，电视新闻已经成为安抚和操纵大众的平淡工具，而不是告知大众。与此同时，大量的有进取心的个人也开始自己对网络新闻进行评论和评论，创造出一个私人的、个性化的网络新闻领域。[第2段]记者和政府权力的“第四产业”之间的关系一直是不稳定的。在独裁统治下，国家对媒体的控制模糊了新闻和宣传之间的界限。即使在民主国家，有组织的媒体也可能害怕失去进入权力走廊的机会，害怕失去政治关切，害怕破坏自己作为富有的信息处理组织的地位。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MASONRY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"There hammer on the anvil smote, there chisel clove and graver wrote; There forged was blade and bound was hilt; The delver mined, the mason built."[PARAGRAPH:2]- J. R. R. Tolkien, The Lord of the Rings</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“铁锤上有锤子，凿子和雕刻刀写在那里；锻造的是刀刃，被缚的是刀柄；德弗尔铸造的是石匠建造的。”[段：2 ] -J.R.R.托尔金，指环王。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FERTILIZER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Fertilizers are substances which increase the fertility of soil by introducing nutrients that are often lacking. Since deficiencies in substances like nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium are often bottlenecks in plant growth, fertilizer makes plants to grow larger and more quickly. This is especially desirable in agriculture as it allows the same land to feed more people.[PARAGRAPH:2]Fertilization has been a common practice throughout the civilized world since prehistoric times. Farmers in nearly all places fertilized their fields with simple materials like animal (or human) dung, ground-up fish remains, or potsherds (most fertile soil in the Amazon basin is laced with broken pottery, and this appears to have been deliberate on the natives' part).[PARAGRAPH:2]During the 19th and 20th centuries, the range of available fertilizers grew dramatically. Industrial-scale extraction of minerals, particularly nitrates and phosphates, allowed vast increases in farm output. Advances in industrial chemistry allowed factories to create fully synthetic fertilizers too, using customized organic molecules to speed the growth of crops and inhibit the growth of weeds and parasites. This contributes to the success of the "Green Revolution" of the 1960s and 1970s at feeding a world population of seven billion and rising.[PARAGRAPH:2]In general, fertilizer achieves varying success. Used carelessly, it may not contribute to soil fertility (adding more of what's already there is pointless), or even decrease it (adding enough phosphorus to maximize growth may result in all the carbon in the soil being used up quickly). This is a particularly serious problem with "Green Revolution" crops in the modern era. Furthermore, careless or excessive use can lead to fertilizer seeping into waterways, causing oxygen depletion, algal blooms, and other ecological problems.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>肥料是通过引入经常缺乏的养分来提高土壤肥力的物质。由于氮、磷、钾等物质的缺乏往往是植物生长的瓶颈，肥料使植物生长得更大更快。在农业上，这是特别可取的，因为它允许同一土地养活更多的人。[段落：2 ]自史前时代以来，施肥一直是文明世界中的一种普遍做法。几乎所有地方的农民用动物（或人）粪便、地上的鱼遗骸或陶器（Amazon盆地中最肥沃的土壤都是破损的陶器）来种植田地，这在第十九和第二十个世纪中是故意的。可用肥料的范围急剧扩大。工业规模的矿物开采，特别是硝酸盐和磷酸盐的开采，使农业产量大幅增加。工业化学的进步也使工厂能够制造出完全合成的肥料，使用定制的有机分子来加速作物的生长，抑制杂草和寄生虫的生长。这有助于在20世纪60年代和70年代的“绿色革命”中成功地养活世界人口七十亿和上升。[段落：2 ]一般来说，肥料获得了不同的成功。如果不小心使用，它可能不会增加土壤肥力（增加更多已经没有意义的东西），甚至会降低肥力（增加足够的磷以使生长最大化，可能会导致土壤中的所有碳迅速消耗殆尽）。这是当代“绿色革命”作物面临的一个特别严重的问题。此外，不小心或过度使用会导致肥料渗入河道，导致氧气耗尽、藻类大量繁殖和其他生态问题。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MICROBIOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The cause of nutrition and growth resides not in the organism as a whole but in the separate elementary parts - the cells."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Theodor Schwann, Microscopical Researches into the Accordance in the Structure and Growth of Animals and Plants</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“营养和生长的原因不在于整个生物体，而在于单独的基本部分——细胞。”〔段落：2〕施旺，关于动物和植物结构和生长的微观研究</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REPLACEABLE_PARTS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Nothing is particularly hard if you divide it into small jobs."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Henry Ford</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“如果你把它分成小的工作，没有什么特别难的。”[段落：2 ] - Henry Ford</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LASER_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The night is far spent; the day is at hand. Let us therefore cast off the works of darkness, and let us put on the armor of light."[PARAGRAPH:2]- The Bible, Romans</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“夜已远去，白昼已近。因此，让我们抛开黑暗的作品，让我们穿上光明的铠甲。”[段落：2 ]——圣经，罗马人。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POWER_PROJECTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Power projection (or force projection) is a term used in military and political science to refer to the capacity of a state to apply all or some of its elements of national power - political, economic, informational, or military - to rapidly and effectively deploy and sustain forces in and from multiple dispersed locations to respond to crises, to contribute to deterrence, and to enhance regional stability.[PARAGRAPH:2]This ability is a crucial element of a state's power in international relations. Any state able to direct its military forces outside the limited bounds of its territory might be said to have some level of power projection capability, but the term itself is used most frequently in reference to militaries with a worldwide reach (or at least significantly broader than a state's immediate area). Even states with sizable hard power assets (such as a large standing army) may only be able to exert limited regional influence so long as they lack the means of effectively projecting their power on a global scale. Generally, only a select few states are able to overcome the logistical difficulties inherent in the deployment and direction of a modern, mechanized military force.[PARAGRAPH:2]The aircraft carrier strike group, strategic bomber, ballistic missile submarine, and strategic airlifter are all examples of power projection platforms. Military units designed to be light and mobile, such as airborne forces (paratroopers and air assault forces) and amphibious assault forces, are utilized in power projection. Forward basing is another method of power projection, which, by pre-positioning military units or stockpiles of arms at strategically located military bases outside a country's territory, reduces the time and distance needed to mobilize them.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>权力投射（或武力投射）是军事和政治科学中的一个术语，指一个国家运用其全部或部分国家权力要素（政治、经济、信息或军事）在多个分散地点迅速有效地部署和维持部队以应对危机的能力有助于威慑，增强地区稳定。[第2段]这种能力是国家在国际关系中的力量的关键因素。任何能够将其军事力量引向其领土范围以外的国家都可以说具有某种程度的力量投射能力，但这一术语本身最常用于指在全世界范围内（或至少比一个国家的直接地区大得多）的军事。即使是拥有大量硬实力资产的国家（如一支庞大的常备军），只要它们缺乏在全球范围有效投射其实力的手段，也可能只能发挥有限的区域影响力。一般来说，只有少数几个州能够克服现代机械化军事力量的部署和方向所固有的后勤困难。[第2段]航母打击群、战略轰炸机、弹道导弹潜艇和战略空中升降机都是动力投射平台的例子。设计为轻型和机动的军事单位，如空降部队（伞兵和空袭部队）和两栖攻击部队，都被用于力量投射。前向基地是另一种力量投射方法，通过在一国领土以外的战略军事基地预先部署军事单位或储存武器，减少动员军事单位所需的时间和距离。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_INFRASTRUCTURE</Tag>
		<English>Infrastructure</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>基础设施</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CYBERNETICS</Tag>
		<English>Cybernetics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>控制论</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TRANSHUMANISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Transhumanism is an international and intellectual movement that aims to transform the human condition by developing and making widely available sophisticated technologies to greatly enhance human intellect and physiology.[PARAGRAPH:2]Transhumanist thinkers study the potential benefits and dangers of emerging technologies that could overcome fundamental human - as well as ethical - limitations of utilizing such technologies. The most common transhumanist thesis is that human beings may eventually be able to transform themselves into different beings with abilities so greatly expanded from the natural condition as to merit the label of posthuman beings.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“传播学”是一项国际性和智力性的运动，旨在通过开发和制造广泛可用的尖端技术来改变人类的状况，从而大大提高人类的智力和生理学。〔2〕跨文化思想家研究新兴技术所能克服的潜在益处和危险。利用这类技术的基本人类和伦理限制。最常见的跨人文主义论断是，人类最终可能会将自己转变成不同的人，其能力从自然条件大大扩展，因此值得贴上后人类的标签。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_TOURISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Tourism is travel for pleasure or business; also the theory and practice of touring, the business of attracting, accommodating, and entertaining tourists, and the business of operating tours. Tourism may be international, or within the traveller's country. The World Tourism Organization defines tourism more generally, in terms which go "beyond the common perception of tourism as being limited to holiday activity only", as people "traveling to and staying in places outside their usual environment for not more than one consecutive year for leisure, business and other purposes".[PARAGRAPH:2]Tourism can be domestic or international, and international tourism has both incoming and outgoing implications on a country's balance of payments. Today, tourism is a major source of income for many countries, and affects the economy of both the source and host countries, in some cases being of vital importance.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>旅游业是为娱乐或商务目的而进行的旅行；也是旅游业的理论和实践、吸引、容纳和娱乐游客的业务以及经营旅游业的业务。旅游业可以是国际性的，也可以是在旅行者的国家内。世界旅游组织对旅游的定义更为普遍，“旅游”仅限于“仅限于假日活动”，因为人们“旅行和停留在通常环境之外的地方，不超过一年的休闲、商业和其他目的”。无论是国内旅游还是国际旅游，国际旅游都会对一国的国际收支产生影响。今天，旅游业是许多国家的主要收入来源，对来源国和东道国的经济都有影响，在某些情况下至关重要。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PASTORALISM</Tag>
		<English>Pastoralism</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>畜牧</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RIFLING</Tag>
		<English>Rifling</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>膛线</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SOCIOLOGY</Tag>
		<English>Sociology</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>社会学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ECONOMICS</Tag>
		<English>Economics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>经济学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ENGINEERING</Tag>
		<English>Engineering</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>工程学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SATELLITES_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The earth is the cradle of the mind but one cannot eternally live in a cradle."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Konstantin Tsiolkovsky</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“地球是心智的摇篮，但不能永远生活在摇篮里。”[段落：2 ] - Konstantin Tsiolkovsky</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AUTOMATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Automation is the art of making machines which perform tasks on their own, without active input or oversight from a human operator. Automatic constructs have existed as toys for the rich since ancient times, the products of individual craftsmanship, but widespread use of automation to control machines is a twentieth-century phenomenon.[PARAGRAPH:2]The demand for automation first came from the need to make machinery function where humans cannot or will not; be it in an extremely hostile environment, in a factory where machines ran faster than the human eye can follow, or in a job too menial and unstimulating for the average person to be content doing. Over time, automation has become more popular and flexible, especially with the rise of electronic computers.[PARAGRAPH:2]Automatic equipment invariably saves human labor, but it also displaces labour. The simple tasks involved in doing the machine's job are replaced by specialized jobs tending the machines. Or not replaced at all.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>自动化是一门制造机器的艺术，这些机器可以自己执行任务，而不需要人工的积极投入或监督。自古以来，自动构造作为富足玩具已经存在，是个体工艺的产物，但是自动化控制机器的广泛使用是一个二十世纪的现象。[第2段]自动化的需求首先来自于使机器功能在人类不能或不需要的地方；无论是在极端恶劣的环境中，在机器运行速度超过人眼所能跟随的工厂，还是在一个对普通人来说太卑微、太不刺激的工作中。随着时间的推移，自动化已经变得越来越普及和灵活，特别是随着电子计算机的兴起。〔2〕自动化设备总是节省人力，但也代替劳动。做机器工作所涉及的简单任务被照料机器的专门工作所取代。或者根本没有被替换。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CONSUMERISM_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Many a small thing has been made large by the right kind of advertising."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Mark Twain</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“许多小东西都是通过正确的广告制作的。”[段落：2 ] - Mark Twain</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_URBAN_PLANNING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Urban planning is a technical and political process concerned with the development and use of land, planning permission, protection and use of the environment, public welfare, and the design of the urban environment, including air, water, and the infrastructure passing into and out of urban areas, such as transportation, communications, and distribution networks. Urban planning is also referred to as urban and regional planning, regional planning, town planning, city planning, rural planning or some combination in various areas worldwide. It takes many forms and it can share perspectives and practices with urban design.[PARAGRAPH:2]Urban planning guides orderly development in urban, suburban and rural areas. Although predominantly concerned with the planning of settlements and communities, urban planning is also responsible for the planning and development of water use and resources, rural and agricultural land, parks and conserving areas of natural environmental significance. Practitioners of urban planning are concerned with research and analysis, strategic thinking, architecture, urban design, public consultation, policy recommendations, implementation and management.[PARAGRAPH:2]Urban planners work with the cognate fields of architecture, landscape architecture, civil engineering, and public administration to achieve strategic, policy and sustainability goals. Early urban planners were often members of these cognate fields. Today urban planning is a separate, independent professional discipline. The discipline is the broader category that includes different sub-fields such as land-use planning, zoning, economic development, environmental planning, and transportation planning.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>城市规划是一个涉及土地开发利用、规划许可、环境保护和利用、公共福利、城市环境设计（包括空气、水）和进出城市地区的基础设施（如交通、通信等）的技术和政治过程，以及分销网络。城市规划又称为城市与区域规划、区域规划、城镇规划、城市规划、农村规划或世界各地的某些组合。它具有多种形式，它可以与城市设计共享观点和实践。〔2〕城市规划指导城市、郊区和农村的有序发展。城市规划虽然主要涉及住区和社区的规划，但也负责规划和开发用水和资源、农村和农业用地、公园和具有自然环境意义的保护区。城市规划的实践者关心研究和分析、战略思维、建筑、城市设计、公众咨询、政策建议、实施和管理。〔2〕城市规划师与建筑、景观建筑、土木工程等相关领域一起工作；以及公共行政以实现战略、政策和可持续性目标。早期的城市规划者常常是这些同源领域的成员。今天，城市规划是一门独立的专业学科。该学科是更广泛的范畴，包括不同的子领域，如土地利用规划、分区、经济发展、环境规划和交通规划。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SPACEFLIGHT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Utilizing the now well-developed science of rocketry, the modern exploration of space began in October 1957 when the Soviet Union launched Sputnik 1. This tiny satellite orbited the earth for 57 days, providing information on radiation and other phenomena in the upper atmosphere. In less than a year, the United States had also launched a satellite, Explorer 1. This started the "space race", years of competition between the U.S. and the U.S.S.R. to achieve new frontiers in space exploration. Space flight advanced rapidly from the simple sub-orbital flights of the 1950s, to manned missions to Earth's moon in the late 1960s. The rapid growth of space technology led to many practical applications, such as weather and surveillance satellites, and vastly improved worldwide communications. Today, although hindered by severe government budget cuts, the exploration of space continues.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>利用现在发展良好的火箭科学，现代太空探索始于1957年10月苏联发射人造卫星1号。这颗小卫星绕地球运行了57天，提供了高层大气辐射和其他现象的信息。在不到一年的时间里，美国还发射了一颗卫星，探索者1号。这就开始了“太空竞赛”，即美国和苏联多年来为实现太空探索的新前沿而展开的竞争。空间飞行从20世纪50年代的简单亚轨道飞行迅速发展到20世纪60年代末的载人登月任务，空间技术的迅速发展带动了气象卫星、监视卫星等许多实际应用，极大地改善了全球通信。今天，尽管受到政府预算大幅削减的阻碍，太空探索仍在继续。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LASER</Tag>
		<English>Laser</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>激光</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ETHICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Ethics is the philosophical study which addresses moral questions - matters of right and wrong, virtue and vice, justice and injustice. This has preoccupied thinkers since ancient times, but formal discussion and contemplation of ethics as a logic-based endeavour, as distinct from traditions of religious or secular law, are mostly a product of the classical and medieval periods.[PARAGRAPH:2]Different cultures produce widely divergent schools of ethics, ranging from the law-oriented systems common in China to the relatively individualist virtue-ethical schools of the ancient Greeks. Ethics may be highly abstract or applied as a practical matter to questions of professional conduct and personal behavior. They may emphasize the intent of the moral actor, the fulfillment of certain laws and precepts, the consequences of the action itself, or any combination of the above.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>伦理学是研究道德问题的哲学，这些问题包括对与错、善与恶、正义与非正义。自古以来，这就一直是思想家们所关注的问题，但与传统宗教和世俗法不同的是，对伦理作为一种基于逻辑的努力的正式讨论和思考，大多是古典和中世纪时期的产物。[段落：2 ]不同的文化产生了广泛不同的伦理学派，从中国常见的以法律为导向的制度到古希腊人相对个人主义的美德伦理学派。伦理可能是高度抽象的，或者作为一个实际问题应用于职业行为和个人行为的问题。它们可能强调道德行为人的意图、某些法律和戒律的实现、行为本身的后果或上述任何组合。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_HUMANITIES</Tag>
		<English>Humanities</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>人文科学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATIONHOOD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Needs to be written</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>需要写</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REPLACEABLE_PARTS</Tag>
		<English>Replaceable Parts</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>可更换部件</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RADIO</Tag>
		<English>Radio</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>无线电</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REFINING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>When the demand for oil-based fuels for lighting and other purposes began to soar in the 19th century, scientists began searching for a way to make use of crude oil. This research led to techniques in which crude oil was broken down, or refined, into a number of different fuels, including kerosene and gasoline. As consumer demand continued to increase, commercial refineries were set up to purify crude oil. The new petroleum products produced as a result of the development and perfection of the refining process led to the use of oil-based fuels in many consumer and industrial applications. These include the use of petrol to power automobiles, and the use of oil for heating and for the generation of electrical power.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>当19世纪对照明和其他用途的油基燃料的需求开始飙升时，科学家们开始寻找利用原油的方法。这项研究产生了将原油分解或提炼成多种不同燃料的技术，包括煤油和汽油。随着消费者需求的持续增加，商业炼油厂的建立是为了净化原油。由于炼油工艺的发展和完善而产生的新的石油产品导致在许多消费和工业应用中使用油基燃料。这些措施包括使用汽油为汽车提供动力，以及使用石油加热和发电。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REPRESENTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Representation is the practice of having one person stand in for the interests of another person, or of many people. In the context of politics, a government official can be said to 'represent' a 'constituency' who select that official, support them, and hold them accountable for the government's actions. This is a feature of democratic governments.[PARAGRAPH:2]Representative democracy began to evolve in ancient Athens and Rome. The working-class Roman plebeians, in particular, played a major role in creating the concept. In the 490s BC, the plebeians went on a mass strike and refusing to do any more labor until the elite patrician class created the office of the "plebeian tribune." The tribunes were elected by the plebeians to protect their interests from the relatively wealthy and powerful patricians. Toward this end, the tribunes were empowered to block any action taken by the Senate, which was called "veto" from the Latin for "I forbid." Likewise, they were legally sacrosanct and any person who so much as touched a tribune or interfered with their duty in any way could be put to death.[PARAGRAPH:2]This idea, that the masses could vote not only on policy issues but on the creation of officials to protect their interests and govern the state on their behalf, remained largely dormant in Western society until the rise of the commercial republics of the late Middle Ages. After that time it began to flourish during the Enlightenment era, for a simple reason. Direct democracy, in which all citizens vote on all actions taken by the state, becomes impossibly unwieldy when the state contains more than, at most, about ten thousand citizens. It is also impractical if the citizenry is spread over a large area so that it cannot meet regularly. For a republic that is several days' travel across, or which has many thousands of voters, to function, representation becomes vital.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first large European state to employ representative democracy in a significant way was England. The English parliament, which originated as a means for the king to gather the representatives of the populace to hear his wishes and agree on ways to fund his plans, slowly evolved into a body which held the "purse strings" of the entire English government. Ultimately, kings became unable to run their government without Parliament's approval. The efforts of Charles I to do so in the 1630s and 1640s led ultimately to the English Civil War, and to Charles I's execution by beheading.[PARAGRAPH:2]Thus, representative democracy became established as an alternative to, and potentially an antagonist toward, the notion of the 'divine right of kings' then dominant in continental Europe. This conflict between monarchy and democracy was resolved amicably in England after the 'Glorious Revolution' of 1688, which created a constitutional monarchy headed by a reasonably popular king- and one who knew not to overstep the limits of what the people would tolerate.[PARAGRAPH:2]To this day, this pattern of conflict between representative bodies (legislatures and elected executive officials) and unelected autocrats is a persistent one throughout the world.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>代表是让一个人代表另一个人或许多人的利益。在政治背景下，一个政府官员可以说是“代表”了一个“选民”，他们选择了这个官员，支持他们，并要求他们对政府的行为负责。这是民主政府的一个特点。[段：2 ]代表性民主在古代Athens和罗马开始发展。尤其是工人阶级的罗马平民，在创造这一概念方面发挥了重要作用。公元前49年代，平民举行大规模罢工，拒绝再做任何劳动，直到贵族精英阶层建立了“平民论坛”的办公室。论坛是由平民选举出来的，以保护他们的利益，免受相对富裕和强大的贵族。为此，论坛被授权阻止参议院采取的任何行动，从拉丁语中被称为“否决”，“我不允许”。同样，他们在法律上是神圣不可侵犯的，任何一个触碰论坛者或以任何方式干涉他们职责的人都可能被处死。在中世纪晚期商业共和国崛起之前，大众不仅可以在政策问题上投票，还可以在官员的产生上投票，以保护他们的利益和代表他们治理国家。在那之后，它开始在启蒙时代蓬勃发展，原因很简单。直接民主，即所有公民对国家采取的所有行动进行投票，当国家的公民人数最多超过1万人时，这种民主就变得不可能实现。如果公民分散在一大片地区，以致不能定期开会，那也是不切实际的。对于一个有好几天行程的共和国来说，或者有成千上万的选民参与其中，代表性就变得至关重要。[段：2 ]欧洲第一个以代表性的方式使用代表性民主的国家是英国。英国议会最初是国王召集民众代表听取其意愿并就资助其计划的方式达成一致的一种手段，后来慢慢演变成一个掌握着整个英国政府“钱袋子”的机构。最终，没有议会的批准，国王们无法管理政府。查尔斯一世在1630年和1640年所做的努力最终导致了英国内战，查尔斯对我的斩首处决。[第2段]，代议制民主被确立为对“欧洲神权”的概念的另一种选择，也可能是一种对立的“君权神授”的概念。君主政体与民主的冲突在1688的“光荣革命”后在英国友好地解决了，它创造了一个由一个相当受欢迎的国王领导的君主立宪政体，一个知道不超越人们容忍的限度的人。这种代表机构（立法机关和民选行政官员）与未经民选的独裁者之间的冲突模式在全世界一直存在。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MYTHOLOGY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Mythology refers variously to the collected myths of a group of people. Myths are the stories people tell to explain nature, history and customs. Myth is a feature of every culture. Many sources for myths have been proposed, ranging from personification of nature or personification of natural phenomena, to truthful or hyperbolic accounts of historical events to explanations of existing rituals. A culture's collective mythology helps convey belonging, shared and religious experiences, behavioral models and moral and practical lessons.[PARAGRAPH:2]One theory claims that myths are distorted accounts of historical events. According to this theory, storytellers repeatedly elaborate upon historical accounts until the figures in those accounts gain the status of gods. Other theories propose that myths began as allegories for natural phenomena: Apollo represents the sun, Poseidon represents water, and so on. According to another theory, myths began as allegories for philosophical or spiritual concepts: Athena represents wise judgment, Aphrodite desire, and so on. Some thinkers claimed that myths result from the personification of inanimate objects and forces. According to these thinkers, the ancients worshiped natural phenomena, such as fire and air, gradually deifying them. According to the myth-ritual theory, myth is tied to ritual. In its most extreme form, this theory claims myths arose to explain rituals.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>神话是指人们收集的各种神话。神话是人们用来解释自然、历史和习俗的故事。神话是每一种文化的特征。人们提出了许多神话的来源，从自然的拟人化或自然现象的拟人化，到对历史事件的真实或夸张的叙述，再到对现有仪式的解释。一个文化的集体神话有助于传达归属、分享和宗教体验、行为模式和道德和实践的教训。[段落：2 ]一个理论声称神话是对历史事件的歪曲。根据这一理论，讲故事的人反复阐述历史记载，直到这些记载中的人物获得神的地位。其他的理论认为神话起源于自然现象的寓言：阿波罗代表太阳，波塞冬代表水，等等。根据另一种理论，神话最初是哲学或精神概念的寓言：雅典娜代表明智的判断，阿芙罗狄蒂的欲望，等等。一些思想家认为神话是无生命物体和力量的拟人化。在这些思想家看来，古人崇拜火、气等自然现象，逐渐将其神化。根据神话仪式理论，神话与仪式紧密相连。在最极端的形式下，这个理论声称神话是用来解释仪式的。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BALLISTICS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The rise of industrial machine tools in the late 19th century had huge effects on the development of artillery. More precise manufacturing meant ammunition that could be fired at far longer ranges, with more predictable fuzing and gunlaying. Advances in metallurgy made for stronger gun barrels and longer range. For the first time, indirect-fire guns were useful for something other than specialist roles. The effective range of artillery increased by as much as a factor of ten within a generation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>19世纪末工业机床的兴起对火炮的发展产生了巨大的影响。更精确的制造意味着弹药可以在更远的射程发射，引信和炮弹的安放也更容易预测。冶金技术的进步使炮筒更坚固，射程更长。这是第一次，间接射击枪是有用的东西，而不是专家的作用。炮兵的有效射程在一代之内增加了10倍。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PHOTOGRAPHY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Photography is the practice of using artifical tools to capture visual images in a durable form. Photography relies on optical devices (usually lenses) to focus incoming light onto a light-sensitive surface, which is then altered by the light so that the effect of the light on the surface can be stored for later reference.[PARAGRAPH:2]Experiments with photography began around 1800 with efforts to capture images created in a camera obscura (pinhole camera) using light-sensitive chemicals. These efforts began to bear fruit in the 1820s with the development of the photographic plate. Early photography required that the photograph be exposed to the image it was meant to record for a period of hours, making it impractical for any purpose other than taking pictures of landscapes or buildings. By the late 1830s, Louis Daguerre had refined the process until the exposure time had fallen to ten minutes, making it practical for an individual person to be photographed. In 1839, the French government presented Daguerre's method, "open source," as a gift of France to the world.[PARAGRAPH:2]Meanwhile, other experimentalists worked on promising avenues, such as the creation of photographic 'film' which would form a 'negative,' reversed version of the image (light parts would be dark and vice versa). Further advances in making photographs durable, reproducible, and quick-exposing continued throughout the 19th century.[PARAGRAPH:2]Around 1900, Eastman and Kodak introduced photographic film - a flexible roll of material that could be used as a backing for light-sensitive chemicals in the camera, removing the need for large, fragile glass photographic plates. Film replaced plates for almost all types of photography other than scientific applications. (Glass plate photography revolutionized astronomy, for instance, by allowing astronomers to record observations or gather up all the light coming to their telescope from the same star onto a single plate for an hours-long exposure).[PARAGRAPH:2]Color photography, meanwhile, had been practiced as early as the 1860s based on improved scientific understanding of light. However, it was impractical for normal applications until the mid-20th century, representing a further advance over the previously monochrome photos of the era. By the 1970s and '80s, the art of photography had largely stabilized on the standard of film cameras capable of imaging multiple colors on the same piece of film, which would then be "developed" in a laboratory using special chemicals to stabilize and desensitize the film. The resulting film would then form 'negatives' from which accurate reproductions of the original image could be reconstructed.[PARAGRAPH:2]However, photography was once again revolutionized by the rise of electronic 'digital' cameras. Today, digital cameras that electronically detect light and send the resulting images into digital storage have largely replaced chemical film. Digital cameras have the advantages of requiring no development, storing nigh-unlimited numbers of photos, and being so easily miniaturized that they can be casually attached to a device the size of a pack of cards, as a cheap extra feature.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>摄影是使用人工工具以持久的形式捕捉视觉图像的实践。摄影依靠光学设备（通常是透镜）将入射光聚焦到感光表面上，然后光被改变，以使表面上的光的影响可以被存储以备以后参考。[段落：2 ]摄影的实验开始于1800左右，用光敏化学物质捕捉相机暗盒（针孔相机）中产生的图像。随着照相底片的发展，这些努力在19世纪20年代开始取得成果。早期的摄影要求将照片暴露在它原本要记录的图像中数小时，这使得它在拍摄风景或建筑物以外的任何目的都不切实际。到了19世纪30年代末，路易斯·达盖尔改进了这个过程，直到曝光时间降到10分钟，使个人被拍摄变得切实可行。1839，法国政府将笪谷耳热的方法“开源”作为法国赠送给世界的礼物。（段落：2）同时，其他实验主义者致力于有前途的途径，如创建照片“胶片”，这将形成一个“负面的”反转版本的图像（光部分将是黑暗的，反之亦然）。在十九世纪整个期间，使照片耐用、重现性好、曝光迅速的新进展。[段：2 ]大约1900，伊士曼和柯达推出了照相胶卷——一种柔韧的卷材，可以用作照相机中光敏化学物质的支撑物，消除了对大面积的需要，易碎的玻璃照相底片。除了科学应用外，几乎所有类型的摄影都用胶卷代替了底片。（格拉斯板块照相术使天文学家产生了革命性的变化，例如，天文学家可以记录观测结果，或者将来自同一恒星的所有光聚集到一块板上，持续一小时曝光）。早在19世纪60年代，人们就在提高对光的科学认识的基础上进行了实践。然而，在20世纪中叶之前，这对于正常的应用是不现实的，这代表了对那个时代以前单色照片的进一步改进。到了20世纪70年代和80年代，摄影艺术基本上稳定在能够在同一片胶片上成像多种颜色的胶片相机的标准上，然后在实验室中使用特殊的化学物质来稳定和降低胶片的感光度。最终的电影将形成“底片”，从中可以重建原始图像的精确复制。[段落：2 ]然而，摄影又一次被电子数码相机的崛起革命化。如今，电子检测光线并将结果图像送入数字存储器的数码相机已经在很大程度上取代了化学胶片。数码相机的优点是无需开发，可以存储几乎无限数量的照片，而且很容易微型化，可以随意地连接到一包卡片大小的设备上，作为一种廉价的额外功能。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NAVIGATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>In the early days of seafaring, sailors operated solely through a process known as "piloting", in which the position and course of the ship was determined by referring to geographical landmarks. The need to stay in view of the shore severely limited the extent of sea voyages. Through experience, sailors learned to apply the science of astronomy to their profession, noting the positions and movement of particular stars. They realized that even when the shore was out of sight, they could steer by certain reliable stars. This crude, yet practical application of astronomy allowed the adventurous to sail into the unknown with a reasonable chance of finding their way. As a result, ship building technology quickly improved, producing larger, more stable ships designed for longer voyages.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在航海的早期，水手们仅仅通过一个称为“领航”的过程来操作，在这个过程中，船只的位置和航向是通过参考地理标志来确定的。必须站在岸边观望，这严重限制了海上航行的范围。通过经验，水手们学会了将天文学应用到他们的职业中，注意到特定恒星的位置和运动。他们意识到，即使在看不见海岸的情况下，他们也可以靠某些可靠的恒星来导航。这种简陋而实用的天文学应用，使敢于冒险的人有了一个合理的机会去探索未知的世界。因此，造船技术迅速改进，生产出更大、更稳定的船舶，用于更长的航程。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_JUDICIARY</Tag>
		<English>Judiciary</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>司法</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GLOBALISM_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"I am a citizen of the world."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Diogenes of Sinope</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我是世界公民”[段落：2 ] - Diogenes of Sinope</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FISHING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Give a man a fish and you feed him for a day. Teach a man to fish and you feed him for a lifetime."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Lao Tzu</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“给一个人一条鱼，你就喂他一天。教一个人钓鱼，你养活他一辈子。”[段落：2 ] - Lao Tzu</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ALLOYS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Evidence of the use of bronze, an alloy of copper and tin, dates back to Thailand in 4500 BC. Several hundred years later, bronze working was discovered in the Middle East. Artifacts from this period show that bronze was initially used for decorative purposes only. This is because tin was not readily available. It wasn't until approximately 2000 BC, when tin was regularly imported from neighboring regions, that bronze replaced copper in the construction of larger items. Bronze was harder and less brittle than copper, and it held a sharper edge. Tools, weapons, and armor made from bronze were also cheaper to produce and more durable. The period of time when bronze was the metal of choice for such items was known as the Bronze Age. The Bronze Age lasted until iron working became prevalent in approximately 1200 BC.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>青铜是铜和锡的合金，其使用的证据可以追溯到公元前4500年的泰国。几百年后，在中东发现了青铜制品。这一时期的文物表明，青铜最初只用于装饰目的。这是因为锡不易得到。直到公元前2000年左右，当锡从邻近地区定期进口时，青铜才在建造更大的物品时取代了铜。青铜比铜硬，不那么脆，而且它有一个更锋利的边缘。青铜制造的工具、武器和盔甲也更便宜，更耐用。青铜时代是这类物品的首选金属。青铜时代一直持续到公元前1200年左右，炼铁开始盛行。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NATIONALISM_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"What is patriotism but love of the good things we ate in our childhood?"[PARAGRAPH:2]- Lin Yutang, The Importance of Living</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“什么是爱国主义，而不是对童年吃过的好东西的热爱？”〔段落：2〕-林语堂，生活的重要性</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FORTIFICATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Fortifications are structures built to aid in the defense of a point or area against attackers. Various types of fortification have existed since prehistoric times: the proto-city of Jericho was protected by a wall over three meters high as early as 9000 BCE, although this may have been as much a flood control measure as a military defense. The growth of civilization and advances in the killing power of weapons made fixed defenses ever more important.[PARAGRAPH:2]The basic concept of walling a city is to deter casual raiders and force even a determined army into a protracted, costly siege. Incorporating defensible features into buildings, such as narrow windows and entryways, provides cover to defenders and make it hard for attackers to push into the building safely.[PARAGRAPH:2]Advances in engineering during medieval times, and larger labor forces made available by advances in agriculture, allowed a great increase in the scale of defensive works. Entire provinces could be protected by walls like the famous Great Wall of China, or Hadrian's Wall in Britain. Individual points could be held with great castles and fortresses, strong enough that it would take years of siege to starve them out, as a mass assault by soldiers using normal means was guaranteed to fail.[PARAGRAPH:2]This goal of demanding multi-year sieges became impractical with the invention of gunpowder-based artillery, but the art of fortification remained prominent. Architects devised new ways to build defenses that would absorb and deflect cannon fire, sheltering troops from enemy guns and channeling attackers into zones where the defenders' guns could be brought to bear.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>防御工事是为了帮助防御一个点或地区的攻击而建造的结构。从史前时代起，就存在着各种防御工事：早在公元前9000年，杰里科的原始城市就被一堵3米高的墙所保护，尽管这可能和军事防御一样是防洪措施。文明的发展和武器的杀戮力量的进步使固定防御变得更加重要。[段落：2 ]城墙的基本概念是阻止偶然的袭击者，甚至迫使一支坚定的军队陷入长期的、代价高昂的围攻中。将可防御的特征融入到建筑物中，例如狭窄的窗户和入口，为防御者提供掩护，使攻击者难以安全地推进建筑物。[段落：2 ]中世纪时期工程的进步，以及农业进步所带来的更大的劳动力，使防御工程的规模大大增加。整个省份都可能受到长城的保护，比如著名的中国长城，或者英国的哈德良长城。每一个据点都可以用城堡和堡垒来支撑，强大到足以用几年的围攻把他们饿死，因为士兵使用正常手段进行大规模的攻击是有可能失败的。[段落：2 ]这项要求多年围攻的目标对于发明火药的火炮来说是不切实际的，但是防御工事的艺术仍然很突出。建筑师们设计了新的方法来建造防御工事，吸收和转移炮火，保护部队免受敌人的炮火袭击，并引导攻击者进入防御工事的炮火可以承受的区域。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_GENERALSHIP_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Victorious warriors win first and then go to war, while defeated warriors go to war first and then seek to win."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Sun Tzu, The Art of War</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“胜利的战士先赢，然后去打仗，而战败的勇士先打仗，然后争取胜利。”[段落：2 ] - Sun Tzu，战争艺术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_DIVINATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>People of the ancient world were fascinated and awed by the forces of nature surrounding them. Earthquakes, storms and other phenomena were generally regarded as signs from heaven. Individuals and groups arose to formulate explanations for these events, and pass the knowledge along to the tribe. The priests and priestesses of mysticism, often called oracles, claimed union with the divine through meditation and trance-like contemplation.[PARAGRAPH:2]Oracles across the world developed complex rites and rituals to appease and interact with gods and spirits. One of the most common forms of supernatural power invoked was divination - the ability to foretell the future using signs and portents such as dreams, the motions of the stars, the guts of sacrificial animals, the fracture lines in a tortoise's shell, visions experienced while under the influence of various drugs, and so on. Divination served the common human need to obtain information about the unknown future.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>古代世界的人们被周围的自然力量所吸引和敬畏。地震、风暴和其他现象通常被认为是来自天堂的征兆。个人和团体开始为这些事件制定解释，并将知识传递给部落。神秘主义者的祭司和祭司们，通常称为神谕，通过冥想和恍惚般的冥想要求与神圣结合。[段落：2 ]世界各地的神谕发展了复杂的仪式和仪式来安抚和与神和灵互动。其中一种最常见的超自然力量是占卜，占卜是一种利用诸如梦、星星的运动、献祭动物的内脏、龟壳上的骨折线、在各种药物的影响下经历的幻觉等迹象和征兆来预测未来的能力。占卜服务于人类获取未知未来信息的共同需要。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RENEWABLE_ENERGY</Tag>
		<English>Renewable Energy</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>可再生能源</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BALLISTICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Artillery adds dignity to what would otherwise be a vulgar brawl."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Frederick the Great</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“炮兵增加了尊严，使之成为一种粗俗的斗殴。”[段落：2 ] - Frederick the Great</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LITERATURE</Tag>
		<English>Literature</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>文献</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_STEEL_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"There never was a good knife made of bad steel."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Benjamin Franklin</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“从来没有一把用坏钢做的好刀。”[段落：2 ] -本杰明·富兰克林</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AVIATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"What railways have done for nations, airways will do for the world."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Claude Grahame-White, The Aeroplane</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“铁路为国家所做的一切，航空公司将为世界服务。”[段落：2 ] - Claude Grahame White，飞机。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AESTHETICS</Tag>
		<English>Aesthetics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>美学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ENGINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>An engine or motor is a machine designed to convert one form of energy into mechanical energy. Heat engines burn a fuel to create heat, which is then used to create a force. Electric motors convert electrical energy into mechanical motion; pneumatic motors use compressed air and clockwork motors in wind-up toys use elastic energy.[PARAGRAPH:2]Internal combustion piston engines  were tested in France in 1807 by de Rivaz and independently, by the Niépce brothers. They were theoretically advanced by Carnot in 1824. In 1853-57 Eugenio Barsanti and Felice Matteucci invented and patented an engine using the free-piston principle that was possibly the first 4-cycle engine.[PARAGRAPH:2]The invention of an internal combustion engine which was later commercially successful was made during 1860 by Etienne Lenoir. The Otto cycle in 1877 was capable of giving a far higher power to weight ratio than steam engines and worked much better for many transportation applications such as cars and aircraft.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>发动机或马达是一种将一种形式的能量转换为机械能的机器。热机燃烧一种燃料来产生热量，然后用来产生一种力。电动马达将电能转换为机械运动；气动马达在压缩玩具中使用压缩空气和发条马达使用弹性能量。〔2〕内燃活塞发动机在法国于1807由de Rivaz独立测试，并由Ni Access PCE兄弟进行测试。它们理论上是卡诺在1824年提出的。在1853-57年，Eugenio Barsanti和费利斯马图基发明并使用了自由活塞原理发明了一种发动机，这可能是第一个4循环发动机。[段落：2 ]内燃机的发明在1860期间由艾蒂安列诺尔制造。1877年的奥托循环能够提供比蒸汽机高得多的功率重量比，并且在许多交通应用中工作得更好，如汽车和飞机。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_REFINING_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The formula for success: rise early, work late, and strike oil."[PARAGRAPH:2]- J. Paul Getty</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“成功的公式：早起，工作晚，打击石油。”[段落：2 ] - J. Paul Getty</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AVIATION</Tag>
		<English>Aviation</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>航空学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_SUPERMATERIALS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Needs to be written.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>需要写下来。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_POTTERY</Tag>
		<English>Pottery</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>制陶术</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FUSION</Tag>
		<English>Fusion</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>核聚变</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EDUCATION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Education is the kindling of a flame, not the filling of a vessel."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Socrates</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“教育是火焰的点燃，而不是容器的填充。”[段落：2 ] - Socrates</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_RADIO_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"A world without radio is a deaf world."[PARAGRAPH:2] - Ernest Yeboah</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一个没有无线电的世界是一个聋人的世界。”[段落：2 ] - Ernest Yeboah</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMBINED_ARMS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Combined arms is an approach to warfare which seeks to integrate different combat arms of a military to achieve mutually complementary effects (for example, using infantry and armor in an urban environment, where one supports the other, or both support each other).[PARAGRAPH:2]The 17th century saw increasing use of combined arms at lower (regimental) level. King Gustavus Adolphus of Sweden was the proponent of the idea. For fire support he attached teams of "commanded musketeers" to cavalry units and fielded light 3-pounder guns to provide infantry units with organic artillery.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the eighteenth century, the concept of the legion was revived. Legions now consisted of musketeers, light infantry, dragoons and artillery in a brigade sized force. These legions often combined professional military personnel with militia. Perhaps the most notable example is the use of light cavalry, light infantry and light horse artillery in advance detachments by France's La Grande Armée during the Napoleonic Wars.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>联合兵种是一种作战方法，它试图将一支军队的不同作战兵种结合起来，以达到相互补充的效果（例如，在城市环境中使用步兵和装甲，其中一种支持另一种，[二者相互支持] [ [段：2 ]十七世纪]越来越多地使用组合军团在较低（团）级。瑞典国王古斯塔夫斯·阿道夫是这一想法的支持者。为了火力支援，他将“指挥火枪手”的队伍附在骑兵部队上，并派出轻三炮来为步兵部队提供有机火炮。[段：2 ]在十八世纪，军团的概念复活了。军团现在由火枪手、轻步兵、龙骑兵和大炮组成。这些军团经常将专业军事人员与民兵结合起来。也许最显著的例子是在拿破仑战争期间，法国的拉格朗德武装在先遣分遣队中使用轻骑兵、轻步兵和轻马炮兵。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_FISSION</Tag>
		<English>Fission</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>核裂变</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_ERA_DIGITAL</Tag>
		<English>Digital</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese></Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_AERODYNAMICS_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Oh! I have slipped the surly bonds of Earth and danced the skies on laughter-silvered wings."[PARAGRAPH:2]- John Gillespie Magee Jr., High Flight</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“哦！我滑下了地球的黏结，舞动着天空，在银色的翅膀上欢笑。”[段落：2 ]——约翰·吉莱斯皮·麻吉</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PNEUMATICS</Tag>
		<English>Pneumatics</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>气体力学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PATRONAGE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Never respect men merely for their riches, but rather for their philanthropy; we do not value the sun for its height, but for its use."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Gamaliel Bailey</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“永远不要仅仅因为他们的财富而尊敬他们，而应该尊重他们的慈善事业；我们不重视太阳的高度，而是为了它的用途。”[段落：2 ] - Gamaliel Bailey</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ECOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"We do not inherit the Earth from our ancestors, we borrow it from our children."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Wendell Berry, The Unforeseen Wilderness</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“我们不从祖先那里继承地球，我们从我们的孩子那里借来它。”[段落：2 ]——Wendell Berry，未预见的荒野。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_PASTORALISM_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The greatness of a nation can be judged by the way its animals are treated."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Mohandas Gandhi</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“一个国家的伟大可以通过它对待动物的方式来判断。”[段落：2 ] - Mohandas Gandhi</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EXPLORATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>The earliest intercontinental explorers were part of government-funded expeditions, as with Zheng He, Christopher Columbus, and Bartholomew Diaz. Soon it became clear that there were vast riches to be had from trade in luxury goods with remote lands, and where long range seafaring continued to thrive, private enterprise soon followed.[PARAGRAPH:2]For the people of the time, a trip from Europe to trade for spices, gems, silk and other precious goods in Asia was immensely time-consuming, requiring the most advanced ships and years of time and effort by a crew of skilled sailors. Quite a few ships that attempted the voyage never made it back, being destroyed by storms or hostile locals over the tens of thousands of kilometres of sea voyage.[PARAGRAPH:2]The risks involved created a powerful incentive to limit the financial hazards of the trip - any one merchant who invested in such an expedition might be ruined if something went wrong. Groups of wealthy men began to organize 'companies', bands that would pool their resources and share the costs of the long, immensely profitable trips.[PARAGRAPH:2]Some of these companies were able to secure royal guarantees from their home nations of exclusive trading rights- early examples include the English, Dutch, and French East India Companies. Over time, these organizations became extremely powerful, as the first ancestors of the modern multinational corporation.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>最早的洲际探险家是政府资助的探险队的一员，如郑和、克里斯托弗·哥伦布和巴塞洛缪·迪亚兹。很快，很明显，从遥远的土地上的奢侈品贸易中获得了巨大的财富，而长期的航海业继续繁荣起来，私营企业很快就开始了。[段：2 ]对于当时的人们来说，从欧洲到香料、宝石、丝绸和其他贵重物品在亚洲的贸易是非常耗时的。需要最先进的船只，需要熟练水手的多年时间和努力。有几艘试图航行的轮船从来没有返航过，在几万公里的海上航行中被风暴或敌对的当地人摧毁。[第2段]所涉及的风险创造了一个强有力的动机来限制这次旅行的财务风险。出错了。一群富有的人开始组织“公司”，这些乐队可以汇集他们的资源，分享长期的、非常有利可图的旅行的费用。[第2段]这些公司中的一些公司能够从他们的独占贸易权中获得王室担保。早期的例子包括英国人，荷兰人，以及法国东印度公司。随着时间的推移，这些组织变得极其强大，成为现代跨国公司的第一个祖先。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_METALLURGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The purest ore is produced from the hottest furnace; the brightest thunderbolt is elicited from the darkest storm."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Charles Caleb Colton, Lacon</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“最纯净的矿石是从最热的炉子中产生的，最亮的雷电是从最黑暗的风暴中引出的”（段落：2）- Charles Caleb Colton，莱肯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ARTIFICIAL_INTELLIGENCE_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"The mystery which surrounds a thinking machine already surrounds a thinking man."[PARAGRAPH:2]- B. F. Skinner, Contingencies of Reinforcement</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“围绕一个思维机器的神秘已经包围了一个思维的人。”[段落：2 ]——B. F. Skinner，强化的偶然性。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPASS</Tag>
		<English>Compass</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>罗盘</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MYTHOLOGY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"Not at all similar are the race of the immortal gods and the race of men who walk upon the earth."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Homer, The Iliad</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“不朽的神的种族和行走在地球上的人的种族一点也不相似。”[段落：2 ] -荷马，伊利亚特。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CHARITY_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"If you haven't got any charity in your heart, you have the worst kind of heart trouble."[PARAGRAPH:2]- Bob Hope</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>“如果你心中没有任何慈善机构，你就有最严重的心脏病。”[段落：2 ] -鲍勃·霍普</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOLOGY</Tag>
		<English>Biology</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>生物学</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_CONSTRUCTION_QUOTE</Tag>
		<English>"And on the pedestal these words appear: 'My name is Ozymandias, king of kings: Look on my works, ye Mighty, and despair!'"[PARAGRAPH:2]- Percy Bysshe Shelley, Ozymandias</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在台座上，有这样的话，说，我的名是诸王之王奥兹曼迪亚斯，你们这大能的绝望的人，当看我的作为〔段落：2〕- Percy Bysshe Shelley，奥兹曼迪斯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
