<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Civ4GameText>
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HITTITES_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>Hittie Empire</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>赫梯帝国</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HITTITES_PEOPLES</Tag>
		<English>Hittites People</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>赫梯诸部</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SUPPI</Tag>
		<English>Suppiluliuma</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>赫梯-苏庇路里乌玛一世</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_IRON_FORGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>About 2000 B.C. the Hittites appeared in northern Asia Minor, a region rich in iron. In 1650 B.C. the Hittites began building a powerful empire. They extended their control in Asia Minor, seized northern Syria from the Egyptians, and expanded into northern Mesopotamia, where they conquered the Babylonians. Hittite culture was greatly influenced by contacts with the Babylonians.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]While they were less advanced than the peoples of Mesopotamia, they had learned to extract iron from ore - they were the first to make tools and weapons of iron. The Hittites heated iron ore and pounded out impurities before plunging it into cold water. The tools and weapons they made with iron were harder and had sharper edges than those made out of bronze or copper. Because iron was plentiful, the Hittites were able to arm more people at less expense.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Hittites tried to keep this valuable technology secret. But as their empire collapsed about 1200 B.C., Hittite ironsmiths migrated to serve customers elsewhere. The new knowledge thus spread across Asia, Africa, and Europe, ushering in the Iron Age.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>大约在公元前2000年，赫梯人出现在小亚细亚北部，一个富含铁的地区。公元前1650年，赫梯人开始建立一个强大的帝国。他们扩大了对小亚细亚的控制，从埃及人手中夺取了叙利亚北部，并扩展到美索不达米亚北部，在那里他们征服了巴比伦人。赫梯人的文化在很大程度上受到了与巴比伦人接触的影响。虽然他们不如美索不达米亚的人民先进，但他们已经学会了从矿石中提取铁--他们是第一个用铁制造工具和武器的人。赫梯人将铁矿石加热并捣碎杂质，然后将其投入冷水中。他们用铁制造的工具和武器比用青铜或铜制造的工具和武器更坚硬，边缘更锋利。由于铁很丰富，赫梯人能够以较少的费用武装更多的人。[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]赫梯人试图对这项宝贵的技术保密。但随着他们的帝国在公元前1200年左右崩溃，赫梯人的铁匠们迁移到其他地方为顾客服务。新的知识因此在亚洲、非洲和欧洲传播开来，迎来了铁器时代。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HITTITES_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Hittites</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>赫梯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_KINGDOM_OF_PONTUS</Tag>
		<English>Kingdom of Pontus</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>本都王国</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HITTITES_DESC</Tag>
		<English>The Hittites</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>赫梯文明</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HITTITES_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Hittites</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>赫梯</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_SUPPI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Suppiluliuma I[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]King of the Hittites[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] c. 1350 BC[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Suppiluliuma I (Shuppiluliuma) was king of the Hittites (ca. 1358 BC - 1323 BC). He achieved fame as a great warrior and statesman, successfully challenging the then-dominant Egyptian empire for control of the lands between the Mediterranean and the Euphrates.[PARAGRAPH:2]Suppiluliuma began his career as advisor and general to Tudhaliya III, then based at Samuha. In this capacity he defeated the Hittites' enemies among the Hayasa and the Kaskas. Both enemies then united around charismatic leaders to counter him; of these Karanni founded a semblance of a royal court in Hayasa, and Piyapili failed to do likewise for the Kaska. Suppiluliuma and Tudhaliya defeated these threats in turn, to the extent that the Hittite court could settle in Hattusa again.[PARAGRAPH:2]At some point, Suppiluliuma deposed and probably murdered his liege. Some of the priests later reported this to Suppiluliumas's son, successor, and biographer Mursili II, holding it as an outstanding crime of the whole dynasty.[PARAGRAPH:2]Suppiluliuma married a sister to the Hayasan king Hukkana, and his daughter Muwatti to Maskhuiluwa of the Arzawan state Mira. He retook Arzawan territory as far as Hapalla. His most permanent victory was against the Mitanni kingdom, which he reduced to a client state under his son-in-law Shattiwazza. He was also a master builder of large stone structures decorated with stone reliefs. It was during his reign that concepts of the sacred nature of royal leaders developed.[PARAGRAPH:2]Suppiluliuma then took advantage of the tumultuous reign of the Pharaoh Akhenaten, and seized control of Egyptian territory in Syria, inciting many Egyptian vassals to revolt.[PARAGRAPH:2]His success encouraged the widow of the Egyptian king Nibhuruyira (usually identified with Akhenaten or Tutankhamun) to write to him, asking him to send one of his sons to be her husband and rule Egypt, since she had no heir and did not wish to marry a commoner. Suppliluliuma dispatched an ambassador to Egypt to investigate; he reported that the situation was accurately described, and the king decided to take advantage of this windfall; unfortunately, Prince Zannanza died on the way, and the marriage alliance never was consummated.[PARAGRAPH:2]Suppililiuma was furious at this turn at events and unleashed his armies against Egypt's vassal states in Canaan and Northern Syria capturing much territory.[PARAGRAPH:2]Unfortunately, many of the Egyptian prisoners carried a plague which would eventually ravage the Hittite heartland and lead to the deaths of both of Suppiluliuma I and his successor, Arnuwanda II.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Annals of Suppiluliuma, compiled after his death by his son Mursili II, is an important primary source for the 14th century BC. One of Suppiluliuma's letters, addressed to Akenaten, was preserved in the Amarna letters (EA 41) archive at Akhetaten. It expresses his hope that the good relations which existed between Egypt and Hatti under Akhenaten's father would continue into Akhenaten's new reign.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[H1]苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世[\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]赫梯国王[\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]在位：约公元前1350年[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]背景：[PARAGRAPH:1]苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世（Shuppiluliuma）是赫梯人的国王（约公元前1358年-前1323年）。他以伟大的战士和政治家的身份成名，成功地挑战了当时占统治地位的埃及帝国对地中海和幼发拉底河之间土地的控制。在这个职位上，他打败了赫梯人的敌人哈亚萨人和卡斯卡斯人。这两个敌人后来都团结在有魅力的领导人周围来对付他；其中卡兰尼在哈亚沙建立了一个类似于王室的法庭，而皮亚皮利也没能为卡斯卡做同样的事。苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世和Tudhaliya依次击败了这些威胁，以至于赫梯宫廷可以再次在哈图萨定居。 [PARAGRAPH:2]在某个时候，苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世废黜了他的主子，并可能谋杀了他的主子。一些祭司后来向苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世的儿子、继任者和传记作者穆尔西里二世报告了此事，认为这是整个王朝的突出罪行。 [PARAGRAPH:2]苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世把妹妹嫁给了哈亚山国王Hukkana，把女儿Muwatti嫁给了阿尔扎万国Mira的Maskhuiluwa。他重新占领了Arzawan的领土，一直到Hapalla。他最持久的胜利是对米坦尼王国的胜利，他把米坦尼王国降为他女婿沙提瓦扎手下的一个客户国家。他也是一位建造大型石质结构的大师，用石质浮雕进行装饰。正是在他的统治期间，王室领袖的神圣性概念得到了发展。[PARAGRAPH:2]随后，苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世利用法老Akhenaten的动荡统治，控制了埃及在叙利亚的领土，煽动许多埃及附庸造反。 [PARAGRAPH:2]他的成功鼓励了埃及国王尼布鲁伊拉（通常被认为是阿肯那顿或图坦卡蒙）的寡妇写信给他，要求他派他的一个儿子做她的丈夫，统治埃及，因为她没有继承人，也不希望嫁给一个平民。苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世派遣了一位大使到埃及进行调查；他报告说，情况描述得很准确，国王决定利用这笔意外之财；不幸的是，Zannanza王子在途中死亡，婚姻联盟从未完成。 [PARAGRAPH:2]苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世对这一事件的转变感到愤怒，发动军队攻打埃及在迦南和北叙利亚的附庸国，占领了许多领土。 [PARAGRAPH:2]不幸的是，许多埃及俘虏携带了一种瘟疫，最终蹂躏了赫梯人的心脏地带，并导致苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世 I和他的继任者Arnuwanda II的死亡。苏皮卢利乌玛斯一世那顿父亲时期埃及和哈提之间存在的良好关系能够持续到阿肯那顿的新统治时期。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_IRON_FORGE</Tag>
		<English>Iron Forge</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>铁匠铺</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_HITTITES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Hittites (Hebrew Hittim), were ancient people of Asia Minor and the Middle East, inhabiting the land of Hatti on the central plateau of what is now Anatolia, Turkey, and some areas of northern Syria. The Hittites, whose origin is unknown, spoke an Indo-European language. They invaded the region, which became known as Hatti, about 1900 bc and imposed their language, culture, and rule on the earlier inhabitants, a people speaking a non-Indo-European agglutinative language. The first town settled by the Hittites was Nesa, near present-day Kayseri, Turkey. Shortly after 1800 BC they conquered the town of Hattusas, near the site of present-day Bogazkale. Nothing more is known of Hittite history until, in the 17th century bc, the so-called Old Hittite Kingdom was founded by the Hittite leader Labarna (reigned about 1680-1650 bc), or Tabarna, and Hattusas became its capital. Labarna conquered nearly all of central Anatolia and extended his rule to the sea. His successors extended Hittite conquests into northern Syria. Mursili I (reigned about 1620-1590 bc), the second ruler after Labarna, conquered what is now ?alab (Aleppo), Syria, and raided Babylon about 1595 BC. Mursili?s assassination was followed by a period of internal strife and external weakness that ended during the reign of King Telipinu (reigned about 1525-1500 bc). To ensure the stability of the kingdom, he issued strict rules governing the royal succession. The law code may also have been compiled during his reign. Of Telipinu?s successors only the names are known.[PARAGRAPH:2]About 1450 BC the so-called New Hittite Kingdom was founded. One of its most important members, the royal prince Suppiluliuma (reigned about 1380-1346 bc), usurped the throne during a period of foreign invasions. After liberating his country and defeating his main enemy, the kingdom of Mitanni in northern Mesopotamia, he led his armies farther into Syria. There his conquests were made easier by a weakening of Egyptian power during the reign of the pharaoh Amenhotep IV, or Akhenaton. Thus the Hittite Kingdom under Suppiluliuma became a great empire rivaling the power of Egypt, Babylonia, and Assyria. After the death of Suppiluliuma, the Hittites were largely able to maintain their empire, although only by constant warfare. During the 15th and 14th centuries bc their holdings extended westward to the Aegean Sea, eastward into Armenia, southeastward into upper Mesopotamia, and southward into Syria as far as present-day Lebanon.[PARAGRAPH:2]During the last half of the 14th century bc, the Hittites continued to come into frequent conflict with Egypt. The two great powers struggled for control of Syria until a battle was fought in Kadesh, Syria, between the Hittite king Muwatalli (reigned about 1315-1296 bc) and the Egyptian pharaoh Ramses II. Although Ramses claimed a great victory, the Hittites continued to maintain their hold on Syria. The Hittite king Hattusili III (reigned about 1289-1265 bc) concluded a treaty of peace and alliance with Ramses years later and subsequently gave him his daughter in marriage. Thereafter, relations between the Hittites and Egyptians remained friendly until the Hittite Empire fell shortly after 1200 bc to invaders called the Sea Peoples in Egyptian records.[PARAGRAPH:2]The downfall of the empire was followed by confusion and conflict. Subsequently a number of Hittite city-states, the most famous of which was Carchemish, emerged in southeastern Anatolia and northern Syria. These states were peopled by an intermingled ethnic group, called Syro-Hittites, consisting primarily of the Hittites, of peoples from the former Hittite Empire, and the previous inhabitants of the two areas. The Syro-Hittite rulers used the Luwian language, in which hieroglyphics were employed for writing. Some of these city-states were conquered in the 10th century bc by the Aramaeans. Even after it was conquered, all of Syria was still called Hatti by the Assyrians. Both the city-states that were conquered by the Aramaeans and those that remained independent finally were made provinces of the Assyrian Empire under Sargon II about 715 bc.[PARAGRAPH:2]The primary sources of information about the Hittites came from Egyptian records, notably those of the 19th Dynasty, and from certain passages in the Bible. The earliest of these passages, calling the Hittites "Sons of Heth," possibly refers to the period of the Hittite Kingdom. Later passages allude to the Syro-Hittites.[PARAGRAPH:2]In 1906 the royal archives of the Hittites themselves were discovered in excavations at Bogazkale. These discoveries cast doubt on many items of information gathered from Egyptian sources. For example, certain military engagements were mentioned as victories for the Hittites, whereas the Egyptian records identify the engagements as Hittite defeats. The importance of the discovery is that the archives made it possible to decipher the Hittite language, thus revealing information about previously unknown aspects of the culture, such as political organization, legislation, religion, and literature.[PARAGRAPH:2]Most of the texts found in the archives were written in the Hittite language, but treaties and state letters were written in Akkadian, the international language of the period. Other texts were written in the Hurrian language of southeastern Anatolia and northern Mesopotamia, a language unrelated to any known linguistic group. The Hittites used the cuneiform system of writing taken from the Babylonians, but they also employed a system of hieroglyphs to inscribe a language closely related to Hittite, possibly a Luwian dialect. Although the hieroglyphs were used during the period of the empire, most inscriptions belong to the period after its downfall. The literature of the Hittites was highly developed, particularly in the form of historical records and stories.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Hittite king acted as the supreme priest, military commander, and chief judge of the land. During the old kingdom he was assisted by the pankus, an advisory council of nobles, which later disappeared. The empire was administered by provincial governors acting as deputies of the king. Territories beyond the empire were frequently ruled as vassal kingdoms, and formal treaties were made with their rulers.[PARAGRAPH:2]The most outstanding achievements of the Hittite civilization lay in the fields of legislation and the administration of justice. The law codes of the Hittites reveal a strong Babylonian influence, but their administration of justice was far more lenient than that of the Babylonians. The Hittites rarely resorted to the death penalty or to bodily mutilation, both of which were characteristic of other civilizations of the ancient Middle East. Furthermore, Hittite justice rested in the main on the principle of restitution rather than on retribution or vengeance. The penalty for thievery, for example, was restoration of the stolen object and payment of some additional recompense; restitution in kind was gradually replaced by payment of money.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Hittite economy was basically agricultural. The principal crops were wheat and barley, and the chief animals were cattle and sheep. The Hittites also had mineral riches in the form of copper, lead, silver, and iron. Their metallurgical techniques were advanced for the time; they may have been the first people to work iron.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Hittites worshiped a variety of gods. A recurrent phrase in state documents is an invocation to the "thousand gods of Hatti", deities worshiped apparently throughout Asia Minor before and during the period of Hittite domination. Scholars have traced Sumerian, Babylonian, Assyrian, Hurrian, Luwian, and other foreign influences in the Hittite pantheon.[PARAGRAPH:2]In the rock sanctuary of Yazilikaya, near Bogazkale, is a remarkable series of reliefs cut into rock. The reliefs depict two long processions of gods and goddesses advancing toward each other. The majority of the gods remain unidentified, but the two deities heading the procession are the storm god, or weather god, and the sun goddess, the chief deities worshiped by the Hittites. Excavations at the sanctuary revealed a temple built in front of one chamber; the other, smaller chamber seems to have been devoted to the cult of a deceased king.[PARAGRAPH:2]Hittite mythology, like Hittite religion, represents a combination of elements that reflect the diversity of cults within the empire. Of special interest are certain epic poems containing myths, originally Hurrian with Babylonian motifs. These myths deal with several successive generations of gods who ruled the universe and with a monster who challenged the rule of the last king of the gods. They are similar to Greek myths contained in the Theogony by the Greek poet Hesiod and may have been their prototypes. How the myths might have reached Greece is not clear, but it is possible they were transmitted during the Mycenaean ascendancy in Greece (1400-1200 bc). Mycenaean Greeks are known to have been in western Anatolia then and to have traded with Hittite-held Syria. Hittite records refer to contacts between Hittite rulers and those of the kingdom of Ahhiyawa, which some scholars identify with the country of the Achaeans. Whether or not Hittite cultural elements were transmitted abroad, many of them survived in Anatolia until the first Roman penetration into Asia Minor in 190 bc. Such deities as the Great Mother and the storm god (called Jupiter Dolichenus by the Romans) were still worshiped at that time.[PARAGRAPH:2]The art and architecture of the Hittites reveal the influence of nearly all the contemporary cultures of the ancient Near East, and especially of Babylonia. Nevertheless, the Hittites achieved a certain independence of style that renders their art distinct. Their building materials were generally stone and brick, but they also used wooden columns. Their often massive palaces, temples, and fortifications frequently were adorned by stylized and intricate carved reliefs on walls, gates, and entrances.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[TAB]赫梯人（希伯来语Hittim），是小亚细亚和中东的古代人，居住在现在土耳其安纳托利亚和叙利亚北部一些地区中央高原的哈蒂。赫梯人的起源不详，他们说的是印欧语。大约在公元前1900年，他们入侵了这个地区，这个地区被称为哈蒂，并将他们的语言、文化和统治强加给了早期的居民，即说非印欧粘着语言的民族。赫梯人定居的第一个城镇是奈萨，靠近今天的土耳其凯泽里。公元前1800年后不久，他们征服了哈图萨斯镇，该镇位于今天的博加兹卡勒遗址附近。直到公元前17世纪，所谓的旧赫梯王国由赫梯领导人拉巴纳（约公元前1680-1650年在位）或塔巴纳（Tabarna）建立，哈图萨斯（Hattusas）成为其首都，赫梯历史才为人所知。拉巴纳几乎征服了安纳托利亚中部的所有地区，并将其统治延伸至大海。他的继任者将赫梯人的征服扩展到叙利亚北部。穆西里一世（约公元前1620-1590年在位），拉巴纳之后的第二位统治者，征服了现在的世界？大约在公元前1595年，叙利亚阿拉布（阿勒颇）袭击了巴比伦。穆西里？在特利普努国王（约公元前1525-1500年在位）统治期间，一段内乱和外部软弱的时期结束了。为了确保王国的稳定，他颁布了严格的王室继承规定。《法典》也可能是在他的统治时期编纂的。泰利普努的？s的继任者只有名字是已知的。大约在公元前1450年，所谓的新赫梯王国建立了。其最重要的成员之一，苏皮卢利马王子（约公元前1380-1346年在位）在外国入侵期间篡夺了王位。在解放了他的国家并击败了他的主要敌人美索不达米亚北部的米坦尼王国后，他带领军队进一步进入叙利亚。在法老阿蒙霍特普四世（又名阿赫纳顿）统治期间，埃及权力的削弱使他的征服变得更加容易。因此，苏皮卢马统治下的赫梯王国成为了一个与埃及、巴比伦尼亚和亚述相抗衡的伟大帝国。苏皮卢马（Supiluliuma）去世后，赫梯人基本上能够维持他们的帝国，尽管只是通过不断的战争。在公元前15世纪和14世纪，他们的领地向西延伸至爱琴海，向东延伸至亚美尼亚，向东南延伸至上美索不达米亚，向南延伸至叙利亚，直至今天的黎巴嫩。[PARAGRAPH:2]在公元前14世纪后半叶，赫梯人继续频繁与埃及发生冲突。这两个大国为争夺叙利亚的控制权而斗争，直到赫梯国王穆瓦塔利（约公元前1315-1296年在位）和埃及法老拉美西斯二世在叙利亚的卡德什爆发战争。尽管拉美西斯声称取得了巨大的胜利，但赫梯人继续保持对叙利亚的控制。赫梯国王哈图西利三世（约公元前1289-1265年在位）多年后与拉美西斯签订了和平与结盟条约，随后将女儿嫁给了他。此后，赫梯人和埃及人之间的关系一直保持友好，直到公元前1200年后不久，赫梯帝国被埃及记录中称为海洋民族的入侵者攻陷。
[PARAGRAPH:2]帝国的垮台随之而来的是混乱和冲突。随后，安纳托利亚东南部和叙利亚北部出现了一些赫梯城邦，其中最著名的是卡切米什。这些州居住着一个称为锡罗赫人的混合民族，主要由赫梯人、前赫梯帝国的人以及这两个地区的前居民组成。锡罗赫梯统治者使用卢威语，用象形文字书写。其中一些城邦在公元前10世纪被亚拉姆人征服。即使被征服，整个叙利亚仍然被亚述人称为哈提。公元前715年左右，被亚兰人征服的城邦和最终保持独立的城邦都成为萨尔贡二世统治下的亚述帝国的省份。关于赫梯人的信息主要来源于埃及的记录，尤其是第19王朝的记录，以及圣经中的某些段落。这些经文中最早的一段称赫人为“赫人之子”，可能指的是赫人王国时期。后来的段落暗指锡罗赫梯人。1906年，在Bogazkale的发掘中发现了赫梯人的皇家档案。这些发现使人们对从埃及收集的许多信息产生了怀疑。例如，某些军事交战被称为赫人的胜利，而埃及的记录将这些交战确定为赫人的失败。这一发现的重要性在于，这些档案使解读赫梯语成为可能，从而揭示了有关该文化先前未知方面的信息，如政治组织、立法、宗教和文学。[PARAGRAPH:2]档案中发现的大多数文本都是用赫梯语写成的，但条约和国家信件都是用当时的国际语言阿卡迪亚语写成的。其他文本是用安纳托利亚东南部和美索不达米亚北部的胡里安语编写的，这种语言与任何已知的语言群体都无关。赫梯人使用取自巴比伦人的楔形文字系统，但他们也使用象形文字系统来刻写与赫梯人密切相关的语言，可能是卢威方言。虽然象形文字是在帝国时期使用的，但大多数铭文都属于帝国灭亡后的时期。赫梯人的文学高度发达，尤其是以历史记录和故事的形式。赫梯国王担任最高祭司、军事指挥官和国家首席法官。在旧王国时期，他得到了贵族顾问委员会pankus的协助，后来该委员会消失了。帝国由担任国王代表的省长管理。帝国以外的领土经常被作为附庸国统治，并与其统治者签订了正式条约。[PARAGRAPH:2]赫梯文明最杰出的成就在于立法和司法领域。赫梯人的法典显示出巴比伦人的强大影响力，但他们的司法比巴比伦人的司法要宽大得多。赫梯人很少诉诸死刑或身体残害，这两种都是古代中东其他文明的特征。此外，赫梯人的正义主要基于恢复原状的原则，而不是报复或复仇。例如，盗窃的惩罚是恢复被盗物品并支付一些额外的赔偿；实物赔偿逐渐被金钱支付所取代。[PARAGRAPH:2]赫梯人的经济基本上是农业经济。主要农作物是小麦和大麦，主要牲畜是牛羊。赫梯人也有铜、铅、银和铁等矿藏。他们的冶金技术是当时先进的；他们可能是第一批炼铁的人。
赫梯人崇拜各种各样的神。国家文件中经常出现的一个短语是对“哈蒂千神”的召唤，在赫人统治之前和统治期间，整个小亚细亚都在崇拜这些神。学者们追踪了苏美尔人、巴比伦人、亚述人、胡里安人、卢维安人和其他外国势力对赫梯万神殿的影响。[PARAGRAPH:2]在博加兹卡勒附近的亚兹利卡亚岩石保护区内，有一系列引人注目的雕刻成岩石的浮雕。浮雕描绘了两条长长的队伍，神灵和女神朝着对方前进。大多数神仍然身份不明，但游行队伍中的两位神是风暴神或天气神，以及赫梯人崇拜的主要神太阳女神。在圣殿的发掘中发现，在一个墓室前建有一座神庙；另一个较小的房间似乎是专门为已故国王举行的祭祀活动。[PARAGRAPH:2]赫梯神话与赫梯宗教一样，代表了反映帝国内部邪教多样性的元素组合。特别令人感兴趣的是某些包含神话的史诗，最初是带有巴比伦主题的胡里安史诗。这些神话涉及统治宇宙的几代神，以及挑战众神中最后一位国王统治的怪物。它们与希腊诗人赫西奥德（Hesiod）的神权论中所包含的希腊神话相似，可能是它们的原型。神话是如何传到希腊的尚不清楚，但有可能是在迈锡尼统治希腊期间（公元前1400-1200年）传播的。众所周知，迈锡尼希腊人当时在安纳托利亚西部，并与赫梯控制的叙利亚进行贸易。赫梯人的记录指的是赫梯统治者与阿希亚瓦王国统治者之间的接触，一些学者认为阿希亚瓦王国是阿契亚人的国家。无论赫梯文化元素是否传播到国外，其中许多都在安纳托利亚存活下来，直到公元前190年罗马人第一次渗透到小亚细亚。伟大的母亲和风暴神（罗马人称之为朱庇特·多利切诺斯）等神在当时仍然受到崇拜。赫人的艺术和建筑揭示了古代近东几乎所有当代文化的影响，尤其是巴比伦尼亚文化的影响。然而，赫梯人在风格上取得了一定的独立性，这使得他们的艺术与众不同。他们的建筑材料通常是石头和砖，但他们也使用木柱。他们的宫殿、寺庙和防御工事通常都是巨大的，墙壁、大门和入口上都有风格化的复杂雕刻浮雕装饰。[PARAGRAPH:2]</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
