<?xml version='1.0' encoding='GBK'?>
<Civ4GameText>
	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_OLM2</Tag>
		<English>Discover two of Arithmetics, Writing and Calendar by 400 BC</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>公元前400年前发现算数，文字，历法中的2项</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_OLM1_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>Mother Culture of Mesoamerica</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>中美洲文化起源</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UP_OLM</Tag>
		<English>Excess Food provides extra Commerce.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>多余的食物提供额外的商业</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OLMECS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Olmec were an ancient Pre-Columbian people living in the tropical lowlands of south-central Mexico, roughly in what are the modern-day states of Veracruz and Tabasco on the Isthmus of Tehuantepec. Their immediate cultural influence, however, extends far beyond this region. The Olmec flourished during the Formative (or Preclassic) period, dating from 1200 BC to about 400 BC, and are believed to have been the progenitor civilization of later Mesoamerican civilizations.[PARAGRAPH:2]Olmec history originated at its base within San Lorenzo Tenochtitl锟n, where distinctively Olmec features begin to emerge before 1200 BC. The rise of civilization here was probably assisted by the local ecology of well-watered rich alluvial soil, encouraging high maize production. This ecology may be compared to that of other ancient centers of civilization: the Nile, Indus, and Yellow River valleys, and Mesopotamia. It is thought that the dense population concentration at San Lorenzo encouraged the rise of an elite class that eventually ensured Olmec dominance and provided the social basis for the production of the symbolic and sophisticated luxury artifacts that define Olmec culture. Many of these luxury artifacts, such as jade, obsidian and magnetite, came from distant locations and suggest that early Olmec elites had access to an extensive trading network in Mesoamerica. The source of the most valued jade, for example, is found in the Motagua River valley in eastern Guatemala, and their obsidian is mainly from sources also in the Guatemala highlands, such as El Chayal and San Mart锟n Jilotepeque.[PARAGRAPH:2]The first Olmec center, San Lorenzo, was all but abandoned around 900 BC at about the same time that La Venta rose to prominence. Environmental changes may have been responsible for this move, with certain important rivers changing course. A wholesale destruction of many San Lorenzo monuments also occurred around this time, circa 950 BC, which may point to an internal uprising or, less likely, an invasion. Following the decline of San Lorenzo, La Venta became the most prominent Olmec center, lasting from 900 BC until its abandonment around 400 BC. During this period, the Great Pyramid and various other ceremonial complexes were built at La Venta.[PARAGRAPH:2]It is not known with any clarity what caused the eventual extinction of the Olmec culture. It is known that between 400 and 350 BC, population in the eastern half of the Olmec heartland dropped precipitously, and the area would remain sparsely inhabited until the 19th century. This depopulation was likely the result of environmental changes: perhaps the result of important rivers changing course or silting up due to agricultural practices. What ever the cause, within a few hundred years of the abandonment of the last Olmec cities, successor cultures had become firmly established. The Tres Zapotes site, on the western edge of the Olmec heartland, continued to be occupied well past 400 BC, but without the hallmarks of the Olmec culture. This post-Olmec culture, often labeled Epi-Olmec, has features similar to those found at Izapa, some 330 miles (550 km) to the southeast.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[TAB]W米克人是一个生活在墨西哥中南部热带低地的前哥伦布时代的人，大致生活在今天的特万特佩克地峡的韦拉克鲁斯州和塔巴斯科州。然而，他们的直接文化影响远远超出了这个地区。W米克文明在形成期（或前经典时期）蓬勃发展，可追溯到公元前1200年至公元前400年，被认为是后来中美洲文明的祖先文明[PARAGRAPH:2]W米克的历史起源于它在圣洛伦佐特诺奇蒂尔的基地，在那里独特的W米克特征在公元前1200年前开始出现。这里文明的兴起可能得益于当地的生态环境，那里有充足的水，肥沃的冲积土，鼓励了玉米的高产。这种生态可以与其他古代文明中心相比较：尼罗河、印度河、黄河流域和美索不达米亚。人们认为，圣洛伦佐的人口密集促使了精英阶层的崛起，这一阶层最终确保了W米克的统治地位，并为W米克文化的象征性和复杂的奢侈品的生产提供了社会基础。许多这些奢侈的文物，如玉石、黑曜石和磁铁矿，都来自遥远的地方，表明早期W米克精英有机会进入中美洲广泛的贸易网络。例如，最有价值的玉石来源于危地马拉东部的莫塔瓜河流域，它们的黑曜石主要来源于危地马拉高地，如El Chayal和San Martin Jilotepeque[PARAGRAPH:2]第一W米克中心，圣洛伦佐，大约在公元前900年左右，在拉文塔崛起的同一时期，几乎被遗弃。环境变化可能是造成这一变化的原因，一些重要河流改变了航道。大约在公元前950年左右，圣洛伦佐的许多纪念碑也发生了大规模的破坏，这可能意味着一场内部起义，或者不太可能是入侵。在圣洛伦佐衰落之后，拉文塔成为最著名的奥尔梅克中心，从公元前900年一直持续到公元前400年左右被遗弃。在此期间，大金字塔和其他各种仪式建筑都在拉文塔建造[PARAGRAPH:2]目前还不清楚是什么导致了W米克文化的最终灭绝。众所周知，在公元前400年至350年间，W米克中心地带东半部的人口急剧下降，直到19世纪，该地区的人口仍然稀少。这种人口减少很可能是环境变化的结果：也许是重要河流改道或由于农业活动而淤积的结果。不管是什么原因，在最后几座W米克城市被遗弃后的几百年里，后继者的文化已经牢固地建立起来。特雷斯萨波特斯遗址，位于W米克中心地带的西边，在公元前400年以后一直被占领，但没有W米克文化的特征。这种后W米克文化，通常被标记为Epi Olmec，其特征与在东南约330英里（550公里）的伊扎帕发现的类似。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_TEZCATLIPOCA</Tag>
		<English>Tezcatlipoca</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>W米克-泰斯卡塔利波卡</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_OLM1</Tag>
		<English>Build 4 culture-producing buildings by 400 BC</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>公元前400年前建成4个文化建筑</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OLMECS_ADJECTIVE</Tag>
		<English>Olmec</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>W米克</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_DOM_OLMECS</Tag>
		<English>It is the year 1600 BC. In the tropical lowlands near the Gulf of Mexico, population reaches the critical threshold for the formation of complex societies. This sixth cradle of civilization will see the rise of the Olmecs, forerunners to all Mesoamerican cultures.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>现在是公元前1600年。在墨西哥湾附近的热带低地，人口达到了形成复杂社会的关键门槛。这个文明的第六个摇篮将见证W米克人的崛起，他们是所有中美洲文化的先驱。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_VICTORY_CAPITAL_GREAT_ARTISTS</Tag>
		<English>Great Artists in capital: %d1 / %d2</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>首都已入驻的大艺术家：%d1 / %d2</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_VICTORY_CULTURE_BUILDINGS_BUILT</Tag>
		<English>Culture buildings built: %d1 / %d2</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>已建成的文化建筑：%d1 / %d2</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>AI_DIPLO_FIRST_CONTACT_LEADER_TEZCATLIPOCA_1</Tag>
		<English>Welcome to the Olmec heartland, [CT_NAME]. I am Tezcatlipoca, god-ruler of these lands. Shall I order my men to carve your likeness in stone?</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>欢迎来到W米克中心地带，[CT_NAME]。我是泰斯卡塔利波卡，这片土地的统治者。我可以命令我的人把你的肖像刻在石头上吗？</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_OLMEC_COLOSSAL_HEAD_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The best-recognized aspect of the Olmec civilzation are the enormous helmeted heads. As no known pre-Columbian text explains these, these impressive monuments have been the subject of much speculation. Once theorized to be ballplayers, it is now generally accepted that these heads are portraits of rulers. According to archaeologist David Grove, the unique elements in the headgear can also be recognized in headdresses of human figures on other Gulf Coast monuments, suggesting that these are personal or group symbols. The heads range in size from the Rancho La Cobata head, at 3.4 m high, to the pair at Tres Zapotes, at 1.47 m. It has been calculated that the largest heads weigh more than 20 tons.</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>[TAB]W米克文明最为人所知的方面是巨神头像。由于没有已知的前哥伦布时代的史料记载，这些令人印象深刻的纪念碑一直是许多猜测的主题。这些头像曾经被理论化为棒球运动员，现在人们普遍认为这些头像是统治者的肖像。根据考古学家大卫・格罗夫的说法，在其他墨西哥湾海岸纪念碑上的人物头饰中也能识别出头饰中的独特元素，这表明这些头饰是个人或群体的象征。从1米到4米的头部，这对猎头的重量超过了4米。</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_URV_POL2_TEOTL_OLMECS</Tag>
		<English>Settle three Great Artists in your capital</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>在你的首都入驻3个大艺术家</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_OLM3</Tag>
		<English>Be the first to discover Compass</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>率先发现罗盘</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OLMECS_DESC</Tag>
		<English>The Olmecs</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>W米克文明</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OLMECS_SHORT_DESC</Tag>
		<English>Olmecs</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>W米克</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UP_OLM_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>The Power of Nixtamal:</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>The Power of Nixtamal:</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_OLM3_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>A Magnetite Artifact</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>磁铁飞行器</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_OLMEC_COLOSSAL_HEAD</Tag>
		<English>Colossal Head</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>巨神头像(Colossal Head)</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OLMECS_DEFAULT</Tag>
		<English>%s2 City-States</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>%s2城邦</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UHV_OLM2_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>The Long Count Begins</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>长历纪年</Chinese>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIV_OLMECS_PEOPLES</Tag>
		<English>Peoples of the Gulf lowlands</English>
		<L1/><L2/><L3/><L4/>
		<Chinese>海湾低地人</Chinese>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
